xTuple ERP<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2008 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section979997" role="standard">
  <title id="Anchor61009">Topic: Submitting Reports and Jobs to the Batch
  Manager</title>
  <para>While the majority of xTuple ERP reports and other jobs run quickly
  and easily, some require more time to generate. In some cases, it may make
  sense to submit these longer, more complex reports or jobs to the xTuple ERP
  Batch Manager for processing. Submitting a job or report to the Batch
  Manager enables you to specify when the report or job should be run. For
  example, you can schedule the process to run during off-peak hours, when
  demand for server resources is lowest.</para>
  <note>
    <para>Some reports and jobs may place a heavy load on Server resources.
    Not only will these reports and jobs take extra time to generate, they may
    also slow down performance for other users attached to the same
    Server.</para>
  </note>
  <section id="Section980001">
    <title>Submitting Reports</title>
    <para>To understand how reports are sent to the Batch Manager, consider
    the I/M Module report "Time-Phased Item Usage Statistics by Item," as
    shown below:</para>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_tpItemStats.png" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>I/M Report: Time-Phased Item Usage Statistics by
          Item</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <note>
      <para>For details on installing and setting up the Batch Manager at your
      site, please see the Batch Manager documentation available in the
      Downloads area of the xTuple community website.</para>
    </note>
    <para>This is a report with the potential to place a heavy load on Server
    resources. As you can see in the screen shot, the report is asking the
    Database to provide all records of Item Usage for Item Number COPY21 over
    the past three years. If this is a routinely used Item, the records
    indicating Item usage could be extensive.</para>
    <para>So, rather than run the report immediately by selecting the PRINT
    button, it might be wiser to schedule the report for printing during
    off-peak hours. To schedule an alternate time for generating the report,
    select the SUBMIT button. The following screen will appear:</para>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_submitReportBatch.png" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Submit Report to Batch Manager</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>When submitting a report to the Batch Manager for printing, you are
    presented with the following options:</para>
    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Scheduled</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>Specify when you would like the report to be run.</para>
          <variablelist>
            <varlistentry>
              <term>ASAP</term>
              <listitem>
                <para>Select to have the report run as soon as
                possible.</para>
              </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
              <term>Scheduled</term>
              <listitem>
                <para>Schedule a date and time to run the report. Specify a
                date in the first field using a standard date format. Use the
                arrow buttons in the second field to specify a time of
                day.</para>
              </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
          </variablelist>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Document Name</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>Displays the name of the report being submitted to the Batch
          Manager.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Email From</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>Enter the email address of the person who is sending the
          email. The Batch Manager will print the report to .PDF format and
          then email it to the person whose email address appears in the
          "Response Email To" field.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Response Email To</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>Enter the email address where you want the report to be sent
          once it has been generated and printed. The recipient will receive
          an email with the submitted report attached in.PDF format.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Response Body</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>Enter text to be included in the body of the email sent to the
          recipient.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
    <note>
      <para>When a report or other job is submitted to the Batch Manager with
      a scheduled time of ASAP, the Batch Manager sets the scheduled time to
      the current time. However, a job will not necessarily be run immediately
      if it is scheduled for the current time. Any pre-existing jobs with
      scheduled times prior to the current time must be completed first. In
      other words, ASAP jobs will not necessarily be run immediately.
      Previously scheduled jobs will be run first.</para>
    </note>
    <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
    available:</para>
    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>CANCEL</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>Closes the screen without generating a report, returning you
          to the application desktop.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>SUBMIT</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>Submits the report to the Batch Manager, using the specified
          parameters.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
  </section>
  <section id="Section980032">
    <title>Submitting Jobs</title>
    <para>To understand how jobs are sent to the Batch Manager, consider the
    P/D Module job "Update Actual Costs by Class Code," as shown below:</para>
    <tip>
      <para>If you schedule an MRP or MPS job submitted to the Batch Manager
      to run on a periodic basis&mdash;daily, weekly, monthly&mdash;the cutoff
      date used for the run will automatically be updated by the number of
      days in the specified reschedule interval (Day = +1, Week = +7, and
      Month = +30).</para>
    </tip>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_batchUpdateActual.png" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Update Actual Costs by Class Code</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <note>
      <para>For details on installing and setting up the Batch Manager at your
      site, please see the Batch Manager documentation available in the
      Downloads area of the xTuple community website.</para>
    </note>
    <para>This is a job with the potential to place a heavy load on Server
    resources. As you can see in the screen shot, the job is asking the
    Database to update all Actual Costs for all Class Codes. If there are
    hundreds or thousands of Items on file, the amount of work required to
    complete this request could be extensive.</para>
    <para>So, rather than run the job immediately by selecting the UPDATE
    button, it might be wiser to schedule the job for processing during
    off-peak hours. To schedule an alternate time for processing the job,
    select the SUBMIT button. The following screen will appear:</para>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_submitJobBatch.png" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Submit Job to Batch Manager</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>When submitting a job to the Batch Manager for processing, you are
    presented with the following options:</para>
    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Action</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>Displays the name of the job being submitted to the Batch
          Manager.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Response Email</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>Enter the email address where you want notification that the
          job is complete to be sent once it has been completed. The recipient
          will receive an email letting them know the submitted job has been
          completed.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Scheduled</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>Specify when you would like the job to be run.</para>
          <variablelist>
            <varlistentry>
              <term>ASAP</term>
              <listitem>
                <para>Select to have the job run as soon as possible.</para>
              </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
              <term>Scheduled</term>
              <listitem>
                <para>Schedule a date and time to run the job. Specify a date
                in the first field using a standard date format. Use the arrow
                buttons in the second field to specify a time of day.</para>
              </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
          </variablelist>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
    <note>
      <para>When a report or other job is submitted to the Batch Manager with
      a scheduled time of ASAP, the Batch Manager sets the scheduled time to
      the current time. However, a job will not necessarily be run immediately
      if it is scheduled for the current time. Any pre-existing jobs with
      scheduled times prior to the current time must be completed first. In
      other words, ASAP jobs will not necessarily be run immediately.
      Previously scheduled jobs will be run first.</para>
    </note>
    <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
    available:</para>
    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>CANCEL</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>Closes the screen without submitting the job, returning you to
          the application desktop.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>SUBMIT</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>Submits the job to the Batch Manager, using the specified
          parameters.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
  </section>
</section>