<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section672209">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>topics</primary>
      <secondary>count tag basics</secondary>
    </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>count tags</primary>
      <secondary>explained</secondary>
    </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>count slips</primary>
      <secondary>explained</secondary>
    </indexterm>Topic: Count Tag Basics</title>
  <para id="Para672210">Count Tags are used to spearhead Inventory counts. If
  you are involved with Inventory counting, then you need to understand how
  Count Tags work. In this section, we cover Count Tag basics--from creating,
  to entering, to posting Count Tags.</para>
  <note>
    <para id="Para672212">The difference between Count Tags and Cycle Count
    Tags relates to the manner in which each is created. Count Tags, which are
    the subject of this section, are created manually. Cycle Count Tags, on
    the other hand, are created as the result of a Cycle Count request. To
    learn more about Cycle Counting, see the section dedicated to that
    topic.</para>
  </note>
  <section id="Section672214">
    <title><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>count tags</primary>
        <secondary>mechanics of</secondary>
      </indexterm>Creating Count Tags</title>
    <para id="Para672215">For this exercise, let's imagine we want to count
    Item B1, which is located in Warehouse WEST. To begin, we need to create a
    Count Tag for this Item/Warehouse combination, as shown in the following
    screen:</para>
    <para id="Para672219"><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_createCTbyItem.png"
                       id="Graphic672217" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption672220">Create Count Tag by Item</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18ed568">
        <para id="Para672221">Item Number: Enter the Item Number of the Item
        we want to create a Count Tag for--namely, Item B1.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18ed58c">
        <para id="Para672222">Warehouse: Selected WEST.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18ed5b0">
        <para id="Para672223">Mark Created Count Tag as Priority: Selected.
        Count Tags marked as having priority status are listed first in any
        prioritized lists. For example, priority Count Tags will appear at the
        top of the Count Tag Edit List; whereas, non-priority Count Tags will
        appear at the bottom of the list.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18ed5d4">
        <para id="Para672224">Freeze Inventory: Selected. We are specifying
        that Inventory be frozen while we are counting Item B1. Freezing
        Inventory during the Inventory counting process helps preserve the
        integrity of Quantity on Hand (QOH) values. For more information on
        freezing and thawing, see the section devoted to freezing and
        thawing.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18ed5f8">
        <para id="Para672225">Comments: This is a scrolling text field with
        word-wrapping for entering comments related to the Count Tag. Use the
        Comments field to enter any instructions or other comments that need
        to reach and be read by Inventory counters.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para id="Para672226">Once our parameters have been entered, we are ready
    to select the CREATE TAG button. Doing so will create our Count Tag. To
    verify the Count Tag has been created, we open the Count Tag Edit List.
    Sure enough, the Count Tag does appear on the list, as shown in the
    following screenshot:</para>
    <para id="Para672230"><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_cntTagEditList-1.png"
                       id="Graphic672228" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption672231">Count Tag Edit List Showing Count
          Tag</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <note>
      <para id="Para672233">Count Tag Numbers are generated automatically by
      the system in a sequential pattern, using specifications entered on the
      Warehouse master. Within the Warehouse master you can specify both the
      prefix to be used by Count Tags created in the given Warehouse (e.g.,
      WEST) and also the starting point for the numeric sequence.</para>
    </note>
  </section>
  <section id="Section672235">
    <title><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>count tags</primary>
        <secondary>mechanics of</secondary>
      </indexterm>Entering Count Quantities</title>
    <para id="Para672236">Okay, let's assume we have now physically gone into
    Warehouse WEST and counted Item B1. Our count discovered 635 units on
    hand. We are now ready to open the Count Tag and enter our Inventory count
    total. To open the Count Tag, either double-click on it or highlight it
    and then select the EDIT button. The Count Tag entry screen opens up, as
    shown in the following screenshot:</para>
    <para id="Para672240"><anchor id="Anchor21825" role="Cross-Ref"
    xreflabel="21825: Figure: Figure 4.3:  Enter Count Tag Details" />
    <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_enterCntTag-1.png"
                       id="Graphic672238" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption672242">Enter Count Tag Details</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para id="Para672243">In the "Count Qty." field we enter 635. This is the
    Quantity on Hand (QOH) we discovered during our Inventory count.
    Interestingly, the system is showing a different QOH for Item B1 in
    Warehouse WEST. If you look closely at <link endterm="Anchor21825"
    id="XRef672245" linkend="Anchor21825"> Enter Count Tag
    Details</link>Figure 6.90, you can see the system believes there are 640
    units on hand. Inventory discrepancies such as this can arise from a
    number of different causes--from undocumented Scrap transactions, to
    pilferage, etc. The important point is that by entering and posting a
    Count Tag with current physical Inventory information, you can update the
    system and revise QOH totals.</para>
    <note>
      <para id="Para672248">Count Tags may also be entered by selecting the
      "Enter Count Tag" option from the Physical Inventory submenu.</para>
    </note>
    <para id="Para672249">Continuing on, we go ahead and enter a comment to
    associate with the Count Tag. This comment, which is optional, may contain
    any information you want to associate with the Count Tag. We are now ready
    to select the SAVE button. As you can see in the following screenshot, the
    count total is now registered on the Count Tag Edit List:</para>
    <para id="Para672253"><anchor id="Anchor86804" role="Cross-Ref"
    xreflabel="86804: Figure: Figure 4.4:  Count Tag Details in Edit List" />
    <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_cntTagEditList-2.png"
                       id="Graphic672251" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption672255">Count Tag Details in Edit List</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
  </section>
  <section id="Section672257">
    <title><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>inventory</primary>
        <secondary>variances identified</secondary>
      </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>count tags</primary>
        <secondary>variances and</secondary>
      </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>cycle counts</primary>
        <secondary>variances and</secondary>
      </indexterm>Inventory Variances Identified</title>
    <para id="Para672260">Looking at <link endterm="Anchor86804"
    id="XRef672259" linkend="Anchor86804"> Count Tag Details in Edit
    List</link>Figure 6.91, you see that the QOH discrepancy has created a
    negative Inventory Asset variance. The Count Tag Edit List is a good
    starting point for identifying and tracking these discrepancies. Note that
    the list gives you the ability to highlight records when variances exceed
    either a monetary value or percentage you define. When a record is
    highlighted, it will be easy to locate because it will display in red
    type. Inventory Asset variances--if they exist--will also post to the
    General Ledger when Count Tags are posted, providing yet another starting
    point for investigating discrepancies.</para>
    <tip>
      <para id="Para672263">If you want to change the count quantity for a
      Count Tag prior to posting it, simply open the Count Tag for
      editing.</para>
    </tip>
    <para id="Para672264">Before we post this Count Tag, let's take a quick
    look at the I/M Module display Quantities on Hand by Item to verify the
    QOH total we"re seeing on the Count Tag Edit List. As expected, the
    following screen shows us a QOH of 640 for Item B1 in Warehouse
    WEST:</para>
    <para id="Para672268"><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_qohBeforeCntTag-1.png"
                       id="Graphic672266" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption672269">QOH Before Count Tag Posted</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
  </section>
  <section id="Section672271">
    <title><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>count tags</primary>
        <secondary>posting of explained</secondary>
      </indexterm>Posting Count Tags</title>
    <para id="Para672272">We are now ready to post our Count Tag and update
    the system record. After highlighting our Count Tag on the Count Tag Edit
    List, we select the POST button. The following screen appears:</para>
    <para id="Para672276"><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_postCntTag-1.png"
                       id="Graphic672274" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption672277">Post Count Tag</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <note>
      <para id="Para672279">Count Tags can be posted in several ways. You can
      post them individually from the Count Tag Edit List. Or you can post
      them in batches, using the Post Count Tags utility found on the Physical
      Inventory submenu.</para>
    </note>
    <para id="Para672280">Looking at the Post Count Tag screen, we see our
    count total and the comment we associated with the Count Tag. If we need
    to include an additional comment--for whatever reason--we may do so at
    this point. Notice that the option "Thaw Inventory" is selected. If you
    recall, we elected to freeze Inventory at the time we created the Count
    Tag. Now that our count is complete, we want to be sure to thaw Inventory
    so QOH for the Item will be updated appropriately. For more information on
    freezing and thawing, see the section dedicated to that topic.</para>
    <para id="Para672281">The final step is to post the Count Tag. To do so,
    we select the POST COUNT button. Posting a Count Tag removes the Tag from
    the Count Tag Edit List. And, as you can see from the following screen
    shot, Quantity on Hand for the Item is also updated to reflect the Count
    Tag total:</para>
    <para id="Para672285"><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_qohAfterCntTag-1.png"
                       id="Graphic672283" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption672286">QOH After Count Tag Posted</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
  </section>
  <section id="Section672288">
    <title><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>count slips</primary>
        <secondary>mechanics of</secondary>
      </indexterm>Entering Count Slips</title>
    <para id="Para672289">We have seen how to post an Inventory count total
    using a Count Tag. Now let's repeat the same process, but add Count Slips
    into the mix. If Count Tags are the parents, then Count Slips are the
    children. Count Slips are used to contribute Inventory count totals to a
    Count Tag.</para>
    <para id="Para672290">To begin, we will create another Count Tag, using
    the same Item/Warehouse combination used in the previous example. The
    following screenshot of the Count Tag Edit List shows both the
    newly-created Count Tag and also the "Enter Count Slip" option selected
    from the right-click menu:</para>
    <para id="Para672294"><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_enterCntSlip-1.png"
                       id="Graphic672292" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption672295">Count Slip Option on Count Tag Edit
          List</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para id="Para672296">As this next scenario will show, having the ability
    to contribute count subtotals from various sources can be extremely
    useful. Selecting the "Enter Count Slip" option brings up the Count Slip
    interface, as shown in the following screen:</para>
    <para id="Para672300"><anchor id="Anchor71986" role="Cross-Ref"
    xreflabel="71986: Figure: Figure 4.9:  Enter Count Slip Details" />
    <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_enterCntSlip-2.png"
                       id="Graphic672298" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption672302">Enter Count Slip Details</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <note>
      <para id="Para672304">Unlike Count Tags, Count Slips do not have to be
      created before they can be entered.</para>
    </note>
    <para id="Para672307">As you can see in <link endterm="Anchor71986"
    id="XRef672306" linkend="Anchor71986"> Enter Count Slip
    Details</link>Figure 6.96, the Enter Count Slip screen presents us with a
    range of information and options. For the purpose of this exercise, we
    will enter the following:</para>
    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para672309">Count Tag #</term>
        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18edcb8">
          <para>Displays the Count Tag Number (WEST65) of the parent Count
          Tag.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para672310">Item Number</term>
        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18edd00">
          <para>Displays the Item Number (B1) of the Item being
          counted.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para672311">Warehouse</term>
        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18edd48">
          <para>Displays the Warehouse (WEST) where the count is being
          conducted.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para672312">Counted Qty. TD</term>
        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18edd90">
          <para>No count quantities have been entered to-date for this Count
          Tag. But if any had been entered previously, the count quantity
          total would display here.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para672313">Slip #</term>
        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18eddd8">
          <para>Entered 100 to identify this first Count Slip. As we will see
          below, restrictions may apply to Count Slip Numbers.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para672314">Slip Qty</term>
        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18ede20">
          <para>Entered 250. This is the count total discovered in Location
          RACK01. Our next step will be to enter a Slip quantity for the other
          Location in Warehouse WEST.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para672315">Location</term>
        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18ede68">
          <para>Specified Location RACK01. Because Item B1 is a Multiple
          Location Control (MLC) Item, we will be entering a separate Count
          Slip for each of the two Locations where the Item is stored.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para672316">Lot/Serial #</term>
        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18edeb0">
          <para>Nothing displayed. If Item B1 were a Lot/Serial Item,
          Lot/Serial Numbers associated with the specified Location would
          display here.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para672317">Comments</term>
        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18edef8">
          <para>Entered comment related to the Count Slip. In this case, the
          person who performed the count on Location RACK01 (i.e., Bob),
          entered a comment and also identified himself.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
    <para id="Para672318">Once all the required information has been entered,
    we select the SAVE button to add the Count Slip total to the parent Count
    Tag.</para>
    <note>
      <para id="Para672320">Count Slips may also be entered by selecting the
      "Enter Count Slip" option from the Physical Inventory submenu.</para>
    </note>
  </section>
  <section id="Section672322">
    <title><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>count tags</primary>
        <secondary>configuration options for</secondary>
      </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>count slips</primary>
        <secondary>configuration options for</secondary>
      </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>configuration</primary>
        <secondary>for inventory counts</secondary>
      </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>inventory</primary>
        <secondary>cycle count configuration</secondary>
      </indexterm>Configuration Options</title>
    <para id="Para672323">So far, we have only counted one Location: RACK01.
    Item B1 is also stored in Location RACK02. Counting Inventory at that
    Location falls to another employee (i.e., Sandra). As before, the employee
    enters the required information on the Count Slip. However, when she
    attempts to save the Count Slip quantity to the Count Tag total, she
    encounters the following error message:</para>
    <para id="Para672327"><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_cntSlipError.png"
                       id="Graphic672325" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption672328">Duplicate Count Slip Error
          Message</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para id="Para672329">As the message indicates, the system has been
    configured to disallow duplicate Count Slip Numbers. To correct the
    problem, the employee must return to the Enter Count Slip screen and enter
    a unique Count Slip Number.</para>
    <note>
      <para id="Para672331">By default, OpenMFG allows only one unposted Count
      Tag per Item Site. If an unposted Count Tag already exists for an Item
      Site, then an additional duplicate Count Tag may not be added.</para>
    </note>
    <para id="Para672332">OpenMFG provides a range of possible configurations
    for the I/M Module, many of which have an impact on Count Tag processing.
    The following screen shows the Configure I/M options found within the
    System Module:</para>
    <para id="Para672336"><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_configIM.png" id="Graphic672334" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption672337">I/M Module Configuration
          Options</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para id="Para672338">For our purposes, we are only going to concern
    ourselves with the configuration options related to Count Tags and Count
    Slips. You or your OpenMFG administrator may select from the following
    options to establish the default behavior for your site:</para>
    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para672340"><indexterm significance="normal">
            <primary>count tags</primary>
            <secondary>count slip discrepancies and</secondary>
          </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
            <primary>count slips</primary>
            <secondary>count tag discrepancies and</secondary>
          </indexterm>When Count Tag Qty. exceeds Slip Qty</term>
        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18fa048">
          <para>Select one of the following options for handling discrepancies
          in count quantities:</para>
          <para id="Para672341">Post Difference to Default Location, if any -
          Select to post excess Count Tag quantity to an Item's default
          location if the Item's Count Tag quantity exceeds its Count Slip
          quantity. Applies only if a default location has been defined for
          the Item. Default locations are defined for an Item in the Item Site
          section of the I/M Module.</para>
          <para id="Para672342">Do Not Post Count Tag - Select to prevent
          Count Tag quantity from being posted if it exceeds the Item's Count
          Slip quantity.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para672344"><indexterm significance="normal">
            <primary>count slips</primary>
            <secondary>auditing of</secondary>
          </indexterm>Count Slip # Auditing</term>
        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18fa0d8">
          <para>Select one of the following Count Slip number auditing
          methods:</para>
          <para id="Para672345">No Slip # Checks, allow Duplications - Allows
          any Count Slip numbers to be used. Duplicate Count Slip numbers will
          also be allowed.</para>
          <para id="Para672346">Disallow Unposted Slip # Duplications within a
          Warehouse - Prevents duplicate "Unposted" Count Slip numbers from
          existing within a given Warehouse. However, duplicate "Unposted"
          Count Slip numbers may exist within multiple Warehouses.</para>
          <para id="Para672347">Disallow All Unposted Slip # Duplications -
          Prevents duplicate "Unposted" Count Slip numbers from existing
          within multiple Warehouses.</para>
          <para id="Para672348">Disallow All Slip # Duplications within a
          Warehouse - Prevents duplicate Count Slip numbers from existing
          within a given Warehouse. However, duplicate Count Slip numbers may
          exist within multiple Warehouses.</para>
          <para id="Para672349">Disallow All Slip # Duplications - Prevents
          duplicate Count Slip Numbers from existing within multiple
          Warehouses.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
    <para id="Para672350">Getting back to our scenario, the employee corrects
    the Count Slip Number problem and successfully saves the Count Slip
    quantity to the Count Tag total. In the next screen, you can see the Count
    Tag Edit List with both Count Slips displayed:</para>
    <para id="Para672354"><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_cntSlipEditList-1.png"
                       id="Graphic672352" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption672355">Count Tag Edit List with Unposted Count
          Slips</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <tip>
      <para id="Para672357">To display Count Slips associated with a Count Tag
      record, select the "Show Count Slips" option on the Count Tag Edit List.
      If the Count Slips do not appear at first, be sure to select the QUERY
      button.</para>
    </tip>
  </section>
  <section id="Section672359">
    <title><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>count slips</primary>
        <secondary>edit list for</secondary>
      </indexterm>Count Slip Edit List</title>
    <para id="Para672360">Just as Count Tags have their own edit list, Count
    Slips also have an edit list. To access the Count Slip Edit List,
    highlight a Count Tag record and open the right-click menu. The following
    screenshot shows the Count Slip Edit List:</para>
    <para id="Para672364"><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_cntSlipEditList-2.png"
                       id="Graphic672362" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption672365">Count Slip Edit List</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para id="Para672366">From the Count Slip Edit List, you can edit, post,
    and delete Count Slips--or create new ones. As you can see, the list
    provides detailed information about each Count Slip record. For this
    exercise, we will be posting both of our Count Slips from this
    screen.</para>
    <para id="Para672367">To verify that the Count Slips are showing as posted
    on the Count Tag Edit List, we return to that screen. Sure enough, the
    Count Slips are showing as posted:</para>
    <para id="Para672371"><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_cntTagEditList-3.png"
                       id="Graphic672369" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption672372">Count Tag Edit List with Posted Count
          Slips</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para id="Para672373">To review, then, we have used Count Slips to collect
    Inventory quantities from a variety of different Locations using different
    employees. As we have shown, Count Slips enable you to divide up the task
    of Inventory counting. You can use multiple employees and multiple Count
    Slips, yet have all count quantities applied to a single Count Tag.</para>
    <para id="Para672374">Now that all Count Slip quantities have been
    collected, we are ready to post our Count Tag, as shown in the following
    screenshot:</para>
    <para id="Para672378"><anchor id="Anchor71186" role="Cross-Ref"
    xreflabel="71186: Figure: Figure 4.15:  Post Count Tag with Count Slip Comments" />
    <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_postCntTag-2.png"
                       id="Graphic672376" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption672380">Post Count Tag with Count Slip
          Comments</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para id="Para672383">As <link endterm="Anchor71186" id="XRef672382"
    linkend="Anchor71186"> Post Count Tag with Count Slip
    Comments</link>Figure 6.102 shows, the cumulative count quantity is
    displaying as expected. In the Current Comments field we see the Count
    Slip comments posted by each of our employees. Again, we want to be sure
    to thaw the Inventory at posting. Finally, we simply select the POST COUNT
    button, and the system is now updated with the most current QOH
    information for Item B1 in Warehouse WEST.</para>
  </section>
  <section id="Section672386">
    <title><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>count tags</primary>
        <secondary>mechanics of</secondary>
      </indexterm>Creating Multiple Count Tags</title>
    <para id="Para672387">Throughout this example, we have focused on the
    creation of single Count Tags. But OpenMFG also enables you to create
    manual Count Tags in batches. To see how this is done, we open the Create
    Count Tags by Class Code utility, as shown in the following screen:</para>
    <para id="Para672391"><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_createCTbyClass.png"
                       id="Graphic672389" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption672392">Create Count Tags by Class
          Code</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para id="Para672393">For this scenario, we will be creating Count Tags
    for all Items belonging to Class Code Books located in Warehouse WEST. A
    comment is entered, and then we then select the CREATE TAGS option. To see
    the resulting Count Tags, we once again open the Count Tag Edit
    List:</para>
    <para id="Para672397"><anchor id="Anchor70270" role="Cross-Ref"
    xreflabel="70270: Figure: Figure 4.17:  Count Tags Created by Class Code" />
    <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_cntTagEditList-4.png"
                       id="Graphic672395" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption672399">Count Tags Created by Class
          Code</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para id="Para672402">As you can see in <link endterm="Anchor70270"
    id="XRef672401" linkend="Anchor70270"> Count Tags Created by Class
    Code</link>Figure 6.104, multiple Count Tags have been created--one for
    each of the Items fitting our criteria. These Count Tags can now be
    processed using the basic techniques described throughout this
    example.</para>
  </section>
</section>