<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section672757">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>topics</primary>
      <secondary>cycle counting</secondary>
    </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>cycle count tags</primary>
      <secondary>explained</secondary>
    </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>cycle counts</primary>
      <secondary>explained</secondary>
    </indexterm>Topic: Cycle Counting</title>
  <para id="Para672758">If you need to count Inventory on a regular basis,
  then you will need to know how to perform Cycle Counts. Let's start with a
  definition: A Cycle Count is a periodic issue of a Count Tag to count
  Inventory quantity within an Item Site. The "periodic" aspect of Cycle
  Counting will be the focus of this section.</para>
  <tip>
    <para id="Para672760">You may find it useful to refer also to the section
    dedicated to Count Tags, where the mechanics of Count Tag processing are
    discussed in more detail.</para>
  </tip>
  <section id="Section672762">
    <title><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>cycle counts</primary>
        <secondary>by class code explained</secondary>
      </indexterm>Cycle Counting by Class Code</title>
    <para id="Para672763">To begin, let's create a scenario in which we have a
    Warehouse called "WEST" and a Class Code called "Books". Our aim will be
    to Cycle Count all the Items belonging to Class Code Books located in
    Warehouse WEST. The following screenshot shows the Item Sites we will be
    Cycle Counting:</para>
    <para id="Para672767"><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_itemSitesWest.png" id="Graphic672765"/>
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption672768">Item Sites in WEST Warehouse</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para id="Para672769">It just so happens that all the Items located in
    Warehouse WEST also belong to Class Code Books. The next thing to do is to
    see whether any Count Tags already exist for these Item Sites. To check on
    pre-existing Count Tags, we open the Count Tag Edit List and specify our
    Warehouse/Class Code combination. After selecting the QUERY button, we see
    that no Count Tags currently exist for this combination, as shown in the
    following screenshot:</para>
    <para id="Para672773"><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_cycleEditList-1.png" id="Graphic672771"/>
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption672774">Empty Count Tag Edit List</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para id="Para672775">Before we create the Count Tags for our Items in
    Warehouse WEST, let's first understand the underlying issues involved with
    Cycle Counting.</para>
    <note>
      <para id="Para672777">Cycle Count Tags are the Count Tags created when a
      Cycle Count is performed.</para>
    </note>
  </section>
  <section id="Section672779">
    <title><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>cycle counts</primary>
        <secondary>frequency of</secondary>
      </indexterm>Cycle Count Frequency</title>
    <para id="Para672780">First of all, we need to look at Cycle Count
    frequency settings. These settings indicate how frequently an Item Site
    should be Cycle Counted. For example, if the Cycle Count frequency for an
    Item Site is set to "30", this indicates the Item Site should be Cycle
    Counted every 30 days; if the setting is "5", the Item Site should be
    Cycle Counted every 5 days, etc. The following screenshot shows the Item
    Site master for Item B1, one of our target Items:</para>
    <para id="Para672784"><anchor id="Anchor43066" role="Cross-Ref" xreflabel="43066: Figure: Figure 4.3:  Cycle Count Frequency for Item in WEST Warehouse"/>
    <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_itemSiteB1.png" id="Graphic672782"/>
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption672786">Cycle Count Frequency for Item in WEST
          Warehouse</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para id="Para672789">As you can see in <xref endterm="Anchor43066" linkend="Anchor43066"/>
    FINDME
  Figure 6.108, the Cycle Count frequency for Item B1
    is set to "1". This means the Item Site should be Cycle Counted on a daily
    basis. In fact, all our target Items in Warehouse WEST share the same
    frequency setting. They are all due to be Cycle Counted every day.</para>
    <tip>
      <para id="Para672792">A Cycle Count frequency must be specified on an
      Item Site master for Cycle Count Tags to be created. If no Cycle Count
      frequency is specified, no Cycle Count Tags will be created when the
      Create Cycle Count Tags utility is run.</para>
    </tip>
    <para id="Para672793">You might well ask: How do I manage my Cycle Count
    due dates? Or, How can I keep track of when Item Sites were last counted?
    The answer is that OpenMFG monitors this information for you. Take a look
    at the next screenshot, which shows the I/M Module display Item Sites by
    Class Code:</para>
    <para id="Para672797"><anchor id="Anchor40341" role="Cross-Ref" xreflabel="40341: Figure: Figure 4.4:  Last Counted Dates for Target Item Sites"/>
    <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_cycleSitesByClass-1.png" id="Graphic672795"/>
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption672799">Last Counted Dates for Target Item
          Sites</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para id="Para672800">The Item Sites by Class Code display is one of a
    series of I/M Module displays dedicated to rendering Item Site
    information. As you can see in <xref endterm="Anchor40341" linkend="Anchor40341"/>
    FINDME
  Figure 6.109, we are displaying all Item Sites in Warehouse
    WEST belonging to Class Code Books. Not only do we see Item Numbers and
    Item Descriptions, but to the right of the screen we also see a column
    labeled "Last Cnt"d." This column displays the date when a given Item Site
    was last counted. OpenMFG monitors this information and displays it for us
    here.</para>
    <note>
      <para id="Para672805">The term "Last Counted date" has a very specific
      meaning. Item Sites are only considered to have been counted if Count
      Tags for them have been posted. Simply issuing a Count Tag is not enough
      to mark an Item Site as having been counted. Issued Count Tags must be
      posted for the count to be registered.</para>
    </note>
  </section>
  <section id="Section672807">
    <title><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>cycle count tags</primary>
        <secondary>mechanics of</secondary>
      </indexterm>Creating Cycle Count Tags</title>
    <para id="Para672808">Okay, we have identified when our Item Sites were
    last counted: 02/04/2004. That was yesterday. Remember, the Cycle Count
    frequency for these Item Sites indicates they should be Cycle Counted
    daily. So now we need to initiate a Cycle Count. To do so, we open the
    Create Cycle Count Tags by Warehouse screen, as shown below:</para>
    <para id="Para672812"><anchor id="Anchor98817" role="Cross-Ref" xreflabel="98817: Figure: Figure 4.5:  Create Cycle Count Tags by Warehouse"/>
    <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_createCycleCntTags.png" id="Graphic672810"/>
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption672814">Create Cycle Count Tags by
          Warehouse</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para id="Para672817">As you can see in <xref endterm="Anchor98817" linkend="Anchor98817"/>
    FINDME
  Figure 6.110, we have specified the parameters required to
    produce our desired result--namely, the creation of Cycle Count Tags for
    Items in Class Code Books located in Warehouse WEST. Here are the
    parameters we specified:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1907088">
        <para id="Para672819">Warehouse: Selected WEST.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19070ac">
        <para id="Para672820">Class Code: Selected Books.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19070d0">
        <para id="Para672821">Mark Created Count Tag as Priority: Selected.
        Count Tags marked as having priority status are listed first in any
        prioritized lists. For example, priority Count Tags will appear at the
        top of the Count Tag Edit List; whereas, non-priority Count Tags will
        appear at the bottom of the list.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19070f4">
        <para id="Para672822">Freeze Inventory: Selected. We are specifying
        that Inventory be frozen during the Cycle Count. Freezing Inventory
        during a Cycle Count helps preserve the integrity of Quantity on Hand
        (QOH) values. For more information on freezing and thawing, see the
        section dedicated to that topic.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1907118">
        <para id="Para672823">Maximum Number of Tags to Create: Entered 20.
        Indicate the maximum number of Cycle Count Tags you want to be
        created--up to a maximum of 1,000--during the Cycle Count. In our
        case, we are dealing with fewer than 20 Item Sites. By entering a
        maximum of 20 will cover our bases.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x190713c">
        <para id="Para672824">Comments: This is a scrolling text field with
        word-wrapping for entering comments related to the Cycle Count. Use
        the Comments field to enter any instructions or other comments that
        need to reach and be read by the cycle counters.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para id="Para672825">Once our parameters have been entered, we are ready
    to select the CREATE TAGS button. Doing so will create our Cycle Count
    Tags. To verify the Cycle Count Tags have in fact been created, we return
    to the Count Tag Edit List. Sure enough, they do appear on the list, as
    shown in the following screenshot:</para>
    <para id="Para672829"><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_cycleEditList-2.png" id="Graphic672827"/>
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption672830">Count Tags Edit List Showing Cycle Count
          Tags</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <note>
      <para id="Para672832">Cycle Count Tag Numbers are generated
      automatically by the system in a sequential pattern, using
      specifications entered on the Warehouse master. Within the Warehouse
      master you can specify both the prefix to be used by Count Tags created
      in the given Warehouse (e.g., WEST) and also the starting point for the
      numeric sequence.</para>
    </note>
    <para id="Para672833">At this point, the Cycle Count Tags would be
    processed in exactly the same way as manually created Count Tags are
    processed. Again, for more information on the mechanics of Count Tag
    processing, refer to the section dedicated specifically to this
    topic.</para>
    <para id="Para672834">Because we will not be covering Count Tag mechanics
    in this example, let's assume we have counted the Item Sites and posted
    the results. Our target Item Sites have now been counted. The final step
    would be to verify that the Last Counted date for these Item Sites has
    been updated. Let's look again at the Item Sites by Class Code display, as
    shown in the following screen:</para>
    <para id="Para672838"><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_cycleSitesByClass-2.png" id="Graphic672836"/>
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption672839">Item Site Display Showing Updated Last
          Counted Dates</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para id="Para672840">When we look at the "Last Cnt"d" column, we see that
    today's date is displaying: 02/05/04. As expected, the date has been
    updated to correspond with our Cycle Count activity. We have now
    successfully completed the cycle.</para>
  </section>
</section>