<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section672121">
  <title id="Anchor80983"><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>topics</primary>
      <secondary>freezing and thawing</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>freezing</primary>
      <secondary>explained</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>thawing</primary>
      <secondary>explained</secondary>
    </indexterm>Topic: Freezing and Thawing</title>
  <para>The freezing/thawing mechanism is designed to ensure you get accurate
  Inventory counts without having to shut down operations. All you have to do
  is follow these simple steps:</para>
  <orderedlist continuation="restarts" inheritnum="ignore">
    <listitem>
      <para>Prior to beginning an Inventory count, freeze your <indexterm
          significance="normal">
          <primary>quantity on hand</primary>
          <secondary>freezing and thawing of</secondary>
        </indexterm>Quantity on Hand.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>Once you finish the count and post your numbers, thaw your
      Quantity on Hand.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>The Quantity on Hand indicated on screen will be accurate because
      it reflects not only the numbers from your count but also any Inventory
      activity that may have occurred during the time your count was
      underway.</para>
    </listitem>
  </orderedlist>
  <para>To give you a better feel for how freezing and thawing works, consider
  the following hypothetical scenarios. These scenarios approach the issue of
  Inventory accuracy from a number of different perspectives.</para>
  <section id="Section672129">
    <title><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>freezing</primary>
        <secondary>implications of not using</secondary>
      </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>thawing</primary>
        <secondary>implications of not using</secondary>
      </indexterm>Counting Inventory without Freeze/Thaw</title>
    <para>In our first scenario, we show an Inventory count where Quantity on
    Hand is not frozen prior to the count. The numbers you see in the figure
    correspond to the following chronological narrative:</para>
    <orderedlist continuation="restarts" inheritnum="ignore">
      <listitem>
        <para>The plant's Inventory manager decides to count Inventory and
        issues a Count Tag. He does not select the "Freeze Inventory" option
        on the Count Tag screen.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>The count begins and a quantity of 14 is counted. At this point
        the count is done, but for some reason the Count Tag is not posted
        right away. Perhaps the manager goes to lunch--or is called to perform
        another task.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Meanwhile, activity is occurring inside the Warehouse. We see
        that 5 units are received into Inventory and 2 units are
        issued.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>This Warehouse activity is reflected on screen. The indicated
        Quantity on Hand rises or falls with each Inventory
        transaction.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>After lunch, the Count Tag is now posted. The posted quantity
        reflects the quantity counted earlier--which was 14. This value will
        now display as the indicated Quantity on Hand.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>However, as you can see from the far left-hand column in the
        diagram, the indicated Quantity on Hand does not equal the actual
        Quantity on Hand. Why? Because the Inventory count did not consider
        ongoing Warehouse activity. The numbers are off--and this is a
        problem.</para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <para><anchor id="Anchor75689" role="Cross-Ref"
    xreflabel="75689: Figure: Figure 3.1:  Scenario A: Inventory Count without Freezing Inventory" />
    <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Drawing_inventoryNoFreeze.png"
                       id="Graphic672141" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption672145">Scenario A: Inventory Count without
          Freezing Inventory</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
  </section>
  <section id="Section672147">
    <title><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>freezing</primary>
        <secondary>prior to counting</secondary>
      </indexterm>Freezing Inventory Before Counting</title>
    <para>The second scenario is similar to the first--except for one
    important detail. In "Scenario B," the Inventory manager decides to freeze
    Inventory prior to beginning the Inventory count. Again, the numbers shown
    in the diagram correspond to the following chronological narrative:</para>
    <orderedlist continuation="restarts" inheritnum="ignore">
      <listitem>
        <para>Noticing a discrepancy between actual Quantity on Hand and
        indicated Quantity on Hand, the Inventory manager orders an Inventory
        count.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>When creating the Count Tag, he selects the "Freeze Inventory"
        option.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Because the Inventory is frozen, the indicated Quantity on Hand
        will not change until Inventory is thawed at the end of the process.
        As you can see, the indicated Quantity on Hand is frozen at 10 until
        after the thaw.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>The count begins and a quantity of 14 is counted. At this point
        the count is done and the manager goes to lunch--waiting to post the
        count until after he returns.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Meanwhile, activity is occurring inside the Warehouse. We see
        that 5 units are received into Inventory and 2 units are issued. This
        Warehouse activity is not reflected on screen because Inventory has
        been frozen.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>After lunch, the manager posts the Count Tag. But notice that
        the indicated Quantity on Hand does not change to the Count Tag total
        of 14. Until Inventory is thawed, the indicated Quantity on Hand will
        remain at its frozen level.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>When posting the Count Tag, the manager selects the "Thaw Frozen
        Inventory" option. As Inventory is thawing, the software performs a
        number of calculations. First, it retrieves the Count Tag total. Then
        it looks for any Warehouse transactions. Finally it returns an
        indicated Quantity on Hand of 17. The equation would look something
        like this: 14 + 5 - 2 = 17.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>As a result of the thawing process, the indicated Quantity on
        Hand equals the actual Quantity on Hand. The numbers are correct.
        There is no problem.</para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Drawing_inventoryFreeze.png"
                       id="Graphic672158" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption672161">Scenario B: Freezing Inventory Before
          Beginning Inventory Count</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
  </section>
</section>
