<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section665443">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>topics</primary>
      <secondary>item costing</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>items</primary>
      <secondary>costing explained</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>costing</primary>
      <secondary>for items explained</secondary>
    </indexterm>Topic: Item Costing</title>
  <para>Assigning Costs to Items is an essential step in the process of
  Inventory Accounting. In this section, we will cover the basics of Item
  costing--looking first at how Costs are assigned to simple purchased Items.
  And then we will examine more complex manufactured Items and the layers of
  Costs associated with them.</para>
  <section id="Section665446">
    <title><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>actual costs</primary>
        <secondary>comparison to standard costs</secondary>
      </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>standard costs</primary>
        <secondary>comparison to actual costs</secondary>
      </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>costing</primary>
        <secondary>actual vs. standard</secondary>
      </indexterm>Actual Cost vs. Standard Cost</title>
    <para>But first, let's get a couple of key definitions out of the way.
    There are two kinds of Costs in OpenMFG: Actual Costs and Standard Costs.
    You should familiarize yourself with the following definitions for these
    two terms:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Actual Cost: The real-time Cost associated with an Item,
        including current material and production charges. The Actual Cost of
        an Item may fluctuate given changes in the Cost for materials, or
        other Costs related to changes in Bills of Materials or Bills of
        Operations. The Actual Cost provides a current record of charges
        actually incurred by an Item.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Standard Cost: The Cost used for posting General Ledger
        transactions. Standard Cost is distinguished from Actual Cost in the
        sense that Standard Cost is fixed, whereas Actual Cost is subject to
        fluctuations arising from material or production changes. The two
        Costs may diverge. However, they can be brought back into alignment by
        posting Actual Cost to Standard.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <tip>
      <para>To see General Ledger (G/L) traffic for Inventory transactions,
      Standard Costs must be assigned to the affected Items. If no Standard
      Costs are assigned, the costing aspects of the transactions will not be
      recorded.</para>
    </tip>
  </section>
  <section id="Section665453">
    <title><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>costing</primary>
        <secondary>assigning to items</secondary>
      </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>items</primary>
        <secondary>assigning costs to</secondary>
      </indexterm>Assigning Item Costs</title>
    <para>To begin, let's assign Costs to the purchased Item B1. This Item
    currently has no Costs assigned to it, as we can see from the Maintain
    Item Costs screen shown below:</para>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_maintItemCost-1.png"
                       />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Initial Maintain Item Costs Screen for
          Purchased Item B1</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>When you assign Costs to an Item, you begin by entering Actual Costs
    for the Item. Once the Actual Costs have been entered, you can then assign
    Standard Costs. You assign Standard Costs by posting the Actual Costs to
    Standard. We"ll talk more about Standard Cost posting later.</para>
    <para>By definition, purchased Items have material Cost. And so, the first
    Actual Cost we will assign to Item B1 is its material Cost. To do so, we
    select the NEW COST button, as shown below:</para>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_createItemCost-1.png"
                       />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Create Item Cost for Material</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>As you can see, the "Material" Costing Element is showing in the
    drop-down menu. This is a system-defined Costing Element available to all
    purchased Items. For the purposes of this exercise, we"ll assign a
    material Cost of $6.00 to Item B1. After we select the SAVE button, we are
    returned to the Maintain Item Costs screen, where the newly-added Actual
    Cost is recorded, as shown in the following screenshot:</para>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_maintItemCost-2.png"
                       />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Actual Cost Entered for Item
          B1</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
  </section>
  <section id="Section665474">
    <title><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>actual costs</primary>
        <secondary>posting of explained</secondary>
      </indexterm>Posting Actual to Standard</title>
    <para>Because we want to track the costing aspects of Inventory
    transactions involving Item B1 in the General Ledger, we need to post the
    Actual Cost to the Standard Cost. There are several ways to accomplish
    this posting, but for now we will use the right-click menu's "Post Actual
    Cost to Standard" option. As you can see in the next screen, the Standard
    Cost column now shows the same amount as the Actual Cost column:</para>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_maintItemCost-3.png"
                       />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Actual Cost Posted to Standard Cost for
          Item B1</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <note>
      <para>The timetable for posting Actual Cost updates to Standard Cost
      should be guided by Accounting practices at your site. Variances between
      Actual Cost and Standard Cost may provide you with useful supply chain
      or production-related information.</para>
    </note>
  </section>
  <section id="Section665483">
    <title>Updating Actual Costs</title>
    <para>So, we"ve discussed how to enter Actual Costs and how to post them
    to Standard. The next question is: How do you update Costs when the Costs
    for an Item change? And also: How do you ensure that any changes are
    recognized wherever the Item is used?</para>
    <para>To answer these questions, let's continue looking at our purchased
    Item B1. This Item, a book, has an Actual Cost of $6.00--and this Actual
    Cost has been posted to Standard. As you can see in the following
    screenshot, Item B1 is a component in the Bill of Materials for Item SET,
    which is a set of books:</para>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_costSingleBOM.png"
                       />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Costed View of Component Items</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>Let's say our Vendor increases the price for Item B1 from $6.00 to
    $7.00. Using the Maintain Item Costs screen, we would record this
    increased Actual Cost, as shown in the following screenshot:</para>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_updateActCost.png"
                       />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Update Actual Cost for Item B1</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <note>
      <para>The system will automatically update Actual Costs for purchased
      Items when Vouchers are posted--that is, if the vouchered Cost per Item
      differs from the current Actual Cost on file. The Actual Cost on record
      may increase or decrease, depending on the cost per Item entered when
      Purchase Orders are vouchered.</para>
    </note>
    <para>The Actual Cost for Item B1 has now been updated, reflecting the
    change in the Vendor pricing. If we return now to the Costed Bill of
    Materials for Item SET, we can see how the change affected one of the
    manufactured Items where Item B1 is used:</para>
    <para> <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_costSingleBOM2.png"
                       />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Actual Cost of Component Item
          Updated</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>You have to look closely at the example to fully appreciate the
    subtle changes that have occurred. For one thing, you can see that the
    unit Cost for Item B1 has been updated to $7.00. This change affected the
    "Total Cost" for the parent Item SET. However, the Actual and Standard
    Costs for Item SET have not been affected:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Total Cost = $13.00</para>
        <para>Actual Cost = $12.00</para>
        <para>Standard Cost = $12.00</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
  <section id="Section665513">
    <title>Rolling Up Actual Costs</title>
    <para>Why does the above-mentioned difference exist? The reason is that
    the Cost update for Item B1 has not yet been "rolled up." Once a Cost
    update has been rolled up, the change will be recognized wherever the Item
    is used. In our current example, the Costed Bill of Materials for Item SET
    reflects the update, but the Actual and Standard Costs for Item SET have
    not yet absorbed the change.</para>
    <tip>
      <para>To determine whether Costs have been rolled up, look closely at
      the dates when Costs were last updated on the Maintain Item Costs
      screen. You can also look for differences between the Total Cost and the
      Actual and Standard Costs for an Item on the Costed Bill of Materials
      display.</para>
    </tip>
    <para>Another point to consider is that the screen in our example is
    displaying data using the "Use Actual Cost" parameter. Note the difference
    when the "Use Standard Cost" option is selected instead, as shown in the
    following screen:</para>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_costSingleBOM3.png"
                       />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>No Affect on Standard Cost from Actual
          Cost Update</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>As you can see, no change is showing in the Standard Cost for Item
    B1. The Standard Cost is still $6.00. The reason for this is that the
    Actual Cost update has not yet been posted to Standard.</para>
    <para>To roll up the Item B1 Cost update so that Item SET recognizes the
    change, we open the Update Actual Costs by Item screen, as shown
    below:</para>
    <para> <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_updateActCost2.png"
                       />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Roll Up Actual Cost Update</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>As you can see in the example, we have selected the "Roll Up Actual
    Costs" option. Here we are performing a Cost roll up--which is to say that
    we are seeking to impact Actual Costs for all Items that use Item B1.
    After we select the UPDATE button, all Items that use Item B1 will
    recognize the Actual Cost update. To verify the change has been
    recognized, we return to the Costed Bill of Materials for Item SET, as
    shown below:</para>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_costSingleBOM4.png"
                       />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Actual Cost Rolled Up and Recognized by
          Parent Item</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>Sure enough, the Total Cost for Item SET is now equal to its Actual
    Cost. We have successfully rolled up the Cost update for the component
    Item B1. The update has been recognized by the parent Item. And the update
    has been recognized not only by Item SET--but also by any other parent
    Items where Item B1 is used.</para>
    <tip>
      <para>Our example has focused on Cost roll ups for individual Items. But
      you may also perform multiple simultaneous roll ups by Class Code. Keep
      in mind, though, that multiple updates may put a strain on server
      resources. Consider performing Cost updates by Class Code during
      off-peak hours.</para>
    </tip>
    <para>Incidentally, we could have achieved the same result by updating
    lower level material Costs for the parent Item SET, as shown below:</para>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_updateActCost3.png"
                       />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Manufactured Item Perspective on Cost
          Roll Up</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>With the option "Update Lower Level Material Costs" selected, any
    component Item material changes will be recognized by the parent Item. In
    this case, the changes made to Item B1 will be reflected in the Actual
    Cost for Item SET.</para>
  </section>
  <section id="Section665554">
    <title>Standard Cost Roll Ups</title>
    <para>The process for updating and rolling up Standard Costs mirrors the
    Actual Costs process described above. Let's assume we have already posted
    the Actual Cost update to Standard for Item B1--using the Maintain Item
    Costs screen, for example. That means, the Standard Cost for Item B1 is
    now also $7.00, as we see reflected in the Costed Bill of Materials for
    Item SET:</para>
    <para> <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_costSingleBOM5.png"
                       />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Standard Cost Updated for Item
          B1</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>When the "Use Standard Costs" option is selected as in the example,
    you can see that the Total Cost for Item SET differs from the Standard
    Cost. This means that the Standard Cost update for Item B1 has not been
    recognized. To ensure that parent Items recognize the Standard Cost
    change, we must roll up the Standard Cost, as shown below:</para>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_postActCost.png"
                       />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Rolling Up Standard Cost</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>With the "Roll Up Standard Costs" option selected, we post the
    update and return once again to the Costed Bill of Materials display for
    Item SET. As the following screen shows, the Standard Cost update has
    successfully been recognized by the parent Item:</para>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_costSingleBOM6.png"
                       />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Standard Cost Update Recognized by
          Parent Item</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
  </section>
  <section id="Section665577">
    <title>User-Defined Costing Elements</title>
    <para>In addition to the system-defined "Material" Costing Element, you
    may also create user-defined Costing Elements. These accessory elements
    enable you to specify additional Item costs.</para>
    <para>To add a user-defined Costing Element, we again select the NEW COST
    button. The available elements are shown in the following screenshot. As
    you can see, the "Material" element is no longer available in the
    drop-down list. That is because the "Material" Costing Element is already
    in use.</para>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_createItemCost-2.png"
                       />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Add User-Defined Costing
          Element</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>We will select the "Freight Surcharge" element and specify a Cost of
    $0.25. The following screen shows this new Cost has been added to the
    Actual Cost for Item B1.</para>
    <note>
      <para>There is no requirement that all Actual Costs must be posted to
      Standard. You may post certain Costs and not others--depending on the
      needs of your site.</para>
    </note>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_maintItemCost-4.png"
                       />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>User-Defined Cost Added to Actual
          Cost</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>The master list of user-defined Costing Elements can be found in the
    Master Information section of the P/D Module. The following screen shows
    the list of Costing Elements created for this scenario:</para>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_userCostElem.png"
                       />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Master List of User-Defined Costing
          Elements</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>When creating a user-defined Costing Element, you may specify the
    "Accept P/O Distributions" option. Select this option if you want the
    Costing Element to be used for distributing Costs related to Purchase
    Order Vouchers. If selected, the Costing Element will be included as one
    of the available Costing Elements when Voucher Item Costs are
    distributed.</para>
    <tip>
      <para>In addition to using Costing Elements, you may also create Costing
      Items--that is, Items assigned the Item Type "Costing." A Costing Item
      is a kind of pseudo Item used solely to provide a costed value for a
      Costing Element. Simply insert a Costing Item into a Bill of Materials,
      add Costs to the Item, and then link the Item to a Costing Element. You
      may then track the Costs of the pseudo Item as a user-defined
      Cost.</para>
    </tip>
  </section>
  <section id="Section665603">
    <title><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>costing</primary>
        <secondary>for manufactured items</secondary>
      </indexterm>Manufactured Item Costing</title>
    <para>Okay, we"ve covered how to assign Costs to a purchased Item. Now
    let's look at costing for a manufactured Item.</para>
    <para>The manufactured Item we will be using in this next scenario is Item
    TDMR100, a yellow toy truck having four component Items. The fourth
    component--Item TDPKIT--is also manufactured. Item TDPKIT is the packaging
    used to package the yellow toy truck. The next screen shows an indented
    Bill of Materials for Item TDMR100:</para>
    <para> <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_indentBOMTruck.png"
                       />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Indented Bill of Materials</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>Because manufactured Items consist of component Items--sometimes
    extending to several layers--the costing issues are more complex than they
    are for purchased Items. New Costs are assigned in the same way as they
    are for purchased Items. But the layers of Costs and the relationships
    between them make costing for manufactured Items unique.</para>
    <note>
      <para>New Costs are assigned to manufactured Items in the same way that
      new Costs are assigned to purchased Items. You simply select the NEW
      COST button on the Maintain Item Costs screen and specify a Costing
      Element and Cost amount.</para>
    </note>
    <para>All Costs have already been assigned to Item TDMR100--and to all its
    component Items. So we will jump right into understanding how these Costs
    fit together.</para>
    <para>Let's start by looking at Costs associated with the manufactured
    component Item TDPKIT, the packaging for our yellow truck. As we saw in
    the example, Item TDPKIT is the fourth component listed on the Bill of
    Materials for the parent Item. The Costs for Item TDPKIT are shown in the
    following screenshot:</para>
    <para> <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_maintItemCost-5.png"
                       />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Item Costing for Manufactured Component
          Item TDPKIT</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>A few key points about manufactured Item costing can be made by
    looking closely at the information displayed in the example:</para>
    <orderedlist continuation="restarts" inheritnum="ignore">
      <listitem>
        <para>Three system-defined Costing Elements are available to
        manufactured Items: "Material," "Direct Labor," and "Overhead."</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Material Costs for manufactured Items are always lower
        level--which means they are associated with component Items, not with
        the parent Item.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Direct labor and overhead Costs are this level--meaning, if in
        use, these Costs are associated with the parent Item they refer
        to.</para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <note>
      <para>This level Costs are associated with the parent Item they refer
      to. Lower level Costs are associated with component Items.</para>
    </note>
    <para>As you can see, Item TDPKIT has material, direct labor, and overhead
    Costs associated with it. The labor and overhead Costs are displaying as
    this level (that is, not lower level). And the material Costs, as
    expected, are shown as lower level Costs. Let's look first at how the
    lower level material Costs totalling $0.55 were arrived at. If you recall,
    Item TDPKIT has two component Items: TDK1 and TDK2. The following
    screenshot shows Item costing for these two Items:</para>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_maintItemCost-6.png"
                       />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Costs for Component Items</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>Items TDK1 and TDK2 are basic purchased Items having material Costs
    only. Doing some simple math, we see how the lower level material Costs
    for Item TDPKIT were calculated:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>$0.30 (TDK1) + $0.25 (TDK2) = $0.55</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
  <section id="Section665644">
    <title><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>labor costs</primary>
        <secondary>explained</secondary>
      </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>overhead costs</primary>
        <secondary>explained</secondary>
      </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>costing</primary>
        <secondary>labor costs explained</secondary>
      </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>costing</primary>
        <secondary>overhead costs explained</secondary>
      </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>work centers</primary>
        <secondary>labor charges for</secondary>
      </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>work centers</primary>
        <secondary>overhead charges for</secondary>
      </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>costing</primary>
        <secondary>work centers and</secondary>
      </indexterm>Labor and Overhead Costs</title>
    <para>So, that explains the material Costs for Item TDPKIT. Now let's look
    at the Item's direct labor Costs. We"ll explore the overhead Costs a
    little later. Referring back to the example, you recall that direct labor
    Costs for Item TDPKIT total $1.00. How was this amount determined? The
    answer to that question is the subject of our next scenario.</para>
    <para>Direct labor Costs are tied to the manufacturing process, to the
    Operations required to make an Item. So, to calculate labor Costs, we need
    to know how long it takes to make the Item and what the labor rates are.
    To gather this information, we will need to look at a series of different
    screens. We"ll begin by examining the Bill of Operations for Item
    TDPKIT:</para>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_booTDPKIT.png" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Bill of Operations for Item
          TDPKIT</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>As you can see, there is only one Operation listed on the Bill of
    Operations. It is Standard Operation "TD-A," which is performed in Work
    Center "Assembly." We can learn more about this Operation by
    double-clicking on it to open it, as shown in the following screen:</para>
    <para> <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_booItemTDPKIT.png"
                       />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Operation Detail from TDPKIT Bill of
          Operations</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>The Bill of Operations Item screen shown in the example contains
    extensive controls used to define the Operation. Looking closely at the
    screenshot, we see Standard Operation "TD-A" is in use. Standard
    Operations are not required, but in this case one is being used.</para>
    <note>
      <para>Setup time and run time values will carry over from the Standard
      Operation master if a Standard Operation is in use.</para>
    </note>
  </section>
  <section id="Section665668">
    <title>Setup and Run Time Charges</title>
    <para>The Work Center "Assembly" has been specified from the drop-down
    menu. And the following setup time and run time values have been
    entered:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Setup time = 5 minutes (charged only once per Operation)</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Run time = 1 minute (charged per each unit of Item
        TDPKIT)</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>It's important to highlight the differences in how setup times and
    run times are charged. As you might expect, run time is the amount of time
    required to execute an Operation. In our scenario, the Operation involves
    assembling packaging for the yellow toy truck. With a run time of 1 minute
    and a per value of 1 EACH, that means it takes 1 minute to assemble the
    packaging for one unit of Item TDPKIT. So, if a Work Order calls for 100
    units of packaging, then run time will be charged 100 times--for a total
    of 100 minutes.</para>
    <para>Setup time is charged differently. Setup time refers to the amount
    of time needed to prepare the Work Center to perform the Operation. Setup
    time is charged only once per Operation--regardless of the number of units
    required by a Work Order. In other words, to use our previous example, if
    a Work Order calls for 100 units of packaging, the setup time charge would
    be 5 minutes.</para>
    <note>
      <para>Setup time is charged only once per Operation, regardless of the
      quantity ordered.</para>
    </note>
    <para>You should pay attention also to how reporting of setup and run time
    is specified. We see inthe example that both times are to be reported as
    Direct Labor. This means that all labor required to set up the Work Center
    and also to run the Operation will appear as Direct Labor Cost for the
    Item.</para>
    <para>We referred earlier to Standard Operation "TD-A." The following
    screen shows the master for this Standard Operation:</para>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_standOpTDPKIT.png"
                       />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Standard Operation Master</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>The setup and run time values entered on the Standard Operation
    master transfer to the Bill of Operations if and when the Standard
    Operation is specified. As you can see, the same values appear here as we
    saw in the example. These values may be changed at the Operation level,
    but any permanent changes must be made to the Standard Operation master
    itself.</para>
    <para>So we now know the amount of time required for the Operation. Next
    we need to determine the rate charged for labor. For that information, we
    must turn to the Work Center master for Work Center "Assembly," as shown
    in the next screenshot:</para>
    <para> <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_workCenterTDPKIT.png"
                       />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Work Center Master</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>Just as Standard Operations may be used for Bill of Operations
    Items, so may Standard Labor Rates be used for Work Centers. As you can
    see in the example, the Standard Labor Rate "MA10" is specified for both
    run and setup labor. To determine what the dollar amount is for this
    standard rate, we open the Standard Labor Rates master list found in the
    Master Information section of the P/D Module. The specific details for
    rate "MA10" are shown in the following screen:</para>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_standLabRate.png"
                       />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Standard Labor Rate</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>As you can see, the Standard Labor Rate = $10.00. This means that
    for our Assembly Operation, $10 is the hourly rate charged for setup; it
    is also the hourly rate charged for run time.</para>
    <para>Let's review, then, the information we have gathered so far in our
    effort to reconstruct how direct labor Costs for manufactured component
    Item TDPKIT were arrived at:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Setup time = 5 mins (converted to hours: 5/60 = .0833333)</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Run time = 1 min (converted to hours: 1/60 = .016666)</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Setup rate = $10/hr</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Run rate = $10/hr</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>We now have enough information to calculate the direct labor Cost.
    The following formula is the one we will use:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>(setup time x setup rate) + (run time x run rate) = direct labor
        Cost</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>This formula works because, as you recall, the "Assembly" Operation
    specifies that setup time and run time are both reported as direct labor.
    All we have to do now is insert the correct values, and the equation looks
    like this:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>(.0833333 x $10.00) + (.016666 x $10.00) = $1.00</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>To verify that $1.00 is indeed the direct labor Cost for Item
    TDPKIT, let's look at the Maintain Item Costs screen for Item TDPKIT
    again:</para>
    <para> <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_maintItemCost-5.png"
                       />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Item Costing for Item TDPKIT</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>Sure enough, the reported direct labor Cost for Item TDPKIT = $1.00.
    As you can see, this amount has been posted to the Standard Cost for the
    Item.</para>
    <para>Finally, we need to determine how overhead Cost for Item TDPKIT is
    arrived at. Referring back to the Work Center master shown in the example,
    we recall that the overhead rate per hour = $10.00 To calculate overhead
    Cost then, we would use the following formula:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>setup time + run time x overhead rate = overhead Cost</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>If we now insert the correct values, the equation looks like
    this:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>.0833333 + . 016666 x $10.00 = $1.00</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>Again, referring to the Item Costing detail shown in the example, we
    can verify that reported overhead Costs for Item TDPKIT = $1.00.</para>
  </section>
  <section id="Section665737">
    <title><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>costing</primary>
        <secondary>multi-level explained</secondary>
      </indexterm>Multi-Level Costing</title>
    <para>We"ve now covered the fundamentals of manufactured Item costing. But
    remember: Item TDPKIT is a fairly simple manufactured Item. We will look
    next at costing for the more complex parent Item TDMR100. The same
    processes will be used to determine its Costs, but the factors we have to
    consider are more complicated.</para>
    <para>To begin, let's look at the Costs for Item TDMR100, as shown in the
    following screen:</para>
    <para> <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_maintItemCost-7.png"
                       />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Item Costing for Parent Item
          TDMR100</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>For starters, note the distinctions between the lower level and this
    level Costs. As we discussed earlier, this level Costs are associated with
    the parent Item they refer to. Lower level Costs are associated with
    component Items. For Item TDMR100, the levels may be broken down as
    follows:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>This level: Direct labor and overhead Costs for parent Item
        TDMR100</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Lower level: Direct labor and overhead Costs associated with
        component Item TDPKIT; total material Costs for all non-manufactured
        component Items.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>To better understand how these levels fit together, let's open the
    Costed Indented Bill of Materials display, found in the Costing section of
    the P/D Module. This is a useful display because it shows not only Bill of
    Materials Items, but also the Costs associated with each:</para>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_costedIndentBOM.png"
                       />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Costed Indented Bill of Materials
          Display for Item TDMR100</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>As you can see, Item TDMR100 consists of four component Items--one
    of which, Item TDPKIT, has two component Items of its own.</para>
    <para>We"ve already determined that material Costs for manufactured Items
    are always lower level. So, to determine material Costs for Item TDMR100,
    we must look to the non-manufactured component Items: TDMRY, TDMRB, TDMRW,
    TDK1, and TDK2.</para>
    <para>Conveniently, the only Costs assigned to these Items are material
    Costs. As a result, we simply have to add up the extended Costs for these
    Items to determine the overall material Cost for Item TDMR100.</para>
    <tip>
      <para>When using the Costed Indented Bill of Materials display, be sure
      to distinguish between unit Cost and extended Cost. The extended Cost
      represents the unit Cost multiplied by the quantity required by the Bill
      of Materials.</para>
    </tip>
    <para>When we add all these material Costs together--TDMRY ($0.0025),
    TDMRB ($2.5000), TDMRW ($1.2500), TDK1 ($0.3000), and TDK2 ($0.2500)--we
    get an overall material Cost for Item TDMR100 of $8.0525. Referring back
    to the example, we can verify on the Maintain Item Costs screen that this
    amount is in fact the reported material Cost for Item TDMR100.</para>
    <para>Next, we need to examine how direct labor Costs for Item TDMR100 are
    determined. As before, we begin with the Bill of Operations, as shown in
    the following screenshot:</para>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_booTDMR100.png"
                       />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Bill of Operations for Item
          TDMR100</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>As you can see, the Bill of Operations for Item TDMR100 contains
    three Operations--as compared to the one Operation we saw for component
    Item TDPKIT. We"ve already discussed how to locate costing information on
    both the Operation and Work Center screens. So, rather than repeat that
    process here, we"ve extracted the pertinent information into the following
    table:</para>
    <para><informaltable>
        <tgroup cols="5">
          <thead>
            <row>
              <entry><para>Work Center</para></entry>
              <entry><para>Setup + Run Time</para></entry>
              <entry><para>Setup Rate</para></entry>
              <entry><para>Run Rate</para></entry>
              <entry><para>Overhead Rate</para></entry>
            </row>
          </thead>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry><para>Assembly</para></entry>
              <entry><para>.03333 hrs.</para></entry>
              <entry><para>$10</para></entry>
              <entry><para>$10</para></entry>
              <entry><para>$10</para></entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry><para>Paint</para></entry>
              <entry><para>.16666 hrs.</para></entry>
              <entry><para>$10</para></entry>
              <entry><para>$10</para></entry>
              <entry><para>$10</para></entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry><para>Ship</para></entry>
              <entry><para>.05000 hrs.</para></entry>
              <entry><para>$10</para></entry>
              <entry><para>$10</para></entry>
              <entry><para>$10</para></entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </informaltable></para>
    <para>As you can see, all the rates (setup, run, and overhead) are the
    same: $10.00. This fact enables us to combine the setup and run times into
    one. If the rates were not identical, the setup and run times would have
    to be multiplied individually by the appropriate rate.</para>
    <para>To determine the direct labor Cost for Item TDMR100, then, we follow
    the same equation we introduced earlier:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>(setup time x setup rate) + (run time x run rate) = direct labor
        Cost</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>To simplify things this time around, we"ve combined the setup and
    run times for each Operation into a single value. With those values
    inserted, the equation now looks like this:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>(.03333 + .16666 + .05000) x $10.00 = $2.50</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>Looking back at the Maintain Item Costs screen shown in the example,
    we can verify that the direct labor Costs for Item TDMR100 are indeed
    $2.500. To calculate overhead Cost, we would again use a formula we
    introduced earlier:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>setup time + run time x overhead rate = overhead Cost</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>And with values for each of the Operations for Item TDMR100
    inserted, the overhead Cost equation would appear as follows:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>(.03333 + .16666 + .05000) x $10.00 = $2.50</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>As expected, this result corresponds to the overhead Costs reported
    for Item TDMR100 in the example. We have now accounted for all the Costs
    associated with our manufactured Item TDMR100.</para>
  </section>
</section>
