<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section665443">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>topics</primary>
      <secondary>item costing</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>items</primary>
      <secondary>costing explained</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>costing</primary>
      <secondary>for items explained</secondary>
    </indexterm>Topic: Item Costing</title>
  <para id="Para665444">Assigning Costs to Items is an essential step in the
  process of Inventory Accounting. In this section, we will cover the basics
  of Item costing--looking first at how Costs are assigned to simple purchased
  Items. And then we will examine more complex manufactured Items and the
  layers of Costs associated with them.</para>
  <section id="Section665446">
    <title><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>actual costs</primary>
        <secondary>comparison to standard costs</secondary>
      </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>standard costs</primary>
        <secondary>comparison to actual costs</secondary>
      </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>costing</primary>
        <secondary>actual vs. standard</secondary>
      </indexterm>Actual Cost vs. Standard Cost</title>
    <para id="Para665447">But first, let's get a couple of key definitions out
    of the way. There are two kinds of Costs in OpenMFG: Actual Costs and
    Standard Costs. You should familiarize yourself with the following
    definitions for these two terms:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d95f8">
        <para id="Para665448">Actual Cost: The real-time Cost associated with
        an Item, including current material and production charges. The Actual
        Cost of an Item may fluctuate given changes in the Cost for materials,
        or other Costs related to changes in Bills of Materials or Bills of
        Operations. The Actual Cost provides a current record of charges
        actually incurred by an Item.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d961c">
        <para id="Para665449">Standard Cost: The Cost used for posting General
        Ledger transactions. Standard Cost is distinguished from Actual Cost
        in the sense that Standard Cost is fixed, whereas Actual Cost is
        subject to fluctuations arising from material or production changes.
        The two Costs may diverge. However, they can be brought back into
        alignment by posting Actual Cost to Standard.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <tip>
      <para id="Para665451">To see General Ledger (G/L) traffic for Inventory
      transactions, Standard Costs must be assigned to the affected Items. If
      no Standard Costs are assigned, the costing aspects of the transactions
      will not be recorded.</para>
    </tip>
  </section>
  <section id="Section665453">
    <title><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>costing</primary>
        <secondary>assigning to items</secondary>
      </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>items</primary>
        <secondary>assigning costs to</secondary>
      </indexterm>Assigning Item Costs</title>
    <para id="Para665454">To begin, let's assign Costs to the purchased Item
    B1. This Item currently has no Costs assigned to it, as we can see from
    the Maintain Item Costs screen shown below:</para>
    <para id="Para665458"><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_maintItemCost-1.png"
                       id="Graphic665456" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption665459">Initial Maintain Item Costs Screen for
          Purchased Item B1</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para id="Para665460">When you assign Costs to an Item, you begin by
    entering Actual Costs for the Item. Once the Actual Costs have been
    entered, you can then assign Standard Costs. You assign Standard Costs by
    posting the Actual Costs to Standard. We"ll talk more about Standard Cost
    posting later.</para>
    <para id="Para665461">By definition, purchased Items have material Cost.
    And so, the first Actual Cost we will assign to Item B1 is its material
    Cost. To do so, we select the NEW COST button, as shown below:</para>
    <para id="Para665465"><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_createItemCost-1.png"
                       id="Graphic665463" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption665466">Create Item Cost for Material</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para id="Para665467">As you can see, the "Material" Costing Element is
    showing in the drop-down menu. This is a system-defined Costing Element
    available to all purchased Items. For the purposes of this exercise, we"ll
    assign a material Cost of $6.00 to Item B1. After we select the SAVE
    button, we are returned to the Maintain Item Costs screen, where the
    newly-added Actual Cost is recorded, as shown in the following
    screenshot:</para>
    <para id="Para665471"><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_maintItemCost-2.png"
                       id="Graphic665469" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption665472">Actual Cost Entered for Item
          B1</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
  </section>
  <section id="Section665474">
    <title><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>actual costs</primary>
        <secondary>posting of explained</secondary>
      </indexterm>Posting Actual to Standard</title>
    <para id="Para665475">Because we want to track the costing aspects of
    Inventory transactions involving Item B1 in the General Ledger, we need to
    post the Actual Cost to the Standard Cost. There are several ways to
    accomplish this posting, but for now we will use the right-click menu's
    "Post Actual Cost to Standard" option. As you can see in the next screen,
    the Standard Cost column now shows the same amount as the Actual Cost
    column:</para>
    <para id="Para665479"><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_maintItemCost-3.png"
                       id="Graphic665477" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption665480">Actual Cost Posted to Standard Cost for
          Item B1</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <note>
      <para id="Para665482">The timetable for posting Actual Cost updates to
      Standard Cost should be guided by Accounting practices at your site.
      Variances between Actual Cost and Standard Cost may provide you with
      useful supply chain or production-related information.</para>
    </note>
  </section>
  <section id="Section665483">
    <title>Updating Actual Costs</title>
    <para id="Para665484">So, we"ve discussed how to enter Actual Costs and
    how to post them to Standard. The next question is: How do you update
    Costs when the Costs for an Item change? And also: How do you ensure that
    any changes are recognized wherever the Item is used?</para>
    <para id="Para665485">To answer these questions, let's continue looking at
    our purchased Item B1. This Item, a book, has an Actual Cost of $6.00--and
    this Actual Cost has been posted to Standard. As you can see in the
    following screenshot, Item B1 is a component in the Bill of Materials for
    Item SET, which is a set of books:</para>
    <para id="Para665489"><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_costSingleBOM.png"
                       id="Graphic665487" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption665490">Costed View of Component Items</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para id="Para665491">Let's say our Vendor increases the price for Item B1
    from $6.00 to $7.00. Using the Maintain Item Costs screen, we would record
    this increased Actual Cost, as shown in the following screenshot:</para>
    <para id="Para665495"><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_updateActCost.png"
                       id="Graphic665493" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption665496">Update Actual Cost for Item B1</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <note>
      <para id="Para665498">The system will automatically update Actual Costs
      for purchased Items when Vouchers are posted--that is, if the vouchered
      Cost per Item differs from the current Actual Cost on file. The Actual
      Cost on record may increase or decrease, depending on the cost per Item
      entered when Purchase Orders are vouchered.</para>
    </note>
    <para id="Para665499">The Actual Cost for Item B1 has now been updated,
    reflecting the change in the Vendor pricing. If we return now to the
    Costed Bill of Materials for Item SET, we can see how the change affected
    one of the manufactured Items where Item B1 is used:</para>
    <para id="Para665503"><anchor id="Anchor39159" role="Cross-Ref"
    xreflabel="39159: Figure: Figure 9.3:  Actual Cost of Component Item Updated" />
    <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_costSingleBOM2.png"
                       id="Graphic665501" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption665505">Actual Cost of Component Item
          Updated</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para id="Para665508">You have to look closely at <link
    endterm="Anchor39159" id="XRef665507" linkend="Anchor39159"> Actual Cost
    of Component Item Updated</link>Figure 5.75 to fully appreciate the subtle
    changes that have occurred. For one thing, you can see that the unit Cost
    for Item B1 has been updated to $7.00. This change affected the "Total
    Cost" for the parent Item SET. However, the Actual and Standard Costs for
    Item SET have not been affected:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d9b08">
        <para id="Para665510">Total Cost = $13.00</para>
        <para id="Para665511">Actual Cost = $12.00</para>
        <para id="Para665512">Standard Cost = $12.00</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
  <section id="Section665513">
    <title>Rolling Up Actual Costs</title>
    <para id="Para665514">Why does the above-mentioned difference exist? The
    reason is that the Cost update for Item B1 has not yet been "rolled up."
    Once a Cost update has been rolled up, the change will be recognized
    wherever the Item is used. In our current example, the Costed Bill of
    Materials for Item SET reflects the update, but the Actual and Standard
    Costs for Item SET have not yet absorbed the change.</para>
    <tip>
      <para id="Para665516">To determine whether Costs have been rolled up,
      look closely at the dates when Costs were last updated on the Maintain
      Item Costs screen. You can also look for differences between the Total
      Cost and the Actual and Standard Costs for an Item on the Costed Bill of
      Materials display.</para>
    </tip>
    <para id="Para665519">Another point to consider is that <link
    endterm="Anchor39159" id="XRef665518" linkend="Anchor39159"> Actual Cost
    of Component Item Updated</link>Figure 5.75 is displaying data using the
    "Use Actual Cost" parameter. Note the difference when the "Use Standard
    Cost" option is selected instead, as shown in the following screen:</para>
    <para id="Para665524"><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_costSingleBOM3.png"
                       id="Graphic665522" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption665526">No Affect on Standard Cost from Actual
          Cost Update</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para id="Para665527">As you can see, no change is showing in the Standard
    Cost for Item B1. The Standard Cost is still $6.00. The reason for this is
    that the Actual Cost update has not yet been posted to Standard.</para>
    <para id="Para665528">To roll up the Item B1 Cost update so that Item SET
    recognizes the change, we open the Update Actual Costs by Item screen, as
    shown below:</para>
    <para id="Para665532"><anchor id="Anchor18335" role="Cross-Ref"
    xreflabel="18335: Figure: Figure 9.5:  Roll Up Actual Cost Update" />
    <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_updateActCost2.png"
                       id="Graphic665530" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption665534">Roll Up Actual Cost Update</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para id="Para665537">As you can see in <link endterm="Anchor18335"
    id="XRef665536" linkend="Anchor18335"> Roll Up Actual Cost
    Update</link>Figure 5.77, we have selected the "Roll Up Actual Costs"
    option. Here we are performing a Cost roll up--which is to say that we are
    seeking to impact Actual Costs for all Items that use Item B1. After we
    select the UPDATE button, all Items that use Item B1 will recognize the
    Actual Cost update. To verify the change has been recognized, we return to
    the Costed Bill of Materials for Item SET, as shown below:</para>
    <para id="Para665542"><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_costSingleBOM4.png"
                       id="Graphic665540" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption665543">Actual Cost Rolled Up and Recognized by
          Parent Item</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para id="Para665544">Sure enough, the Total Cost for Item SET is now
    equal to its Actual Cost. We have successfully rolled up the Cost update
    for the component Item B1. The update has been recognized by the parent
    Item. And the update has been recognized not only by Item SET--but also by
    any other parent Items where Item B1 is used.</para>
    <tip>
      <para id="Para665546">Our example has focused on Cost roll ups for
      individual Items. But you may also perform multiple simultaneous roll
      ups by Class Code. Keep in mind, though, that multiple updates may put a
      strain on server resources. Consider performing Cost updates by Class
      Code during off-peak hours.</para>
    </tip>
    <para id="Para665547">Incidentally, we could have achieved the same result
    by updating lower level material Costs for the parent Item SET, as shown
    below:</para>
    <para id="Para665551"><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_updateActCost3.png"
                       id="Graphic665549" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption665552">Manufactured Item Perspective on Cost
          Roll Up</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para id="Para665553">With the option "Update Lower Level Material Costs"
    selected, any component Item material changes will be recognized by the
    parent Item. In this case, the changes made to Item B1 will be reflected
    in the Actual Cost for Item SET.</para>
  </section>
  <section id="Section665554">
    <title>Standard Cost Roll Ups</title>
    <para id="Para665555">The process for updating and rolling up Standard
    Costs mirrors the Actual Costs process described above. Let's assume we
    have already posted the Actual Cost update to Standard for Item B1--using
    the Maintain Item Costs screen, for example. That means, the Standard Cost
    for Item B1 is now also $7.00, as we see reflected in the Costed Bill of
    Materials for Item SET:</para>
    <para id="Para665559"><anchor id="Anchor22474" role="Cross-Ref"
    xreflabel="22474: Figure: Figure 9.8:  Standard Cost Updated for Item B1" />
    <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_costSingleBOM5.png"
                       id="Graphic665557" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption665561">Standard Cost Updated for Item
          B1</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para id="Para665564">When the "Use Standard Costs" option is selected as
    in <link endterm="Anchor22474" id="XRef665563" linkend="Anchor22474">
    Standard Cost Updated for Item B1</link>Figure 5.80, you can see that the
    Total Cost for Item SET differs from the Standard Cost. This means that
    the Standard Cost update for Item B1 has not been recognized. To ensure
    that parent Items recognize the Standard Cost change, we must roll up the
    Standard Cost, as shown below:</para>
    <para id="Para665569"><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_postActCost.png"
                       id="Graphic665567" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption665570">Rolling Up Standard Cost</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para id="Para665571">With the "Roll Up Standard Costs" option selected,
    we post the update and return once again to the Costed Bill of Materials
    display for Item SET. As the following screen shows, the Standard Cost
    update has successfully been recognized by the parent Item:</para>
    <para id="Para665575"><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_costSingleBOM6.png"
                       id="Graphic665573" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption665576">Standard Cost Update Recognized by
          Parent Item</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
  </section>
  <section id="Section665577">
    <title>User-Defined Costing Elements</title>
    <para id="Para665578">In addition to the system-defined "Material" Costing
    Element, you may also create user-defined Costing Elements. These
    accessory elements enable you to specify additional Item costs.</para>
    <para id="Para665579">To add a user-defined Costing Element, we again
    select the NEW COST button. The available elements are shown in the
    following screenshot. As you can see, the "Material" element is no longer
    available in the drop-down list. That is because the "Material" Costing
    Element is already in use.</para>
    <para id="Para665583"><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_createItemCost-2.png"
                       id="Graphic665581" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption665584">Add User-Defined Costing
          Element</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para id="Para665585">We will select the "Freight Surcharge" element and
    specify a Cost of $0.25. The following screen shows this new Cost has been
    added to the Actual Cost for Item B1.</para>
    <note>
      <para id="Para665587">There is no requirement that all Actual Costs must
      be posted to Standard. You may post certain Costs and not
      others--depending on the needs of your site.</para>
    </note>
    <para id="Para665591"><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_maintItemCost-4.png"
                       id="Graphic665589" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption665592">User-Defined Cost Added to Actual
          Cost</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para id="Para665593">The master list of user-defined Costing Elements can
    be found in the Master Information section of the P/D Module. The
    following screen shows the list of Costing Elements created for this
    scenario:</para>
    <para id="Para665597"><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_userCostElem.png"
                       id="Graphic665595" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption665598">Master List of User-Defined Costing
          Elements</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para id="Para665599">When creating a user-defined Costing Element, you
    may specify the "Accept P/O Distributions" option. Select this option if
    you want the Costing Element to be used for distributing Costs related to
    Purchase Order Vouchers. If selected, the Costing Element will be included
    as one of the available Costing Elements when Voucher Item Costs are
    distributed.</para>
    <tip>
      <para id="Para665601">In addition to using Costing Elements, you may
      also create Costing Items--that is, Items assigned the Item Type
      "Costing." A Costing Item is a kind of pseudo Item used solely to
      provide a costed value for a Costing Element. Simply insert a Costing
      Item into a Bill of Materials, add Costs to the Item, and then link the
      Item to a Costing Element. You may then track the Costs of the pseudo
      Item as a user-defined Cost.</para>
    </tip>
  </section>
  <section id="Section665603">
    <title><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>costing</primary>
        <secondary>for manufactured items</secondary>
      </indexterm>Manufactured Item Costing</title>
    <para id="Para665604">Okay, we"ve covered how to assign Costs to a
    purchased Item. Now let's look at costing for a manufactured Item.</para>
    <para id="Para665605">The manufactured Item we will be using in this next
    scenario is Item TDMR100, a yellow toy truck having four component Items.
    The fourth component--Item TDPKIT--is also manufactured. Item TDPKIT is
    the packaging used to package the yellow toy truck. The next screen shows
    an indented Bill of Materials for Item TDMR100:</para>
    <para id="Para665609"><anchor id="Anchor98976" role="Cross-Ref"
    xreflabel="98976: Figure: Figure 8.8:  Indented Bill of Materials" />
    <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_indentBOMTruck.png"
                       id="Graphic665607" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption665611">Indented Bill of Materials</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para id="Para665612">Because manufactured Items consist of component
    Items--sometimes extending to several layers--the costing issues are more
    complex than they are for purchased Items. New Costs are assigned in the
    same way as they are for purchased Items. But the layers of Costs and the
    relationships between them make costing for manufactured Items
    unique.</para>
    <note>
      <para id="Para665614">New Costs are assigned to manufactured Items in
      the same way that new Costs are assigned to purchased Items. You simply
      select the NEW COST button on the Maintain Item Costs screen and specify
      a Costing Element and Cost amount.</para>
    </note>
    <para id="Para665615">All Costs have already been assigned to Item
    TDMR100--and to all its component Items. So we will jump right into
    understanding how these Costs fit together.</para>
    <para id="Para665616">Let's start by looking at Costs associated with the
    manufactured component Item TDPKIT, the packaging for our yellow truck. As
    we saw in <link endterm="Anchor98976" id="XRef665618"
    linkend="Anchor98976"> Indented Bill of Materials</link>Figure 5.86, Item
    TDPKIT is the fourth component listed on the Bill of Materials for the
    parent Item. The Costs for Item TDPKIT are shown in the following
    screenshot:</para>
    <para id="Para665623"><anchor id="Anchor30461" role="Cross-Ref"
    xreflabel="30461: Figure: Figure 8.9:  Item Costing for Manufactured Component Item TDPKIT" />
    <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_maintItemCost-5.png"
                       id="Graphic665621" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption665625">Item Costing for Manufactured Component
          Item TDPKIT</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para id="Para665626">A few key points about manufactured Item costing can
    be made by looking closely at the information displayed in <link
    endterm="Anchor30461" id="XRef665628" linkend="Anchor30461"> Item Costing
    for Manufactured Component Item TDPKIT</link>Figure 5.87:</para>
    <orderedlist continuation="restarts" inheritnum="ignore">
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18da1c8">
        <para id="Para665630">Three system-defined Costing Elements are
        available to manufactured Items: "Material," "Direct Labor," and
        "Overhead."</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18da1ec">
        <para id="Para665631">Material Costs for manufactured Items are always
        lower level--which means they are associated with component Items, not
        with the parent Item.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e7a00">
        <para id="Para665632">Direct labor and overhead Costs are this
        level--meaning, if in use, these Costs are associated with the parent
        Item they refer to.</para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <note>
      <para id="Para665634">This level Costs are associated with the parent
      Item they refer to. Lower level Costs are associated with component
      Items.</para>
    </note>
    <para id="Para665635">As you can see, Item TDPKIT has material, direct
    labor, and overhead Costs associated with it. The labor and overhead Costs
    are displaying as this level (that is, not lower level). And the material
    Costs, as expected, are shown as lower level Costs. Let's look first at
    how the lower level material Costs totalling $0.55 were arrived at. If you
    recall, Item TDPKIT has two component Items: TDK1 and TDK2. The following
    screenshot shows Item costing for these two Items:</para>
    <para id="Para665639"><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_maintItemCost-6.png"
                       id="Graphic665637" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption665640">Costs for Component Items</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para id="Para665641">Items TDK1 and TDK2 are basic purchased Items having
    material Costs only. Doing some simple math, we see how the lower level
    material Costs for Item TDPKIT were calculated:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e7ad8">
        <para id="Para665642">$0.30 (TDK1) + $0.25 (TDK2) = $0.55</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
  <section id="Section665644">
    <title><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>labor costs</primary>
        <secondary>explained</secondary>
      </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>overhead costs</primary>
        <secondary>explained</secondary>
      </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>costing</primary>
        <secondary>labor costs explained</secondary>
      </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>costing</primary>
        <secondary>overhead costs explained</secondary>
      </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>work centers</primary>
        <secondary>labor charges for</secondary>
      </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>work centers</primary>
        <secondary>overhead charges for</secondary>
      </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>costing</primary>
        <secondary>work centers and</secondary>
      </indexterm>Labor and Overhead Costs</title>
    <para id="Para665645">So, that explains the material Costs for Item
    TDPKIT. Now let's look at the Item's direct labor Costs. We"ll explore the
    overhead Costs a little later. Referring back to <link
    endterm="Anchor30461" id="XRef665647" linkend="Anchor30461"> Item Costing
    for Manufactured Component Item TDPKIT</link>Figure 5.87, you recall that
    direct labor Costs for Item TDPKIT total $1.00. How was this amount
    determined? The answer to that question is the subject of our next
    scenario.</para>
    <para id="Para665649">Direct labor Costs are tied to the manufacturing
    process, to the Operations required to make an Item. So, to calculate
    labor Costs, we need to know how long it takes to make the Item and what
    the labor rates are. To gather this information, we will need to look at a
    series of different screens. We"ll begin by examining the Bill of
    Operations for Item TDPKIT:</para>
    <para id="Para665653"><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_booTDPKIT.png" id="Graphic665651" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption665654">Bill of Operations for Item
          TDPKIT</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para id="Para665655">As you can see, there is only one Operation listed
    on the Bill of Operations. It is Standard Operation "TD-A," which is
    performed in Work Center "Assembly." We can learn more about this
    Operation by double-clicking on it to open it, as shown in the following
    screen:</para>
    <para id="Para665659"><anchor id="Anchor59303" role="Cross-Ref"
    xreflabel="59303: Figure: Figure 8.12:  Operation Detail from TDPKIT Bill of Operations" />
    <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_booItemTDPKIT.png"
                       id="Graphic665657" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption665661">Operation Detail from TDPKIT Bill of
          Operations</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para id="Para665664">The Bill of Operations Item screen shown in <link
    endterm="Anchor59303" id="XRef665663" linkend="Anchor59303"> Operation
    Detail from TDPKIT Bill of Operations</link>Figure 5.90 contains extensive
    controls used to define the Operation. Looking closely at the screenshot,
    we see Standard Operation "TD-A" is in use. Standard Operations are not
    required, but in this case one is being used.</para>
    <note>
      <para id="Para665667">Setup time and run time values will carry over
      from the Standard Operation master if a Standard Operation is in
      use.</para>
    </note>
  </section>
  <section id="Section665668">
    <title>Setup and Run Time Charges</title>
    <para id="Para665669">The Work Center "Assembly" has been specified from
    the drop-down menu. And the following setup time and run time values have
    been entered:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e7e5c">
        <para id="Para665670">Setup time = 5 minutes (charged only once per
        Operation)</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e7e80">
        <para id="Para665671">Run time = 1 minute (charged per each unit of
        Item TDPKIT)</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para id="Para665672">It's important to highlight the differences in how
    setup times and run times are charged. As you might expect, run time is
    the amount of time required to execute an Operation. In our scenario, the
    Operation involves assembling packaging for the yellow toy truck. With a
    run time of 1 minute and a per value of 1 EACH, that means it takes 1
    minute to assemble the packaging for one unit of Item TDPKIT. So, if a
    Work Order calls for 100 units of packaging, then run time will be charged
    100 times--for a total of 100 minutes.</para>
    <para id="Para665673">Setup time is charged differently. Setup time refers
    to the amount of time needed to prepare the Work Center to perform the
    Operation. Setup time is charged only once per Operation--regardless of
    the number of units required by a Work Order. In other words, to use our
    previous example, if a Work Order calls for 100 units of packaging, the
    setup time charge would be 5 minutes.</para>
    <note>
      <para id="Para665675">Setup time is charged only once per Operation,
      regardless of the quantity ordered.</para>
    </note>
    <para id="Para665676">You should pay attention also to how reporting of
    setup and run time is specified. We see in <link endterm="Anchor59303"
    id="XRef665678" linkend="Anchor59303"> Operation Detail from TDPKIT Bill
    of Operations</link>Figure 5.90 that both times are to be reported as
    Direct Labor. This means that all labor required to set up the Work Center
    and also to run the Operation will appear as Direct Labor Cost for the
    Item.</para>
    <para id="Para665680">We referred earlier to Standard Operation "TD-A."
    The following screen shows the master for this Standard Operation:</para>
    <para id="Para665684"><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_standOpTDPKIT.png"
                       id="Graphic665682" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption665685">Standard Operation Master</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para id="Para665686">The setup and run time values entered on the
    Standard Operation master transfer to the Bill of Operations if and when
    the Standard Operation is specified. As you can see, the same values
    appear here as we saw in <link endterm="Anchor59303" id="XRef665688"
    linkend="Anchor59303"> Operation Detail from TDPKIT Bill of
    Operations</link>Figure 5.90. These values may be changed at the Operation
    level, but any permanent changes must be made to the Standard Operation
    master itself.</para>
    <para id="Para665690">So we now know the amount of time required for the
    Operation. Next we need to determine the rate charged for labor. For that
    information, we must turn to the Work Center master for Work Center
    "Assembly," as shown in the next screenshot:</para>
    <para id="Para665694"><anchor id="Anchor13529" role="Cross-Ref"
    xreflabel="13529: Figure: Figure 8.14:  Work Center Master" /> <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_workCenterTDPKIT.png"
                       id="Graphic665692" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption665696">Work Center Master</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para id="Para665697">Just as Standard Operations may be used for Bill of
    Operations Items, so may Standard Labor Rates be used for Work Centers. As
    you can see in <link endterm="Anchor13529" id="XRef665699"
    linkend="Anchor13529"> Work Center Master</link>Figure 5.92, the Standard
    Labor Rate "MA10" is specified for both run and setup labor. To determine
    what the dollar amount is for this standard rate, we open the Standard
    Labor Rates master list found in the Master Information section of the P/D
    Module. The specific details for rate "MA10" are shown in the following
    screen:</para>
    <para id="Para665704"><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_standLabRate.png"
                       id="Graphic665702" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption665706">Standard Labor Rate</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para id="Para665707">As you can see, the Standard Labor Rate = $10.00.
    This means that for our Assembly Operation, $10 is the hourly rate charged
    for setup; it is also the hourly rate charged for run time.</para>
    <para id="Para665708">Let's review, then, the information we have gathered
    so far in our effort to reconstruct how direct labor Costs for
    manufactured component Item TDPKIT were arrived at:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e8030">
        <para id="Para665709">Setup time = 5 mins (converted to hours: 5/60 =
        .0833333)</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e8054">
        <para id="Para665710">Run time = 1 min (converted to hours: 1/60 =
        .016666)</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e8078">
        <para id="Para665711">Setup rate = $10/hr</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e809c">
        <para id="Para665712">Run rate = $10/hr</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para id="Para665713">We now have enough information to calculate the
    direct labor Cost. The following formula is the one we will use:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e80e4">
        <para id="Para665714">(setup time x setup rate) + (run time x run
        rate) = direct labor Cost</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para id="Para665715">This formula works because, as you recall, the
    "Assembly" Operation specifies that setup time and run time are both
    reported as direct labor. All we have to do now is insert the correct
    values, and the equation looks like this:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e812c">
        <para id="Para665716">(.0833333 x $10.00) + (.016666 x $10.00) =
        $1.00</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para id="Para665717">To verify that $1.00 is indeed the direct labor Cost
    for Item TDPKIT, let's look at the Maintain Item Costs screen for Item
    TDPKIT again:</para>
    <para id="Para665721"><anchor id="Anchor90804" role="Cross-Ref"
    xreflabel="90804: Figure: Figure 8.16:  Item Costing for Item TDPKIT" />
    <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_maintItemCost-5.png"
                       id="Graphic665719" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption665723">Item Costing for Item TDPKIT</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para id="Para665724">Sure enough, the reported direct labor Cost for Item
    TDPKIT = $1.00. As you can see, this amount has been posted to the
    Standard Cost for the Item.</para>
    <para id="Para665725">Finally, we need to determine how overhead Cost for
    Item TDPKIT is arrived at. Referring back to the Work Center master shown
    in <link endterm="Anchor13529" id="XRef665727" linkend="Anchor13529"> Work
    Center Master</link>Figure 5.92, we recall that the overhead rate per hour
    = $10.00 To calculate overhead Cost then, we would use the following
    formula:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e81e0">
        <para id="Para665729">setup time + run time x overhead rate = overhead
        Cost</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para id="Para665730">If we now insert the correct values, the equation
    looks like this:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e8228">
        <para id="Para665731">.0833333 + . 016666 x $10.00 = $1.00</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para id="Para665734">Again, referring to the Item Costing detail shown in
    <link endterm="Anchor90804" id="XRef665733" linkend="Anchor90804"> Item
    Costing for Item TDPKIT</link>Figure 5.94, we can verify that reported
    overhead Costs for Item TDPKIT = $1.00.</para>
  </section>
  <section id="Section665737">
    <title><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>costing</primary>
        <secondary>multi-level explained</secondary>
      </indexterm>Multi-Level Costing</title>
    <para id="Para665738">We"ve now covered the fundamentals of manufactured
    Item costing. But remember: Item TDPKIT is a fairly simple manufactured
    Item. We will look next at costing for the more complex parent Item
    TDMR100. The same processes will be used to determine its Costs, but the
    factors we have to consider are more complicated.</para>
    <para id="Para665739">To begin, let's look at the Costs for Item TDMR100,
    as shown in the following screen:</para>
    <para id="Para665743"><anchor id="Anchor56668" role="Cross-Ref"
    xreflabel="56668: Figure: Figure 8.17:  Item Costing for Parent Item TDMR100" />
    <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_maintItemCost-7.png"
                       id="Graphic665741" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption665745">Item Costing for Parent Item
          TDMR100</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para id="Para665746">For starters, note the distinctions between the
    lower level and this level Costs. As we discussed earlier, this level
    Costs are associated with the parent Item they refer to. Lower level Costs
    are associated with component Items. For Item TDMR100, the levels may be
    broken down as follows:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e8348">
        <para id="Para665747">This level: Direct labor and overhead Costs for
        parent Item TDMR100</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e836c">
        <para id="Para665748">Lower level: Direct labor and overhead Costs
        associated with component Item TDPKIT; total material Costs for all
        non-manufactured component Items.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para id="Para665749">To better understand how these levels fit together,
    let's open the Costed Indented Bill of Materials display, found in the
    Costing section of the P/D Module. This is a useful display because it
    shows not only Bill of Materials Items, but also the Costs associated with
    each:</para>
    <para id="Para665753"><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_costedIndentBOM.png"
                       id="Graphic665751" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption665755">Costed Indented Bill of Materials
          Display for Item TDMR100</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para id="Para665756">As you can see, Item TDMR100 consists of four
    component Items--one of which, Item TDPKIT, has two component Items of its
    own.</para>
    <para id="Para665757">We"ve already determined that material Costs for
    manufactured Items are always lower level. So, to determine material Costs
    for Item TDMR100, we must look to the non-manufactured component Items:
    TDMRY, TDMRB, TDMRW, TDK1, and TDK2.</para>
    <para id="Para665758">Conveniently, the only Costs assigned to these Items
    are material Costs. As a result, we simply have to add up the extended
    Costs for these Items to determine the overall material Cost for Item
    TDMR100.</para>
    <tip>
      <para id="Para665760">When using the Costed Indented Bill of Materials
      display, be sure to distinguish between unit Cost and extended Cost. The
      extended Cost represents the unit Cost multiplied by the quantity
      required by the Bill of Materials.</para>
    </tip>
    <para id="Para665761">When we add all these material Costs together--TDMRY
    ($0.0025), TDMRB ($2.5000), TDMRW ($1.2500), TDK1 ($0.3000), and TDK2
    ($0.2500)--we get an overall material Cost for Item TDMR100 of $8.0525.
    Referring back to <link endterm="Anchor56668" id="XRef665763"
    linkend="Anchor56668"> Item Costing for Parent Item TDMR100</link>Figure
    5.95, we can verify on the Maintain Item Costs screen that this amount is
    in fact the reported material Cost for Item TDMR100.</para>
    <para id="Para665765">Next, we need to examine how direct labor Costs for
    Item TDMR100 are determined. As before, we begin with the Bill of
    Operations, as shown in the following screenshot:</para>
    <para id="Para665769"><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_booTDMR100.png"
                       id="Graphic665767" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption665770">Bill of Operations for Item
          TDMR100</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para id="Para665771">As you can see, the Bill of Operations for Item
    TDMR100 contains three Operations--as compared to the one Operation we saw
    for component Item TDPKIT. We"ve already discussed how to locate costing
    information on both the Operation and Work Center screens. So, rather than
    repeat that process here, we"ve extracted the pertinent information into
    the following table:</para>
    <para id="Para665823"><informaltable>
        <tgroup cols="5">
          <thead>
            <row>
              <entry><para id="Para665784">Work Center</para></entry>
              <entry><para id="Para665786">Setup + Run Time</para></entry>
              <entry><para id="Para665788">Setup Rate</para></entry>
              <entry><para id="Para665790">Run Rate</para></entry>
              <entry><para id="Para665792">Overhead Rate</para></entry>
            </row>
          </thead>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry><para id="Para665794">Assembly</para></entry>
              <entry><para id="Para665796">.03333 hrs.</para></entry>
              <entry><para id="Para665798">$10</para></entry>
              <entry><para id="Para665800">$10</para></entry>
              <entry><para id="Para665802">$10</para></entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry><para id="Para665804">Paint</para></entry>
              <entry><para id="Para665806">.16666 hrs.</para></entry>
              <entry><para id="Para665808">$10</para></entry>
              <entry><para id="Para665810">$10</para></entry>
              <entry><para id="Para665812">$10</para></entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry><para id="Para665814">Ship</para></entry>
              <entry><para id="Para665816">.05000 hrs.</para></entry>
              <entry><para id="Para665818">$10</para></entry>
              <entry><para id="Para665820">$10</para></entry>
              <entry><para id="Para665822">$10</para></entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </informaltable></para>
    <para id="Para665824">As you can see, all the rates (setup, run, and
    overhead) are the same: $10.00. This fact enables us to combine the setup
    and run times into one. If the rates were not identical, the setup and run
    times would have to be multiplied individually by the appropriate
    rate.</para>
    <para id="Para665825">To determine the direct labor Cost for Item TDMR100,
    then, we follow the same equation we introduced earlier:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18f3048">
        <para id="Para665826">(setup time x setup rate) + (run time x run
        rate) = direct labor Cost</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para id="Para665827">To simplify things this time around, we"ve combined
    the setup and run times for each Operation into a single value. With those
    values inserted, the equation now looks like this:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18f3090">
        <para id="Para665828">(.03333 + .16666 + .05000) x $10.00 =
        $2.50</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para id="Para665831">Looking back at the Maintain Item Costs screen shown
    in <link endterm="Anchor56668" id="XRef665830" linkend="Anchor56668"> Item
    Costing for Parent Item TDMR100</link>Figure 5.95, we can verify that the
    direct labor Costs for Item TDMR100 are indeed $2.500. To calculate
    overhead Cost, we would again use a formula we introduced earlier:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18f30d8">
        <para id="Para665833">setup time + run time x overhead rate = overhead
        Cost</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para id="Para665834">And with values for each of the Operations for Item
    TDMR100 inserted, the overhead Cost equation would appear as
    follows:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18f3120">
        <para id="Para665835">(.03333 + .16666 + .05000) x $10.00 =
        $2.50</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para id="Para665836">As expected, this result corresponds to the overhead
    Costs reported for Item TDMR100 in <link endterm="Anchor56668"
    id="XRef665838" linkend="Anchor56668"> Item Costing for Parent Item
    TDMR100</link>Figure 5.95. We have now accounted for all the Costs
    associated with our manufactured Item TDMR100.</para>
  </section>
</section>