<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2008 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section>
  <title id="Anchor81167"><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>topics</primary>
      <secondary>multiple location control</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>MLC</primary>
      <see>multiple location control</see>
    </indexterm>Topic: Distributing Multiple Location Control (MLC)
  Items</title>
  <para>Whenever you attempt to change the Quantity on Hand of a Multiple
  Location Control (MLC) Item, you are presented with several distribution
  options. <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>multiple location control</primary>
      <secondary>explained</secondary>
    </indexterm>In this section we describe those options, taking you
  step-by-step through the distribution process.</para>
  <note>
    <para>These extra distribution options are required for MLC Items. Items
    that do not have Multiple Location Control turned on are not
    affected.</para>
  </note>
  <section id="Section672849">
    <title>Receiving into Inventory</title>
    <para>In the example we will be using here, the Item in question is Item
    YTRUCK1, a yellow toy truck. We will be receiving quantity of this Item
    into Inventory, using a miscellaneous Material Receipt transaction--as
    found Inventory Module.</para>
    <note>
      <para>Items are received into Inventory by various paths--from Shipping,
      from Manufacturing, or through miscellaneous Material Receipt
      transactions. Although this example describes a miscellaneous Material
      Receipt transaction, the distribution sequence is the same when
      receiving MLC Items by other means.</para>
    </note>
    <para>As you can see from the following screen, the truck is located in
    three Warehouse Locations--"01-01-01", "01-01-02" and "01-01-03". That is
    the definition of an MLC Item. It is an Item that is located in more than
    one Warehouse Location. You will notice that "01-01-01" is the Default
    Location for this Item.</para>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_distrStockToLoc.png" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Distribute Stock To/From Warehouse Locations</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <note>
      <para>If you ever change your mind or need to cancel a distribution
      while it is in process, simply select the CANCEL button. This will stop
      the distribution and no transactions will be posted. You can begin the
      transaction again at a later point when you are ready to.</para>
    </note>
    <para>The "Distribute Stock To/From Warehouse Locations" screen will
    display whenever you are performing operations that change the Quantity on
    Hand of MLC Items. You may encounter this screen in any of the following
    modules:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Inventory Module: Most all options listed under the "Inventory
        Transactions" submenu. Also any option that involves issuing goods to
        shipping or receiving goods into Inventory.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Manufacture Module: Any option that involves production posting,
        operations posting, or the issuing and returning of materials.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>As you can see in the example, the Material Receipt operation that
    brought us to this point calls for the distribution of 300 units of Item
    YTRUCK1. None of the units have been distributed so far--leaving all 300
    units still to be distributed. The next question is this: Which
    Location(s) do we want to distribute the 300 trucks to?</para>
    <note>
      <para>Items are not required to have a default Location. Instead,
      default Locations may optionally be assigned to Items within Item Site
      definitions.</para>
    </note>
    <para>Several options are available to us:</para>
    <orderedlist continuation="restarts" inheritnum="ignore">
      <listitem>
        <para>We can select the DEFAULT AND POST button. Doing so will
        automatically distribute 300 truck units to the Default Location--in
        this case, "01-01-01"--and then post the distribution, creating a
        transaction record.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>We can select the DEFAULT button, which will distribute any
        balance to the Default Location. This option is typically used after
        you have already distributed quantities to other Locations and have a
        balance remaining.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>We can select the CANCEL button and start over at any
        point</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Or we can decide to distribute some to each Location by
        selecting the Locations individually from the "Valid Locations"
        list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
  </section>
  <section id="Section672877">
    <title><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>inventory</primary>
        <secondary>mlc distribution of</secondary>
      </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>multiple location control</primary>
        <secondary>distributing quantity and</secondary>
      </indexterm>Distributing Quantity</title>
    <para>For the purpose of this exercise, let's choose the third
    option--distributing some to one Location and some to the other. To begin,
    we will double-click on Location "01-01-02". The following distribution
    screen will appear:</para>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_distrToLoc.png" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Initial Distribution to First Location</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>As you can see in the example, we must specify how many toy trucks
    to distribute to this Location. We decide to distribute 100 trucks,
    entering this amount in the "Qty. to this Location" field.</para>
    <note>
      <para>Because this initial distribution of 100 units is the first
      distribution for this transaction, the Quantity Tagged displays as
      "0".</para>
    </note>
    <para>Once we have entered the quantity of 100, we then select the
    DISTRIBUTE button, which returns us to the previous screen:</para>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_distrStockToLoc2.png" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Display Showing Partial Distribution to First
          Location</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>The display now shows 100 trucks tagged for distribution to Location
    "01-01-02". If we were to select the POST button at this point, the
    following error message would appear:</para>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_distrError.png" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Error Message: Cannot Perform Partial
          Distribution</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>As the error message indicates, the system does not allow the
    posting of partial distributions. The entire transaction quantity of an
    MLC Item must be completely distributed before the transaction can be
    posted. The next step, then, is to distribute the remaining quantity.
    Let's distribute the remaining 200 truck units to Location
    "01-01-01".</para>
    <para>Since "01-01-01" is the default location, we have a couple of
    options here:</para>
    <orderedlist continuation="restarts" inheritnum="ignore">
      <listitem>
        <para>We could select the DEFAULT button. Doing so would automatically
        distribute the remaining quantity to "01-01-01". The operation would
        then be ready for posting.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Or we could double-click on "01-01-01" to bring us to the
        distribution screen we saw earlier.</para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <para>Let's choose the second option--double-clicking on the line for
    Location "01-01-01". The following distribution screen will appear:</para>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_distrToLoc-2.png" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Partial Distribution to Default Location</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>The screen shows a balance of 200 truck units remaining to be
    distributed--with a quantity of 100 units already tagged. We enter "200"
    into the "Qty. to this Location" field and then select the DISTRIBUTE
    button, which returns us to the previous screen:</para>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_distrStockToLoc3.png" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Display Showing Distribution to Second Location</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <note>
      <para>If you decide to distribute quantities differently--after having
      distributed them once already--you may do so before you select the POST
      button. Simply follow the steps above, substituting new quantities where
      appropriate.</para>
    </note>
    <para>The required quantity has now been completely tagged--100 trucks for
    distribution to "01-01-02" and 200 trucks for distribution to "01-01-01".
    We are now ready to select the POST button. Doing so will complete the
    transaction, returning you to the operation screen that initially
    precipitated the distribution sequence. The MLC Item has been successfully
    distributed.</para>
  </section>
  <section id="Section672923">
    <title><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>multiple location control</primary>
        <secondary>issuing from inventory</secondary>
      </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>inventory</primary>
        <secondary>mlc distribution of</secondary>
      </indexterm>Issuing from Inventory</title>
    <para>You follow a similar procedure as described in the examples above
    when issuing (i.e., removing) Stock from Inventory. However, instead of
    increasing the Quantity on Hand in a Location, the quantity is decreased
    when Stock is issued. The following scenarios represent some of the
    instances in which Stock is removed from Inventory:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Shipping a Sales Order</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Issuing Materials to a Work Order</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Scrapping quantity from a Location</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <note>
      <para>When you issue Stock for an MLC Item, you will only be able to
      remove quantity from Locations whose Quantity on Hand (QOH) is greater
      than "0". This means that if a Location has no QOH, you will not be able
      to issue stock from that Location. The MLC distribution screen will only
      feature Locations with a positive QOH. By way of contrast, all valid
      Locations will be display when receiving Stock into
      Inventory--regardless of the QOH.</para>
    </note>
  </section>
</section>
