<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2008 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section555045" role="openmfg">
  <title>Topic: MPS Basics</title>
  <para>Master Production Scheduling (MPS) is a planning system which serves
  several important purposes:</para>
  <orderedlist continuation="restarts" inheritnum="ignore">
    <listitem>
      <para>Increases visibility into future demand</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>Provides capability for anticipating future demand</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>Drives the plan for lower level components (i.e., Material
      Requirements) based on the Forecast</para>
    </listitem>
  </orderedlist>
  <para>Typically, MPS is used to plan for Items having "independent" demand.
  Independent demand Items are defined as those Items which derive their
  demand directly from Customer requirements through Sales Orders. By
  contrast, "dependent" demand Items are normally purchased Items and
  subassemblies. The demand for dependent Items is derived indirectly--that
  is, based on the demand for their parent Items in a Bill of
  Materials.</para>
  <para>In this section, we will demonstrate OpenMFG's MPS functionality,
  using a Production Plan called COLLECTORS-2007. We have linked a Planning
  Item, COLLECTORS-LINE, to this Production Plan. Both the Plan and the
  Planning Item are included in the data for the OpenMFG Demo Database.</para>
  <note>
    <para>The scenarios described in this section refer to Items and other
    data found in the OpenMFG Demo Database. The Demo Database is available
    for download from the OpenMFG website.</para>
  </note>
  <para>The Bill of Materials for the COLLECTORS-LINE Planning Item is
  composed of three MPS planned Items, each of which have the following
  quantities per:</para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>BTRUCK1: .5</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>RTRUCK1: .3</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>WTRUCK1: .2</para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>Our Production Plan for the COLLECTORS-LINE Planning Item currently
  contains forecast periods for the first three months of 2007. In the example
  we will be using, we will actually adjust the dates and quantities for these
  periods to accommodate demand that is anticipated in late 2006, earlier than
  originally expected. To accommodate a current date that will be different
  from the date on which this section was written, you will be instructed to
  use date offsets of +28, +58, and +88 days. So, for example, if we forecast
  1,000 units of the COLLECTORS-LINE Planning Item for November 2006, the
  planning system will create Orders for 500 BTRUCK1"s, 300 RTRUCK1's and 200
  WTRUCK1"s. (See the quantity per values shown above for each Item in the
  COLLECTORS-LINE\qs Bill of Materials). The COLLECTORS-LINE itself is a
  logical construct, and, as such, no Planned Orders will be created for
  it.</para>
  <note>
    <para>In our scenario, we will be forecasting using a Planning Item--a
    special type of Item used to defined families or lines of products.
    However, the system also allows you to place individual MPS Items on a
    Production Schedule.</para>
  </note>
  <section id="Section555062">
    <title><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>production plans</primary>
        <secondary>releasing and updating</secondary>
      </indexterm>Updating and Releasing Production Plans</title>
    <para>To begin the process of understanding how MPS works, we will first
    update and release our Production Plan (i.e., Forecast). To access the
    master list of Production Plans, follow these steps:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Pull down the M/S Module menu</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select the Planning submenu</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select the "List Production Plans" option</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Click on the COLLECTORS-2007 Production Plan</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Then click the EDIT button</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>Now that we have opened the Production Plan for editing, we can
    drill down and modify the scheduled date and quantity for the
    COLLECTORS-LINE Planning Item. As you recall, COLLECTORS-LINE is the
    Planning Item whose Bill of Materials we discussed above. To begin, follow
    these steps:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select the first scheduled line item</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Click the EDIT button</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>The following screen will appear:</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/F058-ProdPlanItem.png"
                       />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Production Plan Item Screen</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a "Planned Date" that is +28 days from today</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter "1,000" in the "Qty." field</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Click the SAVE button</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Repeat the previous step for the other two line items on the
        Production Plan</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>For the second line, set the date to +58 days from today with a
        quantity of 2000</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>For the third line, set the date to +88 days from today with a
        quantity of 3000</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>On the Production Plan screen, change the "Start Date" field to
        today's date</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Click the SAVE button</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>Now that we have finished updating the Production Plan, we are ready
    to release it. Production Plans must be in a released state ("R") if they
    are to be considered when the MPS planning system is run. To release the
    Production Plan, follow these steps:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Open the List Production Plans screen</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Right-click on the COLLECTORS-2007 Production Plan</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select the "Release" option from the right-click menu</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Note that the status for the plan has changed from "U"
        (un-released) to "R" (released)</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Click the CLOSE button to close the Production Plans
        screen</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
  <section id="Section555093">
    <title><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>mps</primary>
        <secondary>running of</secondary>
      </indexterm>Running MPS</title>
    <para>Because our Production Plan has been released, the MPS planning
    system will recognize it when MPS is run. The next step is to run MPS by
    Planner Code, as follows:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Pull down the M/S Module menu</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select the Scheduling submenu</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Choose the "Run MPS by Planner Code" option</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Check "All Planner Codes," "All Warehouses," and enter a "Cutoff
        Date" that is 1 year in the future (+365), as shown below:</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/F059-MPS-Run.png" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Run MPS by Planner Code</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Click the CREATE button</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Wait while MPS runs in the background</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Screen will close when MPS is finished</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <note>
      <para>In a production environment, you can select the SUBMIT button to
      send the MPS run to the Batch Manager for processing. Because the Batch
      Manager is not available for demonstration databases, please do not use
      this option.</para>
    </note>
  </section>
  <section id="Section555110">
    <title><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>mps</primary>
        <secondary>displaying results for</secondary>
      </indexterm>Displaying Results of an MPS Run</title>
    <para>Once the MPS run is finished, we can go look at the Planned Orders
    generated by the run. To view the results of an MPS run, follow these
    steps:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Pull down the M/S Module menu</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select the Displays submenu</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select the "Planned Orders by Planner Code" option</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Use the default settings and click the QUERY button, to get
        results as shown below:</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/F060-MPS-OrdDisplay.png"
                       />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Planned Orders by Planner Code
          Display</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>The Planned Orders by Planner Code display shows us the top-down
    nature of the Forecast. Notice how the planned quantities match the
    quantity per ratio for each Planning Item component. Also notice how the
    Orders are grouped into three separate date buckets.</para>
  </section>
  <section id="Section555124">
    <title><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>mps</primary>
        <secondary>detailed information for</secondary>
      </indexterm>Displaying MPS Detail for an MPS Item</title>
    <para>We can understand how our new Planned Orders fit into a broader
    context by examining the MPS Detail display. To access the MPS Detail
    screen, follow these steps:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Pull down the M/S Module menu</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select the Displays submenu</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Choose the "MPS Detail" option</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select an absolute Calendar for the current year. (The M/S
        module is configured to use the "2007" absolute Calendar by
        default.)</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Click on the BTRUCK1 Item in the Item Sites display</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Information about BTRUCK1 will be displayed, as shown
        below:</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para> <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/F061-MPSDetail.png" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>MPS Detail Display</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>The example shows the MPS Detail for the selected Item based on the
    Calendar selected. In this case, the Calendar being used is a special
    absolute Calendar that shows the last three months of 2006 and the first
    two months of 2007. As you follow this scenario, you should select the
    Calendar appropriate for the current date--whatever the current date may
    be. If you need a 2008 Calendar, simply select it from the drop-down list
    and then click again on the Item whose MPS Detail information you want to
    display. Also, depending on the time of year, you may need to scroll to
    the right to see the Forecast and Planned Orders.</para>
    <para>Now that we have generated the planned MPS Orders, let's see the
    impact these will have on the plan for Material Requirements Planning
    (MRP) Items.</para>
  </section>
  <section id="Section555144">
    <title><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>mrp</primary>
        <secondary>running of</secondary>
      </indexterm>Running MRP</title>
    <para>To see how MRP will respond to the MPS Orders we created, it will be
    necessary to run MRP. To run MRP by Planner Code, follow these
    steps:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Pull down the M/S Module menu</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select the Scheduling submenu</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Choose the "Run MRP by Planner Code" option</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Check "All Planner Codes," "All Warehouses," and enter a Cutoff
        Date that is 1 year in the future (+365).</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/F062-MRP-Run.png" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Run MRP by Planner Code</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Click the CREATE button</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Wait while MRP runs in the background</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Screen will close when MRP is finished</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
  <section id="Section555159">
    <title><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>mrp</primary>
        <secondary>displaying results for</secondary>
      </indexterm>Displaying Results of MRP after MPS Run</title>
    <para>Once the MRP run is finished, we can go look at the Planned Orders
    generated by the run. To view the results of an MRP run, follow these
    steps:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Pull down the M/S Module menu</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select the Displays submenu</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select the "Planned Orders by Planner Code" option</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Use the default settings and click the QUERY button</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>As you can see, the MRP run generated multiple Planned Orders which
    were not present after we ran MPS initially. The reason for this is
    simple: The extra Orders are MRP Orders generated to satisfy the demand
    created by the MPS Orders. Essentially, we forecasted demand and then
    discovered what materials would be needed to meet that demand--net
    existing Quantity on Hand, other demand, existing supplies, and expected
    receipts.</para>
    <para>If you want to filter out MRP or MPS Items, you may do so on the
    Planned Orders by Planner Code screen by following these steps:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Check the "Selected" radio button</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select "MRP-MRP Items" or "MPS-MPS Items"</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Click the QUERY button</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/F063-MRP-Run-Output.png"
                       />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Planned Orders by Planner Code
          Display</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Click CLOSE to exit the display.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>If you want to continue further and act upon the advice provided by
    the MPS and MRP planning systems, you can proceed by right-clicking on a
    specific Planned Order and releasing it. For more information on releasing
    Planned Orders, see the Basic Business Process Flow chapter of the OpenMFG
    Demo Guide.</para>
  </section>
</section>
