<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2008 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section672485" role="openmfg">
  <title id="Anchor14508">Topic: Order Parameters and MRP</title>
  <para>This section is designed to briefly illustrate the interaction between
  Order Parameters and Material Requirements Planning (MRP). As you will see,
  Order Parameters play a key role in the execution of MRP.</para>
  <section id="Section672488">
    <title><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>material requirements planning</primary>
        <secondary>order parameters and</secondary>
      </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>order parameters</primary>
        <secondary>for mrp</secondary>
      </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>item sites</primary>
        <secondary>order parameter settings</secondary>
      </indexterm>Item Site Settings</title>
    <para>For the purposes of this exercise, we will be looking at the Order
    Parameter settings for a purchased Item--Item V1. The following screenshot
    shows the Item Site master for Item V1:</para>
    <para> <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_ordParamItemSite.png"
                       />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Item Site with Order Parameters
          Selected</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>As you can see in the example, the "Enforce Order Parameters" flag
    is set for this Item Site. Selecting this option tells the system to
    enforce the specified Order Parameters when MRP is run. The "on Manual
    Orders" option applies to manual Work Orders only and does not have an
    impact on MRP.</para>
    <para>Let's define the significance of each Order Parameter
    setting:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Reorder Level: Specifies when a Planned Replenishment Order
        should be created for an Item Site. If Planned Availability minus
        Safety Stock falls below the Reorder Level, then a Replenishment Order
        will be created when MRP is run. The Replenishment Order quantity will
        be equal to the quantity required to return Planned Availability to
        either the Reorder Level or the Order Up To quantity--whichever is
        greater. We will look at Planned Availability later in this section.
        In this example, the Reorder Level is set to 30. So, when Planned
        Availability minus Safety Stock falls below 30, MRP (when it is run)
        will recognize this and reorder quantities for the Item Site.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Order Up To: Indicates the level of Planned Availability an Item
        Site should be replenished up to when MRP is run. In cases where the
        Reorder Level for an Item Site exceeds the Order Up To (OUT), MRP will
        replenish the Item Site up to the Reorder Level. In this example, the
        OUT Level is 100. So, in our example, when Planned Availability falls
        below the Reorder Level, MRP (when it is run) will replenish the Item
        Site quantity up to 100.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <tip>
      <para>Setting the Order Up To Level to "0" removes any restrictions on
      maximum Order quantities. Removing quantity restrictions can be an
      effective strategy to help ensure that all Order demands are satisfied
      when MRP is run. Order demands may not be met if Order Up To Levels are
      set below the demand threshold.</para>
    </tip>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Minimum Order: Indicates the minimum quantity that may be
        entered for a Planned Replenishment Order when MRP is run. In this
        example, no minimum Order quantity is specified.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Order Multiple: Indicates the quantity multiple that should be
        used for Planned Replenishment Orders when MRP is run. In this
        example, the Order multiple = 1.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><indexterm significance="normal">
            <primary>planned orders</primary>
            <secondary>consolidation of</secondary>
          </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
            <primary>material requirements planning</primary>
            <secondary>consolidation of planned orders and</secondary>
          </indexterm>Group MRP Orders Every: Value entered specifies the
        length of a period--measured in days--within which Planned
        Replenishment Orders will be grouped together (i.e, consolidated) to
        meet scheduled demand for the period. This functionality serves to
        limit the total number of Planned Replenishment Orders, thereby
        simplifying order processing. For example, to consolidate demand for
        an Item Site into 30-day buckets, set the value to "30." When MRP is
        run, the system will automatically consolidate all demand falling
        within the 30-day horizon into a single Planned Purchase Order or
        Planned Work Order. The grouping of Planned Orders moves forward in
        time, meaning the system will create as many buckets as will fit
        within the cutoff date specified when MRP is run. The initial grouping
        of Planned Orders is handled differently than subsequent buckets. The
        following formula specifies how the date range for the initial period
        is determined:</para>
        <para>Start Date = Today's Date</para>
        <para>End Date = Today's Date + Lead Time</para>
        <para>All subsequent periods are determined using the following
        calculations:</para>
        <para>Start Date = End Date of Previous Period + 1</para>
        <para>End Date = Start Date of Current Period + Group Value</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <tip>
      <para>To enforce <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>just-in-time</primary>
          <secondary>delivery of planned orders</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>planned orders</primary>
          <secondary>just-in-time delivery and</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>material requirements planning</primary>
          <secondary>just-in-time delivery and</secondary>
        </indexterm>Just-In-Time (JIT) delivery methods, set the MRP group
      value to "0." This will ensure that Planned Order due dates are the same
      as the demand due dates to which they correspond. If the MRP Order
      grouping value is set to "0", the initial period will be determined in
      the same way as for all Planned Order groups:</para>
      <para>Start Date = Today's Date</para>
      <para>End Date = Today's Date + Lead Time</para>
      <para>However, the date range for all subsequent JIT Planned Orders will
      be based on the following calculations:</para>
      <para>Start Date = Demand Due Date - Lead Time</para>
      <para>End Date = Demand Due Date</para>
    </tip>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Safety Stock: Specifies the quantity of Stock you want to keep
        in Inventory to protect against unplanned, unforeseeable trends in
        your Order forecasts. When Material Requirements Planning (MRP) is
        run, the system considers the Safety Stock value when determining
        whether to create Planned Replenishment Orders. If Planned
        Availability minus Safety Stock is below the Reorder Level, then
        Planned Orders will be created. If not below the Reorder Level, then
        no Planned Orders will be created. The system's calculation
        effectively creates a buffer Inventory (if needed) to handle
        unexpected fluctuations in demand. In this example, Safety Stock is
        set to 20.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <tip>
      <para>If you do not want to use the Safety Stock functionality, set the
      Safety Stock value to "0".</para>
    </tip>
  </section>
  <section id="Section672525">
    <title>Viewing Planned Availability</title>
    <para>Planned Availability--also known as available quantity--describes
    Inventory quantity available for consumption by Work Orders or Sales
    Orders. To determine available quantity, the system uses the following
    formula:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Planned Availability = Unallocated Qty. + Qty. on Order</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>Let's look now at Planned Availability for Item V1. The Inventory
    Availability by Item screen found in the I/M Module provides us with this
    detail, as shown below:</para>
    <para> <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_availOrdParamItem.png"
                       />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Inventory Availability Display Showing
          Availability Below Reorder Level</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>As you can see from the screenshot, the available quantity is
    displayed in orange. The orange-colored font is used to indicate that
    Planned Availability has fallen below the Reorder Level. Whenever this
    scenario occurs, Planned Replenishment Orders will be generated the next
    time MRP is run.</para>
    <para>The following columns are of interest to us now:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>QOH = 25: In this example, the Quantity on Hand (QOH) is equal
        to the available quantity. If quantities of Item V1 were in any way
        allocated, these two values would not be the same.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Allocated = 0: Item quantity is considered allocated if Sales
        Orders or Work Orders are demanding the Item. In this case, no
        outstanding demands for Item V1 have been created in the system, and
        so the allocated quantity = 0.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Unallocated = 25: Because Item V1 is not currently allocated to
        any Sales Orders or Work Orders, the unallocated quantity equals the
        QOH.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Reorder Lvl. = 30: This is the Reorder Level specified on the
        Item Site definition.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>OUT Level = 100: This is the Order Up To Level specified on the
        Item Site definition.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Available = 25: Doing some simple math, you can see that the
        available quantity of Item V1 in Warehouse EAST is below the Reorder
        Level--5 units below it, in fact. As a result, a Planned Replenishment
        Order for Item V1 should be created when MRP is run.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
  <section id="Section672546">
    <title>Running MRP</title>
    <para>Now let's run MRP and see what happens. Based on our knowledge of
    the Item Site Order Parameters and the available quantity for Item V1, we
    know that a Planned Replenishment Order will be created. We know this
    because the following condition is true:</para>
    <blockquote>
      <para>Planned Availability (25) - Safety Stock (20) &lt; Reorder Level
      (30).</para>
    </blockquote>
    <para>Whenever Planned Availability minus Safety Stock falls below the
    Reorder Level, a Planned Order will be generated when MRP is run. The only
    question now is what will the Planned Order quantity be?</para>
    <para>The following M/S Module screen, "Run MRP by Item," is one of two
    utilities used to run MRP--the other is "Run MRP by Planner Code." For
    this exercise, we will be running MRP by Item, as shown in the following
    screenshot:</para>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_createPlanRepOrd.png"
                       />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Running MRP by Item</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>We enter Item V1 in the Item Number field, specify the Warehouse
    where the Item Site is located, and set the Cutoff Date for the current
    day. Once we select the CREATE button, MRP is off and running. To see the
    resulting Planned Replenishment Orders, we open the M/S Display "Planned
    Orders by Item," as shown in the following screen:</para>
    <para> <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_planOrdDisp1.png"
                       />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>MRP Created Planned Purchase
          Order</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>As you can see in the example, a Planned Purchase Order has been
    generated for 75 units of Item V1. So how did the system determine that 75
    units was the required quantity?</para>
    <para>Well, when MRP creates Planned Orders, the system looks at both the
    Reorder Level and the Order Up To (OUT) Level. It determines which of the
    two has the greater value--and then it places an Order to replenish
    available quantity up to that value. In our example, the OUT Level (100)
    is the greater value. And so we have the following scenario:</para>
    <blockquote>
      <para>25 (Current Available Qty.) + 75 (Needed Replenishment Qty.) = 100
      (OUT Level)</para>
    </blockquote>
    <para>So you can see, MRP generated a Planned Order for 75 units of Item
    V1 to restore available quantity to the OUT Level.</para>
    <note>
      <para>Because Item V1 is a purchased Item, the Replenishment Order is a
      Planned Purchase Order. Had the Item been a manufactured Item, Planned
      Work Orders would have been created--and also Planned Purchase Orders,
      depending on the availability and Reorder Levels of required component
      Items.</para>
    </note>
  </section>
  <section id="Section672573">
    <title><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>planned orders</primary>
        <secondary>converting to actual orders</secondary>
      </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>material requirements planning</primary>
        <secondary>conversion of planned orders</secondary>
      </indexterm>Converting Planned Orders to Actual Orders</title>
    <para>The next step is to convert the Planned Purchase Order to a Purchase
    Request. Doing so will make Purchasing aware of the requirement. We can
    release the Order using the "Release Order" option from the right-click
    menu. After choosing that option, we are prompted to create a Purchase
    Request, as shown below:</para>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_planOrdDisp2.png"
                       />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Convert Planned Order to Purchase
          Request</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>A quick check of the details on the "Purchase Request" screen shows
    us that the quantity ordered is correct. We now select the CREATE button
    to generate the Purchase Request and forward it to Purchasing. To verify
    this activity, we turn to the P/O Module Display Purchase Requests by
    Item, as shown below:</para>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_purchReqDispl.png"
                       />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Release Purchase Request</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>Sure enough, there's the Purchase Request for the correct quantity.
    Once again, we select the "Release Order" option from the right-click
    menu. Because Item Sources have been defined for the Item, we are asked to
    pick a Vendor from among the list of possible Vendors for this Item, as
    shown in the next screen:</para>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_prItemSource.png"
                       />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Select Item Source during Purchase
          Request Conversion</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>We choose the Vendor Smithson Industries from the list, because this
    is the Vendor with the highest ranking. After selecting the Vendor, we are
    asked whether we want to add the Item to an existing open Purchase
    Order--or whether we would like to create a new Purchase Order for this
    Item:</para>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_openPOExists.png"
                       />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Choose Existing or New PO</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>After making our choice, we are brought straight to the Purchase
    Order Line Item screen. As you can see in the next screenshot, all the
    correct values have automatically been entered: Item Number, Order
    quantity, unit price, extended price, due date, etc.:</para>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_prPOItem.png" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>P/O Line Item with Values
          Pre-Populated</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>We verify the details and then select the SAVE button. Finally we
    are brought to the Purchase Order header, as shown below:</para>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_poFromPurchReq.png"
                       />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Purchase Order Originated by MRP
          Replenishment</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>As you can see, we have successfully created a Purchase Order using
    MRP replenishment functionality. All we have to do now is post the
    Purchase Order, and the replenishment quantity will be well on its
    way.</para>
  </section>
</section>
