<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section672485" role="openmfg">
  <title>Topic: Order Parameters and MRP</title>
  <para id="Para672486">This section is designed to briefly illustrate the
  interaction between Order Parameters and Material Requirements Planning
  (MRP). As you will see, Order Parameters play a key role in the execution of
  MRP.</para>
  <section id="Section672488">
    <title><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>material requirements planning</primary>
        <secondary>order parameters and</secondary>
      </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>order parameters</primary>
        <secondary>for mrp</secondary>
      </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>item sites</primary>
        <secondary>order parameter settings</secondary>
      </indexterm>Item Site Settings</title>
    <para id="Para672489">For the purposes of this exercise, we will be
    looking at the Order Parameter settings for a purchased Item--Item V1. The
    following screenshot shows the Item Site master for Item V1:</para>
    <para id="Para672493"><anchor id="Anchor93905" role="Cross-Ref"
    xreflabel="93905: Figure: Figure 1.12:  Item Site with Order Parameters Selected" />
    <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_ordParamItemSite.png"
                       id="Graphic672491" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption672495">Item Site with Order Parameters
          Selected</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para id="Para672498">As you can see in <link endterm="Anchor93905"
    id="XRef672497" linkend="Anchor93905"> Item Site with Order Parameters
    Selected</link>Figure 6.21, the "Enforce Order Parameters" flag is set for
    this Item Site. Selecting this option tells the system to enforce the
    specified Order Parameters when MRP is run. The "on Manual Orders" option
    applies to manual Work Orders only and does not have an impact on
    MRP.</para>
    <para id="Para672500">Let's define the significance of each Order
    Parameter setting:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1868964">
        <para id="Para672501">Reorder Level: Specifies when a Planned
        Replenishment Order should be created for an Item Site. If Planned
        Availability minus Safety Stock falls below the Reorder Level, then a
        Replenishment Order will be created when MRP is run. The Replenishment
        Order quantity will be equal to the quantity required to return
        Planned Availability to either the Reorder Level or the Order Up To
        quantity--whichever is greater. We will look at Planned Availability
        later in this section. In this example, the Reorder Level is set to
        30. So, when Planned Availability minus Safety Stock falls below 30,
        MRP (when it is run) will recognize this and reorder quantities for
        the Item Site.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1868988">
        <para id="Para672502">Order Up To: Indicates the level of Planned
        Availability an Item Site should be replenished up to when MRP is run.
        In cases where the Reorder Level for an Item Site exceeds the Order Up
        To (OUT), MRP will replenish the Item Site up to the Reorder Level. In
        this example, the OUT Level is 100. So, in our example, when Planned
        Availability falls below the Reorder Level, MRP (when it is run) will
        replenish the Item Site quantity up to 100.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <tip>
      <para id="Para672504">Setting the Order Up To Level to "0" removes any
      restrictions on maximum Order quantities. Removing quantity restrictions
      can be an effective strategy to help ensure that all Order demands are
      satisfied when MRP is run. Order demands may not be met if Order Up To
      Levels are set below the demand threshold.</para>
    </tip>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18689f4">
        <para id="Para672505">Minimum Order: Indicates the minimum quantity
        that may be entered for a Planned Replenishment Order when MRP is run.
        In this example, no minimum Order quantity is specified.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1868a18">
        <para id="Para672506">Order Multiple: Indicates the quantity multiple
        that should be used for Planned Replenishment Orders when MRP is run.
        In this example, the Order multiple = 1.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1868a3c">
        <para id="Para672508"><indexterm significance="normal">
            <primary>planned orders</primary>
            <secondary>consolidation of</secondary>
          </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
            <primary>material requirements planning</primary>
            <secondary>consolidation of planned orders and</secondary>
          </indexterm>Group MRP Orders Every: Value entered specifies the
        length of a period--measured in days--within which Planned
        Replenishment Orders will be grouped together (i.e, consolidated) to
        meet scheduled demand for the period. This functionality serves to
        limit the total number of Planned Replenishment Orders, thereby
        simplifying order processing. For example, to consolidate demand for
        an Item Site into 30-day buckets, set the value to "30." When MRP is
        run, the system will automatically consolidate all demand falling
        within the 30-day horizon into a single Planned Purchase Order or
        Planned Work Order. The grouping of Planned Orders moves forward in
        time, meaning the system will create as many buckets as will fit
        within the cutoff date specified when MRP is run. The initial grouping
        of Planned Orders is handled differently than subsequent buckets. The
        following formula specifies how the date range for the initial period
        is determined:</para>
        <para id="Para672509">Start Date = Today's Date</para>
        <para id="Para672510">End Date = Today's Date + Lead Time</para>
        <para id="Para672511">All subsequent periods are determined using the
        following calculations:</para>
        <para id="Para672512">Start Date = End Date of Previous Period +
        1</para>
        <para id="Para672513">End Date = Start Date of Current Period + Group
        Value</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <tip>
      <para id="Para672516">To enforce <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>just-in-time</primary>
          <secondary>delivery of planned orders</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>planned orders</primary>
          <secondary>just-in-time delivery and</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>material requirements planning</primary>
          <secondary>just-in-time delivery and</secondary>
        </indexterm>Just-In-Time (JIT) delivery methods, set the MRP group
      value to "0." This will ensure that Planned Order due dates are the same
      as the demand due dates to which they correspond. If the MRP Order
      grouping value is set to "0", the initial period will be determined in
      the same way as for all Planned Order groups:</para>
      <para id="Para672517">Start Date = Today's Date</para>
      <para id="Para672518">End Date = Today's Date + Lead Time</para>
      <para id="Para672519">However, the date range for all subsequent JIT
      Planned Orders will be based on the following calculations:</para>
      <para id="Para672520">Start Date = Demand Due Date - Lead Time</para>
      <para id="Para672521">End Date = Demand Due Date</para>
    </tip>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1874a00">
        <para id="Para672522">Safety Stock: Specifies the quantity of Stock
        you want to keep in Inventory to protect against unplanned,
        unforeseeable trends in your Order forecasts. When Material
        Requirements Planning (MRP) is run, the system considers the Safety
        Stock value when determining whether to create Planned Replenishment
        Orders. If Planned Availability minus Safety Stock is below the
        Reorder Level, then Planned Orders will be created. If not below the
        Reorder Level, then no Planned Orders will be created. The system's
        calculation effectively creates a buffer Inventory (if needed) to
        handle unexpected fluctuations in demand. In this example, Safety
        Stock is set to 20.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <tip>
      <para id="Para672524">If you do not want to use the Safety Stock
      functionality, set the Safety Stock value to "0".</para>
    </tip>
  </section>
  <section id="Section672525">
    <title>Viewing Planned Availability</title>
    <para id="Para672526">Planned Availability--also known as available
    quantity--describes Inventory quantity available for consumption by Work
    Orders or Sales Orders. To determine available quantity, the system uses
    the following formula:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1874a90">
        <para id="Para672527">Planned Availability = Unallocated Qty. + Qty.
        on Order</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para id="Para672528">Let's look now at Planned Availability for Item V1.
    The Inventory Availability by Item screen found in the I/M Module provides
    us with this detail, as shown below:</para>
    <para id="Para672532"><anchor id="Anchor80872" role="Cross-Ref"
    xreflabel="80872: Figure: Figure 1.16:  Inventory Availability Display Showing Availability Below Reorder Level" />
    <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_availOrdParamItem.png"
                       id="Graphic672530" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption672534">Inventory Availability Display Showing
          Availability Below Reorder Level</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para id="Para672535">As you can see from the screenshot, the available
    quantity is displayed in orange. The orange-colored font is used to
    indicate that Planned Availability has fallen below the Reorder Level.
    Whenever this scenario occurs, Planned Replenishment Orders will be
    generated the next time MRP is run.</para>
    <para id="Para672538">The following columns in <link endterm="Anchor80872"
    id="XRef672537" linkend="Anchor80872"> Inventory Availability Display
    Showing Availability Below Reorder Level</link>Figure 6.22 are of interest
    to us now:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1874b44">
        <para id="Para672540">QOH = 25: In this example, the Quantity on Hand
        (QOH) is equal to the available quantity. If quantities of Item V1
        were in any way allocated, these two values would not be the
        same.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1874b68">
        <para id="Para672541">Allocated = 0: Item quantity is considered
        allocated if Sales Orders or Work Orders are demanding the Item. In
        this case, no outstanding demands for Item V1 have been created in the
        system, and so the allocated quantity = 0.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1874b8c">
        <para id="Para672542">Unallocated = 25: Because Item V1 is not
        currently allocated to any Sales Orders or Work Orders, the
        unallocated quantity equals the QOH.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1874bb0">
        <para id="Para672543">Reorder Lvl. = 30: This is the Reorder Level
        specified on the Item Site definition.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1874bd4">
        <para id="Para672544">OUT Level = 100: This is the Order Up To Level
        specified on the Item Site definition.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1874bf8">
        <para id="Para672545">Available = 25: Doing some simple math, you can
        see that the available quantity of Item V1 in Warehouse EAST is below
        the Reorder Level--5 units below it, in fact. As a result, a Planned
        Replenishment Order for Item V1 should be created when MRP is
        run.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
  <section id="Section672546">
    <title>Running MRP</title>
    <para id="Para672547">Now let's run MRP and see what happens. Based on our
    knowledge of the Item Site Order Parameters and the available quantity for
    Item V1, we know that a Planned Replenishment Order will be created. We
    know this because the following condition is true:</para>
    <blockquote>
      <para id="Para672548">Planned Availability (25) - Safety Stock (20) &lt;
      Reorder Level (30).</para>
    </blockquote>
    <para id="Para672549">Whenever Planned Availability minus Safety Stock
    falls below the Reorder Level, a Planned Order will be generated when MRP
    is run. The only question now is what will the Planned Order quantity
    be?</para>
    <para id="Para672550">The following M/S Module screen, "Run MRP by Item,"
    is one of two utilities used to run MRP--the other is "Run MRP by Planner
    Code." For this exercise, we will be running MRP by Item, as shown in the
    following screenshot:</para>
    <para id="Para672554"><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_createPlanRepOrd.png"
                       id="Graphic672552" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption672555">Running MRP by Item</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para id="Para672556">We enter Item V1 in the Item Number field, specify
    the Warehouse where the Item Site is located, and set the Cutoff Date for
    the current day. Once we select the CREATE button, MRP is off and running.
    To see the resulting Planned Replenishment Orders, we open the M/S Display
    "Planned Orders by Item," as shown in the following screen:</para>
    <para id="Para672560"><anchor id="Anchor34728" role="Cross-Ref"
    xreflabel="34728: Figure: Figure 1.15:  MRP Created Planned Purchase Order" />
    <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_planOrdDisp1.png"
                       id="Graphic672558" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption672562">MRP Created Planned Purchase
          Order</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para id="Para672565">As you can see in <link endterm="Anchor34728"
    id="XRef672564" linkend="Anchor34728"> MRP Created Planned Purchase
    Order</link>Figure 6.24, a Planned Purchase Order has been generated for
    75 units of Item V1. So how did the system determine that 75 units was the
    required quantity?</para>
    <para id="Para672567">Well, when MRP creates Planned Orders, the system
    looks at both the Reorder Level and the Order Up To (OUT) Level. It
    determines which of the two has the greater value--and then it places an
    Order to replenish available quantity up to that value. In our example,
    the OUT Level (100) is the greater value. And so we have the following
    scenario:</para>
    <blockquote>
      <para>25 (Current Available Qty.) + 75 (Needed Replenishment Qty.) = 100
      (OUT Level)</para>
    </blockquote>
    <para id="Para672569">So you can see, MRP generated a Planned Order for 75
    units of Item V1 to restore available quantity to the OUT Level.</para>
    <note>
      <para id="Para672571">Because Item V1 is a purchased Item, the
      Replenishment Order is a Planned Purchase Order. Had the Item been a
      manufactured Item, Planned Work Orders would have been created--and also
      Planned Purchase Orders, depending on the availability and Reorder
      Levels of required component Items.</para>
    </note>
  </section>
  <section id="Section672573">
    <title><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>planned orders</primary>
        <secondary>converting to actual orders</secondary>
      </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>material requirements planning</primary>
        <secondary>conversion of planned orders</secondary>
      </indexterm>Converting Planned Orders to Actual Orders</title>
    <para id="Para672574">The next step is to convert the Planned Purchase
    Order to a Purchase Request. Doing so will make Purchasing aware of the
    requirement. We can release the Order using the "Release Order" option
    from the right-click menu. After choosing that option, we are prompted to
    create a Purchase Request, as shown below:</para>
    <para id="Para672578"><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_planOrdDisp2.png"
                       id="Graphic672576" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption672579">Convert Planned Order to Purchase
          Request</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para id="Para672580">A quick check of the details on the "Purchase
    Request" screen shows us that the quantity ordered is correct. We now
    select the CREATE button to generate the Purchase Request and forward it
    to Purchasing. To verify this activity, we turn to the P/O Module Display
    Purchase Requests by Item, as shown below:</para>
    <para id="Para672584"><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_purchReqDispl.png"
                       id="Graphic672582" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption672585">Release Purchase Request</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para id="Para672586">Sure enough, there's the Purchase Request for the
    correct quantity. Once again, we select the "Release Order" option from
    the right-click menu. Because Item Sources have been defined for the Item,
    we are asked to pick a Vendor from among the list of possible Vendors for
    this Item, as shown in the next screen:</para>
    <para id="Para672590"><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_prItemSource.png"
                       id="Graphic672588" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption672591">Select Item Source during Purchase
          Request Conversion</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para id="Para672592">We choose the Vendor Smithson Industries from the
    list, because this is the Vendor with the highest ranking. After selecting
    the Vendor, we are asked whether we want to add the Item to an existing
    open Purchase Order--or whether we would like to create a new Purchase
    Order for this Item:</para>
    <para id="Para672596"><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_openPOExists.png"
                       id="Graphic672594" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption672597">Choose Existing or New PO</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para id="Para672598">After making our choice, we are brought straight to
    the Purchase Order Line Item screen. As you can see in the next
    screenshot, all the correct values have automatically been entered: Item
    Number, Order quantity, unit price, extended price, due date, etc.:</para>
    <para id="Para672602"><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_prPOItem.png" id="Graphic672600" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption672603">P/O Line Item with Values
          Pre-Populated</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para id="Para672604">We verify the details and then select the SAVE
    button. Finally we are brought to the Purchase Order header, as shown
    below:</para>
    <para id="Para672608"><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_poFromPurchReq.png"
                       id="Graphic672606" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption id="Caption672610">Purchase Order Originated by MRP
          Replenishment</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para id="Para672611">As you can see, we have successfully created a
    Purchase Order using MRP replenishment functionality. All we have to do
    now is post the Purchase Order, and the replenishment quantity will be
    well on its way.</para>
  </section>
</section>