<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section672615" role="openmfg">
  <title id="Anchor58321">Topic: Receiving Lot/Serial Items into
  Inventory</title>
  <para>This section describes the special steps that must be followed when
  receiving Lot/Serial Items into Inventory. Like any other Items, Lot/Serial
  Items can be received in three ways:</para>
  <orderedlist continuation="restarts" inheritnum="ignore">
    <listitem>
      <para>As a Material Receipt transaction</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>As a Shipping Receipt</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>Or as Manufacturing Receipt</para>
    </listitem>
  </orderedlist>
  <section id="Section672621">
    <title><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>lots</primary>
        <secondary>inventory control of</secondary>
      </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>serial numbers</primary>
        <secondary>inventory control of</secondary>
      </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>inventory</primary>
        <secondary>lot quantity controls</secondary>
      </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>inventory</primary>
        <secondary>serial number controls</secondary>
      </indexterm>Item Site Control Method</title>
    <para>To illustrate the receiving process for Lot/Serial Items, we will be
    tracking the receipt of imported gladiolas. These perishable flowers are
    Lot-controlled. While we are focusing here on Lot-controlled Items, the
    steps for receiving Serial-Number-controlled Items are identical--the only
    exception being that Serial Number Items may be received in quantities of
    one (1) only.</para>
    <note>
      <para>Lot-controlled Items and Serial-Number-controlled Items are
      received in the same way. The only difference is that Serial Number
      Items may be received in quantities of one (1) only. Lot-controlled
      Items may be received in any quantity.</para>
    </note>
    <para>But before we begin, let's examine the Item Site definition for our
    imported flowers, otherwise known as Item GLAD02:</para>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_lotNumItemSite.png" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Item Site Definition for Lot-Controlled Item</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>A few points are worth noting when looking at an Item Site
    definition. First, note that the Control Method is specified as Lot #.
    This designation marks an Item as being Lot-controlled. And it is because
    of this specification that GLADO2 in Warehouse STAR will be handled
    differently when quantities of it are received into Inventory. Another
    point to notice is that the Item is marked as perishable. Naturally, an
    imported flower will be vibrant and saleable for only a limited period of
    time. Accounting for the perishable nature of Lot-controlled goods will be
    covered later in this example. Finally, you can see that the Item Site
    specifies that Multiple Location Control (MLC) is turned on. Distribution
    issues related to MLC Items are covered thoroughly in the "Topic:
    Distributing Multiple Location Control (MLC) Items" section. We will be
    covering some of that same ground again here when receiving quantities of
    GLAD02 into Inventory.</para>
  </section>
  <section id="Section672637">
    <title><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>inventory</primary>
        <secondary>lot assignments and</secondary>
      </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>inventory</primary>
        <secondary>serial number assignments and</secondary>
      </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>lots</primary>
        <secondary>assigning to inventory</secondary>
      </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>serial numbers</primary>
        <secondary>assigning to inventory</secondary>
      </indexterm>Assigning Lot Numbers</title>
    <para>Let's begin, then, by receiving a quantity of 150 gladiolas into
    Inventory. We will do so by using the Material Receipt screen, found in
    the Inventory Transactions section of the I/M Module, as shown
    below:</para>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_enterMatRecpt.png" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Enter Material Receipt for Lot-Controlled Item</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>At this point in the process, the Material Receipt screen looks and
    behaves no differently than it would for any other Item. Into the Item
    Number field we enter GLAD02, specifying a Receipt quantity of 150 units.
    Because GLAD02 is a Lot-controlled Item, however, the following screen
    appears when we select the POST button:</para>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_assgnLotNum.png" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Initial Screen for Assigning Lot/Serial Number</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>As you can see, the <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>lots</primary>
        <secondary>assigning numbers to</secondary>
      </indexterm>assignment screen indicates the Item Number and quantity to
    be assigned--namely the original quantity being received, 150 units. Keep
    in mind that you may not exit this sequence once it has been initiated.
    When receiving Lot-controlled Items into Inventory, you are required to
    assign Lot Numbers to some or all of the incoming quantity.</para>
    <note>
      <para>Serial Number assignments are made in the same way that Lot Number
      assignments are made when receiving goods into Inventory. The only
      difference is that Serial Numbers may be assigned to only one (1) Item
      at a time. Lot Numbers may be assigned to any quantity.</para>
    </note>
    <para>To create a Lot Number, we select the NEW button. The following
    screenshot shows the Create Lot/Serial Number screen, with the two
    referring screens that brought us to this point shown in the
    background:</para>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_createLotNum.png" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Create Lot/Serial Number</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>When creating a Lot or Serial Number for incoming quantities, you
    are presented with the following options:</para>
    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Lot/Serial #</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>Enter a Lot or Serial Number to identify the specified
          quantity.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
    <tip>
      <para>Lot or Serial Numbers may be changed at a later point using the
      Reassign Lot/Serial Number screen found in the Inventory Transactions
      section of the I/M Module.</para>
    </tip>
    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Expiration Date</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>Perishable Items, such as flowers, are assigned an expiration
          date using this field. Specify the date on or after which the Item
          should be considered expired. If a Lot/Serial Item is not
          perishable, then an expiration date does not apply. Items are
          designated as perishable or not in the Item Site definition.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Qty. to Assign</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>Specify the quantity to assign to the specified Lot or Serial
          Number.</para>
          <para>For Serial Number Items, you may only assign one Serial Number
          per Item. Fractional quantities may be assigned to Lot Numbers, only
          if the Item in question may be stored in fractional quantities, as
          specified in the Item master.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
    <note>
      <para>Incoming quantities may be assigned to multiple Lot or Serial
      Numbers. The entire incoming quantity does not have to be assigned the
      same number.</para>
    </note>
    <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
    available:</para>
    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>CANCEL</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>Closes the screen without creating a Lot or Serial
          Number.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>ASSIGN</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>Assigns the specified quantity to the indicated Lot or Serial
          Number.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
    <para>Although it is not necessary to do so, we have decided for this
    example to assign the entire incoming quantity of 150 units to Lot Number
    LOT-2. This designation is confirmed in the following screen:</para>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_assgnLotNum-2.png" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Lot Number Assigned to Lot-Controlled Quantity</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
  </section>
  <section id="Section672679">
    <title><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>lots</primary>
        <secondary>distributing to locations</secondary>
      </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>multiple location control</primary>
        <secondary>lot distribution and</secondary>
      </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>serial numbers</primary>
        <secondary>distributing to locations</secondary>
      </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>multiple location control</primary>
        <secondary>serial number distribution and</secondary>
      </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>inventory</primary>
        <secondary>receiving lot quantity</secondary>
      </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>inventory</primary>
        <secondary>receiving serial quantity</secondary>
      </indexterm>Distributing to Multiple Locations</title>
    <para>To complete the Lot Number assignment sequence, we select the ASSIGN
    button. But we are not done there. Since our gladiolas are Multiple
    Location Control (MLC) Items, the following distribution sequence is
    triggered:</para>
    <note>
      <para>For an in-depth discussion covering the distribution of Multiple
      Location Control Items, see <xref linkend="Anchor81167" />.</para>
    </note>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_distrLotNum.png" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Multiple Location Distribution of Lot-Controlled
          Quantity</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>Noting that the quantity to distribute is the full 150 units, we
    select the DEFAULT AND POST button. Selecting this button automatically
    causes the full quantity to be distributed to the default Location. The
    transaction is now complete. We have successfully assigned a Lot Number to
    the 150 gladiolas, specified an expiration date, and received the full
    quantity into Inventory. To verify the result, we open the I/M display
    Location/Lot/Serial Number Detail, as shown in the following
    screen:</para>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_displayLotDetail.png" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Verify Lot Transaction Using Detail Display</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>As you can see in the example, the Warehouse STAR is showing 150
    units of LOT-2 with the specified expiration date. A previously entered
    Lot is also located here, as shown in the display.</para>
  </section>
  <section id="Section672699">
    <title>Receiving from Shipping</title>
    <para>When Lot-controlled Items are purchased using a Purchase Order, they
    are received into Inventory via the Shipping &amp; Receiving (S/R) Module.
    Our next example illustrates this process. Let's begin in the Receiving
    section of the S/R Module. The following Enter Receipt screen shows us
    ready to receive 300 units of imported gladiolas from a flower Vendor
    using Purchase Order #563:</para>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_recvLotSR.png" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Receiving Lot-Controlled Quantity from S/R Module</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>At this point in the process, the Enter Receipt screen looks and
    behaves no differently than it would for any other Item. The standard
    receiving sequence is described in detail in <xref
    linkend="Anchor28097" />. As expected, the following screen appears when
    we highlight the Purchase Order Item and select the ENTER RECEIPT
    button:</para>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_recvLotQty.png" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Enter Purchase Order Item Receipt for Lot-Controlled
          Item</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>For this example, we specify that 300 units were received. After the
    RECEIVE button is selected, we are brought back to the initial receiving
    screen, as shown below:</para>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_recvLotSR-2.png" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Receipt Entered for Lot-Controlled Quantity in S/R
          Module</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>It is when we select the POST button that the special Lot-controlled
    sequence begins, as shown in the following screen:</para>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_createLotSR.png" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Create Lot Number for Quantity Received in S/R
          Module</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>The process from this point forward is identical to the process
    described in the earlier Material Receipt example. We assign a Lot Number
    to the specified quantity. And then, because Item GLAD02 is a Multiple
    Location Control Item, we go through the MLC distribution cycle. To verify
    the results, we can open the I/M display Location/Lot/Serial Number
    Detail, as shown in the following screen:</para>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_displayLotDetail-2.png" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Verify Lot Receipt Using Detail Display</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>As you can see in the example, the Warehouse STAR is now showing 300
    units of LOT-3 with the specified expiration date. The Lot-controlled
    goods have now been successfully assigned and received into Inventory
    using the S/R Module.</para>
  </section>
  <section id="Section672741">
    <title>Receiving from Manufacturing</title>
    <para>The example Item we have been using, Item GLAD02, is a purchased
    Item, not a manufactured Item. And so, we cannot use Item GLAD02 to
    demonstrate how Lot-controlled Items are received from
    manufacturing.</para>
    <para>Because the process of receiving Lot/Serial Items from manufacturing
    is virtually identical to the processes already described, we will not
    cover this topic in much detail. However, we will include the following
    screenshot showing Work Order production posting for Item V0, a
    Lot-controlled, manufactured Item:</para>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Topic_createLotWO.png" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Create Lot Number for Quantity Received from
          Manufacturing</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>As you can see in the example, the now familiar Lot Number
    assignment sequence is triggered as part of the Work Order production
    posting process for this Lot-controlled Item.</para>
  </section>
</section>