<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2008 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="commentType">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>comment types</primary>
      <secondary>creating new</secondary>
    </indexterm>Comment Type</title>
  <para>To create a new Comment Type, select the NEW button. The following
  screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/commentType.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create New Comment Type</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When creating a new Comment Type, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a unique Comment Type name.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Description</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a brief description of the Comment Type.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Editable</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you want to allow users to edit the content of
        Comments entered using the Comment Type. If not selected, users will
        not be able to edit Comments created under the Comment Type—in other
        words, Comments will be read-only.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Module</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the module(s) where you want the Comment Type to be
        available for use. For example, if you only want Comments using this
        Comment Type to appear in the Manufacture module, then select the
        "Manufacture" option from the drop-down list. You can then further
        limit visibility to the Comment Type by selecting one or more sources
        available for each module. Users will only be able to use a Comment
        Type if the Comment Type has been explicitly assigned to a module and
        source. </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Available Sources</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>For each of the available modules, there are corresponding
        places (i.e., sources) where Comments may be entered. In the Sales
        module, for example, you can add Comments to Customers, Sales Orders,
        Quotes, etc. The available sources list indicates all the places in a
        module where Comments can be used.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Granted Sources</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The granted sources list indicates all the places in a module
        where the Comment Type has been made available for use. If a source
        does not appear in the granted list, then the Comment Type won't be
        available for use in that source.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>The following buttons are located between the Available Sources and
  Granted Sources columns:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>ADD-&gt;</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a specific source in the available sources column,
        then select this button to transfer the source to the granted sources
        column. Double-clicking on an available source will also transfer it
        to the granted sources column.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>ADD ALL-&gt;&gt;</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select this button to automatically transfer all available
        sources to the granted sources column.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>&lt;-REVOKE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a specific source in the granted sources column, then
        select this button to remove the source from the granted sources
        column. Double-clicking on a granted v will also remove it from the
        granted sources column.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>&lt;&lt;-REVOKE ALL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select this button to automatically remove all granted sources
        from the granted sources column.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without adding a new Comment Type to the
        master list of Comment Types.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Creates the Comment Type and adds it to the master list of
        Comment Types.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
