<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2008 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section518568">
  <title id="Anchor28938"><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>shipping</primary>
      <secondary>shipping sales orders</secondary>
    </indexterm> Ship Order</title>
  <para>To ship an Order, select the "Ship Order" option. The following screen
  will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/shipOrder.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Ship Order</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <tip>
    <para>Before a Sales Order can be shipped successfully, Sales Account and
    Accounts Receivable (A/R) Account Assignments for the specified Customer
    must be in place.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>When Shipping an Order, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Sales Order #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the Order Number of the Sales Order you want to ship. The
        browse button located to the right of the field leads to a searchable
        list of Sales Orders available for Shipping. This option will be
        disabled if a Transfer Order is specified.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="standard">
      <term>Transfer Order #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the Order Number of the Transfer Order you want to ship.
        The browse button located to the right of the field leads to a
        searchable list of Transfer Orders available for Shipping. This option
        will be disabled if a Sales Order is specified.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="standard">
      <term>From</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Source Warehouse if a Transfer Order is
        selected.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="standard">
      <term>To</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Destination Warehouse if a Transfer Order is
        selected.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Select for Billing</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify this option to select the Sales Order for Billing as
        soon as it is shipped. If selected, the Order will appear on the
        Billing Selections list&mdash;making it available to be converted into an
        Invoice. This option will be selected by default if specified in your
        system-level configuration. This option will be disabled if a Transfer
        Order is specified.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Create and Print Invoice</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify this option to automatically create and print an Invoice
        for the Sales Order as soon as it is shipped. Selecting this option
        enables you to bypass the Billing Selection process. Once the Order is
        shipped, an Invoice will be created and printed. This Invoice will
        appear on the list of unposted Invoices&mdash;making it available for
        posting. By default, the "Select for Billing" option will also be
        selected. This option will be disabled if a Transfer Order is
        specified.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Print Packing List</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify this option to automatically print a Packing List as
        soon as the Order is shipped.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="standard">
      <term>Receive Immediately</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you want the Transfer Order to be received
        automatically at the Destination Warehouse as soon as the Order is
        shipped. If this option is not used, Transfer Order Items must be
        received manually at the Destination Warehouse. This option will be
        disabled if a Sales Order is specified.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>The system will move Transfer Order Items to the specified Transit
    Warehouse when the Order is shipped. If the Order is marked to be received
    immediately, the system will then receive Inventory at the Destination
    Warehouse.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Bill To</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the name of the Customer to be billed for the Sales
        Order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Ship To</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the appropriate Ship-To Address.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>If your site integrates UPS WorldShip with the system, you should
    process Orders in WorldShip after they have been issued to Shipping&mdash;but
    before they have been shipped. For more information, see <xref
    linkend="Anchor29552" />.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Items to Ship</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists Order Line Items available for Shipping.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Shipment Value</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the value of the Items being shipped. The shipment
        value represents the total of the extended prices for all Items
        included in the Shipment. The amount does not include freight or
        Tax.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>freight</primary>
          <secondary>on sales orders</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales orders</primary>
          <secondary>freight charges on</secondary>
        </indexterm>Freight</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the amount of freight charge to be added to the specified
        Order. Freight charges may be entered during the creation or
        modification of an Order&mdash;or at the time of shipment.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>The system supports up-to-date shipment tracking with links to the
    websites of many leading shipping companies (i.e., "Ship Vias").</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Ship Via</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the Ship Via for the Order. The Ship Via field supports
        free-form Ship Vias. If you want to enter a free-form Ship Via, simply
        type the name of the Ship Via into the field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>Get the most up-to-date tracking information directly from the
    shipper's website by using the "Query Shipment Status" option found in the
    "Shipments by Sales Order" report. This feature is enabled for a limited
    number of shipping companies (i.e., "Ship Vias")</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Tracking Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Tracking Numbers associated with an Order may be viewed in the
        Shipments by Sales Order report.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without Shipping the Order, returning you to
        the application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SHIP</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Ships the Order, clearing the screen of previously-displayed
        data.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>If an Order is marked "Ship Complete," you will be prevented from
    shipping the Order until all Line Item quantities are issued to
    Shipping.</para>
  </note>
</section>
