<?xml version="1.0" encoding="US-ASCII"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2011 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section role="xtconnect">
  <title>EDI Relation Pseudo-widget</title>
  <para><remark>This should really be part of the xtbatch docs</remark></para>
  <para id="edirelationWidget"><informalexample role="xtconnect">
      <para>When associating EDI Profiles with EDI recipients, such as
      Customers, Ship-To Addresses, and Vendors, you are presented with the
      following options:</para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>EDI Profiles</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Display lists EDI Profiles associated with this recipient
            (e.g., current Customer) for a particular document type. It also
            shows whether EDI will be sent via email or FTP.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
      <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>ATTACH</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Connect an existing EDI Profile to this EDI recipient for a
            particular document type.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>DETACH</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Detach the selected EDI Profile from the recipient for the
            selected document type.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
      <para><note>
          <para>Selecting the EDIT button will open the EDI Profile so you can
          change it. All EDI recipients who share this EDI Profile will be
          affected by changes.</para>
        </note>To attach an existing EDI Profile to the current recipient,
      select the ATTACH button. The following screen will appear:</para>
      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/edirelation_attach.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>Attach an EDI Profile</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <para>This screen lets you attach an existing EDI Profile to the
      currently selected Recipient for a particular Document Type. This tells
      xTuple Connect which documents should be sent by EDI and the EDI Profile
      to use when sending documents of that type to a particular Recipient.
      The Recipient and Recipient Type are displayed for your information
      while attaching the EDI Profile.</para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Recipient</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>This shows the number of the Customer, Vendor, etc. which
            will receive EDI using the selected EDI Profile.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Recipient Type</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>This shows whether the Recipient is a Customer, Vendor, etc.
            This reduces confusion in cases where a Customer and Vendor have
            the same number (i.e., the same CRM Account is both a Customer and
            Vendor).</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Document Type</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Choose from this list the type of document you want to use
            the EDI Profile for. The list of available Document Types changes
            depending on the Recipient Type. For example, if the Recipient
            Type is Vendor, the Document Type list will not contain "Sales
            Order".</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Show All EDI Profiles</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>The list of EDI Profiles shows only those EDI Profiles that
            have an EDI Form for the currently selected Document Type by
            default. If this box is checked, all EDI Profiles will be listed.
            You may attach an EDI Profile without an appropriate EDI Form but
            it will not be used until the right EDI Form is added to the EDI
            Profile.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>EDI Profiles</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Choose from this list the EDI Profile you want to attach for
            the selected document type.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
      <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>ATTACH</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Attaches the EDI Profile to the recipient and closes the
            screen, returning you to the previous screen.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
      <para>If there is no existing EDI Profile that suits your needs, you can
      create a new one by selecting the NEW button. This does the same thing
      as clicking the NEW button on the EDI Profiles window (see <xref
      linkend="ediProfilesTitle" />). After you have created the new EDI
      Profile and saved it, the Attach EDI Profile window will appear with the
      new EDI Profile selected. Now you can select the Document Type and click
      ATTACH. If you click CANCEL, the new EDI Profile will still be saved but
      will not be attached to the recipient.</para>
    </informalexample></para>
</section>
