<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2011 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section949448">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>comment types</primary>
      <secondary>master list of</secondary>
    </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>comment types</primary>
      <secondary>system-defined</secondary>
    </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>comment types</primary>
      <secondary>user-defined</secondary>
    </indexterm>Comment Types</title>
  <para>Comment Types are required whenever you enter a new Comment. They are
  used to distinguish between different categories of Comments. There are two
  system-defined Comment Types ("Changelog" and "General") and an unlimited
  number of possible user-defined Comment Types. User-defined Comment Types
  may be edited or deleted. System-defined Comment Types cannot be deleted,
  but the "General" Comment Type can be edited. You can also define the sort
  order for Comment Types to influence which Comment Types appear first at the
  top where there are used.</para>
  <para>Another "hidden" feature of Comments is the ability to mark them as
  being either public or private. This feature can be useful if you are
  running xTuple Web Portal products where comments may be viewed in a public
  context. In the <literal>metric</literal> table of the xTuple Database,
  there is a metric called <literal>CommentPublicPrivate</literal> which can
  be manually turned on to enable the public/private Comment feature. If
  public/private Comments are enabled, an additional metric called
  <literal>CommentPublicDefault</literal> defines whether new Comments are
  public or private by default. For more information on how to set this up,
  please contact your xTuple system administrator.</para>
  <para>To access the master list of Comment Types, select the "Comment Types"
  option. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/commentTypes.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Comment Types Master List</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>The "Comment Types" screen displays information on all existing
  Comment Types, including Comment Type name and Comment Type
  description.</para>
  <xi:include href="commentType.xml" xpointer="element(/1)"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
</section>
