<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2011 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="customCommand">
  <title id="customCommandTitle"><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>custom commands</primary>
      <secondary>creating new</secondary>
    </indexterm>Custom Command</title>
  <para>Custom Commands enable you to insert ad hoc functionality into the
  xTuple ERP menu system. Examples of ad hoc features are custom report
  definitions, custom .ui screens, and more. All Custom Commands are launched
  from a special "Custom" menu, which gets created at the bottom of the menu
  tree for modules you are adding Custom Commands to. To create a new Custom
  Command, select the NEW button. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/customCommand.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Enter New Custom Command</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When creating a new Custom Command, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Module</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select the name of the module where you want the custom menu
        option to appear. You may create Custom Commands for any of the
        modules within the system. By default, a menu option named "Custom"
        will be added to the bottom of a module's menu tree when a Custom
        Command is created for that module.</para>
        <note>
          <para>You must restart the application to see any new Custom Command
          menu options. Some changes, like newly-added arguments, are
          effective immediately for existing Custom Commands.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Menu Label</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a name to identify the Custom Command as it will appear on
        the menu tree for the specified module. Each menu label should be used
        to describe a separate Custom Command. There is no limit to the number
        of Custom Commands which may be added to a module.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Priv. Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a name to describe the privilege associated with the
        Custom Command. By associating a privilege with a Custom Command, you
        gain the ability to grant or withhold access to the menu option on a
        user-by-user basis. Users who have been granted the privilege will
        have access to the Custom Command; all others will not. Keep in mind,
        this is an optional setting. If the privilege name is left empty, then
        all users will have access to the Custom Command.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Action Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a programmatic-style name for the Custom Command, so the
        system will be able to locate and process the information easily. This
        is an optional setting but it is recommended. Having an action name
        also makes it possible to create a Hot Key for the Custom Command.
        Because of the Hot Key feature, you should consider using an action
        name which conforms to the already-existing naming convention for Hot
        Key actions. For more information see <xref
        linkend="hotkey" />.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Executable</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The information entered in this field will vary depending on the
        use case&mdash;that is, whether you are launching a custom screen,
        custom report, other executable program, etc. If the Custom Command
        will launch an executable program (e.g., RPTRender), then you should
        enter the path to the location where the executable program is
        located. When users select the associated Custom Command menu option,
        the executable program will be launched.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Description</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter text to describe the Custom Command.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>If you want the system to pass parameters or other arguments to the
  specified executable when it is launched, select the "Arguments" tab. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/customCommand_arguments.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Custom Command Arguments</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>The arguments display lists all arguments defined for the specified
  executable. When trying to open a web page or file (i.e., the Executable is
  set to <code>!openurl</code>), create a new argument and enter the URL to
  open (see <ulink
  url="http://qt.nokia.com/doc/4.5/qdesktopservices.html#openUrl">Qt's
  documentation</ulink> for details). If there are multiple arguments, each
  will be opened.</para>
  <xi:include href="customCommandArgument.xml" xpointer="element(/1)"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
  <section>
    <title>Custom Report Details</title>
    <para>If the Custom Command is designed to launch a custom report, specify
    the location for the standalone report renderer (RPTrender) in the
    "Executable" field. The following examples illustrate how (on Windows) you
    can map to either local or network drives:</para>
    <informalexample>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Local Drive</emphasis>: <code>C:\Program
      Files\xTuple\RPTrender.exe</code></para>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Network URL</emphasis>:
      <code>\\drive_name\dir_name\xTuple\RPTrender.exe</code><note>
          <para>You may encounter cross-platform conflicts when placing
          executables on network drives. To reduce these conflicts, it may be
          necessary to create separate custom menus to support executables
          designed for different operating systems.</para>
        </note><tip>
          <para>Macintosh users should enter an executable path which points
          all the way to the executable file located within a package's
          Contents directory. For example, to launch the report renderer,
          enter the following path:</para>
          <informalexample>
            <para><code>../rptrender.app/Contents/MacOS/rptrender</code></para>
          </informalexample>
          <para>Under Mac, the RPTrender application will not open if the path
          does not continue past the rptrender.app file.</para>
        </tip></para>
    </informalexample>
    <para>The next table shows the range of possible arguments you can pass to
    the report renderer (RPTRender) if you are running custom reports:</para>
    <table>
      <title>Arguments Used for Custom Reports</title>
      <tgroup cols="2">
        <thead>
          <row>
            <entry><para>Syntax</para></entry>
            <entry><para>Description</para></entry>
          </row>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
          <row>
            <entry><para>-databaseURL</para></entry>
            <entry><para>Used to specify the location of the database server.
            This is followed by the server address, database name, and port
            number. If running a custom report, the program will automatically
            connect to the database specified when the report renderer
            (RPTrender) is launched</para><para><emphasis
            role="bold">Example</emphasis>:</para><para><code>-databaseURL=psql://server.manufacturing.com/demo:5432</code></para></entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry><para>-username</para></entry>
            <entry><para>Enter the username RPTrender should use to connect to
            the specified database.</para><para><emphasis
            role="bold">Example</emphasis>:</para><para><code>-username=jsmith</code></para></entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry><para>-passwd</para></entry>
            <entry><para>Enter the password for the specified
            user.</para><para><emphasis
            role="bold">Example</emphasis>:</para><para><code>-passwd=abc123</code></para></entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry><para>-param</para></entry>
            <entry><para>Enter any parameters you want the system to pass to
            the report renderer. These pre-defined parameters will be used
            when RPTrender runs the specified report
            definition.</para><para><emphasis
            role="bold">Example</emphasis>:</para><para><code>-param=user_active:bool</code></para></entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry><para>-print</para></entry>
            <entry><para>This argument tells RPTrender to print the specified
            report definition using the indicated parameters&mdash;if
            any.</para><para><emphasis
            role="bold">Example</emphasis>:</para><para><code>-print</code></para></entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry><para>-close</para></entry>
            <entry><para>Use this argument to close the RPTrender program when
            its work is done.</para><para><emphasis
            role="bold">Example</emphasis>:</para><para><code>-close</code></para></entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry><para>-noAuth</para></entry>
            <entry><para>This argument tell RPTrender that not all login
            fields, if any, are required and it will attempt to login to the
            specified database without presenting the login
            screen.</para><para><emphasis
            role="bold">Example</emphasis>:</para><para><code>-noAuth</code></para></entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry><para>-loadfromdb=</para></entry>
            <entry><para>This argument specifies the name a report definition
            to load from the database that is being connected
            to.</para><para><emphasis
            role="bold">Example</emphasis>:</para><para><code>-loadfromdb=SomeReportName</code></para></entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry><para>-printerName=</para></entry>
            <entry><para>This argument specified the printer to print to by
            it's name. Names vary from system to system and you must determine
            the correct name for this option.</para><para><emphasis
            role="bold">Example</emphasis>:</para><para><code>-printerName=default</code></para></entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry><para>-pdf</para></entry>
            <entry><para>This argument specifies that you want the output to
            be in .pdf format.</para><para><emphasis
            role="bold">Example</emphasis>:</para><para><code>-pdf</code></para></entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry><para>-outpdf=</para></entry>
            <entry><para>This argument specifies the name you want pdf output
            to be sent to.</para><para><emphasis
            role="bold">Example</emphasis>:</para><para><code>-outpdf=myreport.pdf</code></para></entry>
          </row>
        </tbody>
      </tgroup>
    </table>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Custom Screen Details</title>
    <para>If the Custom Command is designed to launch a custom screen, then
    the following text should be entered in the "Executable" field:</para>
    <informalexample>
      <para><code>!customuiform</code></para>
      <para>It should be noted, however, that launching custom screens in this
      matter is a deprecated approach. This same functionality can be
      addressed more elegantly using xTuple's scripting tool set.</para>
    </informalexample>
    <para>The following table shows the range of possible arguments if the
    executable is a custom screen (i.e., ui form):</para>
    <table>
      <title>Arguments Used for Custom Screens</title>
      <tgroup cols="2">
        <thead>
          <row>
            <entry><para>Syntax</para></entry>
            <entry><para>Description</para></entry>
          </row>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
          <row>
            <entry><para>uiform=</para></entry>
            <entry><para>This is a required argument. Use the argument
            followed by the name of the ui form (i.e., the screen) which the
            Custom Command will be executing. The screen name is the name
            entered on the main custom screen window.</para><para><emphasis
            role="bold">Example</emphasis>:</para><para><code>uiform=Calculator</code></para></entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry><para>uiformtype=</para></entry>
            <entry><para>Use this argument to specify which type of screen it
            is. There are two possible values:
            <code><literal>dialog</literal></code> and
            <code><literal>window</literal></code>.</para><para><emphasis
            role="bold">Example</emphasis>:</para><para><code>uiformtype=dialog</code></para><para>This
            is an optional argument. The default value is
            <literal>window</literal>.</para></entry>
          </row>
        </tbody>
      </tgroup>
    </table>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>OpenURL Details</title>
    <para>If the Custom Command should open a file or web page, then the
    following text should be entered in the "Executable" field:</para>
    <para><code>!openurl</code></para>
    <para>This command is good for opening either URLs or files in a
    cross-platform manner.</para>
  </section>
</section>
