<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2011 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section556000">
  <title>Production Time Clock by User</title>
  <para>To view Time Clock information by user, select the "Production Time
  Clock by User" option. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/dspWoEffortByUser.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Production Time Clock by User</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When users post Operations from the Shop Floor Workbench, they have
  the option to post either standard or specified times&mdash;and the run time
  recorded will vary depending on the option chosen. The standard times are
  drawn from the Bill of Operations Item definitions. By contrast, the
  specified times are based on the users' clock in/out times (i.e., "effort").
  The specified effort for an Operation may be complicated by the fact that
  users can be clocked into more than one Work Order at a time. In this case,
  the users' effort will be spread across the various Work Orders they have
  clocked into.</para>
  <para>When displaying Time Clock information by User, you are presented with
  the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Username</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the username of the user whose Time Clock information you
        want to view.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Start W/O Start Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Work Orders scheduled on and after this date will be
        displayed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>End W/O Start Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Work Orders scheduled on and before this date will be
        displayed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Work Orders</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists Work Orders the user has clocked-in to, using the
        specified parameters.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Automatically Update</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to automatically update the information displayed in the
        screen. The list will automatically update every 60 seconds if this
        option is selected.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
