<?xml version="1.0" encoding="US-ASCII"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2011 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section>
  <title>Export Data</title>
  <para>Use the Export Data window to export data from the xTuple ERP database
  into XML files.</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/exportData.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption><para>Export Data screen</para></caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>When you open the Export Data window, you are presented with
  the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Destination Format</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>You can choose to export the data either in the default xTuple
        format or transform that xTuple format using XSLT.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>xTuple XML</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Choosing this option will export the data in the default
              xTuple format. The XML element names in the output file follow
              the query names and columns in the query set selected.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Alternate XML</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>This option lets you choose an XSLT transformation from
              the list of XSLT export filters defined on the <xref
              linkend="configureIE" /> screen.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Query Set</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>A Query Set is a collection of database queries that are run in
        sequence. The Query Set you choose defines the data that will be
        exported. See <xref linkend="queryset" /> for details.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>[ MetaSQL parameter list ]</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Once you select a Query Set from the list, the third table on
        the screen shows the list of MetaSQL parameters used by that Query
        Set. You can edit individual parameters to make them active and give
        them particular values that will be used to control the execution of
        the individual queries in the Query Set. See <xref
        linkend="parameteredit" /> for details.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Export</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Run the database queries in the Query Set to create the XML
        file.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>List</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Edit the value of MetaSQL parameters which have the Type
        QVariantList.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <xi:include href="../widgets/queryset.xml" xpointer="element(/1)"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
  <xi:include href="../widgets/parameteredit.xml" xpointer="element(/1)"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
</section>
