<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2011 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section972514">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>purchase orders</primary>
      <secondary>list of open</secondary>
    </indexterm>Open Purchase Orders</title>
  <para>The "Open Purchase Orders" screen lists all your open Purchase Orders.
  Both unreleased and open (i.e., unvouchered) Purchase Orders are included in
  the list. From this screen you can create new or edit existing Purchase
  Orders. In addition to listing Purchase Orders, this screen can also be used
  to build Purchase Order reports. Use the search filter options to sort the
  information into categories you want to look at.</para>
  <para>Here are some tips for using this screen:</para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>Use the right-click menu to perform actions on a highlighted
      Purchase Order.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>A Purchase Order must be released before it can be
      received.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>An open Purchase Order has been released but not fully Vouchered
      yet.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>Partially-vouchered Purchase Orders will be displayed, as long as
      at least one of the Line Items is still open.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>Unreleased Purchase Orders are considered to be a valid source of
      supply by the planning systems.</para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>The following screenshot shows the "Open Purchase Orders"
  screen:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/unpostedPurchaseOrders.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Open Purchase Orders</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>The following options on this screen are a supplement to the choices
  available under the search filter:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Open</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to include open Purchase Orders in the list.
        Partially-vouchered Purchase Orders will also be displayed, as long as
        at least one of the Line Items is still open.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Unreleased</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to include unreleased Purchase Orders in the list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>The default filter on the "Open Purchase Orders" screen shows all open
  Purchase Orders. You can build your own search criteria using the following
  options:</para>
  <xi:include href="../widgets/parameterwidget.xml" xpointer="parameterwidget"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
</section>
