<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2010 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section970006">
  <title>View Database Log</title>
  <para>The Database Log viewer is designed to simplify the process of
  troubleshooting errors when and if they occur. If you experience an
  unexplained error when using the system, open the Database Log and view the
  messages written there. This information will help system
  administrators&mdash;or your support provider&mdash;to analyze and determine
  the root cause of the problem.</para>
  <para>Software developers who are writing packages for xTuple will also find
  this functionality is useful to them. In addition to capturing qCritical and
  qFatal messages, the Database Log viewer can also be enabled to show qDebug
  and qWarning messages. These qDebug and qWarning messages do not cause the
  error icon to appear (like qCritical and qFatal messages do); however,
  developers can simply keep the Database Log viewer open to see the lower
  level messaging as it appears.</para>
  <note>
    <para>If you are running into database errors which are not being reported
    on in the Database Log viewer, it's possible you may need to check your
    PostgreSQL logs for more information&mdash;and to troubleshoot
    further.</para>
  </note>
  <para>To view the Database Log, select the "View Database Log" option. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/errorLog.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>View Database Log Messages</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>While the information written to the Database Log may seem cryptic to
  the average user, the contents written there are invaluable to support
  technicians and software developers as they attempt to discover the root
  cause of a problem.</para>
  <tip>
    <para>Include the contents of the Log file when reporting problems to your
    support provider. To copy the contents, highlight the portion you want to
    copy, then select the "Copy" option from the right-click menu. Finally,
    paste the copied text into an email or other form of communication (i.e,
    issue tracking system).</para>
  </tip>
  <para>At the bottom of the screen, the following options are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Debug</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to include script debugging information in the log
        output. If not selected, script debugging information will not be
        shown.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Warning</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to include warning message information in the log output.
        If not selected, warning message information will not be shown.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Critical</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to include critical error information in the log output.
        If not selected, critical error information will not be shown. When
        critical errors occur, the error icon will appear in the lower
        left-hand corner of the main desktop to notify you.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Fatal</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to include fatal error information in the log output. If
        not selected, fatal error information will not be shown. When fatal
        errors occur, the error icon will appear in the lower left-hand corner
        of the main desktop to notify you.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CLEAR</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to clear the contents of the screen. This option will
        help you narrow down the cause of an error when troubleshooting
        problems. After the screen has been cleared, it will continue to show
        errors the next time an error is encountered.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
