<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2010 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section>
  <title>Expense Item Setup</title>
  <para>The Expense Item Setup tab is an extension of the standard Item
  maintenance screen. Expense Items are used to create a relationship between
  a specified Reference Item and a General Ledger (G/L) Account or an Expense
  Category. These relationships are critical to the Vouchering functionality
  that is a feature of the Time and Expense Pro version. To access the list of
  Items, follow this path: <guimenuitem>Products &gt; Item &gt;
  List.</guimenuitem> Click on the Expense tab to view expense setup. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/expenseItem.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Expense Item Setup</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <note>
    <para>The Expense tab is only available for Reference item types.</para>
  </note>
  <para>The Expense tab provides the ability to select a related Account or
  Expense Category.</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>ACCOUNT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Identify a General Ledger (G/L) Account to be used for expensing
        Purchasing Expenses to. This is an Expense Account. This Account will
        be used to create distributions when Vouchering expense lines. The
        account will be debited when the Voucher is posted.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>EXPENSE CATEGORY</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Identify an Expense Category to distribute Purchasing Expenses
        to. The Expense Category is used to define a set of General Ledger
        (G/L) Accounts related to an expense. This Account will be used to
        create distributions when Vouchering expense lines. The account will
        be debited when the Voucher is posted.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>DELETE EXPENSE ITEM SETUP</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select this button to remove the relationship between the item
        and the specified General Ledger (G/L) Account or Expense
        Category.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
