<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2010 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section role="standard">
  <title>Open Sheets</title>

  <para>To review detailed information regarding time sheets, follow this
  path: <guimenuitem>CRM &gt; Project &gt; Time and Expense</guimenuitem>. The
  following screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="../images/opensheets.png" />
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Open Sheets</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>When reviewing Time and Expense Sheets, you are presented
  with the following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>All Employees</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to display Sheets for all Employees.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Selected</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify Employee whose Sheets you want to display.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Start Date</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Transactions conducted on and after this date will be
        displayed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>End Date</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Transactions conducted on and before this date will be
        displayed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Status Open</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Check box to view all Open time sheets.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Approved</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Check box to view all Approved time sheets.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Closed</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Check box to view all Closed time sheets.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>When Processing Invoice</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Check box to create invoice when time sheet is processed by
        clicking PROCESS button.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Voucher</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Check box to create voucher when time sheet is processed by
        clicking PROCESS button. This is dependent on the employee being set
        up as a vendor.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Post Time</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Check box to post employee time cost to project by clicking
        PROCESS button. This creates a general ledger entry for cost.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <note>
    <para>Post time only post costs for employees selected as a Contractor.
    This is set up on the financial tab on the employee screen. See chapter on
    system administration.</para>
  </note>

  <para>Top tool bar, the following buttons are available:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Opens screen for creating a new Sheet.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>CLOSE</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen, returning you to the application
        desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>APPROVE</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a Sheet and then select this button to Approve the
        Sheet. This makes the Sheet eligible for Invoicing and Vouchering.
        This also posts the time and expenses to the associated Projects and
        Tasks.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>PROCESS</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a Sheet and then select this button to Process the
        Sheet. Depending on the check boxes selected at the bottom of the
        screen this button has the ability to create and invoice, voucher or
        post employee time cost to the general ledger.</para>

        <para>Highlight multiple Sheets and then select this button to
        consolidate the Sheets into a single invoice. Consolidation will be by
        customer, PO, and Project.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>PRINT</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Runs the report associated with this screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>QUERY</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to generate the display, using the specified
        parameters.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>Right click on the sheet to view the following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>EDIT</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enables you to edit highlighted Sheet. Double-clicking on a
        Sheet will also bring you to the editing screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>VIEW</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a Sheet and then select this button to reach a
        read-only view of the "Edit" screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>DELETE</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a Sheet and then select this button to remove the
        Sheet from the list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
