<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2008 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section>
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>encryption</primary>
      <secondary>for credit cards</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>credit cards</primary>
      <secondary>encryption for</secondary>
    </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>encryption</primary>
      <secondary>for ach</secondary>
    </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>ach</primary>
      <secondary>encryption for</secondary>
    </indexterm>Encryption</title>
  <para>You must have an encryption key defined to successfully process Credit
  Cards and ACH transactions in xTuple ERP. To define the name of the
  encryption key and its location in your system, select the "Encryption"
  option. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/configureEncryption.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Configure Encryption</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <tip>
    <para>All users on your system who need access to Credit Card and ACH
    information must use the same key file. The key file can be a simple text
    file with any contents whatsoever. It should be stored at the same level
    as the xTuple executable file. For Mac users, this would be within the
    MacOS directory inside the Package Contents for your xTuple executable.
    The key file is not stored in the database.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>When establishing the encryption key settings for your Credit Card and
  ACH configuration, you are presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Key File Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the name of your key file. The key file is an encryption
        seed file, which enables you to read encrypted Credit Card and ACH
        information. The key file is required regardless of the Verification
        Service used at your site. The contents of the key file should be at
        least 16 characters long and use a combination of upper and lower case
        letters and numbers. Special characters should not be used.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>If you change the contents of your key file after it has already
    been in production, steps must be taken to convert any data encrypted up
    to that point. The function "alterencrypt" must be used to handle the
    conversion. Please contact your Systems Administrator for more
    information.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Windows Location</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the directory path any Windows machine on your system
        would use to access the key file. All users and machines on the system
        must use the same key file. To ensure consistency and security, the
        file should be stored in a central location.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>If you name the key file "OpenMFG.key" and place it in the
    installation directory, then you do not need to enter the path.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Linux Location</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the directory path any Linux machine on your system
        would use to access the key file. All users and machines on the system
        must use the same key file. To ensure consistency and security, the
        file should be stored in a central location.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Mac Location</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the directory path any Mac machine on your system would
        use to access the key file. All users and machines on the system must
        use the same key file. To ensure consistency and security, the file
        should be stored in a central location.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>