<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2008 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section611608">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>expenses</primary>
      <secondary>as inventory transaction</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>inventory transactions</primary>
      <secondary>expense</secondary>
    </indexterm>Expense Transaction</title>
  <para>Expense transactions are a form of miscellaneous Inventory
  transaction. Expense transactions can be used to remove Items from
  Inventory, while assigning the transactions to preset Expense Categories
  (e.g., Trade Show Expense). To remove Items from Inventory and assign the
  transaction to an Expense Category, select the "Expense" option. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/expenseTrans.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Enter Expense Transaction</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When entering an Expense transaction, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Transaction Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the date you want the transaction to be posted to the
        General Ledger. The current day's date will display by default.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the Item Number of the Item you want to enter an Expense
        transaction for.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Inventory Unit of Measure.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Site</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify Site where the Item Site for the Expense
        transaction is located.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Quantity</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the quantity of Inventory UOM you want to enter an Expense
        transaction for. The number entered will appear as a deduction in the
        "After" column. Non-netable Quantity on Hand is not included in these
        values.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Document #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Creates a user-defined reference for the Expense transaction.
        The Document reference will be posted with the General Ledger (G/L)
        transaction record when the Expense transaction is generated. This
        field may be used for internal tracking and auditing purposes.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Expense Category</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the Expense Category you want to assign the Expense
        transaction to.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Notes</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        Comments related to the Expense transaction.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without posting an Expense transaction,
        returning you to the application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>POST</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Posts the Expense transaction. Issues an Expense transaction and
        decrements Quantity on Hand. Additional steps will be necessary if the
        specified Item is stored in multiple Locations.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>