<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2008 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section>
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>groups</primary>
      <secondary>creating new</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>xtuple administrators</primary>
      <secondary>new groups created by</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>administrators</primary>
      <see>xtuple administrators</see>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>system administrators</primary>
      <see>xtuple administrators</see>
    </indexterm>Group</title>
  <para>To create a new user group, select the NEW button. The following
  screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/group.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>User Group Information</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When creating a new user group, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>groups</primary>
          <secondary>creating names for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a name for the user group. For example, you might name a
        group according to a specific functional area (e.g., Sales,
        Purchasing, etc.).</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Description</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a brief description to describe the user group.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Module</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select an individual module to assign privileges for that
        module. Assign privileges to the user group on a module-by-module
        basis. Select one module, assign the appropriate privileges, and then
        repeat for each subsequent module users in the group will need access
        to. All application modules are included in the list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>privileges</primary>
          <secondary>list of available</secondary>
        </indexterm>Available Privileges</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select appropriate privileges from list of available privileges.
        The privileges listed in this column represent the full range of
        privileges available for the specified module. The list of available
        privileges will change as different modules are specified. To grant
        privileges to a user group, highlight an available privilege and then
        click the ADD button. The highlighted privilege will be added to the
        user group's list of granted privileges. Double-clicking on a
        privilege will also move it to the granted privileges column. You can
        grant all privileges for a specified module by clicking on the ADD ALL
        button.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>privileges</primary>
          <secondary>list of granted</secondary>
        </indexterm>Granted Privileges</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays granted privileges for the specified user group. To
        remove a user group's granted privileges for a specified module,
        highlight a granted privilege and then click the REVOKE button. The
        highlighted privilege will be removed from the user group's list of
        granted privileges. Double-clicking on a privilege will also remove it
        from the granted privileges column. You can remove all granted
        privileges for a specified module by clicking on the REVOKE ALL
        button.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>The following buttons are located between the Available Privileges and
  Granted Privileges columns:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>ADD-&gt;</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a specific privilege in the available privileges
        column, then select this button to transfer the privilege to the
        granted privileges column. Double-clicking on an available privilege
        will also transfer it to the granted privileges column.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>ADD ALL-&gt;&gt;</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select this button to automatically transfer all available
        privileges to the granted privileges column.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>&lt;-REVOKE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a specific privilege in the granted privileges column,
        then select this button to remove the privilege from the granted
        privileges column. Double-clicking on a granted privilege will also
        remove it from the granted privileges column.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>&lt;&lt;-REVOKE ALL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select this button to automatically remove all granted
        privileges from the granted privileges column.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Saves the specified user group's information and adds it to the
        list of registered users.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CLOSE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without saving any changes, returning you to
        the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>