<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.3//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.3/docbookx.dtd">
<chapter>
  <title id="i570955">Report Writer Basics</title>
  <para>This chapter is designed to orient you to some of the basic properties
  of the xTuple report writer&mdash;whether you're running the version
  embedded within the xTuple ERP Suite, or the standalone OpenRPT
  application.</para>
  <section id="i550316">
    <title>xTuple Report Writer</title>
    <para>To open the report writer embedded within the xTuple application,
    log in to an xTuple database using an xTuple client and access the
    <guimenuitem>System &gt; Design &gt; Reports</guimenuitem> menu, as shown
    in the following screen:</para>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/C01_50_ReportSubmenu.png" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Opening the Embedded xTuple Report Writer</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>After you select the “Reports” option, the report definitions master
    list will appear, as shown below. The report definitions master list
    serves as the starting point for working with xTuple reports.</para>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/C01_100_ReportDefs.png" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>xTuple Report Definitions Master List</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>The report definitions master list displays information on all
    existing xTuple reports, including report name, grade, and
    description.</para>
    <tip>
      <para>Standard xTuple report definitions are delivered with a grade of
      “0”. By default, the xTuple client runs the highest numbered grade. To
      ensure that you can always return to the baseline version of a report,
      save your report definitions with a grade higher than 0.</para>
    </tip>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>OpenRPT</title>
    <para>To open the standalone OpenRPT application, locate the OpenRPT
    executable file on your system. Then run the file to open it and reach the
    application desktop. The OpenRPT application desktop is shown in the
    following screenshot:</para>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/C01_75_OpenRPTMain.png" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>OpenRPT Application Desktop</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>The basic functionality of the standalone OpenRPT application is
    identical to the functionality of the embedded report writer. The main
    difference is that OpenRPT can connect to any target database, whereas the
    embedded report writer may only be used by xTuple users connected to an
    xTuple database.</para>
  </section>
  <section id="i543943">
    <title>The Toolbar</title>
    <para>In this section, we will explore the various options found on the
    report writer's toolbar. The toolbar options are the same regardless of
    whether you’re running the embedded xTuple report writer or OpenRPT. For
    now, we will focus only on the toolbar functionality. In subsequent
    chapters, we will explain how to modify existing reports and also how to
    create new reports.</para>
    <para>To see the toolbar using the xTuple report writer, we must first
    open a report definition. The term “report definition” refers to the files
    created by the report writer. Page layout, database queries, and so on are
    all parts of a report definition. For this exercise, we’ll open a new
    report by selecting the NEW button from the report definitions master
    list. The following screen will appear:</para>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/C01_110_NewRept.png" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Blank Report Definition Featuring Toolbar</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <note>
      <para>All the functionality accessible using the toolbar options is also
      available from the drop-down menus.</para>
    </note>
    <para>For the remainder of this section, we will examine each of the
    options on the report writer toolbar. The following screenshot shows a
    close-up view of the toolbar:</para>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/C01_200_ToolbarAll.png" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Report Writer Toolbar Options</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>As we look at the functionality related to each toolbar option, we
    will be moving from left to right&mdash;beginning with the New File
    option.</para>
    <section id="i543954">
      <title>New File</title>
      <para><inlinemediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Toolbar_SaveFile.png" />
          </imageobject>
        </inlinemediaobject></para>
      <para>Clicking the “New File” option opens a new instance of the report
      writer. Select this option to create a new report definition. We will
      discuss creating new report definitions in the Advanced Topics
      chapter.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Open File</title>
      <para><inlinemediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Toolbar_OpenFile.png" />
          </imageobject>
        </inlinemediaobject></para>
      <para>Use the “Open File” option to open a report definition stored on
      your local or network drive. Reports may be stored on local or network
      drives for backup or editing purposes. If you want to open a report
      stored in your xTuple Database, use the EDIT button found on the report
      definitions master list. For details on editing existing reports, see
      the Getting Started chapter.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Save File</title>
      <para><inlinemediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Toolbar_SaveFile.png" />
          </imageobject>
        </inlinemediaobject></para>
      <para>The “Save File” option enables you to save report definitions to
      your local or network drive, where they may be stored for backup or
      editing purposes. This option will not save report definitions to a
      database. To learn more about saving reports to a database, see the
      <xref linkend="i552942" /> section. Report definitions are saved using
      the Extensible Markup Language (XML) format.</para>
    </section>
    <section id="i544927">
      <title>Cut</title>
      <para><inlinemediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Toolbar_Cut.png" />
          </imageobject>
        </inlinemediaobject></para>
      <para>The “Cut” option enables you to click on an object in a report
      definition, remove it, and then, using the “Paste” option, insert it to
      another part of the report.</para>
    </section>
    <section id="i544010">
      <title>Copy</title>
      <para><inlinemediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Toolbar_Copy.png" />
          </imageobject>
        </inlinemediaobject></para>
      <para>The “Copy” option enables you to click on an object in a report,
      copy it (leaving the original in place), and then, using the “Paste”
      option, insert it into another part of the report.</para>
    </section>
    <section id="i544019">
      <title>Paste</title>
      <para><inlinemediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Toolbar_Paste.png" />
          </imageobject>
        </inlinemediaobject></para>
      <para>The “Paste” option enables you to insert into the report
      definition an object that has been cut or copied using the “Cut” option
      or the “Copy” option.</para>
    </section>
    <section id="i544028">
      <title>Show Grid</title>
      <para><inlinemediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Toolbar_ShowGrid.png" />
          </imageobject>
        </inlinemediaobject></para>
      <para>The “Show Grid” option enables you to turn grid lines on for
      visual reference when aligning objects in a report definition. This
      option is a toggle, meaning grid lines may be turned on or off using
      this option.</para>
      <para>Clicking the “Show Grid” option turns grid lines on. The following
      screenshot shows a report definition with grid lines turned on:</para>
      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/C01_265_GridShowing.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>Grid Lines On</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <para>Clicking the “Show Grid” option a second time turns grid lines
      off, as shown in the following screenshot:</para>
      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/C01_267_GridNotShowing.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>Grid Lines Off</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <para>If you want to change the properties of your grid lines, the
      report writer gives you the ability to do so. To change your grid line
      settings, select the “Preferences” option from the Edit menu. The
      following screen will appear:</para>
      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/C01_269_GridPrefsEdit.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>Report Preferences</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <para>When establishing your report definition preferences, you are
      presented with the following options:</para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Default Font</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select the default font to be used in the report definition
            by clicking on the FONT button located to the right of the field.
            Selecting the FONT button will bring up the “Select Font” screen,
            where you may specify font name, font style, font size, and font
            effects. Even though a default font is specified, you may override
            the default font on an object-by-object basis.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Grid Options</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Indicate your grid line settings, using the following
            parameters:</para>
            <variablelist>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Show grid</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Selecting this option turns grid lines on. If this
                  option is not selected, grid lines will be turned off. The
                  “Show Grid” option accomplishes the same result.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Snap to grid</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Selecting this option aligns objects to the grid. If
                  this option is not selected, grid lines will not be aligned
                  to the grid. The “Snap to Grid” option accomplishes the same
                  results.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
            </variablelist>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Grid Size Interval</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Specify the distance (measured in inches) between the points
            of your grid lines, using the following parameters:</para>
            <variablelist>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>X Interval</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Enter an interval for the horizontal axis of your
                  grid, measured in inches.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Y Interval</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Enter an interval for the vertical axis of your grid,
                  measured in inches.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Symmetrical values</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Select if you want the X axis and the Y axis to use
                  the same interval between points. If selected, you will not
                  be able to enter an interval for the Y axis.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
            </variablelist>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
      <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
      available:</para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>OK</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select to save your settings.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>CANCEL</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Closes the screen without saving any changes, returning you
            to the application desktop.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
    </section>
    <section id="i544061">
      <title>Snap to Grid</title>
      <para><inlinemediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Toolbar_SnapGrid.png" />
          </imageobject>
        </inlinemediaobject></para>
      <para>The “Snap to Grid” option forces objects to align to the grid when
      grid lines are turned on. This option is a toggle, meaning snap to grid
      functionality may be turned on or off using this option.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Labels</title>
      <para><inlinemediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Toolbar_Label.png" />
          </imageobject>
        </inlinemediaobject></para>
      <para>The “Label” option enables you to create new Label objects. Label
      objects are used to display descriptive information on a report
      definition, such as titles, headings, etc.</para>
      <para>To create a new Label object, first select the "Label" option.
      Then click in the section of the report definition where you want the
      Label to be located. Doing so will create the Label object in that
      section.</para>
      <note>
        <para>For more information on using Label objects in report
        definitions, see the Getting Started chapter.</para>
      </note>
      <para>Once the Label object has been created, you may then define the
      Label object’s properties. To define a Label object’s properties,
      double-click on the Label object. The following screen will
      appear:</para>
      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/C01_280_LabelDialogue.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>Label Properties</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <para>When defining the properties of a Label object, you are presented
      with the following options:</para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Text</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Enter the text of the Label. Text entered here will display
            in the “Preview” section of the screen.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>HAlign</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Specify how you want text to be aligned horizontally within
            the Label object:</para>
            <variablelist>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>None</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Select if you do not want to specify a horizontal
                  alignment.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Left</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Select to align text on the left margin.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Center</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Select to align text in the center.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Right</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Select to align text on the right margin.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
            </variablelist>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>VAlign</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Specify how you want text to be aligned vertically within
            the Label object:</para>
            <variablelist>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>None</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Select if you do not want to specify a vertical
                  alignment.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Top</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Select to align text on the top margin.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Middle</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Select to align text in the middle.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Bottom</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Select to align text on the bottom margin.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
            </variablelist>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Position/Size</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Specify how you want the Label object to be positioned and
            sized within the section where it is located.<variablelist>
                <varlistentry>
                  <term>X</term>
                  <listitem>
                    <para>Specify the distance, measured in inches, from the
                    section’s left border to the upper-left-hand corner of the
                    Label object.</para>
                  </listitem>
                </varlistentry>
                <varlistentry>
                  <term>Width</term>
                  <listitem>
                    <para>Specify the width of the Label object, measured in
                    inches.</para>
                  </listitem>
                </varlistentry>
                <varlistentry>
                  <term>Y</term>
                  <listitem>
                    <para>Specify the distance, measured in inches, from the
                    section’s top border to the upper-left-hand corner of the
                    Label object.</para>
                  </listitem>
                </varlistentry>
                <varlistentry>
                  <term>Height</term>
                  <listitem>
                    <para>Specify the height of the Label object, measured in
                    inches.</para>
                    <tip>
                      <para>The position and size of a Label object may be
                      modified manually when editing a report
                      definition.</para>
                    </tip>
                  </listitem>
                </varlistentry>
              </variablelist></para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Preview</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Displays a preview of the Label text, using the specified
            font. Selecting the FONT button will bring up the “Select Font”
            screen, where you may specify font name, font style, font size,
            and font effects.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
      <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
      available:</para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>OK</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select to save your settings.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>CANCEL</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Closes the screen without saving any changes, returning you
            to the application desktop.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
    </section>
    <section id="i544087">
      <title>Fields</title>
      <para><inlinemediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Toolbar_Field.png" />
          </imageobject>
        </inlinemediaobject></para>
      <para>The “Field” option enables you to create new Field objects. Field
      objects are used for pulling dynamically generated data into a report
      from the database the report writer is connected to. For example, a
      Field object may be used to include running totals in a report. By
      definition, Field objects are designed to handle a single line of data.
      For multiple lines of data, use a Text Area object.</para>
      <para>To create a new Field object, first select the "Field" option.
      Then click in the section of the report definition where you want the
      Field to be located. Doing so will create the Field object in that
      section.</para>
      <note>
        <para>For more information on using Field objects in report
        definitions, see the Getting Started chapter.</para>
      </note>
      <para>Once the Field object has been created, you may then define the
      Field object’s properties. To define a Field object’s properties,
      double-click on the Field object. The following screen will
      appear:</para>
      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/C01_295_FieldDialogue.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>Field Properties</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <note>
        <para>By definition, Field objects are designed to handle a single
        line of data. For multiple lines of data, use a Text Area
        object.</para>
      </note>
      <para>When defining the properties of a Field object, you are presented
      with the following options:</para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Query Source</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select a query source from the drop-down menu by clicking on
            the arrow to the right of the field. Query sources are used to
            populate report definition objects with dynamic data from the
            database the report writer is connected to.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Column</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Specify the name of the database column you want to use from
            the selected query source. A query source may refer to multiple
            columns in its <literal>SELECT</literal> statement. By indicating
            a specific column, you instruct the query source to return data
            only for that specified column. Other columns appearing in the
            <literal>SELECT</literal> statement will be ignored.</para>
            <note>
              <para>For more information on query sources and the link between
              database fields and report definition objects, please see the
              Getting Started chapter.</para>
            </note>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Display as Running Total</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select if you want the data retrieved from the database to
            be displayed as a running total. No running total will be used if
            this option is not selected.</para>
            <note>
              <para>When running totals are calculated for columns designated
              as Boolean, the “true” values are assigned a value of “1,” while
              “false” values are assigned a value of “0.”</para>
            </note>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Total Format</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>If the “Display as Running Total” option is selected,
            specify one of the following formatting options:</para>
            <variablelist>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>String Format</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Enter a string format to use when formatting the
                  total.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Built-in Locale Format</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Select this option and then choose one of the
                  available options from the drop-down menu by clicking on the
                  arrow to the right of the field. Built-in Locale Formats may
                  only be available in some installations.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Use Subtotal Value</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Select if the running total represents a
                  subtotal.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
            </variablelist>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>HAlign</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Specify how you want text to be aligned horizontally within
            the Field object:</para>
            <variablelist>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>None</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Select if you do not want to specify a horizontal
                  alignment.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Left</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Select to align text on the left margin.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Center</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Select to align text in the center.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Right</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Select to align text on the right margin.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
            </variablelist>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>VAlign</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Specify how you want text to be aligned vertically within
            the Field object:</para>
            <variablelist>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>None</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Select if you do not want to specify a vertical
                  alignment.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Top</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Select to align text on the top margin.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Middle</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Select to align text in the middle.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Bottom</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Select to align text on the bottom margin.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
            </variablelist>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Position/Size</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Specify how you want the Field object to be positioned and
            sized within the section where it is located.</para>
            <variablelist>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>X</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Specify the distance, measured in inches, from the
                  section’s left border to the upper-left-hand corner of the
                  Field object.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Width</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Specify the width of the Field object, measured in
                  inches.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Y</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Specify the distance, measured in inches, from the
                  section’s top border to the upper-left-hand corner of the
                  Field object.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Height</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Specify the height of the Field object, measured in
                  inches.</para>
                  <tip>
                    <para>The position and size of a Field object may be
                    modified manually when editing a report definition.</para>
                  </tip>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
            </variablelist>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Preview</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Displays a preview of the Field, using the specified font.
            Selecting the FONT button will bring up the “Select Font” screen,
            where you may specify font name, font style, font size, and font
            effects.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
      <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
      available:</para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>OK</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select to save your settings.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>CANCEL</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Closes the screen without saving any changes, returning you
            to the application desktop.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Text Areas</title>
      <para><inlinemediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Toolbar_TextArea.png" />
          </imageobject>
        </inlinemediaobject></para>
      <para>The “Text Area” option enables you to create new Text Area
      objects. Text Area objects are used for pulling dynamically generated,
      multi-line data into a report from the database the report writer is
      connected to. By definition, Text Area objects are designed to handle
      multiple lines of data.</para>
      <para>To create a new Text Area object, first select the "Text Area"
      option. Then click in the section of the report definition where you
      want the Text Area to be located. Doing so will create the Text Area
      object in that section.</para>
      <note>
        <para>For more information on using Text Area objects in report
        definitions, see the Getting Started chapter.</para>
      </note>
      <para>Once the Text Area object has been created, you may then define
      the Text Area object’s properties. To define a Text Area object’s
      properties, double-click on the Text Area object. The following screen
      will appear:</para>
      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/C01_305_TextAreaDialogue.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>Text Area Properties</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <note>
        <para>By definition, Text Area objects are designed to handle multiple
        lines of data.</para>
      </note>
      <para>When defining the properties of a Text Area object, you are
      presented with the following options:</para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Query Source</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select a query source from the drop-down menu by clicking on
            the arrow to the right of the field. Query sources are used to
            populate report definition objects with dynamic data from the
            database the report writer is connected to.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Column</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Specify the name of the database column you want to use from
            the selected query source. A query source may refer to multiple
            columns in its <literal>SELECT</literal> statement. By indicating
            a specific column, you instruct the query source to return data
            only for that specified column. Other columns appearing in the
            <literal>SELECT</literal> statement will be ignored.</para>
            <note>
              <para>For more information on query sources and the link between
              database fields and report definition objects, please see the
              Getting Started chapter.</para>
            </note>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Bottom Padding</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Specify the minimum amount of space between the last line of
            text in the Text Area object and the end of the section where the
            Text Area object is located, measured in inches. The amount of
            space between the last line of text and the end of a section will
            always be equal to at least the bottom padding value.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>HAlign</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Specify how you want text to be aligned horizontally within
            the Text Area object:</para>
            <variablelist>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>None</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Select if you do not want to specify a horizontal
                  alignment.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Left</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Select to align text on the left margin.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Center</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Select to align text in the center.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Right</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Select to align text on the right margin.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
            </variablelist>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>VAlign</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Specify how you want text to be aligned vertically within
            the Text Area object:</para>
            <variablelist>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>None</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Select if you do not want to specify a vertical
                  alignment.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Top</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Select to align text on the top margin.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Middle</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Select to align text in the middle.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Bottom</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Select to align text on the bottom margin.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
            </variablelist>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Position/Size</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Specify how you want the Text Area object to be positioned
            and sized within the section where it is located.</para>
            <variablelist>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>X</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Specify the distance, measured in inches, from the
                  section’s left border to the upper-left-hand corner of the
                  Text Area object.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Width</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Specify the width of the Text Area object, measured in
                  inches.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Y</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Specify the distance, measured in inches, from the
                  section’s top border to the upper-left-hand corner of the
                  Text Area object.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Height</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Specify the height of the Text Area object, measured
                  in inches.</para>
                  <tip>
                    <para>The position and size of a Text Area object may be
                    modified manually when editing a report definition.</para>
                  </tip>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
            </variablelist>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Preview</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Displays a preview of the Text Area object, using the
            specified font. Selecting the FONT button will bring up the
            “Select Font” screen, where you may specify font name, font style,
            font size, and font effects.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
      <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
      available:</para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>OK</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select to save your settings.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>CANCEL</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Closes the screen without saving any changes, returning you
            to the application desktop.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Lines</title>
      <para><inlinemediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Toolbar_Line.png" />
          </imageobject>
        </inlinemediaobject></para>
      <para>The “Line” option enables you to create new Line objects. Line
      objects are used for drawing vertical, horizontal, and diagonal
      lines.</para>
      <para>To create a new Line object, first select the "Line" option. Then
      click in the section of the report definition where you want the Line to
      be located. Doing so will create the Line object in that section. Once
      the Line object has been created, click on the object and drag it with
      your mouse. As you will see, dragging the Line object draws the Line in
      any direction and to any length you wish.</para>
      <tip>
        <para>If you hold down the SHIFT key on your keyboard when you are
        dragging a Line object, this will force the Line to straighten out.
        Also, once a Line has been inserted, you may change its orientation by
        clicking and dragging the whole Line or either one of its end
        points.</para>
      </tip>
      <para>After you have inserted a Line object into a report definition,
      you may then define the width of the Line object. To define the width of
      a Line object, double-click on the Line object. The following screen
      will appear:</para>
      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/C01_320_LineDialogue.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>Line Width</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <para>When defining the width of a Line object, you are presented with
      the following options:</para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Width</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Specify the width of the Line, measured in pixels, by
            entering a number either manually or by using the arrows to the
            right of the field. The maximum Line width is 100 pixels.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
      <para>At the bottom of the screen, the following buttons are
      available:</para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>OK</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select to save your settings.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>CANCEL</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Closes the screen without saving any changes, returning you
            to the application desktop.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Bar Codes</title>
      <para><inlinemediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Toolbar_Barcode.png" />
          </imageobject>
        </inlinemediaobject></para>
      <para>The “Bar Code” option enables you to create new bar code objects.
      Bar code objects are used to represent dynamic information stored in a
      database in bar code format.</para>
      <para>To create a new bar code object, first select the "Bar Code"
      option. Then click in the section of the report definition where you
      want the bar code to be located. Doing so will create the bar code
      object in that section.</para>
      <note>
        <para>For more information on using bar code objects in report
        definitions, see the Getting Started and Advanced Topics
        chapters.</para>
      </note>
      <para>Once the bar code object has been created, you may then define the
      bar code object’s properties. To define a bar code object’s properties,
      double-click on the bar code object. The following screen will
      appear:</para>
      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/C01_330_BarcodeDialogue.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>Bar Code Properties</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <para>When defining the properties of a bar code object, you are
      presented with the following options:</para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Format</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select one of the bar code formatting options from the
            drop-down menu by clicking on the arrow to the right of the field.
            The report writer supports the following bar code formats:</para>
            <itemizedlist>
              <listitem>
                <para>3of9</para>
              </listitem>
              <listitem>
                <para>3of9+</para>
              </listitem>
              <listitem>
                <para>128</para>
              </listitem>
              <listitem>
                <para>ean13</para>
              </listitem>
              <listitem>
                <para>ean8</para>
              </listitem>
              <listitem>
                <para>upc-a</para>
              </listitem>
              <listitem>
                <para>upc-e</para>
              </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Query Source</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select a query source from the drop-down menu by clicking on
            the arrow to the right of the field. Query sources are used to
            populate report definition objects with dynamic data from the
            database the report writer is connected to.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Column</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Specify the name of the database column you want to use from
            the selected query source. A query source may refer to multiple
            columns in its <literal>SELECT</literal> statement. By indicating
            a specific column, you instruct the query source to return data
            only for that specified column. Other columns appearing in the
            <literal>SELECT</literal> statement will be ignored.</para>
            <note>
              <para>For more information on query sources and the link between
              database fields and report definition objects, please see the
              Getting Started chapter.</para>
            </note>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Maximum Length of Value</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Specify the maximum number of characters you expect your bar
            code data to contain. The length of the bar code will not exceed
            the value entered here. If fewer characters than the maximum
            number are used, the bar code will be aligned within the bar code
            object based on the alignment specified below.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Alignment</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Specify how you want the bar code to be aligned horizontally
            if its length is fewer characters than the maximum length
            specified above:</para>
            <variablelist>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Left</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Select to align the bar code on the left margin of the
                  bar code object.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Center</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Select to align the bar code in the center of the bar
                  code object.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Right</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Select to align the bar code on the right margin of
                  the bar code object.</para>
                  <note>
                    <para>Bar codes always fill the entire vertical space
                    specified for a bar code object. As a result, no vertical
                    alignment is required.</para>
                  </note>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
            </variablelist>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Position/Size</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Specify how you want the bar code object to be positioned
            and sized within the section where it is located.</para>
            <variablelist>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>X</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Specify the distance, measured in inches, from the
                  section’s left border to the upper-left-hand corner of the
                  bar code object.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Width</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Specify the width of the bar code object, measured in
                  inches.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Y</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Specify the distance, measured in inches, from the
                  section’s top border to the upper-left-hand corner of the
                  bar code object.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Height</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Specify the height of the bar code object, measured in
                  inches.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
            </variablelist>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
      <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
      available:</para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>OK</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select to save your settings.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>CANCEL</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Closes the screen without saving any changes, returning you
            to the application desktop.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
    </section>
    <section id="i544159">
      <title>Images</title>
      <para><inlinemediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Toolbar_Image.png" />
          </imageobject>
        </inlinemediaobject></para>
      <para>The “Image” option enables you to create new Image objects. Image
      objects are used to insert either static or dynamic Images into a report
      definition. Static Images&mdash;a company logo displayed in the Report
      Header, for example&mdash;are embedded within the report definition.
      Dynamic Images&mdash;pictures of products, for example&mdash;are pulled
      from the database the report writer is connected to.</para>
      <para>To create a new Image object, first select the "Image" option.
      Then click in the section of the report definition where you want the
      Image to be located. Doing so will create the Image object in that
      section.</para>
      <note>
        <para>For more information on using Image objects in report
        definitions, see the Advanced Topics chapter.</para>
      </note>
      <para>Once the Image object has been created, you may then edit the
      Image object’s properties. To edit an Image object’s properties,
      double-click on the Image object. The following screen will
      appear:</para>
      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/C01_345_ImageEditor.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>Image Editor</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <para>When editing the properties of an Image object, you are presented
      with the following options:</para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Resize Mode</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Specify one of the following resizing preferences:</para>
            <variablelist>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Clip</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Select to have the Image imported as-is into the Image
                  object. If selected, no resizing of the Image will
                  occur.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Stretch</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Select to enable manual resizing of the Image once it
                  has been imported into the Image object. When manually
                  resizing an Image, the Image’s aspect ratio will be
                  maintained.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
            </variablelist>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Static Image</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select if the Image you are importing is a static Image.
            Static Images are Images which are embedded within a report
            definition. They are not pulled dynamically from a database. An
            example of a static Image would be a company logo inserted on the
            top of a standard Form.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Database</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Specify the following information if the Image you are
            importing will be pulled dynamically from a database the report
            writer is connect to:</para>
            <variablelist>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Query Source</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Select a query source from the drop-down menu by
                  clicking on the arrow to the right of the field. Query
                  sources are used to populate report definition objects with
                  dynamic data from the database the report writer is
                  connected to.</para>
                  <note>
                    <para>For more information on query sources and the link
                    between database fields and report definition objects,
                    please see the Getting Started chapter.</para>
                  </note>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Column</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Specify the name of the database column you want to
                  use from the selected query source. A query source may refer
                  to multiple columns in its <literal>SELECT</literal>
                  statement. By indicating a specific column, you instruct the
                  query source to return data only for that specified column.
                  Other columns appearing in the <literal>SELECT</literal>
                  statement will be ignored.</para>
                  <note>
                    <para>xTuple users can store Images in an xTuple Database
                    using the client interface. Images imported this way are
                    stored in the <literal>image_data</literal> column of the
                    <literal>images</literal> table, using the UU encoding
                    format.</para>
                  </note>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Position/Size</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Specify how you want the Image object to be positioned
                  and sized within the section where it is located.</para>
                  <variablelist>
                    <varlistentry>
                      <term>X</term>
                      <listitem>
                        <para>Specify the distance, measured in inches, from
                        the section’s left border to the upper-left-hand
                        corner of the Image object.</para>
                      </listitem>
                    </varlistentry>
                    <varlistentry>
                      <term>Width</term>
                      <listitem>
                        <para>Specify the width of the Image object, measured
                        in inches.</para>
                      </listitem>
                    </varlistentry>
                    <varlistentry>
                      <term>Y</term>
                      <listitem>
                        <para>Specify the distance, measured in inches, from
                        the section’s top border to the upper-left-hand corner
                        of the Image object.</para>
                      </listitem>
                    </varlistentry>
                    <varlistentry>
                      <term>Height</term>
                      <listitem>
                        <para>Specify the height of the Image object, measured
                        in inches.</para>
                        <note>
                          <para>The position and size of an Image object may
                          be modified manually when editing a report
                          definition.</para>
                        </note>
                      </listitem>
                    </varlistentry>
                  </variablelist>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
            </variablelist>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
      <para>At the bottom of the screen, the following buttons are
      available:</para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>OK</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select to save your settings.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>CANCEL</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Closes the screen without saving any changes, returning you
            to the application desktop.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
    </section>
    <section id="i561129">
      <title>Graph Editor</title>
      <para><inlinemediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Toolbar_Graph.png" />
          </imageobject>
        </inlinemediaobject></para>
      <para>The “Graph” option enables you to create new Graph objects. Graph
      objects are used to insert Graphs into a report definition using dynamic
      data stored in a database the report writer is connected to.</para>
      <para>To create a new Graph object, first select the "Graph" option.
      Then click in the section of the report definition where you want the
      Graph to be located. Doing so will create the Graph object in that
      section.</para>
      <note>
        <para>For more information on using Graph objects in report
        definitions, see the Advanced Topics chapter.</para>
      </note>
      <para>Once the Graph object has been created, you may then edit the
      Graph object’s properties. To edit a Graph object’s properties,
      double-click on the Graph object. The following screen will
      appear:</para>
      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/C01_355_GraphDialogue.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>Graph Editor</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <para>When editing the general properties of a Graph object, you are
      presented with the following options:</para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Query Source</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select a query source from the drop-down menu by clicking on
            the arrow to the right of the field. Query sources are used to
            populate report definition objects with dynamic data from the
            database the report writer is connected to.</para>
            <note>
              <para>For more information on query sources and the link between
              database fields and report definition objects, please see the
              Getting Started chapter.</para>
            </note>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Position/Size</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Specify how you want the Image object to be positioned and
            sized within the section where it is located.</para>
            <variablelist>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>X</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Specify the distance, measured in inches, from the
                  section’s left border to the upper-left-hand corner of the
                  Image object.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Width</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Specify the width of the Image object, measured in
                  inches.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Y</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Specify the distance, measured in inches, from the
                  section’s top border to the upper-left-hand corner of the
                  Image object.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Height</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Specify the height of the Image object, measured in
                  inches.</para>
                  <tip>
                    <para>The position and size of a Graphic object may be
                    modified manually when editing a report definition.</para>
                  </tip>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
            </variablelist>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Base Font</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select the base font to be used in the Graph object by
            clicking on the FONT button located to the right of the field.
            Selecting the FONT button will bring up the “Select Font” screen,
            where you may specify font name, font style, font size, and font
            effects. The base font may be used throughout the Graph
            object.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Title</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Specify the following details for the Graph object’s
            title:</para>
            <variablelist>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Title</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Enter the title you want to appear centered at the top
                  of the Graph.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Use Base Font</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Select to use the specified base font. If not
                  selected, the title font will be used.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Title Font</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Specify the font to be used for the Graph object’s
                  title by clicking on the FONT button located to the right of
                  the field. Selecting the FONT button will bring up the
                  “Select Font” screen, where you may specify font name, font
                  style, font size, and font effects.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
            </variablelist>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
      <para>At the bottom of the screen, the following buttons are
      available:</para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>OK</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select to save your settings.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>CANCEL</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Closes the screen without saving any changes, returning you
            to the application desktop.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
      <para>To define the properties of the Graph object’s data
      axis&mdash;that is, the horizontal axis running along the bottom of the
      Graph&mdash;select the “Data Axis” tab at the top of the “Graph Editor”
      screen. The following screen will appear:</para>
      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/C01_356_GraphDatAxis.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>Graph Editor Data Axis</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <para>When editing the data axis properties of a Graph object, you are
      presented with the following options:</para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Data Axis Labels</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Specify the following details for the data axis
            labels:</para>
            <variablelist>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Column</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Specify the name of the database column you want to
                  use from the selected query source. A query source may refer
                  to multiple columns in its <literal>SELECT</literal>
                  statement. By indicating a specific column, you instruct the
                  query source to return data only for that specified column.
                  Other columns appearing in the <literal>SELECT</literal>
                  statement will be ignored.</para>
                  <note>
                    <para>The term “data axis labels” refers to the
                    identifying information which describes each of the items
                    in a Graph’s series. For example, if a Graph displays
                    information about a series of Item Numbers, then data axis
                    labels would be used to identify each of the Items in the
                    series.</para>
                  </note>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Use Base Font</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Select to use the specified base font. If not
                  selected, the data axis font will be used.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Data Axis Font</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Specify the font to be used for the data axis labels
                  by clicking on the FONT button located to the right of the
                  field. Selecting the FONT button will bring up the “Select
                  Font” screen, where you may specify font name, font style,
                  font size, and font effects.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
            </variablelist>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Data Axis Title</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Specify the following details for the data axis
            title:</para>
            <variablelist>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Title</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Enter the title you want to appear centered along the
                  bottom of the Graph’s data axis.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Use Base Font</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Select to use the specified base font. If not
                  selected, the data axis title font will be used.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Data Axis Title Font</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Specify the font to be used for the data axis title by
                  clicking on the FONT button located to the right of the
                  field. Selecting the FONT button will bring up the “Select
                  Font” screen, where you may specify font name, font style,
                  font size, and font effects.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
            </variablelist>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
      <para>At the bottom of the screen, the following buttons are
      available:</para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>OK</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select to save your settings.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>CANCEL</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Closes the screen without saving any changes, returning you
            to the application desktop.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
      <para>To define the properties of the Graph object’s value
      axis&mdash;that is, the vertical axis running along the left-hand side
      of the Graph&mdash;select the “Value Axis” tab at the top of the “Graph
      Editor” screen. The following screen will appear:</para>
      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/C01_357_GraphValAxis.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>Graph Editor Value Axis</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <para>When editing the value axis properties of a Graph object, you are
      presented with the following options:</para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Min</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Specify the minimum value you want to have appear on the
            Graph object’s value axis.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Max</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Specify the maximum value you want to have appear on the
            Graph object’s value axis.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Expand Min/Max if needed</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select to allow data represented in the Graph to expand
            beyond the minimum and maximum values specified if needed. If not
            selected, data will be restricted to the limits specified for the
            minimum and maximum values.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Use Base Font</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select to use the specified base font. If not selected, the
            value axis font will be used.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Value Axis Font</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Specify the font to be used for values in the value axis by
            clicking on the FONT button located to the right of the field.
            Selecting the FONT button will bring up the “Select Font” screen,
            where you may specify font name, font style, font size, and font
            effects.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Value Axis Title</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Specify the following details for the value axis
            title:</para>
            <variablelist>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Title</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Enter the title you want to appear centered along the
                  left-hand margin of the Graph’s value axis.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Use Base Font</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Select to use the specified base font. If not
                  selected, the value axis title font will be used.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Value Axis Title Font</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Specify the font to be used for the value axis title
                  by clicking on the FONT button located to the right of the
                  field. Selecting the FONT button will bring up the “Select
                  Font” screen, where you may specify font name, font style,
                  font size, and font effects.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
            </variablelist>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
      <para>At the bottom of the screen, the following buttons are
      available:</para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>OK</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select to save your settings.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>CANCEL</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Closes the screen without saving any changes, returning you
            to the application desktop.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
      <para>To define the properties of Graph object series, select the
      “Series” tab at the top of the “Graph Editor” screen. The following
      screen will appear:</para>
      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/C01_358_GraphSeries.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>Graph Editor Series</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <para>When editing the properties of a Graph object series, you are
      presented with the following options:</para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Series</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select a series from the drop-down menu by clicking on the
            arrow to the right of the field. Each Graph must contain at least
            one series&mdash;and may contain multiple series. Using multiple
            series enables you to compare and contrast information from
            different database columns within a single Graph. To create a new
            series, select the NEW button. By default, a new series will be
            given the name “New Series.” You may edit this default name within
            the “Name” field below. To remove a series from the list of
            series, select the REMOVE button.</para>
            <note>
              <para>You may assign different properties to each series in a
              graph (e.g., different colors) to make a clear visual
              distinction between series.</para>
            </note>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Series Properties</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Specify properties for the selected series using the
            following options:</para>
            <variablelist>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Name</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Displays the name of the series. You may edit the name
                  of the series using this field. Any editing changes will be
                  saved automatically.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Column</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Specify the name of the database column you want to
                  use from the selected query source. A query source may refer
                  to multiple columns in its <literal>SELECT</literal>
                  statement. By indicating a specific column, you instruct the
                  query source to return data only for that specified column.
                  Other columns appearing in the <literal>SELECT</literal>
                  statement will be ignored.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Color</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Specify the color you want to use to represent data in
                  the series. Selecting the EDIT button will bring up several
                  color definition screens. You have the ability to specify
                  multiple colors, using either the included color wheel or
                  standard RGB values.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Style</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Specify one of the following options to be used for
                  representing items in the series: “Bars,” “Lines,” or
                  “Points.”</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
            </variablelist>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
      <para>At the bottom of the screen, the following buttons are
      available:</para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>OK</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select to save your settings.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>CANCEL</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Closes the screen without saving any changes, returning you
            to the application desktop.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Managing Report Definitions</title>
    <para>Report definitions created using the report writer are saved in
    Extensible Markup Language (XML) format. This is a universal standard file
    format, which simplifies the process of file sharing. Report definitions
    may be loaded into the report writer from a database, saved locally as
    XML, transferred via email or other method, and then uploaded for use in a
    different database. In this section, we will describe how to manage report
    definitions&mdash;moving them from a database to a local drive and back to
    a database again.</para>
    <section>
      <title>Loading Reports from a Database</title>
      <para>For the purposes of this exercise, we will assume we are
      connecting to an xTuple Database, using the xTuple report writer.
      However, you would follow similar steps using the standalone OpenRPT
      application connected to a different database.</para>
      <para>To begin with, let’s load an existing report definition into the
      report writer from an xTuple Database. From the Master Information
      section of the System Module, select the “Reports” option. The master
      list of report definitions will appear, as shown below:</para>
      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/C01_395_RepMastList.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>Master List of Report Definitions in xTuple
            Database</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <para>We will be working with an xTuple report definition called
      “UsersMasterList.” This is a report which details information about
      xTuple user accounts. We can load the report definition into the report
      writer simply by opening it. To open the report definition, double-click
      on it&mdash;or highlight it and then select the EDIT button. The
      following screen will appear:</para>
      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/C01_400_LoadFrmDB.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>Load Report Definition from Database</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <para>The “UsersMasterList” is now loaded into the report writer. Our
      next step will be to save the report definition to a local drive.</para>
    </section>
    <section id="i547117">
      <title>Saving to XML</title>
      <para>Now that we have loaded the “UsersMasterList” report definition
      into the report writer, let’s save it to our local drive in XML format.
      To do so, select the “Save As” option from the “File” drop-down menu.
      The following screen will appear:</para>
      <para id="i565231"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/C01_405_SaveAsXML.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>Save Report Definition to XML Format</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <para>As you can see, our operating system prompts us to name the file
      and also specify a storage location. We navigate to a directory where
      other report definitions are stored and then give the file the same name
      it had when it was stored in the database. We also add the “.xml”
      extension to the end of the file name.</para>
      <tip>
        <para>The names of report definition files are case-sensitive. To
        ensure accuracy, keep this in mind when sharing report definition
        files from one database to another.</para>
      </tip>
      <para>Using an XML-compatible browser, we can now open the report
      definition and view the XML code, as shown in the following
      screenshot:</para>
      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/C01_410_XMLBrowser.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>Report Definition XML Rendered in a Browser</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <para>So, we have stored the report definition on our local drive in the
      portable XML format. We are now able to share the file with other users,
      load it into the report writer for editing, or save it to another
      database.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Loading from XML</title>
      <para>Before we can save a locally-stored report definition to another
      database, we must first load the XML file into the report writer. To
      load a locally-stored report definition into the report writer, select
      either the “Open File” button or the “Open” option from the “File”
      drop-down menu. The following screen will appear:</para>
      <para id="i565202"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/C01_417_ChooseFile.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>Loading XML File into the Report Writer</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <para>Our operating system prompts us to locate the file we want to load
      into the report writer. Once we locate and select the file, the report
      writer loads it, as shown in the following screenshot:</para>
      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/C01_420_LoadedRptDefXML.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>Report Definition Loaded from XML File</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <para>Now that the report definition has been loaded into the report
      writer, we can transfer it to a database&mdash;which we will do in our
      next step.</para>
    </section>
    <section id="i552942">
      <title>Saving to a Database</title>
      <para>Next we will save the XML report definition to an xTuple Database.
      With the report definition loaded into the report writer, select the
      “Save to DB” option from the “Database” drop-down menu, as shown
      below:</para>
      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/C01_425_SaveToDb.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>Saving Report Definition to Database</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <para>Because in this example we are connected to an xTuple Database, a
      large number of report definitions are already stored on the database.
      The complete list of stored report definitions appears in the next
      screen, which appears after we select the “Save to DB” option from the
      “Database” drop-down menu:</para>
      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/C01_430_LoadDBGrade50.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>Save Report to Database with a Higher Grade</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <para>xTuple can only generate reports using report definitions which
      are saved to its database. To distinguish between different versions of
      a report definition, the report writer employs grades. By default,
      xTuple uses the report definition with the highest grade.</para>
      <tip>
        <para>Standard xTuple report definitions are delivered with a grade of
        “0”. By default, the xTuple client runs the highest numbered grade. To
        ensure that you can always return to the baseline version of a report,
        save your report definitions with a grade higher than 0.</para>
      </tip>
      <para>Because our xTuple Database already contains one version of the
      “UsersMasterList” report definition, let’s save our current version with
      a grade of 50. This will clearly mark our current version as the default
      version xTuple should use. To see the two versions with their different
      grades, open the “Load from DB” option from the “Database” drop-down
      menu. The following screen will appear:</para>
      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/C01_435_ListReportsGrades.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>Note Multiple Grades for a Single Report</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <para>Keep in mind once again that xTuple will use the “UsersMasterList”
      report definition with grade 50 when executing this report.</para>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section id="i547397">
    <title>Parts of a Report Definition</title>
    <para>Report definitions are structured documents used to extract data
    from a database and then print that data on one or more pages. The report
    writer gives you the ability to define simple or complex structures. In
    this section, we will look at the parts of a report definition.</para>
    <section>
      <title>Section Editor</title>
      <para>Report definitions created using the report writer consist of
      three basic sections. Those three sections are as follows:</para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Headers</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Headers are frequently used for titles, column headings, and
            key report information&mdash;such as Customer contact information
            on an Invoice. Headers may contain queries, but unlike the Detail
            sections of a report, Headers will only display the first row
            returned for a query.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Footers</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Footers often contain summary data&mdash;such as
            totals.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Detail Sections</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Detail sections typically contain the core information found
            in a report. Detail section information is typically represented
            in the form of multiple rows of values that were returned by a
            query.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
      <para>To add sections to or remove sections from a report definition,
      use the section editor. To access the section editor, open a report
      definition and select the “Section Editor” option from the “Document”
      drop-down menu. The following screen will appear:</para>
      <para id="i566833"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/C01_500_SectionEditor.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>Section Editor</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <para>As you can see, the section editor contains controls for each of
      the three basic section types. In the following examples, we will
      discuss all the controls found on the section editor screen.</para>
    </section>
    <section id="i570960">
      <title>Report Headers</title>
      <para>Report Headers are commonly used to create report titles. Report
      Headers have the following characteristics:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Always print on the report</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Always print at the top of the page, directly below Page
          Headers</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Directly precede first Detail section</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Only print on the first page</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Only display the first row of data returned by a query</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>For the purposes of this exercise, we will assume we are working
      with a blank report definition having no sections currently defined. To
      add a Report Header to a report definition, select the “Report Header”
      option from the section editor screen. The Report Header section will be
      added to the report definition, as shown in the following screen:</para>
      <para id="i566952"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/C01_501_ReportHeader.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>Report Header Section</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <para>When a section is added to a report definition, the name of the
      section appears in the upper-left-hand corner of the section. As you can
      see, our newly-added section is clearly labeled “Report Header.”</para>
      <para>To remove a Report Header from a report definition, simply uncheck
      the “Report Header” option on the section editor screen.</para>
    </section>
    <section id="i571060">
      <title>Page Headers</title>
      <para>Page Headers are commonly used to contain column headings. Page
      Headers have the following characteristics:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Always print at the top of a page</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Always contain the first information printed on a page</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Directly precede Report Headers</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Only display the first row of data returned by a query</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Allow multiple types for different pages</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Only one allowed per page</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>To accommodate the requirements of multi-page reports, the report
      writer supports the following five different types of Page
      Headers:</para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>First Page</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Prints at the top of the first page of a report</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Even Page(s)</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Prints at the top of even pages of a report</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Any Page(s)</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>May be used to print at the top of any page of a
            report</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Last Page</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Prints at the top of the last page of a report</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Odd Page(s)</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Prints at the top of odd pages of a report</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
      <para>Again, only one Page Header may be printed per page. When a report
      definition contains more than one Page Header, the report writer
      recognizes the Page Headers in the following order of precedence: 1)
      First Page; 2) Last Page; 3) Even Page(s); 4) Odd Page(s); 5) Any
      Page(s).</para>
      <tip>
        <para>If your report definition includes both “Even Page” and “Odd
        Page” Page Headers, don’t include an “Any Page” Header. Based on the
        report writer’s precedence rules, the “Any Page” Header would never
        print in this scenario.</para>
      </tip>
      <para>To add a Page Header to a report definition using the section
      editor, select the type of Page Header you want to add from the “Page
      Header” section of the screen. For this exercise, we will add a first
      Page Header, as shown in the following screen:</para>
      <para id="i567243"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/C01_502_PageHeader.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>First Page Header Section</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <para>As you can see, the Page Header section is added above the Report
      Header section. If subsequent Page Header sections are added, they will
      also be placed above the Report Header section, but below the “First
      Page” Header.</para>
      <para>To remove a Page Header from a report definition, simply uncheck
      the Page Header option you selected on the section editor screen.</para>
    </section>
    <section id="i571059">
      <title>Report Footers</title>
      <para>Report Footers are commonly used to display report totals. Report
      Footers have the following characteristics:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Always print on the report</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Always print at the bottom of the page, directly above Page
          Headers</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Directly follow the last Detail section</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Only print on the first page</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Only display the first row of data returned by a query</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>To add a Report Footer to a report definition, select the “Report
      Footer” option from the section editor screen. The Report Footer section
      will be added to the report definition, as shown in the following
      screen:</para>
      <para id="i567574"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/C01_503_ReportFooter.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>Report Footer Section</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <para>As you can see, the Report Footer section is added below the
      Report Header section. To remove a Report Footer from a report
      definition, simply uncheck the “Report Footer” option on the section
      editor screen.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Page Footers</title>
      <para>Page Footers are commonly used to contain report totals. Page
      Footers have the following characteristics:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Always print at the bottom of a page</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Always contain the last information printed on a page</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Directly follow Report Footers</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Only display the first row of data returned by a query</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Allow multiple types for different pages</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Only one allowed per page</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>To accommodate the requirements of multi-page reports, the report
      writer supports the following five different types of Page
      Footers:</para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>First Page</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Prints at the bottom of the first page of a report</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Even Page(s)</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Prints at the bottom of even pages of a report</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Any Page(s)</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>May be used to print at the bottom any page of a
            report</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Last Page</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Prints at the bottom of the last page of a report</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Odd Page(s)</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Prints at the bottom of odd pages of a report</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
      <para>Again, only one Page Footer may be printed per page. When a report
      definition contains more than one Page Footer, the report writer
      recognizes the Page Footers in the following order of precedence: 1)
      Last Page; 2) First Page; 3) Even Page(s); 4) Odd Page(s); 5) Any
      Page(s).</para>
      <tip>
        <para>If your report definition includes both “Even Page” and “Odd
        Page” Page Footers, don’t include an “Any Page” Footer. Based on the
        report writer’s precedence rules, the “Any Page” Footer would never
        print in this scenario.</para>
      </tip>
      <para>To add a Page Footer to a report definition using the section
      editor, select the type of Page Footer you want to add from the “Page
      Footer” section of the screen. For this exercise, we will add a first
      Page Footer, as shown in the following screen:</para>
      <para id="i567523"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/C01_504_PageFooter.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>Page Footer Section</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <para>As you can see, the Page Footer section is added below the Report
      Footer section. If subsequent Page Footer sections are added, they will
      also be placed below the Report Footer section, but above the “First
      Page” Footer.</para>
      <para>To remove a Page Footer from a report definition, simply uncheck
      the Page Header option you selected on the section editor screen.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Detail Sections</title>
      <para>The core information in a report is displayed in its Detail
      section. Detail sections have the following characteristics:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Generally print in the middle of a page</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Always contain the core information for a report</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Display multiple rows of data returned by a query</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Unlimited allowed</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <note>
        <para>The report writer allows you to incorporate an unlimited number
        of Detail sections into a report definition, although most contain
        just one.</para>
      </note>
      <para>The section editor handles Detail sections differently than it
      handles Header and Footer sections&mdash;that is, the process for adding
      and managing Detail sections is more involved. The following screen
      shows the section editor with a Detail section added:</para>
      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/C01_506_DetailSecEditor.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>Section Editor with Detail Sections Added</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <para>When adding a Detail section to a report definition, you are
      presented with the following options:</para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Detail Sections</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Displays the names of Detail sections added to the report
            definition. Detail sections may be added, edited, removed, or
            moved up and down.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
      <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
      available:</para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>ADD</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Opens screen for adding a new Detail section to the report
            definition, as described below.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>EDIT</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Enables you to edit highlighted Detail section. The edit
            screen is the same as that for adding a new Detail
            section&mdash;except that when editing, the fields will contain
            Detail section information.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>DELETE</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Highlight a Detail section and then select this button to
            remove the Detail section from the list.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>MOVE UP</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Highlight a Detail section and then select this button to
            move the Detail section up the list.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>MOVE DOWN</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Highlight a Detail section and then select this button to
            move the Detail section down the list.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>CLOSE</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Closes the screen, returning you to the application
            desktop.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
      <para>To add a new Detail section to a report definition, select the ADD
      button. The following screen will appear:</para>
      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/C01_507_AddDetail.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>Add New Detail Section</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <para>When adding a new Detail section to a report definition, you are
      presented with the following options:</para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Section Name</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Enter a name to identify the Detail section.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Query Source</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select a query source from the drop-down menu by clicking on
            the arrow to the right of the field. Query sources are used to
            populate report definition objects with dynamic data from the
            database the report writer is connected to.</para>
            <note>
              <para>For more information on query sources and the link between
              database fields and report definition objects, please see the
              Getting Started chapter.</para>
            </note>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Insert Page Break At End of Last Section</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>When this option is checked a new page will be started when
            the section is complete. Additional detail sections and/or a
            report footer is printed on a new page. Page footers will print as
            normal.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Group Sections</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Displays the names of Group sections added to the report
            definition. Group sections may be added, edited, removed, or moved
            up and down.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
      <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
      available:</para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>ADD</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Opens screen for adding a new Group section to the report
            definition, as described below.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>EDIT</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Enables you to edit highlighted Group section. The edit
            screen is the same as that for adding a new Group
            section&mdash;except that when editing, the fields will contain
            Group section information.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>DELETE</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Highlight a Group section and then select this button to
            remove the Group section from the list.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>MOVE UP</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Highlight a Group section and then select this button to
            move the Group section up the list.</para>
            <tip>
              <para>The Group section appearing at the top of the list is
              considered the first, or outermost Group section. During
              processing, the outermost section is handled first, followed by
              the next innermost section, and then the next innermost,
              etc.</para>
            </tip>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>MOVE DOWN</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Highlight a Group section and then select this button to
            move the Group section down the list.</para>
            <tip>
              <para>The Group section appearing at the top of the list is
              considered the first, or outermost Group section. During
              processing, the outermost section is handled first, followed by
              the next innermost section, and then the next innermost,
              etc.</para>
            </tip>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>CLOSE</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Closes the screen, returning you to the application
            desktop.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
      <para>When a Detail section has been added using the section editor, the
      report writer incorporates the Detail section into the report
      definition, as shown in the following screen:</para>
      <para id="i569340"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/C01_508_DetailSections.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>Detail Section</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <para>As you can see, the Detail section has been added to the report
      definition. The Detail section appears in the middle of the page,
      sandwiched between the Report Header and Report Footer.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Group Sections</title>
      <para>While most reports can be defined using a single Detail section
      having multiple columns and rows of data, others require summary
      data&mdash;such as subtotals. For reports requiring summary data, the
      report writer supports Group sections. Group sections have the following
      characteristics:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Always associated with Detail sections</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Defined by Group Headers and Group Footers</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Group Headers always print above Detail sections</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Group Footers always print below Detail sections</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Reference database column on which Group Headers and Group
          Footers will break</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Force new Group Header each time the value of the referenced
          column changes</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Force a new Group Footer each time the value of the referenced
          column changes</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Unlimited allowed</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>To add a Group section to a report definition, select the ADD
      button from the “Detail Section Properties” screen. The following screen
      will appear:</para>
      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/C01_525_GroupSections.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>Group Section Editor</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <para>When adding a Group section to a Detail section, you are presented
      with the following options:</para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Group Name</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Enter a name to identify the Group section.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Column</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Specify the name of the database column you want to use from
            the selected query source. A query source may refer to multiple
            columns in its <literal>SELECT</literal> statement. By indicating
            a specific column, you instruct the query source to return data
            only for that specified column. Other columns appearing in the
            <literal>SELECT</literal> statement will be ignored.</para>
            <note>
              <para>For more information on query sources and the link between
              database fields and report definition objects, please see the
              Getting Started chapter.</para>
            </note>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Show Group Header</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select to include a Group Header in the report definition.
            The Group Header will print above the Detail section. If not
            selected, no Group Header will be included in the report
            definition.</para>
            <tip>
              <para>Be sure to specify a Group Header and/or a Group Footer.
              Without either, no Group section will print on the report
              definition.</para>
            </tip>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Show Group Footer</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select to include a Group Footer in the report definition.
            The Group Header will print below the Detail section. If not
            selected, no Group Footer will be included in the report
            definition.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Insert Page Break After this Footer</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>When checked starts a new page before the next grouped
            section. When this option is checked and a group is ending a page
            break will be created after the group footer, if any. The current
            record will be moved forward after the current page is completed
            rendering but before the next page starts rendering.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
      <para>At the bottom of the screen, the following buttons are
      available:</para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>OK</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select to save your settings.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>CANCEL</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Closes the screen without saving any changes, returning you
            to the application desktop.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
      <para>When a Group Header and Group Footer have been added using the
      section editor, the report writer incorporates both sections into the
      report definition, as shown in the following screen:</para>
      <para id="i570362"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/C01_523_GroupHeadFoot.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>Group Headers and Footers</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <para>As you can see, the Group Header has been added above the Detail
      section, and the Group Footer has been added below the Detail
      section.</para>
      <para>To better understand the relationship between Detail sections and
      Group Headers and Group Footers, let’s look at a sample report generated
      from data in an xTuple Database. The following Sales Analysis report is
      called “Time Phased Sales History by Customer by Item”:</para>
      <para id="i568052"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/C01_520_GroupSectionsReportExample.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>Sample Report Showing Group Headers and Group
            Footers</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <para>The “Time-Phased Sales History by Customer by Item” report
      contains a Detail section with two Group sections associated with it.
      The outermost Group section refers to Customer information. The second,
      innermost Group section refers to Item information. Basically, if you
      study the report you will see that the sections are printed in the
      following descending order:</para>
      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Group Header (Customers</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Group Header (Items</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Detail Section (Dates/Amounts)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Group Footer (Items)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Group Footer (Customers)</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
      <para>Because the report contains data for two Customers, you can see in
      the screenshot that the sequence of sections repeats itself twice. You
      can also see that Group Footers are used to provide both Item and
      Customer subtotals. As we mentioned earlier, Group sections are commonly
      used for summary information.</para>
      <note>
        <para>Group Headers and Group Footers are powerful features which
        enable you to generate reports which provide multiple levels of detail
        and roll-up values. However, you will find that most report
        definitions will conform to the following basic structure:</para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Page Header: Any Page(s)</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Detail Section</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Page Footer: Any Page(s)</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </note>
      <para>The report shown is the actual report printed from data in an
      xTuple Database. The following screenshot shows the report definition
      used to generate the sample report.</para>
      <para id="i570712"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/C01_530_SampleRepDef.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>Report Definition Used for Sample Report</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <para>If some aspects of the report definition shown seem confusing,
      don’t worry. We will be covering the mechanics of report writing in
      subsequent chapters</para>
    </section>
  </section>
</chapter>
