<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.3//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.3/docbookx.dtd">
<chapter>
  <title>Tools</title>
  <para>In this chapter we will examine several third party tools you may find
  useful when creating OpenRPT report definitions. The tools can also be
  helpful to system administrators responsible for maintaining xTuple
  Databases and/or other PostgreSQL databases.</para>
  <para>The first tool we will look at is pgAdmin III, an open source database
  administration utility for PostgreSQL. Next we will look at the ODBC driver
  available for PostgreSQL. We will show you how to install and configure an
  ODBC connection from a Windows client to a PostgreSQL database. Finally, we
  will examine how a query tool can be used to generate SQL that can then be
  copied and pasted into an xTuple report definition Query Source to
  accelerate the development of a new report.</para>
  <section>
    <title>pgAdmin III</title>
    <para>The best description of pgAdmin III can be found on the project’s
    website:</para>
    <simpara>“pgAdmin III is the most popular and feature rich Open Source
    administration and development platform for PostgreSQL, the most advanced
    Open Source database in the world. The application may be used on Linux,
    FreeBSD, Solaris, Mac OSX and Windows platforms to manage PostgreSQL 7.3
    and above running on any platform, as well as commercial versions of
    PostgreSQL such as Pervasive Postgres, EnterpriseDB, Mammoth Replicator
    and SRA PowerGres.</simpara>
    <simpara>“pgAdmin III is designed to answer the needs of all users, from
    writing simple SQL queries to developing complex databases. The graphical
    interface supports all PostgreSQL features and makes administration easy.
    The application also includes a syntax highlighting SQL editor, a
    server-side code editor, an SQL/batch/shell job scheduling agent, support
    for the Slony-I replication engine and much more. Server connection may be
    made using TCP/IP or Unix Domain Sockets (on *nix platforms), and may be
    SSL encrypted for security. No additional drivers are required to
    communicate with the database server.</simpara>
    <simpara>“pgAdmin III is developed by a community of PostgreSQL experts
    around the world and is available in more than a dozen languages. It is
    Free Software released under the Artistic License.”</simpara>
    <para>Those who use pgAdmin III find it to be invaluable for performing
    database maintenance, along with simply examining database structures and
    data.</para>
    <section>
      <title>Where Can I Find pgAdmin III?</title>
      <para>You can download pgAdmin III for free either from the pgAdmin
      website (http://www.pgadmin.org/) or from the PostgreSQL website
      (http://www.postgresql.org). It is available for multiple operating
      systems and features an easy-to-use installation utility.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Connecting to an xTuple Database</title>
      <para>Once you have completed the installation of pgAdmin III, it is
      time to configure a connection to your xTuple Database. To begin, select
      the “Add Server” option from the pgAdmin III “File” menu. You will be
      presented with the following screen:</para>
      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/C05_100_ConToServer.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>pgAdmin III Connection Definition Screen</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <para>You will need to provide the URL or IP address of your server
      along with the port on which PostgreSQL is listening. Then, you will
      identify the name of your xTuple Database&mdash;as well as the username
      and password for the user who will be establishing the
      connection.</para>
      <para>Once the server has been added and you have established a
      connection, the pgAdmin will screen will look as follows:</para>
      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/C05_110_pgAdminIIIMain.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>Table View in pgAdmin III</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <para>pgAdmin III will add your new connection to its list of servers.
      In the future, you can simply double-click on the name of a server to
      initiate a connection.</para>
      <para>Using pgAdmin III is helpful when creating OpenRPT reports because
      it enables you to see all of a database’s tables and their corresponding
      columns. It is also possible to see data&mdash;and even maintain
      data&mdash;by drilling down to a specific table, right clicking on it,
      and selecting the “View Data” from the resulting menu. The following
      screenshot illustrates the data view:</para>
      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/C05_120_pgAdminIIIViewData.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>Viewing and Maintenance of Data</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <para>The pgAdmin III utility is a very powerful tool. Be sure to take
      care when using the “View Data” option, as it enables you to manually
      update data in the database.</para>
      <note>
        <para>Also worth noting is pgAdmin’s SQL Help option located under the
        Help menu. These help filed provide very detailed descriptions and
        examples of SQL commands, syntax, and statements.</para>
      </note>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>What is ODBC?</title>
    <para>The online technical resource Whatis.com provides the following
    definition for ODBC:</para>
    <para>“Open Database Connectivity (ODBC) is an open standard application
    programming interface (API) for accessing a database. By using ODBC
    statements in a program, you can access files in a number of different
    databases, including Access, dBase, DB2, Excel, and Text. In addition to
    the ODBC software, a separate module or driver is needed for each database
    to be accessed. The main proponent and supplier of ODBC programming
    support is Microsoft.</para>
    <para>“ODBC is based on and closely aligned with The Open Group standard
    Structured Query Language (SQL) Call-Level Interface. It allows programs
    to use SQL requests that will access databases without having to know the
    proprietary interfaces to the databases. ODBC handles the SQL request and
    converts it into a request the individual database system
    understands.”</para>
    <section>
      <title>Locating the ODBC Driver For PostgreSQL</title>
      <para>The ODBC driver for PostgreSQL can be downloaded from the
      PostgreSQL web site. If you are running Windows, the driver also comes
      with an installer.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Configuring an ODBC Connection to xTuple</title>
      <para>After installing the PostgreSQL ODBC driver, it is time to
      configure it. This is a simple task. If you are running Windows, you
      perform the configuration by opening your Windows Control Panel,
      selecting Administrative Tools, and then Data Sources (ODBC), as shown
      in the following screen:</para>
      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/C05_200_ODBCSources.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>Configuring ODBC Connection</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <para>On the ODBC Data Source Administrator Panel, click the ADD button
      to begin configuring a connection to your xTuple PostgreSQL database.
      The following screen will appear:</para>
      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/C05_210_ODBCCreatNew.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>Selecting PostgreSQL Driver</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <para>Select the PostgreSQL driver from the list of available drivers
      and click the FINISH button. You will be presented with the following
      screen:</para>
      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/C05_220_ODBCSetup.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>Final Driver Set Up</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <para>When finalizing the set up of the PostgreSQL driver, you are
      presented with the following options:</para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Data Source</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Give your connection a name (leave out spaces).</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Description</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Describe your connection.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Database</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Enter the name of the PostgreSQL database.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Server</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Provide the name or IP address of the PostgreSQL
            server.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Port</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Enter the port on which the PostgreSQL database is
            listening.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>User Name</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Provide a database user’s user name.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Password</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Provide the database user’s password.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
      <para>Now that our ODBC configuration is complete, we will use the
      connection to access data in an xTuple Database.</para>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Capturing SQL with MS Query</title>
    <para>If you know of a query tool that generates SQL statements, you may
    consider using that tool to facilitate the writing of queries used in
    OpenRPT report definitions. Having an external query builder can help to
    accelerate the creation of report definitions. In this section we will
    look at an example of how this process works using one such query builder:
    Microsoft Query, which is a component of the Excel program.</para>
    <note>
      <para>Using external query tools can be helpful, as OpenRPT does not
      currently have a native query builder.</para>
    </note>
    <section>
      <title>What is MS Query?</title>
      <para>Microsoft defines the query builder embedded within its Excel
      application as follows: “Microsoft Query is a program for bringing data
      from external sources into other Microsoft Office programs&mdash; in
      particular, Microsoft Excel. By using Query to retrieve data from your
      corporate databases.”</para>
      <para>Remember, we are most interested in MS Query as a means for
      generating SQL statements which we can then run against our xTuple
      Database. Again, having predefined queries will help accelerate the
      report building process in OpenRPT.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Using Predefined Queries in OpenRPT</title>
      <para>In this section we will illustrate how to use Excel’s MS Query to
      build a query which we will then insert into an OpenRPT report
      definition to generate a report. Below is the final SQL generated by MS
      Query using our ODBC connection to the <literal>usr</literal> table in
      our xTuple Database:</para>
      <para id="i562938"><programlisting>SELECT usr.usr_id, usr.usr_username, usr.usr_propername, usr.usr_passwd,
       usr.usr_locale_id, usr.usr_initials, usr.usr_agent, usr.usr_active,
       usr.usr_email
FROM public.usr usr
ORDER BY usr.usr_username</programlisting></para>
      <para>Now we will show the steps involved to generate the predefined
      query.</para>
      <para>First, open the Excel application. From the “Data” menu select the
      “Get External Data” option. Then select the “New Database Query” option.
      You will be presented with the following screen:</para>
      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/C05_230_ODBC_Excel_ChooseData.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>Selecting ODBC Data Source</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <para>Select the new ODBC connection you just created against your
      PostgreSQL database, and then click the OK button.</para>
      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/C05_300_QueryWizardTableCols.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>Choosing Columns with Query Wizard</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <para>In the left column, scroll to the table <literal>usr</literal> and
      click on it. Then select the “&gt;” button to select all columns in the
      table. Finally, select the NEXT button to be brought to the following
      screen:</para>
      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/C05_310_QueryWizardFilter.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>Filtering Data with Query Wizard</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <para>Next, the Query Wizard provides you with the opportunity to filter
      the data. For this exercise, we will choose not apply a filter to the
      data. Click the NEXT button to reach the following screen:</para>
      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/C05_320_QueryWizardSort.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>Sorting Criteria with Query Wizard</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <para>We will define one sort criteria. In the “Sort by” field select
      the column <literal>usr_username</literal> and check “Ascending” next to
      it. Click the NEXT button to reach the next screen:</para>
      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/C05_330_QueryWizardReturnData.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>Multiple Output Options</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <para>Because we are only using Query to generate an SQL statement, we
      check the option “View data or edit query in Microsoft Query.” Click the
      FINISH button.</para>
      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/C05_340_QueryResultAndSQL.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>Viewing the SQL</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <para>Initially, Query displays the results of the query we just created
      with the Query Wizard. To see the syntax of the SQL statement, click the
      SQL tool in the toolbar.</para>
      <para>To copy this SQL statement for importing into an OpenRPT report
      definition, select the statement and then right click and use the “Copy”
      option. Later you can paste the statement into an OpenRPT Query
      Source.</para>
      <para>Earlier chapters in this user guide covered the details of
      modifying and creating OpenRPT report definitions. The next few screens
      show the core elements of a report definition and the resulting
      output.</para>
      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/C05_400_QueryDetailEditor.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>SQL Pasted in Query Editor</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <para>Above you can see the SQL statement exactly as it was copied from
      Microsoft Query and pasted into an OpenRPT Query Source for a new report
      definition. We will run this report using the xTuple
      application&mdash;and so we will save it with the already-existing
      report definition name “UsersMasterList.” To distinguish this version of
      the report from others, we will assign this version a Grade of “20.” In
      xTuple, report definitions having the highest grade are used. Assuming
      “20” is the highest grade for “UsersMasterList,” our new version will be
      run with users select PRINT from the xTuple master list of users.</para>
      <note>
        <para>The SQL in our example is the exact same SQL statement as it was
        copied from Microsoft Query. MetaSQL has not been added to it. When
        printing the user master list from xTuple, the client passes the
        parameters <literal>locale_id</literal> and
        <literal>showInactive</literal> to the report definition at run time.
        These parameter values can be used to create sophisticated
        <literal>WHERE</literal> clauses that show data on the report based on
        user entries on the User screen. Remember, you can use the MetaSQL
        Editor to test SQL that contains MetaSQL before pasting into a
        report’s Query Source. MetaSQL is covered in another chapter of this
        user guide.</para>
      </note>
      <para>Below is a look at the report definition we created using the
      query we built with Microsoft Query.</para>
      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/C05_410_ReportDef.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>View of Report Definition</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <para>This report definition will be run when an xTuple user selects
      PRINT on the following xTuple screen:</para>
      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/C05_420_ReportPrint.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>xTuple Users Master List</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <para>After we select PRINT, the report definition is printed just as we
      planned:</para>
      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/C05_430_SpecialReportOutput.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>Final Report Output</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <para>The report shown above was generated using the SQL we copied from
      Microsoft Query. It demonstrates the speed and ease with which new
      reports can be created and deployed using OpenRPT.</para>
    </section>
  </section>
</chapter>
