<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.3//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.3/docbookx.dtd">
<chapter id="Chapter658560">
  <title><anchor id="Anchor27334" role="Cross-Ref"
  xreflabel="27334: ChapterTitle: Inventory Management (I/M) Module" />Inventory
  Management (I/M) Module</title>

  <para id="Para562490">In this chapter, we describe the Inventory module.
  This module is responsible for defining and maintaining the following key
  components:</para>

  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1819e48">
      <para id="Para562491">Item Sites</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1819e6c">
      <para id="Para518507">Inventory Transactions</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1819e90">
      <para id="Para518508">Physical Inventory</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1819eb4">
      <para id="Para518509">Warehouses</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1819ed8">
      <para id="Para625111">Warehouse Locations</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1819efc">
      <para id="Para625112">Cost Categories</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1819f20">
      <para id="Para625113">Item Controls</para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>

  <para id="Para518513">The module is also responsible for generating General
  Ledger (G/L) transactions that record and track Physical Inventory movements
  throughout the production environment.</para>

  <section id="Section518514">
    <title><anchor id="Anchor552118" role="Index"
    xreflabel="master information:for i/m module" /> <indexterm
        significance="normal" zone="Anchor552118">
        <primary>master information</primary>

        <secondary>for i/m module</secondary>
      </indexterm>Master Information</title>

    <para id="Para518521">This is the section where you define Master
    Information for the module.</para>

    <xi:include href="guiclient/warehouses.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <xi:include href="guiclient/warehouse.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <xi:include href="guiclient/locations.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <xi:include href="guiclient/location.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <xi:include href="guiclient/costCategories.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <xi:include href="guiclient/costCategory.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <xi:include href="guiclient/expenseCategories.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <xi:include href="guiclient/expenseCategory.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <section id="Section675390">
      <title><anchor id="Anchor44260" role="Cross-Ref"
      xreflabel="44260: Heading1: Item Sites" />Item Sites</title>

      <para id="Para518688">Item Sites identify and define the methods and
      controls used when maintaining a given Item within a given
      Warehouse.</para>
    </section>

    <section id="Section518694">
      <title><anchor id="Anchor41372" role="Cross-Ref"
      xreflabel="41372: Heading2: Enter Item Site" /> <anchor
      id="Anchor552128" role="Index" xreflabel="item sites:creating new" />
      <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor552128">
          <primary>item sites</primary>

          <secondary>creating new</secondary>
        </indexterm>Enter Item Site</title>

      <para id="Para518695">An Item Site identifies and defines the methods
      and controls used when maintaining a given Item within a given
      Warehouse. To enter a new Item Site into your system, select the "Enter
      Item Site" option. The following screen will appear:</para>

      <para id="Para631959"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/IM_IS_enterItemSite.png"
                         id="Graphic631957" />
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption631960">Create New Item Site</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <para id="Para631961">When creating a new Item Site, you are presented
      with the following options:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para518707">Item Number</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18569b0">
            <para>Enter the Item Number of the Item you want to create an Item
            Site for.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para671933">UOM</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18569f8">
            <para>Inventory Unit of Measure.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para518711">Active</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1856a40">
            <para>Select to indicate the Item Site is active.</para>

            <para id="Para518712">Not selecting means the Item Site will be
            considered inactive. If inactive, the Item Site will not appear on
            lists of active Item Sites. To re-activate an Item Site, simply
            select this option.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para591231">Warehouse</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1856a88">
            <para>Specify Warehouse where Item Site is located.</para>

            <para id="Para670298">Use this selection in conjunction with the
            additional Warehouse settings found on the Item Site
            screen.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para653486"><anchor id="Anchor653485" role="Index"
          xreflabel="order parameters:enforcement of;item sites:enforcing order parameters in" />
          <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor653485">
              <primary>order parameters</primary>

              <secondary>enforcement of</secondary>
            </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor653485">
              <primary>item sites</primary>

              <secondary>enforcing order parameters in</secondary>
            </indexterm>Enforce Order Parameters</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1856b60">
            <para>Order Parameters: Select to enforce Order Parameters.</para>

            <para id="Para653487">If this option is selected, then Material
            Requirements Planning (MRP) will follow the Order Parameters
            defined below when generating Planned Replenishment Orders.
            Parameters you define will be saved if this option is turned
            ON/OFF. If you want to enforce Order Parameters on manual Orders
            as well, select the "on Manual Orders" option. For more
            information on how Order Parameters interact with MRP, see the
            <link endterm="Anchor14508" id="XRef653489" linkend="Anchor14508">
            Order Parameters and MRP</link>" section.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <note>
        <para id="Para591572">Running Material Requirements Planning (MRP) on
        your system consists entirely of running the Create Planned
        Replenishment Orders screens--either by Item or by Planner Code. As
        MRP runs, the Planned Replenishment Orders are generated
        automatically.</para>
      </note>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para518722">Reorder Level</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1856bf0">
            <para>The Reorder Level specifies when a Planned Replenishment
            Order should be created for an Item Site. If Planned Availability
            minus Safety Stock falls below the Reorder Level, then a
            Replenishment Order will be created when Material Requirements
            Planning (MRP) is run. The Replenishment Order quantity will be
            equal to the quantity required to return Planned Availability to
            either the Reorder Level or the Order Up To quantity--whichever is
            greater. For more information, see the <link endterm="Anchor14508"
            id="XRef638200" linkend="Anchor14508"> Order Parameters and
            MRP</link> section.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <note>
        <para id="Para617601">Planned Availability differs from Quantity on
        Hand (QOH). The difference is that Planned Availability considers both
        QOH and also the time-phased demands placed on Inventory by Sales
        Orders and Work Orders. MRP uses Planned Availability when calculating
        which Item Sites require Planned Replenishment Orders.</para>
      </note>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para614529">Order Up To</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1856c80">
            <para>The Order Up To (OUT) Level indicates the level of Planned
            Availability an Item Site should be replenished up to when
            Material Requirements Planning (MRP) is run. In cases where the
            Reorder Level for an Item Site exceeds the Order Up To Level, MRP
            will replenish the Item Site up to the Reorder Level. For more
            information, see the <link endterm="Anchor14508" id="XRef638208"
            linkend="Anchor14508"> Order Parameters and MRP</link>
            section.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <tip>
        <para id="Para617380">Setting the Order Up To Level to "0" removes any
        restrictions on maximum Order quantities. Removing quantity
        restrictions can be an effective strategy to help ensure that all
        Order demands are satisfied when MRP is run. Order demands may not be
        met if Order Up To Levels are set below the demand threshold.</para>
      </tip>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para518732">Minimum Order</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1856d10">
            <para>Value entered indicates the minimum quantity that may be
            entered for a Planned Replenishment Order when MRP is run. If the
            "on Manual Orders" option is selected above, manually-created Work
            Orders will recognize the Minimum Order value.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para627359">Maximum Order</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1856d58">
            <para>This is a special setting which regulates the maximum
            quantity for Planned Replenishment Orders when MRP is run. The
            setting does not apply to manual Orders, but to Planned Orders
            only. When a maximum Order quantity is specified, MRP will ignore
            Order multiples and minimum Order specifications--focusing instead
            solely on the maximum Order setting. For example, if the maximum
            Order quantity is set to 10 and there is demand for 17, then
            Planned Orders of 10 and 7 would be generated when MRP is
            run.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <tip>
        <para id="Para631638">Setting the maximum order quantity too low has
        been shown to slow performance when MRP is run. Unless you have
        special needs (i.e., crate packaging limits) which require you to set
        a low maximum order quantity, you should consider setting the maximum
        order value to "0".</para>
      </tip>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para518737">Order Multiple</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1856de8">
            <para>Value entered indicates the quantity multiple that should be
            used for Planned Replenishment Orders when MRP is run. If the "on
            Manual Orders" option is selected above, manually-created Work
            Orders will recognize the Order Multiple value.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para626942">Enforce on Manual Orders</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1856e30">
            <para>Select to enforce Order Parameters on manually-created Work
            Orders.</para>

            <para id="Para626943">If this option is selected, Order Parameters
            will also be enforced whenever Work Orders are manually created.
            This option applies only to the following two parameters: Minimum
            Order and Order Multiple. The other Order Parameters listed below
            do not apply to manually-created Work Orders. For manual Purchase
            Orders, the Minimum Order and Order Multiple parameters are
            determined on a Vendor-by-Vendor basis, using Item Source
            masters.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry role="openmfg">
          <term id="Para624563">Group MPS/MRP Orders Every</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1856e54">
            <para>Specify the length of a periodmeasured in days--within which
            MPS or MRP Planned Orders will be grouped together (i.e,
            consolidated) to meet scheduled demand for the period.</para>

            <para id="Para670332">This functionality serves to limit the total
            number of Planned Orders, thereby simplifying order processing.
            For example, to consolidate demand for an Item Site into 30-day
            buckets, set the value to "30." When MRP is run, the system will
            automatically consolidate all demand falling within the 30-day
            horizon into a single Planned Purchase Order or Planned Work
            Order. The grouping of Planned Orders moves forward in time,
            meaning the system will create as many buckets as will fit within
            the cutoff date specified when MRP is run.</para>

            <para id="Para628073">The initial grouping of Planned Orders is
            handled differently than subsequent buckets. The following formula
            specifies how the date range for the initial period is
            determined:</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para628074">Start Date = Today's Date</para>

      <para id="Para628075">End Date = Today's Date + Lead Time</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1856e9c">
          <para id="Para624897">All subsequent periods are determined using
          the following calculations:</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para id="Para624912">Start Date = End Date of Previous Period +
      1</para>

      <para id="Para624913">End Date = Start Date of Current Period + Group
      Value</para>

      <tip>
        <para id="Para624876">To enforce <anchor id="Anchor624879"
        role="Index"
        xreflabel="just-in-time:delivery of planned orders;planned orders:just-in-time delivery and;material requirements planning:just-in-time delivery and" />
        <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor624879">
            <primary>just-in-time</primary>

            <secondary>delivery of planned orders</secondary>
          </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor624879">
            <primary>planned orders</primary>

            <secondary>just-in-time delivery and</secondary>
          </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor624879">
            <primary>material requirements planning</primary>

            <secondary>just-in-time delivery and</secondary>
          </indexterm>Just-In-Time (JIT) delivery methods, set the MRP group
        value to "0." This will ensure that Planned Order due dates are the
        same as the demand due dates to which they correspond. If the MRP
        Order grouping value is set to "0", the initial period will be
        determined in the same way as for all Planned Order groups:</para>

        <para id="Para624957">Start Date = Today's Date</para>

        <para id="Para624961">End Date = Today's Date + Lead Time</para>

        <para id="Para624943">However, the date range for all subsequent JIT
        Planned Orders will be based on the following calculations:</para>

        <para id="Para624964">Start Date = Demand Due Date - Lead Time</para>

        <para id="Para670380">End Date = Demand Due Date</para>
      </tip>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry role="openmfg">
          <term id="Para670385">MPS Time Fence</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1856fe0">
            <para>Specify the length of the Demand Time Fence by using the
            arrow buttons or manually entering a value up to a maximum of
            999.</para>

            <para id="Para670386">The Demand Time Fence (also known as the
            demand fence) is used by the Master Production Scheduling (MPS)
            system to evaluate when forecasted demand (i.e., from Production
            Plans) should be used in place of actual demand (i.e., from Sales
            Orders)--and vice versa. Measured in days, the Demand Time Fence
            is the period of time extending from the current day to the number
            of days into the future as specified in this field. The Demand
            Time Fence option applies only to those Items which currently
            appear on a released Production Plan. If demand for these Items
            falls within the Demand Time Fence period, then the Forecast will
            be ignored. If demand falls outside the Demand Time Fence, then
            the larger of actual or forecasted demand will be used. MPS
            responds to the demand it locates by creating firm Planned Orders
            for the required quantities.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para593801">Safety Stock</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1857028">
            <para>Specify the quantity of Stock for the Item you want to keep
            in Inventory to protect against unplanned, unforeseeable trends in
            your Order forecasts.</para>

            <para id="Para670350">When Material Requirements Planning (MRP) is
            run, the system considers the Safety Stock value when determining
            whether to create Planned Replenishment Orders. If Planned
            Availability minus Safety Stock is below the Reorder Level, then
            Planned Orders will be created. If not below the Reorder Level,
            then no Planned Orders will be created. The system's calculation
            effectively creates a buffer Inventory (if needed) to handle
            unexpected fluctuations in demand. If you do not want to use the
            Safety Stock functionality, set the Safety Stock value to
            "0".</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para518744">ABC Class</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1857070">
            <para>Specify the ABC classification for the specified
            Item.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para612236">Allow Automatic Updates</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18570b8">
            <para>Select to allow the ABC Class setting for the Item Site to
            be updated whenever the ABC Class update utility is run.</para>

            <para id="Para612247">Not selecting indicates the ABC Class for
            the Item Site should not be updated whenever the ABC Class update
            utility is run.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para518746">Cycl. Cnt. Freq.</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1857100">
            <para>Cnt. Freq.: Select a number using the arrow buttons, or
            manually enter a value up to a maximum of 999.</para>

            <para id="Para593785">A Cycle Count is a periodic issue of a Count
            Tag to count Inventory quantity within an Item Site. The Cycle
            Count frequency defines the length of that period, measured in
            days.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <tip>
        <para id="Para595910">To monitor the frequency of Item Site Cycle
        Counts, view the "Last Counted" column in any of the Item Site
        Reports: by Item, by Class Code, etc. The Last Counted date represents
        the date a Count Tag was last posted (not simply issued) for the Item
        Site.</para>
      </tip>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para518748">Lead Time</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1857190">
            <para>Select a number using the arrow buttons, or manually enter a
            value up to a maximum of 999.</para>

            <para id="Para623768">Specifies the Lead Time for the specified
            Item, measured in days. If the Item is a manufactured Item, then
            the Lead Time refers to the production Lead Time. If the Item is a
            purchased Item, then the Lead Time refers to the planning Lead
            Time. The procurement Lead Time for purchased Items is determined
            on a Vendor-by-Vendor basis, using Item Source masters. Material
            Requirements Planning (MRP) will consider Lead Times when
            calculating Planned Order start dates when MRP is run.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para518750"><anchor id="Anchor557799" role="Index"
          xreflabel="event fences:in item sites;item sites:event fences in" />
          <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor557799">
              <primary>event fences</primary>

              <secondary>in item sites</secondary>
            </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor557799">
              <primary>item sites</primary>

              <secondary>event fences in</secondary>
            </indexterm>Event Fence</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1857268">
            <para>Select a number using the arrow buttons, or manually enter a
            value up to a maximum of 99.</para>

            <para id="Para518751">Specify the period of time, measured in
            days, within which relevant Event notifications should be issued.
            If an Event affecting the Item Site occurs within the Event Fence,
            then the system will issue a notification. Consider the case of a
            manufactured Item whose Event Fence is set to five (5) days.
            Assume that a Work Order exists for this Item and that the
            scheduled start date for that Work Order is three (3) days from
            the current date. If someone were to change the quantity of that
            Work Order, the Event "WoQtyChanged" would be triggered. And
            because the Work Order start date falls within the Event Fence for
            the Item Site, an Event notification would be issued.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para518752">Planner Code</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18572b0">
            <para>Specify the Planner Code you want to assign the Item Site
            to.</para>

            <para id="Para670404">Assigning a Planner Code to an Item Site
            makes it possible to group Item Sites by Planner Code for the
            purposes of Planning.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para561209">Supplied at this Warehouse</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18572f8">
            <para>Select if Item is supplied at specified Warehouse.</para>

            <para id="Para518755">If selected, "Supplied at" means that
            Purchase Orders may be issued for this Item in this Warehouse if
            the Item is a purchased Item, and Work Orders may be issued for
            this Item in this Warehouse if the Item is a manufactured Item.
            These rules apply also to Planned Orders generated when Material
            Requirements Planning (MRP) is run. Planned Orders may only be
            released to "Supplied at" Item Sites.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para614739">Create P/Rs to Meet Demands</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1857340">
            <para>Select to create Purchase Requests whenever Sales Orders or
            Work Orders demand quantities from the Item Site.</para>

            <para id="Para614740">This option pertains to purchased and
            outside-process Items. If you select this option, you are
            indicating that you want Purchase Requests to be generated for the
            Item in question whenever quantities are demanded by either Sales
            Orders or Work Orders. For Sales Orders, the "Create Purchase
            Request" flag on the Sales Order Item screen will automatically be
            selected. For Work Orders using a purchased or outside process
            Item, Purchase Requests will be generated automatically.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <note>
        <para id="Para617348">Purchase Requests created, as specified above,
        to meet Sales Order and Work Order demands will be created regardless
        of an Item's Availability--and also regardless of whether Material
        Requirements Planning (MRP) is being run in parallel.</para>
      </note>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para634824">Create W/Os to Meet Demand</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18573d0">
            <para>Select to create Work Orders whenever Sales Orders demand
            quantities from the Item Site.</para>

            <para id="Para634825">This option pertains to manufactured Items.
            If you select this option, you are indicating that you want Work
            Orders to be generated for the Item in question whenever
            quantities are demanded by a Sales Order. Selecting this option
            will cause the "Create Work Order" flag to be checked whenever you
            enter Sales Order Line Items for the Item Site.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <note>
        <para id="Para634827">Work Orders created, as specified above, to meet
        Sales Order demand will be created regardless of an Item's
        Availability--and also regardless of whether Material Requirements
        Planning (MRP) is being run in parallel.</para>
      </note>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para634812">Sold from this Warehouse</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1857460">
            <para>Select if Item is sold from specified Warehouse.</para>

            <para id="Para518759">If selected, "Sold from" means that Sales
            Orders Line Items may request to Ship from the Warehouse. When
            adding Sales Order Line Items to a Sales Order, a "Sold from"
            Warehouse appears as the "Supplying Warehouse."</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para518760"><anchor id="Anchor560251" role="Index"
          xreflabel="ranking:of item sites;sold ranking:for item sites;item sites:sold ranking of" />
          <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor560251">
              <primary>ranking</primary>

              <secondary>of item sites</secondary>
            </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor560251">
              <primary>sold ranking</primary>

              <secondary>for item sites</secondary>
            </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor560251">
              <primary>item sites</primary>

              <secondary>sold ranking of</secondary>
            </indexterm>Ranking</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1857580">
            <para>Select a number using the arrow buttons, or manually enter a
            value up to a maximum of 10.</para>

            <para id="Para518761">Value entered specifies the order in which
            Item Sites will be chosen during Sales Order and Sales Quote
            creation. If an Item is located in more than one "Sold from"
            Warehouse, the Item Site with the highest ranking will be chosen
            first. If two Item Sites happen to share the same ranking,
            selection will be based on alphabetical order. The highest ranking
            an Item Site can have is one (1).</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para617275">Stocked</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18575c8">
            <para>Select if Item is stocked at specified Warehouse.</para>

            <para id="Para617276">This option pertains to manufactured Items.
            If you select this option, you are indicating that the Item is a
            make-to-stock Item. If not selected, the Item will be identified
            as a make-to-order Item.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para617278"><anchor id="Anchor617277" role="Index"
          xreflabel="control methods:at item site level;item sites:control methods in" />
          <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor617277">
              <primary>control methods</primary>

              <secondary>at item site level</secondary>
            </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor617277">
              <primary>item sites</primary>

              <secondary>control methods in</secondary>
            </indexterm>Control Method</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1867e90">
            <para>Specify the Item Site control method by selecting one of the
            available options:</para>

            <para id="Para518765">None: Select if you don"t care to see
            Inventory history transactions for the Item Site.</para>

            <para id="Para518766">Regular: Select to monitor Inventory history
            transactions for the Item Site using a Regular method. Regular
            means without Lot Number or Serial Number control.</para>

            <para id="Para518767" role="openmfg">Lot #: Select to impose Lot
            Number control methods on the Item Site. Item Sites using Lot
            Number control are subject to unique processing requirements
            whenever Inventory is received or distributed. For additional
            information on some of the unique methods required to handle
            Lot-controlled Items, see the <link endterm="Anchor58321"
            id="XRef591397" linkend="Anchor58321"> Receiving Lot/Serial Items
            into Inventory</link>"Topic: Receiving Lot/Serial Items into
            Inventory"section.</para>

            <para id="Para518768" role="openmfg">Serial #: Select to impose
            Serial Number control methods on the Item Site. Item Sites using
            Serial Number control are subject to unique processing
            requirements whenever Inventory is received or distributed. For
            additional information on some of the unique methods required to
            handle Serial-controlled Items, see the <link
            endterm="Anchor58321" id="XRef638219" linkend="Anchor58321">
            Receiving Lot/Serial Items into Inventory</link> section.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry role="openmfg">
          <term id="Para518769">Perishable</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1867eb4">
            <para>Select if the Item is perishable.</para>

            <para id="Para593600">For Item Sites whose control method is
            either Lot Number or Serial Number, you have the option of also
            designating the Item Site as Perishable. Materials received into a
            Perishable Item Site are required to specify an expiration date,
            thereby increasing your ability to monitor the status of the
            goods.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para593602"><anchor id="Anchor593601" role="Index"
          xreflabel="multiple location control:establishing in item sites" />
          <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor593601">
              <primary>multiple location control</primary>

              <secondary>establishing in item sites</secondary>
            </indexterm>Multiple Location Control</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1867f44">
            <para>Select if the specified Item is to be stored in multiple
            Locations within a single Warehouse.</para>

            <para id="Para567406">Items designated as Multiple Location
            Control (MLC) Items require special processing whenever Item
            quantities are distributed. For more information on distributing
            MLC Item quantities, see the <link endterm="Anchor81167"
            id="XRef593620" linkend="Anchor81167"> Distributing Multiple
            Location Control (MLC) Items</link>"Inter-Warehouse Transfer"
            section.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <tip>
        <para id="Para627349">Exercise caution when adjusting the Multiple
        Location Control (MLC) setting for an Item Site. If you turn off MLC
        for an Item Site which was previously MLC, you will lose detailed
        Inventory records for that Item Site. All quantity will be merged into
        one Quantity on Hand value for the Item Site.</para>
      </tip>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para518771"><anchor id="Anchor557801" role="Index"
          xreflabel="default locations;locations:default;item sites:setting default locations in" />
          <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor557801">
              <primary>default locations</primary>
            </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor557801">
              <primary>locations</primary>

              <secondary>default</secondary>
            </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor557801">
              <primary>item sites</primary>

              <secondary>setting default locations in</secondary>
            </indexterm>Use Default Location</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1868088">
            <para>Default Location: Select to designate one Location within a
            Warehouse as the default Location for the specified Item.</para>

            <para id="Para593625">This option may be used for single Location
            and Multiple Location Control (MLC) Items alike. You may find that
            Inventory distributions for MLC Items are greatly simplified if
            you designate a default Location.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para518772">Location</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18680d0">
            <para>Specify the Warehouse Location to be used as the default
            Location.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para518777">User-Defined</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1868118">
            <para>This is a free-form field for describing storage areas with
            a Warehouse not specifically designated as Warehouse
            Locations.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para518781">Location Comment</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1868160">
            <para>Enter any free-form Comment related to the Warehouse
            Location. This is additional information which may be placed on a
            Pick List or a Pack List.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry role="openmfg">
          <term id="Para627400">Disallow Blank WIP Locations</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1868184">
            <para>Select to require the use of work-in-process (WIP) Locations
            when posting Work Order Operations for Multiple Location Control
            (MLC) finished goods.</para>

            <para id="Para627690">WIP Locations are an optional feature which
            may be defined on the Bill of Operations (BOO) for manufactured
            MLC Items. The feature enables you to track finished goods
            Inventory as it moves through the manufacturing process. If your
            site does not combine Multiple Location Control with Operations
            posting, then this option should be left unchecked.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para543842"><anchor id="Anchor557808" role="Index"
          xreflabel="item sites:cost categories in" /> <indexterm
              significance="normal" zone="Anchor557808">
              <primary>item sites</primary>

              <secondary>cost categories in</secondary>
            </indexterm>Cost Category</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1868214">
            <para>Specify the Cost Category you want to associate with the
            Item Site.</para>

            <para id="Para518782">Item Sites must be assigned a Cost Category.
            This requirement helps ensure that all Inventory transactions
            involving an Item Site will be properly tracked and recorded in
            the General Ledger.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para518786">Notes</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x186825c">
            <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for
            entering free-form Notes related to the Item Site. Notes differ
            from Comments in that Comments are time/date and user
            stamped.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para518788">To the far right of the screen, the following
      buttons are available:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para518789">CANCEL</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18682c8">
            <para>Closes the screen without creating an Item Site, returning
            you to the application desktop.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para627111">SAVE</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1868310">
            <para>Creates the Item Site and adds it to the master list of Item
            Sites.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para627113">To associate Comments with an Item Site, select
      the "Comments" tab. The following screen will appear:</para>

      <para id="Para593860"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/IM_IS_itemSiteComm.png"
                         id="Graphic593858" />
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption593861">Add Item Site Comments</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para594046">Comments</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18683e8">
            <para>Display lists the date Comment entered, Comment Type, user
            who entered Comment, and a content preview.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para594048">To the far right of the screen, the following
      buttons are available:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para594049">NEW</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1868454">
            <para>Opens screen for creating a new Comment.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para594050">VIEW</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x186849c">
            <para>Highlight a Comment and then select this button to reach a
            read-only view of the Comment.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para612992">To create a new Comment, select the NEW button.
      The following screen will appear:</para>

      <para id="Para612996"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/CommentNew.png" id="Graphic612994" />
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption612997">Create New Comment</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para612998">Comment Type</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1868574">
            <para>Specify one of the following Comment Types from the
            drop-down list: ChangeLog or General.</para>

            <para id="Para612999">Comment Types are used to categorize
            Comments. Once you have specified a Comment Type, you may type
            your Comment in the main text area. The text area features
            word-wrapping and scroll-bar support for longer Comments.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para613000">To the far right of the screen, the following
      buttons are available:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para613001">CANCEL</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18685e0">
            <para>Closes the screen without creating the Comment, returning
            you to the previous screen.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para613002">SAVE</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1868628">
            <para>Creates the Comment and adds it to the list of
            Comments.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para627441"><anchor id="Anchor627653" role="Index"
      xreflabel="warehouse locations:restricted;item sites:restricted locations and" />
      <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor627653">
          <primary>warehouse locations</primary>

          <secondary>restricted</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor627653">
          <primary>item sites</primary>

          <secondary>restricted locations and</secondary>
        </indexterm>Warehouse Locations may be restricted to allow for storage
      of certain Items. To view restricted Locations within an Item Site's
      Warehouse, select the "Restricted Locations" tab. The following screen
      will appear:</para>

      <para id="Para627512"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/IM_IS_itemSiteRestr.png"
                         id="Graphic627510" />
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption627513">Restricted Locations for Item Site
            Warehouse</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <para id="Para627445">The Restricted Locations list will show restricted
      Locations associated with the Warehouse the Item Site is located
      in.</para>

      <para id="Para627571">To the far right of the screen, the following
      buttons are available:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para627572">TOGGLE</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1868790">
            <para>Highlight a Warehouse Location and then select this button
            to change the allowed status for the Item.</para>

            <para id="Para627662">Any changes made on the Item Site master
            related to an Item's allowed status will also be saved to the
            Warehouse Location master record.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
    </section>

    <xi:include href="../topics/orderparams_and_mrp.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <section id="Section665983">
      <title><anchor id="Anchor600534" role="Index"
      xreflabel="item sites:master list of" /> <indexterm
          significance="normal" zone="Anchor600534">
          <primary>item sites</primary>

          <secondary>master list of</secondary>
        </indexterm>List Item Sites</title>

      <para id="Para518799">To access the master list of Item Sites in your
      system, select the "List Item Sites" option. The "following screen will
      appear:</para>

      <para id="Para518803"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/IM_IS_listItemSites.png"
                         id="Graphic525579" />
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption518804">Item Sites Master List</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <para id="Para518805">At the top of the screen is a "Search for" field.
      To search for an Item Site, begin typing in the search field. As you
      type, the Item Site list will automatically scroll toward the Item
      Number you are typing. You can also search for Item Sites manually by
      scrolling through the list. The following views are also
      available:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry role="openmfg">
          <term id="Para518806">All Warehouses</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18751bc">
            <para>Select to display a list of all Item Sites for all
            Warehouses.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry role="openmfg">
          <term id="Para518808">Selected</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18751e0">
            <para>Specify Warehouse whose Item Sites you want to
            display.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para518810">Show Inactive Item Sites</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1875228">
            <para>Select to display active as well as inactive Item
            Sites.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para518811">To the far right of the screen, the following
      buttons are available:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para518812">CLOSE</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1875294">
            <para>Closes the screen, returning you to the application
            desktop.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para518813">NEW</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18752dc">
            <para>Opens screen for creating a new Item Site, as described in
            the <link endterm="Anchor41372" id="XRef540340"
            linkend="Anchor41372"> Enter Item Site</link>"Enter Item Site"
            section above.</para>

            <para id="Para627150">Mac users may use COMMAND + N to enter a new
            Item Site.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para518815">EDIT</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1875324">
            <para>Enables you to edit highlighted Item Sites. The edit screen
            is the same as that for creating a new Item Site--except that when
            editing, the fields will contain Item Site information.
            Double-clicking on an Item Site will also bring you to the editing
            screen.</para>

            <para id="Para627159">Mac users may use COMMAND + E to edit an
            existing Item Site.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para518816">VIEW</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x187536c">
            <para>Highlight an Item Site and then select this button to reach
            a read-only view of the "Edit" screen.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para619515">DELETE</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18753b4">
            <para>Highlight an Item Site and then select this button to remove
            the Item Site from the list.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para524236">Right-clicking on an Item Site in the Item Sites
      list enables you to select from the following menu options:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para518818">View Item Site</term>

          <xi:include href="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                      xpointer="element(listitemN0x180ac00N0x187536c)" />
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para518819">Edit Item Site</term>

          <xi:include href="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                      xpointer="element(listitemN0x180ac00N0x1875324)" />
        </varlistentry>

        <xi:include href="widgets/xtreewidget.xml"
                    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                    xpointer="element(xtreewidget.menu.exportcontents)" />
      </variablelist>
    </section>

    <section id="Section678017">
      <title><anchor id="Anchor678016" role="Index"
      xreflabel="availability:by item;availability:workbench for;workbenches:for item availability;items:availability workbench for" />
      <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor678016">
          <primary>availability</primary>

          <secondary>by item</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor678016">
          <primary>availability</primary>

          <secondary>workbench for</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor678016">
          <primary>workbenches</primary>

          <secondary>for item availability</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor678016">
          <primary>items</primary>

          <secondary>availability workbench for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Item Availability Workbench</title>

      <para id="Para678018">The Item Availability Workbench is designed to
      consolidate on one screen the functions performed by personnel who
      manage and track Inventory. To access the Item Availability Workbench,
      select the "Item Availability Workbench" option. The following screen
      will appear:</para>

      <para id="Para678022"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/IM_Disp_availWorkbench1.png"
                         id="Graphic678020" />
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption678023">Running Availability on
            Workbench</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <para id="Para678027" role="openmfg">When displaying Running
      Availability, you are presented with the following options:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678028">Item Number</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18756cc">
            <para>Enter the Item Number of the Item whose Running Availability
            you want to display.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678029">UOM</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1875714">
            <para>Inventory Unit of Measure.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <note>
        <para id="Para678031">When quantity appears in the "Ordered" column,
        this refers to quantity that is on order through either a Work Order
        or Purchase Order. In the case of Purchase Orders, the quantity will
        always be represented in the Inventory Unit of Measure
        (UOM)--regardless of the Vendor UOM used on the Purchase Order.</para>
      </note>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678032">Warehouse</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18757a4">
            <para>Specify Warehouse whose Running Availability you want to
            display.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678033">Show Planned Orders</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18757ec">
            <para>Select to show Planned Orders in the display.</para>

            <para id="Para678034">Planned Orders will display in blue
            type.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678035">QOH</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x187c424">
            <para>Displays Quantity on Hand for specified Item.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678036">Order Multiple</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x187c46c">
            <para>Displays Order Multiple specifying the increments the Item
            must be ordered in. Order Multiple is maintained in the Item Site
            master.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678037">Reorder Level</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x187c4b4">
            <para>Displays the Reorder Level specifying the minimum Quantity
            on Hand allowed before an Item must be reordered. Reorder Level is
            maintained in the Item Site master.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678038">Order Up To Qty</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x187c4fc">
            <para>Indicates the quantity level that MRP Planned Replenishment
            Orders will order up to.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678039">Running Availability</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x187c544">
            <para>Display lists Running Availability for the selected Item,
            using the specified parameters.</para>

            <para id="Para678040">Red lettering indicates the due date has
            passed or Running Availability has dropped below 0.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para678041">To the far right of the screen, the following
      buttons are available:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678042">CLOSE</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x187c5b0">
            <para>Closes the screen, returning you to the application
            desktop.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678043">PRINT</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x187c5f8">
            <para>Runs the report associated with this screen.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para678044">Right-clicking on a Work Order in the Running
      Availability display enables you to select from the following
      options:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678045">View Work Order Details</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x187c664">
            <para></para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <xi:include href="widgets/xtreewidget.xml"
                    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                    xpointer="element(xtreewidget.menu.exportcontents)" />
      </variablelist>

      <para>If you right-click on a Planned Order, the following additional
      options will also be available:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678048">Firm Order</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x187c73c">
            <para></para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678049">Release Order</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x187c784">
            <para></para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678050">Delete Order</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x187c7cc">
            <para></para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para678051">To view Inventory Availability for the specified
      Item, select the "Inventory" tab. The following screen will
      appear:</para>

      <para id="Para678055"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/IM_Disp_availWorkbench2.png"
                         id="Graphic678053" />
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption678056">Inventory Availability on
            Workbench</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <para id="Para678057">When displaying Inventory Availability by Item,
      you are presented with the following options:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678058">Item Number</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x187c8a4">
            <para>Enter the Item Number of the Item whose Inventory
            Availability you want to display.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678059">UOM</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x187c8ec">
            <para>Inventory Unit of Measure.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678060">Show Availability as of</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x187c934">
            <para>Show Availability using one of the following
            criteria:</para>

            <para id="Para678061">Item Site Lead Time: Select to show
            projected Availability based on the Lead Time specified in the
            Item Site master.</para>

            <para id="Para678062">Look Ahead Days: Select a number using the
            arrow buttons, or manually enter a value up to a maximum of 1000.
            Future Availability for the specified Item will be displayed based
            on the value entered here.</para>

            <para id="Para678063">Cutoff Date: Display will show projected
            Inventory Availability as of date entered up to a maximum of 1000
            days.</para>

            <para id="Para678064">Dates: Display will show projected Inventory
            Availability for the date range entered.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678065">Show Reorder Exceptions</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x187c97c">
            <para>Select to show Reorder Exceptions in display. Reorder
            Exceptions are an indication that an Item Site's projected
            Availability will drop below the Reorder Level for the Item
            Site.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678066">Ignore Reorder at 0</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x187c9c4">
            <para>Select to ignore Reorder Exceptions in cases where both the
            Item Site Reorder Level and Planned Availability are equal to zero
            ("0"). If selected, Item Sites matching these criteria will not be
            displayed.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678067">Show Shortages</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x187ca0c">
            <para>Select to only show Inventory shortages in display. A
            shortage describes Inventory quantity whose Availability is
            negative.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678068">All Warehouses</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x187ca54">
            <para>Select to display Inventory Availability for all
            Warehouses.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678069">Selected</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x187ca9c">
            <para>Specify Warehouse whose Inventory Availability you want to
            display.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678070">Availability</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x187cae4">
            <para>Display lists Inventory Availability by Item, using the
            specified parameters.</para>

            <para id="Para678071">If Planned Availability displays in the
            color orange, this means the actual or projected Quantity on Hand
            is at or below the Reorder Level. If the color is red, the current
            or projected Quantity on Hand is below 0.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <note>
        <para id="Para678073">When quantity appears in the "On Order" column,
        this refers to quantity that is on order through either a Work Order
        or Purchase Order. In the case of Purchase Orders, the quantity will
        always be represented in the Inventory Unit of Measure
        (UOM)--regardless of the Vendor UOM used on the Purchase Order.</para>
      </note>

      <para id="Para678074">To the far right of the screen, the following
      buttons are available:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678075">CLOSE</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x187cb74">
            <para>Closes the screen, returning you to the application
            desktop.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678076">QUERY</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x187cbbc">
            <para>Select to generate the display, using the specified
            parameters.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678077">PRINT</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x187cc04">
            <para>Runs the report associated with this screen.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para678078">Right-clicking on an Item in the Availability list
      enables you to select from the following context-sensitive menu
      options:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678079">View Inventory History</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x187cc70">
            <para></para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678080">View Allocations</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x187ccb8">
            <para></para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678081">View Orders</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x187cd00">
            <para></para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678082">Running Availability</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x187cd48">
            <para></para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678083">Issue Count Tag</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x187cd90">
            <para></para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <xi:include href="supportfiles/rightclick.xml"
                    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                    xpointer="element(/1/7/2/9)" />

        <xi:include href="widgets/xtreewidget.xml"
                    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                    xpointer="element(xtreewidget.menu.exportcontents)" />
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para678086">The following additional options are available for
      purchased Items:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678087">Create P/R</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x187ce8c">
            <para></para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678088">Create P/O</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x187ced4">
            <para></para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para678089">The following additional option is available for
      manufactured Items:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678090">Create W/O</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x187cf40">
            <para></para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para678091">To view a Costed Indented Bill of Materials for
      the specified Item, select the "Costed Indented BOM" tab. The following
      screen will appear:</para>

      <para id="Para678095"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/IM_Disp_availWorkbench3.png"
                         id="Graphic678093" />
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption678096">Costed Indented BOM on
            Workbench</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <tip>
        <para id="Para678098">Costed Indented BOM information will be
        displayed only if the specified Item is a manufactured Item.</para>
      </tip>

      <para id="Para678099">When displaying Costs for an indented Bill of
      Materials, you are presented with the following options:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678100">Item Number</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x187d03c">
            <para>Enter the Item Number of the manufactured Item whose
            associated Costs you would like to view using an indented Bill of
            Materials.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678101">UOM</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x187d084">
            <para>Inventory Unit of Measure.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678102">Use Standard Costs</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x187d0cc">
            <para>Select to display Standard Costs for component Items in the
            specified Item's Bill of Materials.</para>

            <para id="Para678103">Both the Unit Cost and Extended Cost for
            each component Item, expressed in terms of Standard Cost, will
            display--assuming Standard Costs have been defined for each
            component Item.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678104">Use Actual Costs</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x187d114">
            <para>Select to display Actual Costs for component Items in the
            specified Item's Bill of Materials.</para>

            <para id="Para678105">Both the Unit Cost and Extended Cost for
            each component Item, expressed in terms of Actual Cost, will
            display--assuming Actual Costs have been defined for each
            component Item.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <note>
        <para id="Para678107">In the Costed Indented Bill of Materials, the
        totals displayed on the screen are derived as follows:</para>

        <para id="Para678108">Total Cost: This total is pulled from the
        Extended Cost column. The total may vary, depending on whether "Use
        Standard Costs" or "Use Actual Costs" is selected.</para>

        <para id="Para678109">Actual Cost: This value represents the Actual
        Cost for the parent Item whose Costed Indented BOM is being
        displayed.</para>

        <para id="Para678110">Standard Cost: This value represents the
        Standard Cost for the parent Item whose Costed Indented BOM is being
        displayed.</para>
      </note>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678111">Costed Bill of Materials</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x187d1a4">
            <para>Display lists Costed Indented Bill of Materials components,
            using the specified parameters.</para>

            <para id="Para678112">The difference between the indented view and
            the single level view is that the indented view displays all
            subcomponents if there is a manufactured component listed on the
            Bill of Materials. The Total Cost, Actual Cost, and Standard Cost
            will be calculated automatically at the bottom of the
            display.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para678113">To the far right of the display are the following
      buttons and display fields:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678114">CLOSE</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1882a00">
            <para>Closes the screen, returning you to the application
            desktop.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678115">PRINT</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1882a48">
            <para>Runs the report associated with this screen.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para678116">Right-clicking on a component in the Costed Bill
      of Materials list enables you to select from the following menu
      options:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678117">Maintain Item Costs</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1882ab4">
            <para></para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678118">View Item Costing</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1882afc">
            <para></para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <xi:include href="widgets/xtreewidget.xml"
                    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                    xpointer="element(xtreewidget.menu.exportcontents)" />
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para678120">To view Inventory History for the specified Item,
      select the "History" tab. The following screen will appear:</para>

      <para id="Para678124"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/IM_Disp_availWorkbench4.png"
                         id="Graphic678122" />
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption678125">Inventory History on
            Workbench</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <para id="Para678126">When displaying Inventory history by Item, you are
      presented with the following options:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678127">Item Number</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1882c1c">
            <para>Enter the Item Number of the Item whose Inventory history
            you want to display.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678128">UOM</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1882c64">
            <para>Inventory Unit of Measure.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678129">Trans. Types</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1882cac">
            <para>Select one of the available transaction types:</para>

            <para id="Para678130">All Transactions: Displays all Inventory
            transactions.</para>

            <para id="Para678131">Receipts: Displays receipts into Inventory
            from Manufacturing, purchases, or miscellaneous receipts.</para>

            <para id="Para678132">Issues: Displays issues from Inventory to
            Manufacturing.</para>

            <para id="Para678133">Shipments: Displays shipments to
            customers.</para>

            <para id="Para678134">Adjustments and Counts: Displays Inventory
            adjustments and counts.</para>

            <para id="Para678138" role="openmfg">Transfers: Displays
            Inter-Warehouse Transfers and Location and Lot/Serial Number
            reassignments.</para>

            <para id="Para678139">Scraps: Displays Scrap transfer from
            Inventory.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <note>
        <para id="Para678141">The system prefixes Order Numbers with letters
        indicating the Order type. For example, Work Orders are prefixed with
        "WO", Purchase Orders with "PO", and Sales Orders with "SO". These
        letters are for display purposes only and are not considered part of
        the Order Number.</para>
      </note>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678142">All Warehouses</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1882d3c">
            <para>Select to display Inventory history by Item for all
            Warehouses.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678143">Selected</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1882d84">
            <para>Specify Warehouse whose Inventory history by Item you want
            to display.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678144">Start Date</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1882dcc">
            <para>This is a required field.</para>

            <para id="Para678145">Inventory transactions conducted on and
            after this date will be displayed.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678146">End Date</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1882e14">
            <para>This is a required field.</para>

            <para id="Para678147">Inventory transactions conducted on and
            before this date will be displayed.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678148">Inventory History</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1882e5c">
            <para>Display lists Inventory history by Item, using the specified
            parameters.</para>

            <para id="Para678149">This display is a nested list, with a plus
            ("+") sign located to the far left of the display next to each
            transaction that may be expanded to lower levels. By clicking your
            mouse on a plus sign, you reveal lower levels of information
            related to the Order. To the far right of the screen, the
            following buttons are available:</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678150">CLOSE</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1882ea4">
            <para>Closes the screen, returning you to the application
            desktop.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678151">QUERY</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1882eec">
            <para>Select to generate the display, using the specified
            parameters.</para>

            <para id="Para678152">Start date and end date must be entered for
            calculation to proceed. Results will be displayed in the
            "Inventory History" list.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678153">PRINT</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1882f34">
            <para>Runs the report associated with this screen.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para678154">Right-clicking on a transaction in the Inventory
      History list enables you to select from the following menu
      options:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678155">View Transaction Information</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1882fa0">
            <para></para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678156">Edit Transaction Information</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1882fe8">
            <para></para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <xi:include href="widgets/xtreewidget.xml"
                    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                    xpointer="element(xtreewidget.menu.exportcontents)" />
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para678158">When editing transaction information, you may
      choose to exclude a transaction from Inventory analysis. Not including a
      transaction in this manner means the following Inventory analyses will
      ignore the transaction: Item Usage Statistics displays, Update Reorder
      Levels, and Update Order Up To Levels.</para>

      <para id="Para678159">If the Order Number is associated with a Work
      Order, the following additional menu option will also be
      available:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678160">View Work Order Information</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x188309c">
            <para></para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para678164" role="openmfg">To view Lot/Serial and/or Location
      information for the specified Item, select the "Lot/Serial/Location"
      tab. The following screen will appear:</para>

      <para id="Para678168"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/IM_Disp_availWorkbench5.png"
                         id="Graphic678166" />
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption678169">Lot/Serial/Location on
            Workbench</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <para id="Para678170">When displaying detailed Location and Lot/Serial
      Number information, you are presented with the following options:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678171">Item Number</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1883174">
            <para>Enter the Item Number of the Item whose detailed
            Location/Lot/Serial Number information you want to display.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678172">UOM</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18831bc">
            <para>Inventory Unit of Measure.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678173">All Warehouses</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1883204">
            <para>Select to display detailed Location/Lot/Serial Number
            information for all Warehouses.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678174">Selected</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x188324c">
            <para>Specify Warehouse whose detailed Location/Lot/Serial Number
            information you want to display.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678175">Locations</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1883294">
            <para>Display lists Location/Lot/Serial Number detail, using the
            specified parameters.</para>

            <para id="Para678176">Items will display in red type if the
            quantity in question has expired.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para678177">To the far right of the screen, the following
      buttons are available:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678178">CLOSE</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1883300">
            <para>Closes the screen, returning you to the application
            desktop.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678179">QUERY</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1883348">
            <para>Select to generate the display, using the specified
            parameters.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678180">PRINT</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1883390">
            <para>Runs the report associated with this screen.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para678181">To view where the specified Item is used for
      manufacturing, select the "Where Used" tab. The following screen will
      appear:</para>

      <para id="Para678185"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/IM_Disp_availWorkbench6.png"
                         id="Graphic678183" />
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption678186">Single Level Where Used on
            Workbench</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <para id="Para678187">When displaying a single level Bill of Materials,
      you are presented with the following options:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678188">Item Number</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1883468">
            <para>Enter the Item Number of the manufactured Item you would
            like to view a single level Bill of Materials for.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678189">UOM</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18834b0">
            <para>Inventory Unit of Measure.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678190">Show Expired Components</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18834f8">
            <para>Select to cause expired components to be listed in the "Bill
            of Materials" display.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678191">Threshold Days</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1883540">
            <para>Select a number using the arrow buttons, or manually enter a
            value up to a maximum of 999.</para>

            <para id="Para678192">Components that have been expired from the
            Bill of Materials within the specified number of days will be
            included in the display.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678193">Show Future Components</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1883588">
            <para>Select to cause future components to be listed in the "Bill
            of Materials" display.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678194">Threshold Days</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18835d0">
            <para>Select a number using the arrow buttons, or manually enter a
            value up to a maximum of 999.</para>

            <para id="Para678195">Components that will be added in future to
            the Bill of Materials within the specified number of days will be
            included in the display.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678196">Bill of Materials</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1883618">
            <para>Display lists single level Bill of Materials components,
            using the specified parameters.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para678197">To the far right of the screen, the following
      buttons are available:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678198">CLOSE</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1883684">
            <para>Closes the screen, returning you to the application
            desktop.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678199">QUERY</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18836cc">
            <para>Select to generate the display, using the specified
            parameters.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678200">PRINT</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1883714">
            <para>Runs the report associated with this screen.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para678201">Right-clicking on an Item in the Bill of Materials
      Items list enables you to select from the following menu options:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678202">Edit Bill of Materials</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1883780">
            <para></para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678203">Edit Bill of Operations</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18837c8">
            <para></para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678204">Edit Item Master</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x188a200">
            <para></para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678205">View Item Inventory History</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x188a248">
            <para></para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <xi:include href="widgets/xtreewidget.xml"
                    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                    xpointer="element(xtreewidget.menu.exportcontents)" />
      </variablelist>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section id="Section518822">
    <title><anchor id="Anchor552132" role="Index"
    xreflabel="inventory:transactions involving;transactions:See also inventory transactions[transactions:aaa]" />
    <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor552132">
        <primary>inventory</primary>

        <secondary>transactions involving</secondary>
      </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor552132">
        <primary>transactions</primary>

        <secondary>See also inventory transactions[transactions</secondary>
      </indexterm>Inventory Transactions</title>

    <para id="Para518823">Inventory transactions are covered in this
    section.</para>

    <section id="Section518829">
      <title><anchor id="Anchor552134" role="Index"
      xreflabel="miscellaneous adjustments;adjustments:miscellaneous for inventory;inventory:miscellaneous adjustments to" />
      <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor552134">
          <primary>miscellaneous adjustments</primary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor552134">
          <primary>adjustments</primary>

          <secondary>miscellaneous for inventory</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor552134">
          <primary>inventory</primary>

          <secondary>miscellaneous adjustments to</secondary>
        </indexterm>Miscellaneous Adjustment</title>

      <para id="Para596462">To make a Miscellaneous Adjustment to the Quantity
      on Hand value for an Item, select the "Miscellaneous Adjustment" option.
      The following screen will appear:</para>

      <para id="Para518834"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/IM_IT_enterMiscAdjustment.png"
                         id="Graphic525621" />
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption518835">Enter Miscellaneous
            Adjustment</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <note>
        <para id="Para596471">Use the Miscellaneous Adjustment utility to
        handle Inventory adjustments not covered by another transaction
        type--for example, Receipt from Purchasing, Receipt from
        Manufacturing, Scrap, etc. For a complete list of Inventory
        transaction Types, see <link endterm="Anchor80421" id="XRef596472"
        linkend="Anchor80421"> Appendix A</link>Appendix A.</para>
      </note>

      <para id="Para518841">When creating a Miscellaneous Adjustment, you are
      presented with the following options:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para518842">Transaction Date</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x188a518">
            <para>Displays the current day's date.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para518844">Item Number</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x188a560">
            <para>Enter the Item Number of the Item you want to create a
            Miscellaneous Adjustment for.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para671942">UOM</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x188a5a8">
            <para>Inventory Unit of Measure.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para518848">Warehouse</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x188a5f0">
            <para>Specify the Warehouse where the Miscellaneous Adjustment
            should be recorded.</para>

            <para id="Para518849">If an Item is located in more than one
            Warehouse, be sure to specify the correct Warehouse for the
            Miscellaneous Adjustment.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para518853">Adjustment Qty.</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x188a638">
            <para>: The number entered will adjust the Quantity on Hand for
            the specified Item. Field accepts positive and negative numbers.
            To enter a negative number, simply prefix the number with a minus
            symbol.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para518855">Relative</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x188a680">
            <para>Select to make a relative adjustment to the Item's Quantity
            on Hand.</para>

            <para id="Para518856">The "Before" value, which represents current
            Quantity on Hand, will increase or decrease relative to the number
            entered in the "Adjustment Qty." field. The new Quantity on Hand
            value will appear beneath the "After" heading. Non-netable
            Quantity on Hand is not included in these values.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para518857">Absolute</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x188a6c8">
            <para>Select to make an absolute adjustment to the Item's Quantity
            on Hand.</para>

            <para id="Para518858">The "Before" value, which represents current
            Quantity on Hand, will be changed to the new value entered in the
            "Adjustment Qty." field. This absolutely new Quantity on Hand
            value will appear beneath the "After" heading. Non-netable
            Quantity on Hand is not included in these values.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para518862">Document #</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x188a710">
            <para>Creates a user-defined reference for the Miscellaneous
            Adjustment. The Document reference will be posted with the General
            Ledger (G/L) transaction record when the Miscellaneous Adjustment
            is generated. This field may be used for internal tracking and
            auditing purposes.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para518867">Comments</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x188a758">
            <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for
            entering Comments related to the adjustment.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para518869">To the far right of the screen, the following
      buttons are available:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para518870">CANCEL</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x188a7c4">
            <para>Closes the screen without posting an adjusted value,
            returning you to the application desktop.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para518871">POST</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x188a80c">
            <para>Posts the adjusted value to the Quantity on Hand balance.
            Additional steps will be necessary if the specified Item is stored
            in multiple Locations. For more information, see the <link
            endterm="Anchor81167" id="XRef537962" linkend="Anchor81167">
            Distributing Multiple Location Control (MLC)
            Items</link>"Inter-Warehouse Transfer" section.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
    </section>

    <xi:include href="../topics/mlc_distribution.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <section id="Section600879" role="openmfg">
      <title>Inter-Warehouse Transfer</title>

      <para id="Para600880">To transfer quantity of an Item from one Warehouse
      to another, select the "Inter-Warehouse Transfer" option. The following
      screen will appear:</para>

      <para id="Para518932"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/IM_IT_interWarehouseTrans.png"
                         id="Graphic525831" />
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption518933">Enter Inter-Warehouse
            Transfer</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <tip>
        <para id="Para524296">An Inter-Warehouse Transfer can only be executed
        if the specified Item is located in more than one Warehouse. To add an
        additional Warehouse for an Item, go to the Enter Item Sites section
        of the Item Sites menu. Locate the desired Item Number using the Item
        Number lookup feature. Then select a new Warehouse in the "Warehouse"
        field. Enter all other required fields and save your results. The Item
        will now also be located in the additional Warehouse. Repeat as often
        as necessary.</para>
      </tip>

      <para id="Para518940">When creating an Inter-Warehouse Transfer, you are
      presented with the following options:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para518941">Transaction Date</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1897afc">
            <para>Displays the current day's date.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para518943">Item Number</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1897b44">
            <para>Enter the Item Number of the Item you want to transfer from
            one Warehouse to another.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para671952">UOM</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1897b8c">
            <para>Inventory Unit of Measure.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para518947">From Whse</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1897bd4">
            <para>Specify the source Warehouse for the transaction.</para>

            <para id="Para518948">If an Item is located in more than one
            Warehouse, be sure to specify the correct Warehouse you want to
            transfer the Item from. The "Before" column displays current
            Quantity on Hand for the Item.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para518949">To Whse.</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1897c1c">
            <para>: Specify the destination Warehouse for the
            transaction.</para>

            <para id="Para518950">If an Item is located in more than one
            Warehouse, be sure to specify the correct Warehouse you want to
            transfer the Item to. The "Before" column displays current
            Quantity on Hand for the Item</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para518954">Transferred Qty.</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1897c64">
            <para>The number entered will adjust the Item's Quantity on Hand
            in both the "From" and "To" Warehouses.</para>

            <para id="Para670460">The values displayed in the "After" column
            represent the new Quantity on Hand in each Location. Non-netable
            Quantity on Hand is not included in these values.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para518959">Document #</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1897cac">
            <para>Creates a user-defined reference for the Inter-Warehouse
            Transfer.</para>

            <para id="Para670467">The Document reference will be posted with
            the General Ledger (G/L) transaction record when the
            Inter-Warehouse Transfer is generated. This field may be used for
            internal tracking and auditing purposes.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para518964">Comments</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1897cf4">
            <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for
            entering Comments related to the transfer.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para518966">To the far right of the screen, the following
      buttons are available:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para518967">CANCEL</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1897d60">
            <para>Closes the screen without posting an Inter-Warehouse
            Transfer, returning you to the application desktop.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para518968">POST</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1897da8">
            <para>Posts the Inter-Warehouse Transfer.</para>

            <para id="Para518969">Creates two transactions, one at each
            affected Warehouse. The Warehouse receiving Inventory is credited
            with the new Inventory amount, while the Warehouse being relieved
            of Inventory is debited. Additional steps will be necessary if the
            specified Item is stored in multiple Locations. For more
            information, see the <link endterm="Anchor81167" id="XRef538112"
            linkend="Anchor81167"> Distributing Multiple Location Control
            (MLC) Items</link>"Inter-Warehouse Transfer" section.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
    </section>

    <section id="Section518970">
      <title><anchor id="Anchor552140" role="Index"
      xreflabel="scrap:as inventory transaction;inventory transactions:scrapping" />
      <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor552140">
          <primary>scrap</primary>

          <secondary>as inventory transaction</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor552140">
          <primary>inventory transactions</primary>

          <secondary>scrapping</secondary>
        </indexterm>Scrap</title>

      <para id="Para518971">To Scrap Items from Inventory, select the "Scrap"
      option. The following screen will appear:</para>

      <para id="Para518975"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/IM_IT_scrap.png" id="Graphic525842" />
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption518976">Enter Scrap Transaction</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <para id="Para518982">When entering a Scrap transaction, you are
      presented with the following options:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para518983">Transaction Date</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1897f34">
            <para>Displays the current day's date.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para518985">Item Number</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1897f7c">
            <para>Enter the Item Number of the Item you want to enter a Scrap
            transaction for.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para671958">UOM</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1897fc4">
            <para>Inventory Unit of Measure.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para580751">Warehouse</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x189800c">
            <para>Specify Warehouse where the Item Site for the Scrap
            transaction is located.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para580756">Scrap Qty.</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1898054">
            <para>Enter the quantity of Inventory UOM identified as Scrap. The
            number entered will appear as a deduction in the "After" column.
            Non-netable Quantity on Hand is not included in these
            values.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para518999">Document #</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x189809c">
            <para>Creates a user-defined reference for the Scrap transaction.
            The Document reference will be posted with the General Ledger
            (G/L) transaction record when the Scrap transaction is generated.
            This field may be used for internal tracking and auditing
            purposes.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519004">Comments</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18980e4">
            <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for
            entering Comments related to the Scrap transaction.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para519006">To the far right of the screen, the following
      buttons are available:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519007">CANCEL</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1898150">
            <para>Closes the screen without posting an Inventory Scrap
            transaction, returning you to the application desktop.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519008">POST</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1898198">
            <para>Posts the Scrap transaction.</para>

            <para id="Para519009">Generates an Inventory Scrap transaction and
            decrements Quantity on Hand. Additional steps will be necessary if
            the specified Item is stored in multiple Locations. For more
            information, see the <link endterm="Anchor81167" id="XRef538116"
            linkend="Anchor81167"> Distributing Multiple Location Control
            (MLC) Items</link>"Inter-Warehouse Transfer" section.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
    </section>

    <section id="Section611608">
      <title><anchor id="Anchor611612" role="Index"
      xreflabel="expenses:as inventory transaction;inventory transactions:expense" />
      <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor611612">
          <primary>expenses</primary>

          <secondary>as inventory transaction</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor611612">
          <primary>inventory transactions</primary>

          <secondary>expense</secondary>
        </indexterm>Expense</title>

      <para id="Para612394">Expense transactions are a form of miscellaneous
      Inventory transaction. Expense transactions can be used to remove Items
      from Inventory, while assigning the transactions to preset Expense
      Categories (e.g., Trade Show Expense). To remove Items from Inventory
      and assign the transaction to an Expense Category, select the "Expense"
      option. The following screen will appear:</para>

      <para id="Para612398"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/IM_IT_enterExpTrans.png"
                         id="Graphic612396" />
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption612399">Enter Expense Transaction</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <para id="Para612400">When entering an Expense transaction, you are
      presented with the following options:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para612401">Transaction Date</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1898324">
            <para>Displays the current day's date.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para612402">Item Number</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x189836c">
            <para>Enter the Item Number of the Item you want to enter an
            Expense transaction for.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para671963">UOM</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18983b4">
            <para>Inventory Unit of Measure.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para612405">Warehouse</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18983fc">
            <para>Specify Warehouse where the Item Site for the Expense
            transaction is located.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para612409">Scrap Qty.</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1898444">
            <para>Enter the quantity of Inventory UOM you want to enter an
            Expense transaction for. The number entered will appear as a
            deduction in the "After" column. Non-netable Quantity on Hand is
            not included in these values.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para612414">Document #</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x189848c">
            <para>Creates a user-defined reference for the Expense
            transaction. The Document reference will be posted with the
            General Ledger (G/L) transaction record when the Expense
            transaction is generated. This field may be used for internal
            tracking and auditing purposes.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para612474">Expense Category</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18984d4">
            <para>Specify the Expense Category you want to assign the Expense
            transaction to.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para612419">Notes</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x189851c">
            <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for
            entering Comments related to the Expense transaction.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para612421">To the far right of the screen, the following
      buttons are available:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para612422">CANCEL</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1898588">
            <para>Closes the screen without posting an Expense transaction,
            returning you to the application desktop.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para612423">POST</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18985d0">
            <para>Posts the Expense transaction.</para>

            <para id="Para612424">Issues an Expense transaction and decrements
            Quantity on Hand. Additional steps will be necessary if the
            specified Item is stored in multiple Locations. For more
            information, see the <link endterm="Anchor81167" id="XRef638235"
            linkend="Anchor81167"> Distributing Multiple Location Control
            (MLC) Items</link>"Inter-Warehouse Transfer" section.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
    </section>

    <section id="Section519010">
      <title><anchor id="Anchor552142" role="Index"
      xreflabel="material receipts:as inventory transaction;inventory transactions:receiving materials;receiving:as inventory transaction" />
      <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor552142">
          <primary>material receipts</primary>

          <secondary>as inventory transaction</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor552142">
          <primary>inventory transactions</primary>

          <secondary>receiving materials</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor552142">
          <primary>receiving</primary>

          <secondary>as inventory transaction</secondary>
        </indexterm> <anchor id="Anchor66681" role="Cross-Ref"
      xreflabel="66681: Heading2: Material Receipt" />Material Receipt</title>

      <para id="Para519011">To record the receipt of materials into Inventory,
      select the "Material Receipt" option. The following screen will
      appear:</para>

      <para id="Para519015"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/IM_IT_materialReceipt.png"
                         id="Graphic525872" />
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption519016">Enter Material Receipt</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <note>
        <para id="Para638248">If an Item is Lot/Serial Number controlled, you
        will be given the opportunity to assign a Lot/Serial Number to
        incoming material during the receiving process. For more information
        on receiving Lot-controlled Items, see the <link endterm="Anchor81167"
        id="XRef638250" linkend="Anchor81167"> Distributing Multiple Location
        Control (MLC) Items</link>"Inter-Warehouse Transfer" section.</para>
      </note>

      <para id="Para638252">When entering a Material Receipt, you are
      presented with the following options:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519023">Transaction Date</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18987c8">
            <para>Displays the current day's date.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519025">Item Number</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18a0600">
            <para>Enter the Item Number of the material you are receiving into
            Inventory.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para671968">UOM</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18a0648">
            <para>Inventory Unit of Measure.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519029">Warehouse</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18a0690">
            <para>Specify Warehouse where material is being received.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519034">Receipt Qty.</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18a06d8">
            <para>: Record the quantity of the Item being received. The Item's
            Quantity on Hand before and after the material receipt will also
            be displayed. Non-netable Quantity on Hand is not included in
            these values. If the material is issued directly to a Work Order,
            the before and after display will be bypassed.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519036">Immediate Issue to Work Order</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18a0720">
            <para>Check to issue material immediately to a Work Order.</para>

            <para id="Para596550">Any Work Order Material Requirements having
            an issue method of either "Mixed" or "Push" may be issued to a
            Work Order using this option. Because "Pull" Items are issued to
            Work Orders using a material backflush, they may not be issued
            from this screen.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <note>
        <para id="Para596604">The full quantity being received will be issued
        to the Work Order if the "Immediate Issue" option is selected. This
        means the quantity issued may exceed or fall short of the Work Order
        Material Requirement quantity. In such cases, adjustments at the Work
        Order level may have to be made to bring the issued quantity into
        alignment with the required quantity. To avoid having to manage
        discrepancies, do not select this option. Instead, consider issuing
        materials manually.</para>
      </note>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519041">Work Order #</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18a07b0">
            <para>Enter the Work Order Number of the Work Order you want to
            issue the received materials to.</para>

            <para id="Para596496">The browse button located to the right of
            the field leads to a searchable Work Orders list. The list will
            include Work Orders whose supplying Warehouse matches the
            Warehouse the materials are being received into.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para596497">Whs.</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18a07f8">
            <para>Specifies supplying Warehouse for the Work Order's parent
            Item.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para596498">Item Number</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18a0840">
            <para>Displays Item Number for the Work Order's parent
            Item.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para671973">UOM</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18a0888">
            <para>Inventory Unit of Measure.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para596501">Status</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18a08d0">
            <para>Displays the Status of the selected Work Order.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519054">Document #</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18a0918">
            <para>Creates a user-defined reference for the Material Receipt.
            The Document reference will be posted with the General Ledger
            (G/L) transaction record when the Material Receipt is generated.
            This field may be used for internal tracking and auditing
            purposes.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519059">Comments</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18a0960">
            <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for
            entering Comments related to the Material Receipt.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para519061">To the far right of the screen, the following
      buttons are available:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519062">CANCEL</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18a09cc">
            <para>Closes the screen without posting and crediting the Material
            Receipt, returning you to the application desktop.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519063">POST</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18a0a14">
            <para>Posts and credits the Material Receipt.</para>

            <para id="Para519064">Additional steps will be necessary if the
            specified Item is stored in multiple Locations. For more
            information, see the <link endterm="Anchor81167" id="XRef638258"
            linkend="Anchor81167"> Distributing Multiple Location Control
            (MLC) Items</link>"Inter-Warehouse Transfer" section.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
    </section>

    <xi:include href="../topics/receiving_lotserial.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <section id="Section666113" role="openmfg">
      <title>Transform</title>

      <para id="Para635325">Transformation is the process of converting
      quantity of one Item into quantity of another Item. The Transform
      utility can be applied in multiple scenarios. For example, let's say you
      manufacture an Item--but when supplies run low, you purchase
      replenishment quantity from a Vendor. You would receive the
      replenishment quantity using an Item Number having the "purchased" Item
      Type. This purchased quantity would then be transformed into quantity of
      your manufactured Item.</para>

      <note>
        <para id="Para623563">You may only transform an Item if the source
        Item is located in the same Warehouse as the target Item.</para>
      </note>

      <para id="Para623537">To transform Inventory quantity, select the
      "Transform" option. The following screen will appear:</para>

      <para id="Para615702"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/IM_IT_transform.png"
                         id="Graphic615700" />
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption615703">Transform Utility</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <para id="Para615735">When transforming Inventory quantity, you are
      presented with the following options:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para615791">Item Number</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18ab8a4">
            <para>Enter the Item Number of the source Item whose quantity you
            want to transform.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para671979">UOM</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18ab8ec">
            <para>Inventory Unit of Measure.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para615761">Warehouse</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18ab934">
            <para>Specify Warehouse where desired source Item quantity is
            located.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para615537">Source</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18ab97c">
            <para>Displays available Warehouse Locations.</para>

            <para id="Para615823">Highlight the Location containing quantity
            you want to transform. If the Item is multiply-located in the
            specified Warehouse, all Locations having valid quantity will
            display.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para616593">Target Item Number</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18ab9c4">
            <para>Specify which Item you want to transform the source Item
            quantity to.</para>

            <para id="Para616594">Target Item Numbers are defined using the
            "Transformations" tab on the Item master for the source Item. If
            no target Item is defined on the Item master, no transformations
            may occur.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para616523">Qty. to Transform</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18aba0c">
            <para>Specify the source Item quantity you want to transform into
            target Item quantity.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para616586">To the far right of the screen, the following
      buttons are available:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para616587">CLOSE</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18aba78">
            <para>Closes the screen without transforming Inventory quantity,
            returning you to the application desktop.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para616588">POST</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18abac0">
            <para>Posts the Inventory transformation.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
    </section>

    <section id="Section658623" role="openmfg">
      <title>List Transfer Orders</title>

      <para id="Para658785">Transfer Orders are used to move Inventory between
      Warehouses. They are distinct from Inter-Warehouse Transfers in three
      primary ways: 1) you can add multiple Items to a single Transfer Order
      and transfer all the Items at once; 2) all Transfer Order transfers
      involve a Transit Warehouse, for tracking Inventory while it is "in
      transit"; and 3) there are reports (i.e., paperwork) associated with
      Transfer Orders. To access the master list of Transfer Orders, select
      the "List Transfer Orders" option. The following screen will
      appear:</para>

      <para id="Para658653"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/IM_IT_listTransOrders.png"
                         id="Graphic658651" />
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption658654">Transfer Orders Master List</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <para id="Para658755">When displaying the master list of Transfer
      Orders, you are presented with the following options:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para658636">Source Warehouse</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18abbbc">
            <para>Specify the source Warehouse(s) you want to display in the
            list:</para>

            <para id="Para658820">All Warehouses: Select to display Transfer
            Orders for all source Warehouses.</para>

            <para id="Para658824">Selected: Specify source Warehouse whose
            Transfer Orders you want to display.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para658804">Destination Warehouse</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18abc04">
            <para>Specify the destination Warehouse(s) you want to display in
            the list:</para>

            <para id="Para658858">All Warehouses: Select to display Transfer
            Orders for all destination Warehouses.</para>

            <para id="Para658859">Selected: Specify destination Warehouse
            whose Transfer Orders you want to display.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para658805">Transfer Orders</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18abc4c">
            <para>Display lists Transfer Orders for the specified
            Warehouse(s).</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para659119">To the far right of the screen, the following
      buttons are available:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para659120">CLOSE</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18abcb8">
            <para>Closes the screen, returning you to the application
            desktop.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para659121">PRINT</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18abd00">
            <para>Runs the report associated with this screen.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para659122">NEW</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18abd48">
            <para>Opens screen for creating a new Transfer Order.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para659123">EDIT</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18abd90">
            <para>Enables you to edit highlighted Transfer Order. The edit
            screen is the same as that for creating a new Transfer
            Order--except that when editing, the fields will contain Transfer
            Order information. Double-clicking on a Transfer Order will also
            bring you to the editing screen.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para659152">VIEW</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18abdd8">
            <para>Highlight a Transfer Order and then select this button to
            view the Transfer Order.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para659124">DELETE</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18abe20">
            <para>Highlight a Transfer Order and then select this button to
            remove the Transfer Order from the list.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para659125">ISSUE STOCK</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18abe68">
            <para>Highlight a Transfer Order and then select this button to
            issue Transfer Order Stock to Shipping.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para659127">COPY</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18abeb0">
            <para>Highlight a Transfer Order and then select this button to
            create a copy of the highlighted Transfer Order.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para659129">Right-clicking on a Transfer Order in the Transfer
      Orders list enables you to select from the following menu
      options:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para659133">Edit</term>

          <xi:include href="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                      xpointer="element(listitemN0x180ac00N0x18abd90)" />
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para659190">View</term>

          <xi:include href="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                      xpointer="element(listitemN0x180ac00N0x18abdd8)" />
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para659199">Delete</term>

          <xi:include href="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                      xpointer="element(listitemN0x180ac00N0x18abe20)" />
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para659205">Issue To Shipping</term>

          <xi:include href="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                      xpointer="element(listitemN0x180ac00N0x18abe68)" />
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para659209">Copy</term>

          <xi:include href="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                      xpointer="element(listitemN0x180ac00N0x18abeb0)" />
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para659213">Print Packing List</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18ac084">
            <para></para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para659217">Add to Packing List Batch</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18ac0cc">
            <para></para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <xi:include href="widgets/xtreewidget.xml"
                    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                    xpointer="element(xtreewidget.menu.exportcontents)" />
      </variablelist>
    </section>

    <section id="Section658633" role="openmfg">
      <title>New Transfer Order</title>

      <para id="Para659677">Transfer Orders are used to move Inventory between
      Warehouses. They are distinct from Inter-Warehouse Transfers in three
      primary ways: 1) you can add multiple Items to a single Transfer Order
      and transfer all the Items at once; 2) all Transfer Order transfers
      involve a Transit Warehouse, for tracking Inventory while it is "in
      transit"; and 3) there are reports (i.e., paperwork) associated with
      Transfer Orders. To enter a new Transfer Order, select the "New Transfer
      Order" option. The following screen will appear:</para>

      <para id="Para659335"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/IM_IT_transferOrdNew.png"
                         id="Graphic659333" />
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption659336">Create New Transfer Order</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <para id="Para659751">When creating a new Transfer Order, you are
      presented with the following options:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para659752">Order #</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b4800">
            <para>Next available Transfer Order Number will automatically
            display, unless your system requires you to enter Transfer Order
            Numbers manually.</para>

            <para id="Para660357">Default values and input parameters for
            Transfer Order Numbers are configurable at the system
            level.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para660779">Order Status</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b4848">
            <para>Displays the current status of the Transfer Order.</para>

            <para id="Para660780">Transfer Orders may be either Open = "O" or
            Closed = "C" depending on the status of the associated Line
            Items.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para660781">Order Date</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b4890">
            <para>Displays current day's date.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para660782">Scheduled Date</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b48d8">
            <para>Displays the Order's earliest scheduled date.</para>

            <para id="Para659764">The scheduled date corresponds to the
            earliest scheduled date for an included Transfer Order Item.
            Because Transfer Orders may contain multiple Transfer Order Items,
            the scheduled date indicates the most recent scheduled date. No
            scheduled date will display in the "Scheduled Date" field until a
            Transfer Order Line Item has been created and a scheduled date
            assigned to it.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para659766"><anchor id="Anchor659765" role="Index"
          xreflabel="pack dates:for transfer orders;transfer orders:pack dates for" />
          <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor659765">
              <primary>pack dates</primary>

              <secondary>for transfer orders</secondary>
            </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor659765">
              <primary>transfer orders</primary>

              <secondary>pack dates for</secondary>
            </indexterm>Pack Date</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b49b0">
            <para>The pack date is the same date as the ship date.</para>

            <para id="Para670504">Because the field can be edited, you have
            the ability to change the pack date and make it different from the
            ship date.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para660299">Agent</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b49f8">
            <para>Specify the Agent associated with the Transfer Order.</para>

            <para id="Para660436">By default, the name of the logged-in user
            will be entered as Purchasing Agent-assuming that user is
            designated as a Purchasing Agent. If the user is not a Purchasing
            Agent, the first alphabetical name in the list of Purchasing
            Agents will be entered.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para660300">Project #</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b4a40">
            <para>Select a Project Number to associate with the Transfer
            Order.</para>

            <para id="Para660301">Projects may be used to link Transfer Orders
            with Work Orders, Sales Orders, Purchase Orders, etc.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para660305"><anchor id="Anchor660304" role="Index"
          xreflabel="tax authorities:for transfer orders" /> <indexterm
              significance="normal" zone="Anchor660304">
              <primary>tax authorities</primary>

              <secondary>for transfer orders</secondary>
            </indexterm>Tax Authority</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b4ad0">
            <para>Specify the Tax Authority associated with the Transfer
            Order.</para>

            <para id="Para660306">The Tax Authority associated with the
            Destination Warehouse will be entered here by default.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para659780">From Warehouse</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b4b18">
            <para>Select a Source Warehouse from the available options. If the
            following Contact and Address information is defined on the
            Warehouse master, then it will be entered automatically; otherwise
            you may enter that information manually:</para>

            <para id="Para660080">Name: The name of the primary Contact at the
            Source Warehouse.</para>

            <para id="Para660081">Job Title: The primary Contact's Job
            Title.</para>

            <para id="Para660146">Voice: The primary Contact's phone
            number.</para>

            <para id="Para660147">Fax: The primary Contact's fax
            number.</para>

            <para id="Para660148">E-Mail: The primary Contact's email
            address.</para>

            <para id="Para659783">Street Address: The street Address for the
            Source Warehouse.</para>

            <para id="Para659784">City: The city the Source Warehouse is
            located in.</para>

            <para id="Para659785">State: The state the Source Warehouse is
            located in.</para>

            <para id="Para659786">Postal Code: The Postal Code for the Source
            Warehouse.</para>

            <para id="Para659787">Country: The country the Source Warehouse is
            located in.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para660236">To Warehouse</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b4b60">
            <para>Select a Destination Warehouse from the available options.
            If the following Contact and Address information is defined on the
            Warehouse master, then it will be entered automatically; otherwise
            you may enter that information manually:</para>

            <para id="Para660237">Name: The name of the primary Contact at the
            Destination Warehouse.</para>

            <para id="Para660238">Job Title: The primary Contact's Job
            Title.</para>

            <para id="Para660239">Voice: The primary Contact's phone
            number.</para>

            <para id="Para660240">Fax: The primary Contact's fax
            number.</para>

            <para id="Para660241">E-Mail: The primary Contact's email
            address.</para>

            <para id="Para660242">Street Address: The street Address for the
            Destination Warehouse.</para>

            <para id="Para660243">City: The city the Destination Warehouse is
            located in.</para>

            <para id="Para660244">State: The state the Destination Warehouse
            is located in.</para>

            <para id="Para660245">Postal Code: The Postal Code for the
            Destination Warehouse.</para>

            <para id="Para660246">Country: The country the Destination
            Warehouse is located in.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para660050">Ship Complete</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b4ba8">
            <para>Select to require that all Transfer Order Line Item
            quantities be issued to Shipping before the Order is
            shipped.</para>

            <para id="Para659822">This feature is designed to prevent partial
            shipments. If selected, users will be prevented from shipping the
            Order unless all Line Item quantities have been issued to
            Shipping. If not selected, partial shipments for the Order will be
            allowed.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para659823">Ship Via</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b4bf0">
            <para>Specify the Ship Via associated with the Transfer
            Order.</para>

            <para id="Para660027">You may enter a free-form Ship Via simply by
            typing the name of the Ship Via into the field.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para659949">Shipping Form</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b4c38">
            <para>Specify the Shipping Form associated with the Transfer
            Order.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para659841">At the top of the screen, the following buttons
      are available:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para659843">SAVE AND ADD TO PACKING LIST BATCH</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b4ca4">
            <para>Creates the Transfer Order, saves it, and adds it to the
            list of Orders available for printing on the Packing List
            Batch.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para659844">SAVE</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b4cec">
            <para>Creates the Transfer Order and saves the Transfer Order
            information.</para>

            <para id="Para659845">The SAVE button must be selected in order to
            save the Transfer Order record. It is not enough to save Transfer
            Order Line Item information. The Transfer Order header must also
            be saved.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para659846">CANCEL</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b4d34">
            <para>Closes the screen without creating a new Transfer Order,
            returning you to the application desktop.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para659963"><anchor id="Anchor659962" role="Index"
      xreflabel="transfer orders:adding line items to" /> <indexterm
          significance="normal" zone="Anchor659962">
          <primary>transfer orders</primary>

          <secondary>adding line items to</secondary>
        </indexterm>To create or modify Transfer Order Line Items, select the
      "Line Items" tab at the top of the "Transfer Order" screen. The
      following screen will appear:</para>

      <para id="Para659970"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/IM_IT_transferOrdLines.png"
                         id="Graphic659968" />
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption660626">Transfer Order Line Items</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <para id="Para660486">When creating or modifying Transfer Order Line
      Items, you are presented with the following options:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para660487">Line Items</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b4e54">
            <para>Display lists Line Items for this Transfer Order.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <note>
        <para id="Para660490">Transfer Order Line Items may exist in any of
        the following statuses:</para>

        <para id="Para660491">"O" = Open</para>

        <para id="Para660492">"C" = Closed</para>

        <para id="Para660941">"X" = Cancelled</para>
      </note>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para660942">Show Canceled Line Items</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b4ee4">
            <para>Select to include in the Line Items display Transfer Order
            Line Items which have been specifically canceled.</para>

            <para id="Para660501">Displaying canceled Line Items can provide
            useful Order history information.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para660698">Require sufficient Inventory</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b4f2c">
            <para>Select to ensure you have enough Quantity on Hand of a Line
            Item prior to issuing Stock to Shipping.</para>

            <para id="Para660699">If selected, this option will prevent you
            from issuing Line Item quantity to Shipping if doing so would
            force Quantity on Hand for the Item Site to fall below zero. Not
            selecting this option means issuing Stock to Shipping may drive
            Item Site Quantity on Hand negative.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para660527">Freight Weight</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b4f74">
            <para>Displays the combined weight of all Transfer Order Line
            Items.</para>

            <para id="Para660528">Freight weight represents the sum of an
            Item's product weight and packaging weight, both of which are
            defined on the Item master. The per unit freight weight multiplied
            by the quantity per gives you the Line Item freight weight. The
            sum of all Line Item freight weights is the combined weight for
            the Order.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para660530"><anchor id="Anchor660529" role="Index"
          xreflabel="freight:on transfer orders;transfer orders:freight charges on" />
          <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor660529">
              <primary>freight</primary>

              <secondary>on transfer orders</secondary>
            </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor660529">
              <primary>transfer orders</primary>

              <secondary>freight charges on</secondary>
            </indexterm>Line Item Freight Subtotal</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b504c">
            <para>Displays the subtotal for all Line Item Freight.</para>

            <para id="Para660966">Freight charges may be added when entering
            or editing a Transfer Order Line Item.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para660687">Tax</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b5094">
            <para>Displays the total amount of Tax to be charged on the
            Transfer Order.</para>

            <para id="Para660688">Sales Tax is calculated at the Transfer
            Order Line Item level. The Tax amount displayed here represents
            the total for all Line Item Tax amounts. To get a detailed view of
            the Tax calculation, click on the Tax link using your
            mouse.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para660531">Total</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b50dc">
            <para>Displays the total amount of the Transfer Order.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <note>
        <para id="Para661005">Any Transfer Order Line Item may be
        shipped--even if the Item or Item Site in question becomes inactive
        after the Sales Order has been created.</para>
      </note>

      <para id="Para660536">At the top of and to the far right of the screen,
      the following buttons are available:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para660537">CLEAR</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b516c">
            <para>Select to clear the contents of the current Transfer Order
            and open a fresh, new Transfer Order for Order entry.</para>

            <para id="Para660538">The Order Number of the Order being cleared
            will display next to the CLEAR button.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <note>
        <para id="Para660540">Selecting the CLEAR button on the Transfer Order
        header does not delete any information which has been saved
        previously.</para>
      </note>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para660541">SAVE</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b51fc">
            <para>Saves the Transfer Order information.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para660542">CANCEL</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b5244">
            <para>Closes the screen without creating a new Transfer Order,
            returning you to the application desktop.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para660543">NEW</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b528c">
            <para>Opens screen for creating a new Transfer Order Line
            Item.</para>

            <para id="Para660544">Mac users may use COMMAND + N to enter a new
            Line Item.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para660545">EDIT</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b52d4">
            <para>Enables you to edit highlighted Transfer Order Line Items.
            The edit screen is the same as that for creating a new Transfer
            Order Line Item--except that when editing, the fields will contain
            Transfer Order Line Item information. Double-clicking on a
            Transfer Order Line Item will also bring you to the editing
            screen.</para>

            <para id="Para660546">Mac users may use COMMAND + E to edit an
            existing Line Item.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para660547">CLOSE</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b531c">
            <para>Highlight a Transfer Order Line Item and then select this to
            close the Transfer Order Line Item.</para>

            <para id="Para660548">If the highlighted Line Item is already
            closed, the label will revert to an OPEN, which may be used to
            open the closed Line Item.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para660549">DELETE</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b5364">
            <para>Highlight a Transfer Order Line Item and then select this to
            remove the Transfer Order Line Item from the list.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para660551"><anchor id="Anchor660550" role="Index"
          xreflabel="shipping:issuing stock to" /> <indexterm
              significance="normal" zone="Anchor660550">
              <primary>shipping</primary>

              <secondary>issuing stock to</secondary>
            </indexterm>ISSUE STOCK</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b53f4">
            <para>Highlight a Transfer Order Line Item and then select this
            button to issue quantity to Shipping.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <tip>
        <para id="Para660804">You may select multiple Line Items for issuing
        to Shipping by highlighting them using your mouse--or a combination of
        your mouse and either the SHIFT or CTRL keys.</para>
      </tip>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para660805">ISSUE LINE BAL.</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b5484">
            <para>Highlight a Transfer Order Line Item and then select this
            button to issue the balance of the Line Item quantity to
            Shipping.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para660558">Right-clicking on an Item in the Line Items list
      enables you to select from the following menu options:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para660559">Edit Line</term>

          <xi:include href="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                      xpointer="element(listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b52d4)" />
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para660560">Close Line</term>

          <xi:include href="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                      xpointer="element(listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b531c)" />
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para660561">Delete Line</term>

          <xi:include href="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                      xpointer="element(listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b5364)" />
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para660562">Return Stock</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b55c8">
            <para></para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para660563">Issue Stock</term>

          <xi:include href="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                      xpointer="element(listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b53f4)" />
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para660564">Issue Line Balance</term>

          <xi:include href="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                      xpointer="element(listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b5484)" />
        </varlistentry>

        <xi:include href="widgets/xtreewidget.xml"
                    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                    xpointer="element(xtreewidget.menu.exportcontents)" />
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para660663"><anchor id="Anchor660662" role="Index"
      xreflabel="transfer orders:adding line items to" /> <indexterm
          significance="normal" zone="Anchor660662">
          <primary>transfer orders</primary>

          <secondary>adding line items to</secondary>
        </indexterm>To add a new Transfer Order Line Item, select the NEW
      button. The following screen will appear:</para>

      <para id="Para659516"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/IM_IT_transferOrdItemNew.png"
                         id="Graphic659515" />
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption659517">Create New Transfer Order Line
            Item</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <para id="Para661072">When creating a new Transfer Order Line Item, you
      are presented with the following options:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para661073">Order #</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c01b0">
            <para>Displays the Transfer Order Number specified on the Transfer
            Order header screen.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para661074">Line #</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c01f8">
            <para>Displays the Line Item Number for the current Line
            Item.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para661075">Item Number</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c0240">
            <para>Enter the Item Number of the Item you want to sell.</para>

            <para id="Para661076">The Item list will contain Items having
            valid Item Sites in the From (i.e., Source) Warehouse.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para661089"><anchor id="Anchor661087" role="Index"
          xreflabel="warehouses:source for transfer orders" /> <indexterm
              significance="normal" zone="Anchor661087">
              <primary>warehouses</primary>

              <secondary>source for transfer orders</secondary>
            </indexterm> <anchor id="Anchor661088" role="Index"
          xreflabel="sales orders:selling warehouses for" /> <indexterm
              significance="normal" zone="Anchor661088">
              <primary>sales orders</primary>

              <secondary>selling warehouses for</secondary>
            </indexterm>From Whs.</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c0318">
            <para>Displays the Source Warehouse specified on the Transfer
            Order header screen.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para661093">Qty. Ordered</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c0360">
            <para>Enter the quantity of the specified Item to be
            transferred.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para661104">Scheduled Date</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c03a8">
            <para>The scheduled date is the date when the Line Item should be
            Shipped. The user who enters the Line Item is responsible for
            determining the scheduled date. After entering the scheduled date,
            hit the TAB key on your keyboard to display values in the
            remaining display only fields.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <note>
        <para id="Para661106">The Transfer Order Item having the earliest
        scheduled date will determine the ship date for the Transfer
        Order.</para>
      </note>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para661116"><anchor id="Anchor661115" role="Index"
          xreflabel="sales orders:availability of items for" /> <indexterm
              significance="normal" zone="Anchor661115">
              <primary>sales orders</primary>

              <secondary>availability of items for</secondary>
            </indexterm>Show Availability</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c0480">
            <para>Select to display Availability information for the Transfer
            Order Item in the following categories:</para>

            <para id="Para661117">On Hand: Displays the current Quantity on
            Hand value.</para>

            <para id="Para661118">Allocated: Displays the quantity allocated
            to current Sales Orders, Transfer Orders, and/or Work Orders in
            the system. An Item is considered allocated to a Sales
            Order/Transfer Order if a Transfer Order Line Item exists for the
            Item--and that Line Item has not yet been issued to Shipping. An
            Item is considered allocated to a Work Order if the Item is a
            material requirement--and the material has not yet been issued to
            the Work Order. Once the current Transfer Order Line Item is
            saved, the "Allocated" value will increase by the quantity
            ordered.</para>

            <para id="Para661119">Unallocated: Displays the Quantity on Hand
            remaining after allocations have been accounted for, as in: QOH -
            Allocated Qty. = Unallocated Qty.</para>

            <para id="Para661120">On Order: If the Transfer Order Item is a
            manufactured Item, the quantity ordered by current Work Orders
            will be displayed. If the Transfer Order Item is a purchased Item,
            the quantity ordered by current Purchase Orders will be
            displayed.</para>

            <para id="Para661121">Available: Displays the available quantity.
            Available quantity is determined using the following formula:
            Unallocated Qty. + On Order Qty. = Available Qty.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para661126">Standard Cost</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c04c8">
            <para>Displays the Standard Cost per unit.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para661661">Line Item Freight</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c0510">
            <para>Enter the amount of freight charges for the entire Line Item
            quantity.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para661647">Tax</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c0558">
            <para>Displays the amount of Tax to be charged for the Transfer
            Order Line Item quantity.</para>

            <para id="Para661648">Sales Tax is calculated at the Transfer
            Order Line Item level. To get a detailed view of the Tax
            calculation, click on the Tax link using your mouse.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para661135">Qty. Shipped to Date</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c05a0">
            <para>Shipped to Date: Displays the total quantity shipped of the
            specified Line Item to date.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <tip>
        <para id="Para661150">You can link Characteristics and Values to an
        Item by using the Item master. Once entered, these Characteristics and
        Values will be available to users entering Transfer Order Line
        Items.</para>
      </tip>

      <para id="Para661151">When selecting or editing Characteristics for a
      Transfer Order Line Item, you are presented with the following
      options:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para661152">Name</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c0630">
            <para>Displays the name of any Item Characteristics associated
            with the Item.</para>

            <para id="Para661153">Characteristics defined as Item
            Characteristics may be associated with Items on the Item
            master.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para661154">Value</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c0678">
            <para>Displays the default Value associated with an Item
            Characteristic, but permits you to specify an alternate
            Value.</para>

            <para id="Para661155">When associating Characteristic Values with
            a Transfer Order Line Item, you have four options: 1) Select the
            default Value; 2) select an alternate pre-defined Value from the
            list; 3) manually enter a new Value in place of the pre-defined
            Value; or 4) make no selection. Making no selection means the
            Characteristics will not be associated with the Transfer Order
            Line Item.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para661156">To the far right of the screen, the following
      buttons are available:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para661157">CLOSE</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c06e4">
            <para>Closes the screen without creating a new Transfer Order Line
            Item, returning you to the Transfer Order header.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para661158">SAVE</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c072c">
            <para>Creates the new Transfer Order Line Item and adds it to the
            list of Transfer Order Line Items.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <note>
        <para id="Para661610">If there is no Item Site for the Item in the
        Destination Warehouse, you will automatically be presented with an
        Item Site screen. Simply enter the required information to create an
        Item Site in the Destination Warehouse. An Item Site must exist in the
        Destination Warehouse before material can be received
        successfully.</para>
      </note>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para661159">PREVIOUS</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c07bc">
            <para>Select to view previous Line Items associated with the
            Transfer Order.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para661160">NEW</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c0804">
            <para>Select to create a new Transfer Order Line Item.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para661161">CANCEL ITEM</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c084c">
            <para>Select to cancel the current Transfer Order Line
            Item.</para>

            <para id="Para661162">Records of canceled Line Items will be
            retained for informational purposes. To view canceled Line Items
            associated with a Transfer Order, select the "Show Canceled Line
            Items" option on the Transfer Order header's "Line Items
            tab.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para661181">To enter Notes related to a Transfer Order Line
      Item, select the "Notes" tab at the bottom of the screen, as shown
      below:</para>

      <para id="Para659548"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/IM_IT_transferOrdItemNotes.png"
                         id="Graphic659546" />
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption659549">Transfer Order Line Item
            Notes</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <para id="Para662050">When adding Notes to a Transfer Order Line Item,
      you are presented with the following options:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para661321">Notes</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c0924">
            <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for
            entering general Notes related to the Transfer Order Line
            Item.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para661324">To add Comments related to a Transfer Order Line
      Item, select the "Comments" tab. The following screen will
      appear:</para>

      <para id="Para659582"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/IM_IT_transferOrdItemComm.png"
                         id="Graphic659581" />
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption659583">Transfer Order Line Item
            Comments</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <note>
        <para id="Para661348">Whenever Transfer Order Line Items are created
        or their quantities are changed, the system will automatically
        generate a Comment, which will appear in the list of Line Item
        Comments.</para>
      </note>

      <para id="Para661349">When adding Comments related to a Transfer Order
      Line Item, you are presented with the following options:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para661350">Comments</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c0a20">
            <para>Display lists Comments for the specified Line Item.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para661352">To the far right of the screen, the following
      buttons are available:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para661353">NEW</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c0a8c">
            <para>Opens screen for creating a new Comment.</para>

            <para id="Para661354">Transfer Order Line Item Comments may only
            be added after the Line Item has been saved to the Transfer
            Order.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para661355">VIEW</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c0ad4">
            <para>Highlight a Comment and then select this button to reach a
            read-only view of the Comment.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para661356">To create a Transfer Order Line Item Comment,
      select the NEW button. The following screen will appear:</para>

      <para id="Para661360"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/CommentNew.png" id="Graphic661358" />
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption661361">Create New Comment</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para661362">Comment Type</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c0bac">
            <para>Specify one of the following Comment Types from the
            drop-down list: ChangeLog or General.</para>

            <para id="Para661363">Comment Types are used to categorize
            Comments. Once you have specified a Comment Type, you may type
            your Comment in the main text area. The text area features
            word-wrapping and scroll-bar support for longer Comments.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para661364">To the far right of the screen, the following
      buttons are available:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para661365">CANCEL</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c0c18">
            <para>Closes the screen without creating a new Comment, returning
            you to the previous screen.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para661366">SAVE</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c0c60">
            <para>Creates the Comment and adds it to the list of Order
            Comments.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para661367">If the Transfer Order Line Item is a manufactured
      Item, you have the ability to view Pending Availability for any of its
      component Items. To view the Pending Availability for Transfer Order
      Line Item component Items, select the "Pending Availability" tab, as
      shown below:</para>

      <para id="Para659602"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/IM_IT_transferOrdItemPend.png"
                         id="Graphic659601" />
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption659603">Pending Availability for Component
            Items</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <para id="Para662108">When displaying Pending Availability for Transfer
      Order component Items, you are presented with the following
      options:</para>

      <note>
        <para id="Para661418">The "Pending Availability" tab features details
        related to component Items and so only applies if a Transfer Order
        Line Item is a manufactured Item. If a Line Item is not manufactured,
        Pending Availability does not apply.</para>
      </note>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para661419">Show Pending Availability as Indented
          BOM</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c0d5c">
            <para>Select to display Pending Availability as an indented Bill
            of Materials.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para661420">Pending Availability</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c0da4">
            <para>Displays Pending Availability for component Items associated
            with sold manufactured Items.</para>

            <para id="Para675809">If you choose the "Show Pending Availability
            as Indented BOM" option, the information will be displayed in a
            nested list--with a plus ("+") sign located to the far left of the
            screen next to each line that may be expanded to lower levels. By
            clicking your mouse on a plus sign, you reveal lower levels of
            information related to the Line Item.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <tip>
        <para id="Para661423">Keep in mind that Pending Availability in this
        case is not the same as Available to Promise. This view to Pending
        Availability reflects current Inventory Levels--it is not a
        time-phased view of Availability.</para>
      </tip>

      <para id="Para662128">Order Notes added to a Transfer Order are used for
      internal purposes only. To add Notes to a Transfer Order, select the
      "Order Notes" tab at the top of the "Transfer Order" screen. The
      following screen will appear:</para>

      <para id="Para659576"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/IM_IT_transferOrdNotes.png"
                         id="Graphic659574" />
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption659397">Transfer Order Notes</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <para id="Para661468">When adding Notes to a Transfer Order, you are
      presented with the following options:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para661469">Order Notes</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c9490">
            <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for
            entering general Notes related to the Transfer Order. These Notes
            are for internal use only.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para661470">To the far right of the screen, the following
      buttons are available:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para661471">SAVE</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c94fc">
            <para>Saves the Order Note.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para661472">CANCEL</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c9544">
            <para>Closes the screen without creating an Order Note, returning
            you to the application desktop.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para661473">To add Comments related to a Transfer Order,
      select the "Comments" tab. The following screen will appear:</para>

      <para id="Para659416"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/IM_IT_transferOrdComm.png"
                         id="Graphic659414" />
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption659417">Transfer Order Comments</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <para id="Para661512">When adding Comments related to a Transfer Order,
      you are presented with the following options:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para661513">Comments</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c961c">
            <para>Display lists Comments for the specified Order.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para661515">To the far right of the screen, the following
      buttons are available:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para661516">NEW</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c9688">
            <para>Opens screen for creating a new Comment.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para661517">VIEW</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c96d0">
            <para>Highlight a Comment and then select this button to reach a
            read-only view of the Comment.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para661518">To create a Transfer Order Comment, select the NEW
      button. The following screen will appear:</para>

      <para id="Para661522"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/CommentNew.png" id="Graphic661520" />
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption661523">Create New Comment</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para661524">Comment Type</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c97a8">
            <para>Specify one of the following Comment Types from the
            drop-down list: ChangeLog or General.</para>

            <para id="Para661525">Comment Types are used to categorize
            Comments. Once you have specified a Comment Type, you may type
            your Comment in the main text area. The text area features
            word-wrapping and scroll-bar support for longer Comments.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para661526">To the far right of the screen, the following
      buttons are available:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para661527">CANCEL</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c9814">
            <para>Closes the screen without creating a new Comment, returning
            you to the previous screen.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para661528">SAVE</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c985c">
            <para>Creates the Comment and adds it to the list of Order
            Comments.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para661529">Shipping Notes are drawn from the Shipping
      Comments (if any) associated with Transit Warehouses. The Notes may vary
      depending on the Transit Warehouse being used. These Notes provide a
      mechanism for transferring information about Transit Warehouses to the
      Transfer Order. To view Transfer Order Shipping Notes, select the
      "Shipping Notes" tab at the top of the "Transfer Order" screen. The
      following screen will appear:</para>

      <para id="Para659442"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/IM_IT_transferOrdShNtes.png"
                         id="Graphic659441" />
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption659443">Transfer Order Shipping
            Notes</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <para id="Para661569">When viewing or editing Shipping Notes for a
      Transfer Order, you are presented with the following options:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para661570">Shipping Notes</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c9934">
            <para>While the content for Shipping Notes may originate from the
            Transit Warehouse master, you can edit the Notes to fit the
            requirements of an Order. This is a scrolling text field with
            word-wrapping.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para661571">To the far right of the screen, the following
      buttons are available:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para661572">SAVE</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c99a0">
            <para>Saves the Shipping Note.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para661573">CANCEL</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c99e8">
            <para>Closes the screen without creating a Shipping Note,
            returning you to the application desktop.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para662295">If you want to speed up your data entry of
      Transfer Order Line Items, you can use the Quick Entry interface. This
      screen allows you to enter multiple Line Items in one session. It also
      simplifies the process by presenting only the minimum required fields.
      To enter Line Items using the Quick Entry interface, select the "Quick
      Entry" tab at the top of the "Transfer Order" screen. The following
      screen will appear:</para>

      <para id="Para659462"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/IM_IT_transferOrdQEntry.png"
                         id="Graphic659461" />
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption659463">Transfer Order Quick Entry</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <tip>
        <para id="Para662320">To get started entering Line Items, place your
        cursor in the "Item" field. You can then move from field-to-field
        using the TAB button on your keyboard.</para>
      </tip>

      <para id="Para662321">When entering Transfer Order Line Items using the
      Quick Entry interface, you are presented with the following
      options:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para662322">Item</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c9ae4">
            <para>Enter an Inventory Item Number.</para>

            <para id="Para662323">This field is used for entering Items stored
            in Inventory.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para662330">Qty.</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c9b2c">
            <para>Enter the quantity you want to transfer.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para662333">Standard Cost</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c9b74">
            <para>Displays the Standard Cost per unit.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para662335">Freight</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c9bbc">
            <para>Enter the Freight amount, if any.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para662336">Due Date</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c9c04">
            <para>Enter the due date.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para662338">To the far right of the screen, the following
      buttons are available:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para662339">SAVE QUICK ENTRIES</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c9c70">
            <para>Select to save all the Line Items entered using the Quick
            Entry interface.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para662340">DELETE QUICK ENTRY</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c9cb8">
            <para>Highlight a Line Item and then select this button to remove
            the Item from the list.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
    </section>

    <section id="Section615525">
      <title><anchor id="Anchor615504" role="Index"
      xreflabel="quantity on hand:resetting QOH balances;inventory transactions:resetting QOH balances" />
      <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor615504">
          <primary>quantity on hand</primary>

          <secondary>resetting QOH balances</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor615504">
          <primary>inventory transactions</primary>

          <secondary>resetting QOH balances</secondary>
        </indexterm>Reset QOH Balances</title>

      <para id="Para615506">To avoid the unnecessary confusion that can occur
      if negative Quantity on Hand (QOH) balances are used for planning
      purposes, the system gives you the ability to quickly and easily reset
      negative QOH values to "0". To reset negative Quantity on Hand balances
      to zero, either globally or locally, select the "Reset QOH Balances"
      option. The following screen will appear:</para>

      <para id="Para519070"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/IM_IT_resetQOHBalances.png"
                         id="Graphic525901" />
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption519071">Reset QOH Balances</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <tip>
        <para id="Para560082">Be sure to thaw any Item Site whose negative
        Quantity on Hand balance you want to reset to "0". An Item Site must
        be unfrozen before its QOH balance can be reset. For more information
        on freezing and thawing, see the <link endterm="Anchor80983"
        id="XRef567659" linkend="Anchor80983"> Freezing and
        Thawing</link>"Topic: Freezing and Thawing" section.</para>
      </tip>

      <para id="Para560062">When resetting Quantity on Hand balances, you are
      presented with the following options:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry role="openmfg">
          <term id="Para519073">All Warehouses</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c9e44">
            <para>Select to reset Quantity on Hand balances for all
            Warehouses.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry role="openmfg">
          <term id="Para519075">Selected</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c9e68">
            <para>Specify Warehouse where Quantity on Hand balances are to be
            reset.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519077">All Class Codes</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c9eb0">
            <para>Select to reset Quantity on Hand balances for all Class
            Codes.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519078">Selected</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c9ef8">
            <para>Specify Class Code whose Quantity on Hand you want to
            reset.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para547799">Pattern</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c9f40">
            <para>Enter a Class Code pattern to select a range of Class
            Codes.</para>

            <para id="Para677019">Refine your search using Regular
            Expressions, as described in <link endterm="Anchor77806"
            id="XRef677018" linkend="Anchor77806"> Pattern Matching with
            Regular Expressions</link>"Topic: Pattern Matching with Regular
            Expressions".</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para519082">To the far right of the screen, the following
      buttons are available:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519083">CANCEL</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c9fac">
            <para>Closes the screen without resetting Quantity on Hand,
            returning you to the application desktop.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para578300">RESET</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c9ff4">
            <para>Resets Quantity on Hand balances for Warehouses and Class
            Codes specified above.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <note>
        <para id="Para578302">Additional steps will be necessary if any Items
        within the specified Class Code(s) are stored in multiple Locations.
        For more information, see the <link endterm="Anchor81167"
        id="XRef578304" linkend="Anchor81167"> Distributing Multiple Location
        Control (MLC) Items</link>"Inter-Warehouse Transfer" section.</para>
      </note>
    </section>

    <section id="Section519086" role="openmfg">
      <title>Relocate Inventory</title>

      <para id="Para519087">To relocate Inventory from one Location to
      another, select the "Relocate Inventory" option. The following screen
      will appear:</para>

      <para id="Para519091"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/IM_IT_relocateInventory.png"
                         id="Graphic525912" />
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption519092">Relocate Inventory</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <para id="Para519098">When relocating Inventory from one Location to
      another, you are presented with the following options:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519099">Item Number</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18ca114">
            <para>Enter the Item Number of the Inventory you are
            relocating.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para671985">UOM</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18ca15c">
            <para>Inventory Unit of Measure.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519103">Warehouse</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18ca1a4">
            <para>Specify Warehouse where Inventory is located.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519105">Source</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18ca1ec">
            <para>Display lists source Locations for the specified Item.
            Select the source Location Inventory is to be transferred
            from.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519107">Target</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d0e24">
            <para>Display lists target Locations for the specified
            Item.</para>

            <para id="Para675833">Select the target Location Inventory is to
            be transferred to.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519112">Qty. to Move</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d0e6c">
            <para>to Move: Enter the quantity of the specified Item you want
            to move from the source Location to the target Location.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para544108">Comments</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d0eb4">
            <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for
            entering Comments related to the Inventory relocation.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para544071">To the far right of the screen, the following
      buttons are available:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para580340">CANCEL</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d0f20">
            <para>Closes the screen without relocating Inventory, returning
            you to the application desktop.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para580341">MOVE</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d0f68">
            <para>Moves specified quantity of Inventory from source Location
            to target Location.</para>

            <para id="Para652102">Additional steps will be necessary if the
            specified Item is stored in multiple Locations. For more
            information, see the <link endterm="Anchor81167" id="XRef652104"
            linkend="Anchor81167"> Distributing Multiple Location Control
            (MLC) Items</link>"Inter-Warehouse Transfer" section.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section id="Section652128" role="openmfg">
    <title>Lot/Serial Control</title>

    <para id="Para652129">Items that are controlled by either Lot or Serial
    Number require special handling.</para>

    <note>
      <para id="Para652131">For information on the special steps required to
      receive Lot/Serial Items into Inventory, see the "Topic: Receiving
      Lot/Serial Items into Inventory" section.</para>
    </note>

    <section id="Section652132" role="openmfg">
      <title>Lot/Serial Comments</title>

      <para id="Para652133">To associate Comments with Lot/Serial Items,
      select the "Lot/Serial Comments" option. The following screen will
      appear:</para>

      <para id="Para652134"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/IM_Lot_lotComments.png"
                         id="Graphic652427" />
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption652135">Lot/Serial Comments</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <para id="Para652136">When associating Comments with Lot/Serial Items,
      you are presented with the following options:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para652137">Item Number</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d10ac">
            <para>Enter the Item Number of the Item you want to create a
            Lot/Serial Comment for.</para>

            <para id="Para652138">The browse button located to the right of
            the field leads to a searchable Item list. The list includes all
            Items--as opposed to Lot/Serial Items only--because an Item may
            not currently be Lot/Serial Number controlled, but it may have
            been in the past.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para671990">UOM</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d10f4">
            <para>Inventory Unit of Measure.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para652140">Lot/Serial #</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d113c">
            <para>Specify the Lot/Serial Number you want to create a Comment
            for.</para>

            <para id="Para670533">Lot/Serial Numbers are created either when
            Lot/Serial Items are received into Inventory or when existing
            quantities are reassigned.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para652142">Comments</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d1184">
            <para>Display lists Comments associated with the specified
            Lot/Serial Number.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para652144">To the far right of the screen, the following
      buttons are available:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para652145">CLOSE</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d11f0">
            <para>Closes the screen, returning you to the application
            desktop.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para652146">NEW</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d1238">
            <para>Opens screen for creating a new Comment.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para652147">VIEW</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d1280">
            <para>Highlight a Comment and then select this button to view the
            Comment.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para652148">To create a new Lot/Serial Comment, select the NEW
      button. The following screen will appear:</para>

      <para id="Para652149"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/CommentNew.png" id="Graphic652474" />
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption652150">Create New Comment</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para652151">Comment Type</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d1358">
            <para>Specify one of the following Comment Types from the
            drop-down list: ChangeLog or General.</para>

            <para id="Para652152">Comment Types are used to categorize
            Comments. Once you have specified a Comment Type, you may type
            your Comment in the main text area. The text area features
            word-wrapping and scroll-bar support for longer Comments.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para652153">To the far right of the screen, the following
      buttons are available:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para652154">CANCEL</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d13c4">
            <para>Closes the screen without creating a new Comment, returning
            you to the previous screen.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para652155">SAVE</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d140c">
            <para>Creates the Comment and adds it to the list of Lot/Serial
            Comments.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
    </section>

    <section id="Section677781" role="openmfg">
      <title>Location/Lot/Serial # Detail</title>

      <para id="Para677782">To locate detailed Location and Lot/Serial Number
      information, select the "Location/Lot/Serial # Detail" option. The
      following screen will appear:</para>

      <para id="Para677786"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/IM_Disp_locationLotDetail.png"
                         id="Graphic677784" />
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption677787">Location/Lot/Serial Number
            Detail</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <para id="Para677788">When displaying detailed Location and Lot/Serial
      Number information, you are presented with the following options:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para677789">Item Number</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d1508">
            <para>Enter the Item Number of the Item whose detailed
            Location/Lot/Serial Number information you want to display.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para677790">UOM</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d1550">
            <para>Inventory Unit of Measure.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para677791">All Warehouses</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d1598">
            <para>Select to display detailed Location/Lot/Serial Number
            information for all Warehouses.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para677792">Selected</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d15e0">
            <para>Specify Warehouse whose detailed Location/Lot/Serial Number
            information you want to display.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para677793">Locations</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d1628">
            <para>Display lists Location/Lot/Serial Number detail, using the
            specified parameters.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para677794">To the far right of the screen, the following
      buttons are available:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para677795">CLOSE</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d1694">
            <para>Closes the screen, returning you to the application
            desktop.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para677796">QUERY</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d16dc">
            <para>Select to generate the display, using the specified
            parameters.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para677797">PRINT</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d1724">
            <para>Runs the report associated with this screen.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
    </section>

    <section id="Section678403" role="openmfg">
      <title>Detailed Inventory History by Lot/Serial #</title>

      <para id="Para678404">To view detailed Inventory history by Lot/Serial
      Number, select the "Detailed Inventory History by Lot/Serial #" option.
      The following screen will appear:</para>

      <para id="Para678408"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/IM_Disp_detailedInvHistLotS.png"
                         id="Graphic678406" />
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption678409">Detailed Inventory History by
            Lot/Serial Number</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <para id="Para678410">When displaying detailed Inventory history by
      Lot/Serial Number, you are presented with the following options:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678411">Lot/Serial #</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d1820">
            <para>Enter the Lot/Serial Number of the Inventory whose detailed
            Inventory history you want to display. This field supports regular
            expressions.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <tip>
        <para id="Para678413">The "Lot/Serial #" field supports pattern
        matching with Regular Expressions. For more information on matching
        patterns using Regular Expressions, see <link endterm="Anchor77806"
        id="XRef678415" linkend="Anchor77806"> Pattern Matching with Regular
        Expressions</link>"Topic: Pattern Matching with Regular
        Expressions".</para>
      </tip>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678417">Trans. Types</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d18b0">
            <para>Select one of the following transaction types from the
            drop-down menu.</para>

            <para id="Para678418">All Transactions: Displays all Inventory
            transactions.</para>

            <para id="Para678419">Receipts: Displays receipts into Inventory
            from Manufacturing, purchases, or miscellaneous receipts.</para>

            <para id="Para678420">Issues: Displays issues from Inventory to
            Manufacturing.</para>

            <para id="Para678421">Shipments: Displays shipments to
            customers.</para>

            <para id="Para678422">Adjustments and Counts: Displays Inventory
            adjustments and counts.</para>

            <para id="Para678423">Transfers: Displays Inter-Warehouse
            Transfers and Location and Lot/Serial Number reassignments.</para>

            <para id="Para678424">Scraps: Displays Scrap transfer from
            Inventory.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678425">Start Date</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d18f8">
            <para>Inventory transactions conducted on and after this date will
            be displayed. Start date and end date must be entered for
            calculation to proceed.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678426">End Date</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d1940">
            <para>Inventory transactions conducted on and before this date
            will be displayed. Start date and end date must be entered for
            calculation to proceed.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678427">Inventory History</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d1988">
            <para>Display lists detailed Inventory history by Lot/Serial
            Number, using the specified parameters.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <note>
        <para id="Para678429">The system prefixes Order Numbers with letters
        indicating the Order type. For example, Work Orders are prefixed with
        "WO", Purchase Orders with "PO", and Sales Orders with "SO". These
        letters are for display purposes only and are not considered part of
        the Order Number.</para>
      </note>

      <para id="Para678430">To the far right of the screen, the following
      buttons are available:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678431">CLOSE</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d1a18">
            <para>Closes the screen, returning you to the application
            desktop.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678432">QUERY</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d1a60">
            <para>Select to generate the display, using the specified
            parameters.</para>

            <para id="Para678433">Start date and end date must be entered for
            calculation to proceed. Results will be displayed in the
            "Inventory History" list.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678434">PRINT</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d1aa8">
            <para>Runs the report associated with this screen.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para678435">Right-clicking on a transaction without an
      assigned Order number in the Inventory History list enables you to
      select from the following menu options:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para678436">View Transaction Information</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d1b14">
            <para></para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <xi:include href="widgets/xtreewidget.xml"
                    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                    xpointer="element(xtreewidget.menu.exportcontents)" />
      </variablelist>
    </section>

    <section id="Section676279" role="openmfg">
      <title>Reassign Lot/Serial Number</title>

      <para id="Para652394">To reassign the Lot/Serial Number for a Lot/Serial
      Item--or to assign a Lot/Serial Number to a quantity located in a
      Lot/Serial Number controlled Item Site--select the "Reassign Lot/Serial
      Number" option. The following screen will appear:</para>

      <para id="Para652398"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/IM_IT_reassignLotSer.png"
                         id="Graphic652396" />
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption652399">Reassign Lot/Serial Number</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <para id="Para652388">When reassigning the Lot/Serial Number for a
      Lot/Serial Item, you are presented with the following options:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para652217">Item Number</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d9048">
            <para>Enter the Item Number of the Item whose Lot/Serial Number
            you want to reassign.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para671995">UOM</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d9090">
            <para>Inventory Unit of Measure.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para652220">Warehouse</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d90d8">
            <para>Specify Warehouse where Inventory is located.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para652221">Source</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d9120">
            <para>Display lists source Locations for the specified
            Item.</para>

            <para id="Para675862">Select the Location containing Inventory
            whose Lot/Serial Number you want to reassign by highlighting the
            line using your mouse.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para652223">Qty. to Reassign</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d9168">
            <para>to Reassign: Enter the quantity of the specified Item whose
            Lot/Serial Number you want to reassign.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para652224">New Lot Number</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d91b0">
            <para>Enter the new Lot Number for the quantity of the specified
            Item whose Lot/Serial Number you want to reassign.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para652225">New Expiration Date</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d91f8">
            <para>Specify the date when the Lot/Serial quantity
            expires.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <note>
        <para id="Para652227">The expiration option is only required and
        available for Item Sites designated as perishable.</para>
      </note>

      <para id="Para652228">To the far right of the screen, the following
      buttons are available:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para652229">CLOSE</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d9288">
            <para>Closes the screen without reassigning the Lot/Serial Number,
            returning you to the application desktop.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para652230">REASSIGN</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d92d0">
            <para>Reassigns the Lot/Serial Number for the quantity of the
            specified Item.</para>

            <para id="Para652231">Additional steps will be necessary if the
            specified Item is stored in multiple Locations. For more
            information, see the "Topic: Distributing Multiple Location
            Control (MLC) Items" section.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section id="Section652234">
    <title><anchor id="Anchor652233" role="Index"
    xreflabel="physical inventory:management of" /> <indexterm
        significance="normal" zone="Anchor652233">
        <primary>physical inventory</primary>

        <secondary>management of</secondary>
      </indexterm>Physical Inventory</title>

    <para id="Para652235">The management of physical Inventory is covered in
    this section.</para>

    <section id="Section519160">
      <title><anchor id="Anchor552152" role="Index"
      xreflabel="count tags:creating by class code/warehouse;physical inventory:creating count tags;class codes:count tags created by" />
      <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor552152">
          <primary>count tags</primary>

          <secondary>creating by class code/warehouse</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor552152">
          <primary>physical inventory</primary>

          <secondary>creating count tags</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor552152">
          <primary>class codes</primary>

          <secondary>count tags created by</secondary>
        </indexterm>Create Count Tags by Class Code/Warehouse</title>

      <para id="Para519161">Count Tags are used to spearhead Inventory counts.
      They are created manually and on-demand, and they are not tied to any
      particular cycle or frequency, as Cycle Count Tags are. To create Count
      Tags by Class Code and Warehouse, select the "Create Count Tags by Class
      Code/Warehouse" option. The following screen will appear:</para>

      <para id="Para519165"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/IM_PI_createCTByClassCode.png"
                         id="Graphic525960" />
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption519166">Create Count Tags by Class
            Code/Warehouse</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <para id="Para597742">When creating Count Tags by Class Code and
      Warehouse, you are presented with the following options:</para>

      <tip>
        <para id="Para597773">By default, the system allows only one unposted
        Count Tag per Item Site. To view all unposted Count Tags in your
        system, see the Count Tag Edit List.</para>
      </tip>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para580819">All Class Codes</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d9534">
            <para>Select to create Count Tags for all Class Codes.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para580820">Selected</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d957c">
            <para>Specify Class Code whose you want to create Count Tags
            for.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para547805">Pattern</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d95c4">
            <para>Enter a Class Code pattern to select a range of Class
            Codes.</para>

            <para id="Para677032">Refine your search using Regular
            Expressions, as described in <link endterm="Anchor77806"
            id="XRef677031" linkend="Anchor77806"> Pattern Matching with
            Regular Expressions</link>"Topic: Pattern Matching with Regular
            Expressions".</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para669371">Warehouse</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d960c">
            <para>Specify Warehouse the Count Tags are to be created
            for.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para669373">Mark Created Count Tag as Priority</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d9654">
            <para>Select to give priority status to Count Tag.</para>

            <para id="Para596694">Count Tags marked as having priority status
            are listed first in any prioritized lists. For example, priority
            Count Tags will appear at the top of the Count Tag Edit List;
            whereas, non-priority Count Tags will appear at the bottom of the
            list.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519175"><anchor id="Anchor558092" role="Index"
          xreflabel="freezing:of inventory;inventory:freezing at count tag creation" />
          <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor558092">
              <primary>freezing</primary>

              <secondary>of inventory</secondary>
            </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor558092">
              <primary>inventory</primary>

              <secondary>freezing at count tag creation</secondary>
            </indexterm>Freeze Inventory</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d972c">
            <para>Select to freeze Inventory.</para>

            <para id="Para519176">The Quantity on Hand value is not updated
            when a transaction is posted against a frozen Item Site. Instead,
            Inventory transactions are pooled and then posted later when the
            Item Site is unfrozen--or thawed. The Quantity on Hand is later
            updated when the Item Site is thawed. For a detailed explanation
            of these concepts, see the <link endterm="Anchor80983"
            id="XRef530040" linkend="Anchor80983"> Freezing and
            Thawing</link>"Topic: Freezing and Thawing" section.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <note>
        <para id="Para597727">When an Item Site is frozen, any Inventory
        transactions entered against that Item Site--including Work
        Orders--will not change Quantity on Hand until after the Item Site is
        thawed.</para>
      </note>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para629459">Ignore Zero Balance Item Sites</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d97bc">
            <para>Select to ignore Item Sites which have a Quantity on Hand
            balance of zero.</para>

            <para id="Para629470">If selected, Count Tags will not be created
            for any Item Site having a Quantity on Hand balance of
            zero.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para629463">Only for Specified Location</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d9804">
            <para>Select if you want to create Count Tags for an individual
            Warehouse Location.</para>

            <para id="Para629486">If selected, you will have the option to
            specify which Warehouse Location you want to have Count Tags
            created for. This option enables you to count individual Warehouse
            Locations separately, without having to post counts for an entire
            Warehouse all at once.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519180"><anchor id="Anchor596803" role="Index"
          xreflabel="cycle counters:creating instructions for;cycle counts:creating instructions for" />
          <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor596803">
              <primary>cycle counters</primary>

              <secondary>creating instructions for</secondary>
            </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor596803">
              <primary>cycle counts</primary>

              <secondary>creating instructions for</secondary>
            </indexterm>Comments</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d98dc">
            <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for
            entering Comments related to the Count Tag. Use the Comments field
            to enter any instructions or other Comments that need to reach and
            be read by the Inventory counters.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para519182">To the far right of the screen, the following
      buttons are available:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519183">CANCEL</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d9948">
            <para>Closes the screen without creating Count Tags, returning you
            to the application desktop.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519184">CREATE TAGS</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d9990">
            <para>Creates Count Tags.</para>

            <para id="Para597791">Count Tag Numbers are generated
            automatically in an ordered sequence.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
    </section>

    <section id="Section629436">
      <title><anchor id="Anchor629435" role="Index"
      xreflabel="count tags:creating by planner code;physical inventory:creating count tags;planner codes:count tags created by" />
      <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor629435">
          <primary>count tags</primary>

          <secondary>creating by planner code</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor629435">
          <primary>physical inventory</primary>

          <secondary>creating count tags</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor629435">
          <primary>planner codes</primary>

          <secondary>count tags created by</secondary>
        </indexterm>Create Count Tags by Planner Code</title>

      <para id="Para629518">Count Tags are used to spearhead Inventory counts.
      They are created manually and on-demand, and they are not tied to any
      particular cycle or frequency, as Cycle Count Tags are. To create Count
      Tags by Planner Code, select the "Create Count Tags by Planner Code"
      option. The following screen will appear:</para>

      <para id="Para629522"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/IM_PI_createCTByPlanCode.png"
                         id="Graphic629520" />
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption629523">Create Count Tags by Planner
            Code</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <para id="Para629524">When creating Count Tags by Planner Code, you are
      presented with the following options:</para>

      <tip>
        <para id="Para629613">By default, the system allows only one unposted
        Count Tag per Item Site. To view all unposted Count Tags in your
        system, see the Count Tag Edit List.</para>
      </tip>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para629614">All Planner Codes</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d9b88">
            <para>Select to create Count Tags for all Planner Codes.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para629615">Selected</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d9bd0">
            <para>Specify Planner Code you want to create Count Tags
            for.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para629529">Pattern</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d9c18">
            <para>Enter a Planner Code pattern to select a range of Planner
            Codes.</para>

            <para id="Para677044">Refine your search using Regular
            Expressions, as described in <link endterm="Anchor77806"
            id="XRef677043" linkend="Anchor77806"> Pattern Matching with
            Regular Expressions</link>"Topic: Pattern Matching with Regular
            Expressions".</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para629537">Warehouse</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d9c60">
            <para>Specify Warehouse the Count Tags are to be created
            for.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para629539">Mark Created Count Tag as Priority</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d9ca8">
            <para>Select to give priority status to Count Tag.</para>

            <para id="Para629540">Count Tags marked as having priority status
            are listed first in any prioritized lists. For example, priority
            Count Tags will appear at the top of the Count Tag Edit List;
            whereas, non-priority Count Tags will appear at the bottom of the
            list.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para629542"><anchor id="Anchor629541" role="Index"
          xreflabel="freezing:of inventory;inventory:freezing at count tag creation" />
          <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor629541">
              <primary>freezing</primary>

              <secondary>of inventory</secondary>
            </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor629541">
              <primary>inventory</primary>

              <secondary>freezing at count tag creation</secondary>
            </indexterm>Freeze Inventory</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d9d80">
            <para>Select to freeze Inventory.</para>

            <para id="Para629543">The Quantity on Hand value is not updated
            when a transaction is posted against a frozen Item Site. Instead,
            Inventory transactions are pooled and then posted later when the
            Item Site is unfrozen--or thawed. The Quantity on Hand is later
            updated when the Item Site is thawed. For a detailed explanation
            of these concepts, see the <link endterm="Anchor80983"
            id="XRef629545" linkend="Anchor80983"> Freezing and
            Thawing</link>"Topic: Freezing and Thawing" section.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <note>
        <para id="Para629548">When an Item Site is frozen, any Inventory
        transactions entered against that Item Site--including Work
        Orders--will not change Quantity on Hand until after the Item Site is
        thawed.</para>
      </note>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para629549">Ignore Zero Balance Item Sites</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e2400">
            <para>Select to ignore Item Sites which have a Quantity on Hand
            balance of zero.</para>

            <para id="Para629550">If selected, Count Tags will not be created
            for any Item Site having a Quantity on Hand balance of
            zero.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para629551">Only for Specified Location</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e2448">
            <para>Select if you want to create Count Tags for an individual
            Warehouse Location.</para>

            <para id="Para629552">If selected, you will have the option to
            specify which Warehouse Location you want to have Count Tags
            created for. This option enables you to count individual Warehouse
            Locations separately, without having to post counts for an entire
            Warehouse all at once.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para629554"><anchor id="Anchor629553" role="Index"
          xreflabel="cycle counters:creating instructions for;cycle counts:creating instructions for" />
          <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor629553">
              <primary>cycle counters</primary>

              <secondary>creating instructions for</secondary>
            </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor629553">
              <primary>cycle counts</primary>

              <secondary>creating instructions for</secondary>
            </indexterm>Comments</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e2520">
            <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for
            entering Comments related to the Count Tag. Use the Comments field
            to enter any instructions or other Comments that need to reach and
            be read by the Inventory counters.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para629555">To the far right of the screen, the following
      buttons are available:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para629556">CANCEL</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e258c">
            <para>Closes the screen without creating Count Tags, returning you
            to the application desktop.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para629557">CREATE TAGS</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e25d4">
            <para>Creates Count Tags.</para>

            <para id="Para629558">Count Tag Numbers are generated
            automatically in an ordered sequence.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
    </section>

    <xi:include href="../topics/freeze_thaw.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <section id="Section601522">
      <title><anchor id="Anchor552156" role="Index"
      xreflabel="count tags:creating by item;physical inventory:creating count tags" />
      <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor552156">
          <primary>count tags</primary>

          <secondary>creating by item</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor552156">
          <primary>physical inventory</primary>

          <secondary>creating count tags</secondary>
        </indexterm>Create Count Tag by Item</title>

      <para id="Para519219">Count Tags are used to spearhead Inventory counts.
      They are created manually and on-demand, and they are not tied to any
      particular cycle or frequency, as Cycle Count Tags are. To create a
      Count Tag by Item, select the "Create Count Tag by Item" option. The
      following screen will appear:</para>

      <para id="Para519223"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/IM_PI_createCTByItem.png"
                         id="Graphic526009" />
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption519224">Create Count Tag by Item</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <para id="Para519230">When creating Count Tags by Item, you are
      presented with the following options:</para>

      <tip>
        <para id="Para597896">By default, the system allows only one unposted
        Count Tag per Item Site. To view all unposted Count Tags in your
        system, see the Count Tag Edit List.</para>
      </tip>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519231">Item Number</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e2d24">
            <para>Enter the Item Number of the Item you want to create a Count
            Tag for.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para672000">UOM</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e2d6c">
            <para>Inventory Unit of Measure.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519235">Warehouse</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e2db4">
            <para>Specify the Warehouse you want the Count Tag created
            for.</para>

            <para id="Para519236">This field will remain blank until you enter
            an Item Number into the "Item Number" field. Once that is entered,
            the Warehouse(s) where the Item is located will display in the
            list.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para558254">Mark Created Count Tag as Priority</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e2dfc">
            <para>Select to give priority status to Count Tag.</para>

            <para id="Para596779">Count Tags marked as having priority status
            are listed first in any prioritized lists. For example, priority
            Count Tags will appear at the top of the Count Tag Edit List;
            whereas, non-priority Count Tags will appear at the bottom of the
            list.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para558255"><anchor id="Anchor558262" role="Index"
          xreflabel="freezing:of inventory;inventory:freezing at count tag creation" />
          <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor558262">
              <primary>freezing</primary>

              <secondary>of inventory</secondary>
            </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor558262">
              <primary>inventory</primary>

              <secondary>freezing at count tag creation</secondary>
            </indexterm>Freeze Inventory</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e2ed4">
            <para>Select to freeze Inventory.</para>

            <para id="Para558256">The Quantity on Hand value is not updated
            when a transaction is posted against a frozen Item Site. Instead,
            Inventory transactions are pooled and then posted later when the
            Item Site is unfrozen--or thawed. The Quantity on Hand is updated
            when the Item Site is thawed. For a detailed explanation of these
            concepts, see the <link endterm="Anchor80983" id="XRef558258"
            linkend="Anchor80983"> Freezing and Thawing</link>"Topic: Freezing
            and Thawing" section.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <note>
        <para id="Para530278">When an Item Site is frozen, any Warehouse
        activity entered against that Item Site--including Work Orders--will
        use the Quantity on Hand shown at the time of freezing.</para>
      </note>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para629675">Only for Specified Location</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e2f64">
            <para>Select if you want to create Count Tags for an individual
            Warehouse Location.</para>

            <para id="Para629676">If selected, you will have the option to
            specify which Warehouse Location you want to have Count Tags
            created for. This option enables you to count individual Warehouse
            Locations separately, without having to post counts for an entire
            Warehouse all at once.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <note>
        <para id="Para629683">An Item must have Multiple Location Control
        (MLC) turned ON to take advantage of the Count Tags by Location
        feature. If the Item is not multiply-located, then this option will
        not be available.</para>
      </note>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para596830"><anchor id="Anchor596826" role="Index"
          xreflabel="cycle counters:creating instructions for;cycle counts:creating instructions for" />
          <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor596826">
              <primary>cycle counters</primary>

              <secondary>creating instructions for</secondary>
            </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor596826">
              <primary>cycle counts</primary>

              <secondary>creating instructions for</secondary>
            </indexterm>Comments</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e3084">
            <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for
            entering Comments related to the Count Tag. Use the Comments field
            to enter any instructions or other Comments that need to reach and
            be read by the Inventory counters.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para519245">To the far right of the screen, the following
      buttons are available:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519246">CLOSE</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e30f0">
            <para>Closes the screen without creating a Count Tag, returning
            you to the application desktop.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519247">CREATE TAG</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e3138">
            <para>Creates Count Tag.</para>

            <para id="Para597832">Count Tag Numbers are generated
            automatically in an ordered sequence.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
    </section>

    <xi:include href="../topics/count_tags.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <section id="Section519249">
      <title><anchor id="Anchor552158" role="Index"
      xreflabel="cycle count tags:creating by warehouse;cycle counts:creating tags for;physical inventory:creating cycle count tags" />
      <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor552158">
          <primary>cycle count tags</primary>

          <secondary>creating by warehouse</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor552158">
          <primary>cycle counts</primary>

          <secondary>creating tags for</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor552158">
          <primary>physical inventory</primary>

          <secondary>creating cycle count tags</secondary>
        </indexterm>Create Cycle Count Tags by Warehouse</title>

      <para id="Para602275">Cycle Count Tags are used to count Inventory on a
      frequent basis, with the rate of frequency defined in the Item Site
      master. The following criteria are used to determine the order in which
      Cycle Count Tags will be created for a specified Warehouse(s):</para>

      <orderedlist continuation="restarts" inheritnum="ignore">
        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18fa57c">
          <para id="Para602383">The system scans the Item Site masters in the
          specified Warehouse(s), specifically targeting Cycle Count frequency
          settings.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18fa5a0">
          <para id="Para602387">The frequency settings are then compared to
          the last counted dates for each Item Site to determine which Item
          Sites have last counted dates most out of sync with their count
          frequency rate; Item Sites whose last counted dates are most out of
          sync with their stated frequency rate will have Cycle Count Tags
          created for them first.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18fa5c4">
          <para id="Para634890">After frequency and last counted date
          parameters have been considered, the Item Site's ABC Class is
          used--with A Class Item Sites having Cycle Count Tags created
          first.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18fa5e8">
          <para id="Para634911">Then, finally, Cycle Count Tags are created
          based on the Item Numbers for the Item Sites in ascending order
          (i.e., 1, 2, 3 ... A, B, C).</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18fa60c">
          <para id="Para602415">The total number of Cycle Count Tags to be
          created is determined beforehand.</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>

      <para id="Para602368">The difference between Cycle Count Tags and Count
      Tags is that Cycle Count Tags are generated dynamically, using the
      criteria listed above. Count Tags are generated manually, on
      demand.</para>

      <tip>
        <para id="Para595926">To monitor the frequency of Item Site Cycle
        Counts, view the "Last Counted" column in any of the Item Site
        Reports: by Item, by Class Code, etc. The Last Counted date represents
        the date a Count Tag was last posted (not simply issued) for the Item
        Site.</para>
      </tip>

      <para id="Para595923">To create Cycle Count Tags by Warehouse, select
      the "Create Cycle Count Tags by Warehouse" option. The following screen
      will appear:</para>

      <para id="Para519254"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/IM_PI_createCycleCTByWareho.png"
                         id="Graphic526024" />
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption519255">Create Cycle Count Tags by
            Warehouse</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <para id="Para519256">When creating Cycle Count Tags by Warehouse, you
      are presented with the following options:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519257">Warehouse</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18fa708">
            <para>Specify Warehouse where Cycle Count will be
            conducted.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519259">Mark Created Count Tag as Priority</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18fa750">
            <para>Select to give priority status to Count Tag.</para>

            <para id="Para596785">Count Tags marked as having priority status
            are listed first in any prioritized lists. For example, priority
            Count Tags will appear at the top of the Count Tag Edit List;
            whereas, non-priority Count Tags will appear at the bottom of the
            list.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519260"><anchor id="Anchor558298" role="Index"
          xreflabel="freezing:of inventory;inventory:freezing during cycle counts;cycle counts:freezing inventory during" />
          <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor558298">
              <primary>freezing</primary>

              <secondary>of inventory</secondary>
            </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor558298">
              <primary>inventory</primary>

              <secondary>freezing during cycle counts</secondary>
            </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor558298">
              <primary>cycle counts</primary>

              <secondary>freezing inventory during</secondary>
            </indexterm>Freeze Inventory</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18fa870">
            <para>Select to freeze Inventory.</para>

            <para id="Para519261">The Quantity on Hand value is not updated
            when a transaction is posted against a frozen Item Site. Instead,
            Inventory transactions are pooled and then posted later when the
            Item Site is unfrozen--or thawed. The Quantity on Hand is updated
            when the Item Site is thawed. For a detailed explanation of these
            concepts, see the <link endterm="Anchor80983" id="XRef530055"
            linkend="Anchor80983"> Freezing and Thawing</link>"Topic: Freezing
            and Thawing" section.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <note>
        <para id="Para629742">When an Item Site is frozen, any Warehouse
        activity entered against that Item Site--including Work Orders--will
        use the Quantity on Hand shown at the time of freezing.</para>
      </note>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para629749">Ignore Zero Balance Item Sites</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18fa900">
            <para>Select to ignore Item Sites which have a Quantity on Hand
            balance of zero.</para>

            <para id="Para629750">If selected, Count Tags will not be created
            for any Item Site having a Quantity on Hand balance of
            zero.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519262">Maximum Number of Tags to Create</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18fa948">
            <para>Select a number using the arrow buttons, or manually enter a
            value up to a maximum of 1,000.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para629755">Item Sites in</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18fa990">
            <para>Specify which of the following codes you want to have Cycle
            Count Tags created for:</para>

            <para id="Para629783">Class Code: If selected, you will be
            presented with Class Code options.</para>

            <para id="Para629787">Planner Code: If selected, you will be
            presented with Planner Code options.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para629772">Only for Specified Location</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18fa9d8">
            <para>Select if you want to create Count Tags for an individual
            Warehouse Location.</para>

            <para id="Para629773">If selected, you will have the option to
            specify which Warehouse Location you want to have Count Tags
            created for. This option enables you to count individual Warehouse
            Locations separately, without having to post counts for an entire
            Warehouse all at once.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para596841"><anchor id="Anchor596837" role="Index"
          xreflabel="cycle counters:creating instructions for;cycle counts:creating instructions for" />
          <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor596837">
              <primary>cycle counters</primary>

              <secondary>creating instructions for</secondary>
            </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor596837">
              <primary>cycle counts</primary>

              <secondary>creating instructions for</secondary>
            </indexterm>Comments</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18faab0">
            <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for
            entering Comments related to the Cycle Count. Use the Comments
            field to enter any instructions or other Comments that need to
            reach and be read by the cycle counters.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para519268">To the far right of the screen, the following
      buttons are available:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519269">CLOSE</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18fab1c">
            <para>Closes the screen without creating a Count Tag, returning
            you to the application desktop.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519270">CREATE TAGS</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18fab64">
            <para>Creates Cycle Count Tags.</para>

            <para id="Para604805">Cycle Count Tag Numbers are generated
            automatically in an ordered sequence.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
    </section>

    <xi:include href="../topics/cycle_counting.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <section id="Section519273">
      <title><anchor id="Anchor552160" role="Index"
      xreflabel="count slips:entering of;physical inventory:entering count slips" />
      <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor552160">
          <primary>count slips</primary>

          <secondary>entering of</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor552160">
          <primary>physical inventory</primary>

          <secondary>entering count slips</secondary>
        </indexterm>Enter Count Slip</title>

      <para id="Para519274">Count Slips are used for contributing Inventory
      count totals to unposted Count Tags. Unlike Count Tags, however, Count
      Slips do not have to be created before they can be entered. To enter a
      Count Slip, select the "Enter Count Slip" option. The following screen
      will appear:</para>

      <para id="Para519278"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/IM_PI_enterCountSlip.png"
                         id="Graphic526034" />
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption519279">Enter Count Slip</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <para id="Para519280">When entering a Count Slip, you are presented with
      the following options:</para>

      <tip>
        <para id="Para597980">Restrictions may be imposed on the creation of
        Count Slips. To learn more, see the <link endterm="Anchor19758"
        id="XRef598062" linkend="Anchor19758"> Configure I/M</link>"Configure
        I/M" section of the <link endterm="Anchor30917" id="XRef598067"
        linkend="Anchor30917"> System Module</link>System Module
        chapter.</para>
      </tip>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519284">Count Tag #</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19073e8">
            <para>Enter the Count Tag Number of the Count Tag you want to
            enter a Count Slip toward.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519286">Item Number</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1907430">
            <para>Displays Item Number automatically when Count Tag Number is
            entered into "Count Tag #" field.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para672005">UOM</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1907478">
            <para>Inventory Unit of Measure.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519290">Warehouse</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19074c0">
            <para>Specify Warehouse where count is being conducted.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519292">Counted Qty. TD</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1907508">
            <para>Displays total for specified Count Tag to date.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519297">Slip #</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1907550">
            <para>Enter a Count Slip Number to identify the Count Slip. Some
            restrictions may apply. To learn more about Count Slip numbering
            restrictions, see the <link endterm="Anchor19758" id="XRef530363"
            linkend="Anchor19758"> Configure I/M</link>"Configure I/M" section
            of the <link endterm="Anchor30917" id="XRef529029"
            linkend="Anchor30917"> System Module</link>System Module
            chapter.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519302">Slip Qty</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1907598">
            <para>Enter the Physical Count total.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para544355">Location</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19075e0">
            <para>Specify the Location you want the Count Slip created
            for.</para>

            <para id="Para552552">The list will show all valid Warehouse
            Locations for the specified Item.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para552553">Lot/Serial #</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1907628">
            <para>Displays related Lot/Serial Number information, if
            applicable.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para631875">Lot Expiration</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1907670">
            <para>If a Lot-controlled Item Site is also perishable, you will
            have the option to enter an expiration date for the counted
            quantity.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para552557">Comments</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19076b8">
            <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for
            entering Comments related to the Count Slip.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para519309">To the far right of the screen, the following
      buttons are available:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para559613">CANCEL</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1907724">
            <para>Closes the screen without creating a Count Slip, returning
            you to the application desktop.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para559614">SAVE</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x190776c">
            <para>Creates Count Slip and adds Count Slip quantity to the total
            of the specified Count Tag.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
    </section>

    <section id="Section519313">
      <title><anchor id="Anchor552162" role="Index"
      xreflabel="count tags:entering of;physical inventory:entering count tags" />
      <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor552162">
          <primary>count tags</primary>

          <secondary>entering of</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor552162">
          <primary>physical inventory</primary>

          <secondary>entering count tags</secondary>
        </indexterm>Enter Count Tag</title>

      <para id="Para519314">Once a Count Tag has been created, the Count Tag
      is ready to have Inventory quantities entered into it. To enter a Count
      Tag, select the "Enter Count Tag" option. The following screen will
      appear:</para>

      <para id="Para519318"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/IM_PI_enterCountTag.png"
                         id="Graphic526054" />
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption519319">Enter Count Tag</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <para id="Para519320">When entering a Count Tag, you are presented with
      the following options:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519324">Count Tag #</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19078f8">
            <para>Enter the Count Tag Number of the Count Tag you want to
            enter details for.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519326">Item Number</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1907940">
            <para>Displays Item Number automatically when Count Tag Number is
            entered into "Count Tag #" field.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para672011">UOM</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1907988">
            <para>Inventory Unit of Measure.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519330">Warehouse</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19079d0">
            <para>Displays Warehouse where count will take place.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519335">Count Qty.</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1907a18">
            <para>Enter the Physical Count total.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519337">Current Comments</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1907a60">
            <para>Display lists all Comments added prior to the current
            session.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para530177"><anchor id="Anchor596870" role="Index"
          xreflabel="cycle counters:creating instructions for;cycle counts:creating instructions for" />
          <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor596870">
              <primary>cycle counters</primary>

              <secondary>creating instructions for</secondary>
            </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor596870">
              <primary>cycle counts</primary>

              <secondary>creating instructions for</secondary>
            </indexterm>New Comments</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1907b38">
            <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for
            entering Comments related to the Count Tag. Use the Comments field
            to enter any instructions or other Comments that need to reach and
            be read by the cycle counters.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para519344">To the far right of the screen, the following
      buttons are available:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519345">CANCEL</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1907ba4">
            <para>Closes the screen without creating a Count Tag, returning
            you to the application desktop.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519346">SAVE</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1907bec">
            <para>Creates Count Tag and adds specified quantity to the Count
            Tag total.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
    </section>

    <section id="Section519348">
      <title><anchor id="Anchor552164" role="Index"
      xreflabel="inventory counts:entering miscellaneous;physical inventory:entering miscellaneous count" />
      <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor552164">
          <primary>inventory counts</primary>

          <secondary>entering miscellaneous</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor552164">
          <primary>physical inventory</primary>

          <secondary>entering miscellaneous count</secondary>
        </indexterm>Enter Miscellaneous Inventory Count</title>

      <para id="Para519349">Miscellaneous Inventory counts can be used to
      enter Inventory totals without engaging the Count Tag or Count Slip
      mechanisms. Entering a miscellaneous Inventory count is a simplified
      method for entering Inventory counts. To enter a miscellaneous Inventory
      count, select the "Enter Misc. Inventory Count" option. The following
      screen will appear:</para>

      <para id="Para519353"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/IM_PI_enterMiscInventoryCou.png"
                         id="Graphic526069" />
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption519354">Enter Miscellaneous Inventory
            Count</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <para id="Para519360">When entering a miscellaneous Inventory count, you
      are presented with the following options:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519361">Item Number</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1912d68">
            <para>Enter the Item Number of the Item you want to enter a
            miscellaneous Inventory count for.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para672018">UOM</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1912db0">
            <para>Inventory Unit of Measure.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519365">Warehouse</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1912df8">
            <para>Specify the Warehouse where you want to record the
            miscellaneous Inventory Count.</para>

            <para id="Para519366">This field will remain blank until you enter
            an Item Number into the "Item Number" field. Once that is entered,
            the Warehouse(s) where the Item is located will display in the
            list.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519370">Count Qty.</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1912e40">
            <para>Enter the miscellaneous Count total.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519375">Comments</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1912e88">
            <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for
            entering Comments related to the Count Tag.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <tip>
        <para id="Para568884">To view a miscellaneous Count total that has
        been entered into the system, open any of the Physical Inventory
        displays featuring Count Tags. While a miscellaneous Count is not
        assigned a Count Tag number, its total will be shown in these Physical
        Inventory displays.</para>
      </tip>

      <para id="Para568880">To the far right of the screen, the following
      buttons are available:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519378">CANCEL</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1912f18">
            <para>Closes the screen without posting a miscellaneous Count,
            returning you to the application desktop.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519379">POST COUNT</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1912f60">
            <para>Posts miscellaneous Count.</para>

            <para id="Para519380">Count quantity is added to the total
            Quantity on Hand.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
    </section>

    <section id="Section519381">
      <title><anchor id="Anchor552166" role="Index"
      xreflabel="count tags:zeroing uncounted by warehouse;zeroing:of uncounted count tags;warehouses:zeroing uncounted count tags in" />
      <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor552166">
          <primary>count tags</primary>

          <secondary>zeroing uncounted by warehouse</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor552166">
          <primary>zeroing</primary>

          <secondary>of uncounted count tags</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor552166">
          <primary>warehouses</primary>

          <secondary>zeroing uncounted count tags in</secondary>
        </indexterm>Zero Uncounted Count Tags by Warehouse</title>

      <para id="Para519382"><anchor id="Anchor577187" role="Index"
      xreflabel="physical inventory:zeroing uncounted count tags;count tags:zeroing uncounted" />
      <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor577187">
          <primary>physical inventory</primary>

          <secondary>zeroing uncounted count tags</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor577187">
          <primary>count tags</primary>

          <secondary>zeroing uncounted</secondary>
        </indexterm>In the event that Count Tags remain uncounted for a
      excessive period of time, you have the ability to enter for these
      uncounted Count Tags a quantity of zero ("0"). Entering a non-null value
      of zero makes it possible to process and post the Count Tags. To reset
      the counted values of uncounted Count Tags to zero, select the "Zero
      Uncounted Count Tags by Warehouse" option. The following screen will
      appear:</para>

      <para id="Para519386"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/IM_PI_zeroUncountedCTByWare.png"
                         id="Graphic526079" />
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption519387">Zero Uncounted Count Tags by
            Warehouse</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <para id="Para519388">When zeroing uncounted Count Tags by Warehouse,
      you are presented with the following options:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry role="openmfg">
          <term id="Para581496">All Warehouses</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19131a0">
            <para>Select to reset uncounted Count Tags to zero for all
            Warehouses.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry role="openmfg">
          <term id="Para581497">Selected</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19131c4">
            <para>Specify Warehouse where uncounted Count Tags are to be
            zeroed.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para581501">Comments</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x191320c">
            <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for
            entering Comments related to the zeroing process.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para519398">To the far right of the screen, the following
      buttons are available:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519399">CLOSE</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1913278">
            <para>Closes the screen without resetting uncounted Count Tags to
            zero, returning you to the application desktop.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519400">ZERO</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19132c0">
            <para>Resets uncounted Count Tags values to zero.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
    </section>

    <section id="Section519401">
      <title><anchor id="Anchor552168" role="Index"
      xreflabel="item sites:thawing by class code;item sites:thawing by warehouse;thawing:of item sites;physical inventory:thawing item sites" />
      <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor552168">
          <primary>item sites</primary>

          <secondary>thawing by class code</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor552168">
          <primary>item sites</primary>

          <secondary>thawing by warehouse</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor552168">
          <primary>thawing</primary>

          <secondary>of item sites</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor552168">
          <primary>physical inventory</primary>

          <secondary>thawing item sites</secondary>
        </indexterm>Thaw Item Sites by Class Code/Warehouse</title>

      <para id="Para519402">To thaw previously frozen Item Sites by Class Code
      and Warehouse, select the "Thaw Item Sites by Class Code Warehouse"
      option. The following screen will appear:</para>

      <para id="Para519406"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/IM_PI_thawItemSitesByClass.png"
                         id="Graphic526098" />
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption519407">Thaw Item Sites by Class
            Code/Warehouse</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <note>
        <para id="Para524344">For a detailed explanation of freezing and
        thawing, see the <link endterm="Anchor80983" id="XRef530069"
        linkend="Anchor80983"> Freezing and Thawing</link>"Topic: Freezing and
        Thawing" section.</para>
      </note>

      <para id="Para580851">When thawing previously frozen Item Sites by Class
      Code and Warehouse, you are presented with the following options:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para580852">All Class Codes</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1913500">
            <para>Select to thaw Item Sites by Warehouse for all Class
            Codes.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para580853">Selected</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1913548">
            <para>Specify Class Code whose Item Sites by Warehouse you want to
            thaw.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para547811">Pattern</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1913590">
            <para>Enter a Class Code pattern to select a range of Class
            Codes.</para>

            <para id="Para677052">Refine your search using Regular
            Expressions, as described in <link endterm="Anchor77806"
            id="XRef677051" linkend="Anchor77806"> Pattern Matching with
            Regular Expressions</link>"Topic: Pattern Matching with Regular
            Expressions".</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519414">Warehouse</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19135d8">
            <para>Specify Warehouse whose Item Sites are to be thawed.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para519416">To the far right of the screen, the following
      buttons are available:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519417">CANCEL</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1913644">
            <para>Closes the screen without thawing previously frozen Item
            Sites, returning you to the application desktop.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519418">THAW</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x191368c">
            <para>Thaws previously frozen Item Sites by specified Class
            Code(s) and Warehouse.</para>

            <para id="Para519419">For a detailed explanation of these
            concepts, see the <link endterm="Anchor80983" id="XRef530085"
            linkend="Anchor80983"> Freezing and Thawing</link>"Topic: Freezing
            and Thawing" section.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
    </section>

    <section id="Section519420">
      <title><anchor id="Anchor552170" role="Index"
      xreflabel="count slips:posting by warehouse;warehouses:posting count slips in;physical inventory:posting count slips" />
      <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor552170">
          <primary>count slips</primary>

          <secondary>posting by warehouse</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor552170">
          <primary>warehouses</primary>

          <secondary>posting count slips in</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor552170">
          <primary>physical inventory</primary>

          <secondary>posting count slips</secondary>
        </indexterm>Post Count Slips</title>

      <para id="Para596919">To post Count Slip totals to their respective
      Count Tag totals by Warehouse, select the "Post Count Slips" option. The
      following screen will appear:</para>

      <para id="Para596923"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/IM_PI_postCountSlipsByWare.png"
                         id="Graphic596921" />
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption596924">Post Count Slips by
            Warehouse</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <para id="Para519427">When posting Count Slips by Warehouse, you are
      presented with the following options:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry role="openmfg">
          <term id="Para519428">All Warehouses</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x191383c">
            <para>Select to post Count Slips for all Warehouses.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry role="openmfg">
          <term id="Para519430">Selected</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1913860">
            <para>Specify Warehouse where Count Slips are to be posted.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para519432">To the far right of the screen, the following
      buttons are available:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519433">CLOSE</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19138cc">
            <para>Closes the screen without posting Count Slip totals,
            returning you to the application desktop.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519434">POST</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1913914">
            <para>Posts Count Slip totals to their respective Count Tag
            totals.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
    </section>

    <section id="Section519435">
      <title><anchor id="Anchor552172" role="Index"
      xreflabel="count tags:posting by warehouse;warehouses:posting count tags in;physical inventory:posting count tags" />
      <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor552172">
          <primary>count tags</primary>

          <secondary>posting by warehouse</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor552172">
          <primary>warehouses</primary>

          <secondary>posting count tags in</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor552172">
          <primary>physical inventory</primary>

          <secondary>posting count tags</secondary>
        </indexterm>Post Count Tags</title>

      <para id="Para519436">To post Count Tag totals (i.e., Inventory counts)
      to the Quantity on Hand for their respective Item Sites for an entire
      Warehouse, select the "Post Count Tags" option. The following screen
      will appear:</para>

      <para id="Para519440"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/IM_PI_postCountTags.png"
                         id="Graphic526126" />
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption519441">Post Count Tags</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <para id="Para519442">When posting Count Tags, you are presented with
      the following options:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry role="openmfg">
          <term id="Para519443">All Warehouses</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x191a0b4">
            <para>Select to post Count Tags for all Warehouses.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry role="openmfg">
          <term id="Para519445">Selected</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x191a0d8">
            <para>Specify Warehouse where Count Tags are to be posted.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519447"><anchor id="Anchor558471" role="Index"
          xreflabel="thawing:of inventory;thawing:at count tag posting;count tags:thawing at posting" />
          <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor558471">
              <primary>thawing</primary>

              <secondary>of inventory</secondary>
            </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor558471">
              <primary>thawing</primary>

              <secondary>at count tag posting</secondary>
            </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor558471">
              <primary>count tags</primary>

              <secondary>thawing at posting</secondary>
            </indexterm>Thaw Frozen Inventory</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x191a1f8">
            <para>Select to thaw all previously frozen Inventory in specified
            Warehouse(s).</para>

            <para id="Para519448">For a detailed explanation of these
            concepts, see the <link endterm="Anchor80983" id="XRef530096"
            linkend="Anchor80983"> Freezing and Thawing</link>"Topic: Freezing
            and Thawing" section.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para634258">Item Sites in</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x191a240">
            <para>Specify which of the following codes you want to have Count
            Tags posted for:</para>

            <para id="Para634259">Class Code: If selected, you will be
            presented with Class Code options.</para>

            <para id="Para634260">Planner Code: If selected, you will be
            presented with Planner Code options.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para519449">To the far right of the screen, the following
      buttons are available:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519450">CANCEL</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x191a2ac">
            <para>Closes the screen without posting Count Slip totals,
            returning you to the application desktop.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519451">POST</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x191a2f4">
            <para>Posts Count Slip totals to their respective Count Tag
            totals.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
    </section>

    <section id="Section519452">
      <title><anchor id="Anchor552174" role="Index"
      xreflabel="count slips:purging posted;physical inventory:purging count slips" />
      <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor552174">
          <primary>count slips</primary>

          <secondary>purging posted</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor552174">
          <primary>physical inventory</primary>

          <secondary>purging count slips</secondary>
        </indexterm>Purge Posted Count Slips</title>

      <para id="Para519453">Purging Count Slips deletes the Count Slips from
      your system, freeing up disk storage space. To purge Count Slips from
      the system once they have been posted, select the "Purge Posted Count
      Slips" option. The following screen will appear:</para>

      <para id="Para519457"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/IM_PI_purgePostedCount.png"
                         id="Graphic526136" />
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption519458">Purge Posted Count Slips</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <para id="Para519459">When purging posted Count Slips, you are presented
      with the following options:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519463">Cutoff Date</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x191a480">
            <para>All posted Count Slips up to and including this date will be
            purged.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry role="openmfg">
          <term id="Para583355">All Warehouses</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x191a4a4">
            <para>Select to purge posted Count Slips for all
            Warehouses.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry role="openmfg">
          <term id="Para583356">Selected</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x191a4c8">
            <para>Specify Warehouse where posted Count Slips are to be
            purged.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para519469">To the far right of the screen, the following
      buttons are available:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519470">CANCEL</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x191a534">
            <para>Closes the screen without purging posted Count Slips,
            returning you to the application desktop.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519471">PURGE</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x191a57c">
            <para>Purges posted Count Slips from the system.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
    </section>

    <section id="Section519472">
      <title><anchor id="Anchor552176" role="Index"
      xreflabel="count tags:purging posted;physical inventory:purging count tags" />
      <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor552176">
          <primary>count tags</primary>

          <secondary>purging posted</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor552176">
          <primary>physical inventory</primary>

          <secondary>purging count tags</secondary>
        </indexterm>Purge Posted Count Tags</title>

      <para id="Para519473">Purging Count Tags deletes the Count Tags from
      your system, freeing up disk storage space. To purge Count Tags from the
      system once they have been posted, select the "Purge Posted Count Tags"
      option. The following screen will appear:</para>

      <para id="Para519477"><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/IM_PI_purgePostedTags.png"
                         id="Graphic526148" />
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption519478">Purge Posted Count Tags</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <para id="Para519479">When purging posted Count Tags, you are presented
      with the following options:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519483">Cutoff Date</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x191a708">
            <para>All posted Count Tags up to and including this date will be
            purged.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry role="openmfg">
          <term id="Para519485">All Warehouses</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x191a72c">
            <para>Select to purge posted Count Tags for all Warehouses.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry role="openmfg">
          <term id="Para519487">Selected</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x191a750">
            <para>Specify Warehouse where posted Count Tags are to be
            purged.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <para id="Para519489">To the far right of the screen, the following
      buttons are available:</para>

      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519490">CANCEL</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x191a7bc">
            <para>Closes the screen without purging posted Count Tags,
            returning you to the application desktop.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term id="Para519491">PURGE</term>

          <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x191a804">
            <para>Purges posted Count Tags from the system.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
    </section>

    <section id="Section519492">
      <title>Physical Inventory Reports</title>

      <para id="Para519493">The Physical Inventory area contains its own
      reports section.</para>
    </section>

    <xi:include href="guiclient/dspFrozenItemSites.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <xi:include href="guiclient/dspCountSlipEditList.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <xi:include href="guiclient/dspCountTagEditList.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <xi:include href="guiclient/dspCountSlipsByWarehouse.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <xi:include href="guiclient/dspCountTagsByItem.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <xi:include href="guiclient/dspCountTagsByWarehouse.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <xi:include href="guiclient/dspCountTagsByClassCode.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />
  </section>

  <section id="Section519902">
    <title>I/M Reports</title>

    <para id="Para519903">This section covers Reports.</para>

    <xi:include href="guiclient/dspItemSitesByItem.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <xi:include href="guiclient/dspItemSitesByClassCode.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <xi:include href="guiclient/dspItemSitesByPlannerCode.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <xi:include href="guiclient/dspItemSitesByCostCategory.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <xi:include href="guiclient/dspValidLocationsByItem.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <xi:include href="guiclient/dspQOHByItem.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <xi:include href="guiclient/dspQOHByClassCode.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <xi:include href="guiclient/dspQOHByItemGroup.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <xi:include href="guiclient/dspQOHByLocation.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <xi:include href="guiclient/dspInventoryLocator.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <xi:include href="guiclient/dspSlowMovingInventoryByClassCode.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <xi:include href="guiclient/dspExpiredInventoryByClassCode.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <xi:include href="guiclient/dspInventoryAvailabilityByItem.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <xi:include href="guiclient/dspInventoryAvailabilityByItemGroup.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <xi:include href="guiclient/dspInventoryAvailabilityByClassCode.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <xi:include href="guiclient/dspInventoryAvailabilityByPlannerCode.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <xi:include href="guiclient/dspInventoryAvailabilityBySourceVendor.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <xi:include href="guiclient/dspSubstituteAvailabilityByItem.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <xi:include href="guiclient/dspInventoryHistoryByItem.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <xi:include href="guiclient/dspInventoryHistoryByItemGroup.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <xi:include href="guiclient/dspInventoryHistoryByOrderNumber.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <xi:include href="guiclient/dspInventoryHistoryByClassCode.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <xi:include href="guiclient/dspInventoryHistoryByClassCode.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <xi:include href="guiclient/dspDetailedInventoryHistoryByLotSerial.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <xi:include href="guiclient/dspDetailedInventoryHistoryByLocation.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <xi:include href="guiclient/dspUsageStatisticsByItem.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <xi:include href="guiclient/dspUsageStatisticsByClassCode.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <xi:include href="guiclient/dspUsageStatisticsByItemGroup.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <xi:include href="guiclient/dspUsageStatisticsByWarehouse.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <xi:include href="guiclient/dspTimePhasedUsageStatisticsByItem.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <xi:include href="guiclient/printItemLabelsByClassCode.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />
  </section>

  <section id="Section521425">
    <title><anchor id="Anchor552326" role="Index"
    xreflabel="utilities:in i/m module" /> <indexterm significance="normal"
        zone="Anchor552326">
        <primary>utilities</primary>

        <secondary>in i/m module</secondary>
      </indexterm>Utilities</title>

    <para id="Para521426">The Utilities for the module are located in this
    section.</para>

    <xi:include href="guiclient/dspUnbalancedQOHByClassCode.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <section id="Section521432">
      <title><anchor id="Anchor552328" role="Index"
      xreflabel="item controls:updating of;item sites:update controls for" />
      <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor552328">
          <primary>item controls</primary>

          <secondary>updating of</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor552328">
          <primary>item sites</primary>

          <secondary>update controls for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Update Item Controls</title>

      <para id="Para539291">The utilities featured in this section are
      designed for updating several of the controls required for the effective
      management of Inventory. To access this section, select the "Update Item
      Controls" option.</para>
    </section>

    <xi:include href="guiclient/updateABCClass.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <xi:include href="guiclient/updateCycleCountFrequency.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <xi:include href="guiclient/updateItemSiteLeadTimes.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <xi:include href="guiclient/updateReorderLevelByItem.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <xi:include href="guiclient/updateReorderLevels.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <xi:include href="guiclient/updateReorderLevelsByClassCode.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <xi:include href="guiclient/updateOUTLevelByItem.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <xi:include href="guiclient/updateOUTLevels.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <xi:include href="guiclient/updateOUTLevelsByClassCode.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <xi:include href="guiclient/summarizeInvTransByClassCode.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />

    <xi:include href="guiclient/createItemSitesByClassCode.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(/1)" />
  </section>
</chapter>