<?xml version='1.0'?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.0/docbookx.dtd">
<article>

  <title>Predefined System Queries</title>

  <synopsis>Review and detail the two predefined system queries and the 
  possible fields that can be referenced from them.</synopsis>
  <para>When creating fields and text labels you have the ability to 
  select a query source and specify a field from that query source to 
  pull information from. Two predefined query sources are defined by 
  the system, Context Query and Parameter Query.</para>

  <section>

    <title>Parameter Query</title>

    <para>The Parameter Query allows you to reference any of the 
    parameter variables that are passed to the report renderer at the 
    time the report is rendered. You can reference the name of any of 
    the parameters and get the passed in value as the result.</para>

  </section>

  <section>

    <title>Context Query</title>

    <para>The Context Query defines several fields that can be 
    referenced that are either defined elsewhere in the report 
    definition for convenience or is information that changes for 
    rendering to rendering of the report for one reason or 
    another.</para>

    <para>Following is a list of the different fields that can 
    references from the Context Query and what they return</para>

    <variablelist>

      <varlistentry>

        <term>report_name</term>

        <listitem>

          <para>This field returns the value as specified in the report 
          Name of the documents properties.</para>

        </listitem>

      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>

        <term>report_title</term>

        <listitem>

          <para>This field returns the value as specified in the report 
          Title of the documents properties.</para>

        </listitem>

      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>

        <term>report_description</term>

        <listitem>

          <para>This field returns the value as specified in teh report 
          Description of the documents properties.</para>

        </listitem>

      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>

        <term>report_date</term>

        <listitem>

          <para>This field returns the current date the report is 
          rendered on using the function formatDate(CURRENT_DATE) for 
          formatting purposes.</para>

        </listitem>

      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>

        <term>report_time</term>

        <listitem>

          <para>This field returns the current time the report is 
          rendered on using the function formatTime(CURRENT_TIMESTAMP) 
          for formatting purposes.</para>

        </listitem>

      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>

        <term>page_number</term>

        <listitem>

          <para>This field returns the current page number that is 
          being rendered when the field is referenced.</para>

        </listitem>

      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>

        <term>page_count</term>

        <listitem>

          <para>This field returns the total page count of the report
          being rendered.</para>

        </listitem>

      </varlistentry>

    </variablelist>

  </section>

</article>

