<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section>
  <title>The XTreeWidget</title>

  <note>
      <para>This file is currently a test of how widgets documentation should be
    written. Let's build an outline as we figure out what the structure should
    be, then do one or two more widgets until we find a structure that works.
    Then we can start writing them all. A good place to get initial content
    might be the Introduction chapter of the User Guide.</para>

      <para>We should also be careful in how we word things. Some individual
    elements (like the Export Contents... varlistentry in the variablelist
    under Right-click menus) might eventually be incorporated by reference in
    other sections or documents. Some elements might have roles that control
    whether they're visible in other contexts, e.g. the entire document might
    be included in the introduction but we might want the Application
    Programming Interface section hidden there and visible in the Developers'
    Guide.</para>
  </note>

  <para>introductory material describing the purpose of the XTreeWidget</para>

  <para>presents data in tabular form</para>

  <section>
      <title>Behavior visible to the user</title>

      <section>
         <title>Sorting Data</title>

         <para>sorting columns</para>
      </section>

      <section>
         <title>Column Memory</title>

         <para>column width memory</para>

         <para>column visibility memory</para>
      </section>

      <section>
         <title>Right-click menus</title>

         <para>Every XTreeWidget can produce a popup menu. The contents of this
      menu differ from one window to another, but every menu contains the
      following:</para>

         <variablelist>
            <varlistentry id="xtreewidget.menu.exportcontents">
               <term>
                  <guimenuitem moreinfo="none">Export Contents</guimenuitem>
               </term>

               <listitem>
                  <para>Export the data displayed on the screen into a plain-text,
            TAB-delimited file. This file may subsequently be imported into a
            spreadsheet or other office tool.</para>
               </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
         </variablelist>
      </section>
  </section>

  <section>
      <title>Application Programming Interface</title>

      <para>Slots</para>

      <para>Signals</para>

      <para>Public Methods</para>

      <para>Protected Methods</para>

      <para>Properties</para>
  </section>

  <section>
      <title>Internals</title>

      <para/>
  </section>
</section>