<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2010 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section531874">
  <title id="Anchor28097"><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>receiving</primary>
      <secondary>entering receipts</secondary>
    </indexterm>Enter Receipt</title>
  <para>To receive Orders into Inventory, select the "Enter Receipt" option.
  The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/enterPoReceipt.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Enter Order Receipts</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When receiving an Order, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Order #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the Order Number of the Purchase Order, Transfer Order or
        Return Authorization whose Line Item(s) you want to receive into
        Inventory. The lookup feature located to the right of the field leads
        to a searchable list of Purchase Orders available for receiving. This
        option will be disabled if a Transfer Order is specified.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="standard">
      <term>Drop Ship</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>If your system is configured to use drop shipping, this
        informational, read-only field will be displayed. It will be selected
        if the Purchase Order entered is a drop ship Order. When receipts for
        drop ship items are posted, the linked Sales Order items will be
        automatically shipped.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="standard">
      <term>Assign all Lot Controlled Items to single Lot #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you want all the Lot-controlled Items in a Receiving
        session to be assigned the same Lot Number. Lot Numbers are assigned
        when Receipt(s) are posted. This option applies to Lot-controlled
        Items only. There is no impact on received Items which are not
        Lot-controlled. For perishable Items, you will also be given the
        opportunity to enter an expiration date. Expiration dates apply only
        to Item Sites marked as perishable.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Order Line Items</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists Order Line Items available for receipt
        confirmation.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>Before a Purchase Order can be received successfully, A/P Account
    Assignments for the specified Vendor must be in place.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Receive Items using bar code:</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This is an optional field which allows you to receive Inventory
        using a Bar Code scanner. Enter a Bar Code for a Purchase Order Line
        Item using a Bar Code scanner&mdash;or manually enter the Bar Code.
        The Bar Code for an Item is stored on the Item master. Once the code
        is entered, specify a quantity and then select the FIND button to
        receive the Inventory quantity. You may also hit the ENTER key on your
        keyboard to select the FIND button.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <variablelist>
    <tip>
      <para>Most scanners allow you to change a setting that automatically
      sends the ENTER command after a scan. This allows keyboard-free
      entry.</para>
    </tip>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty.</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the quantity of Line Items to be received using a Bar
        Code. To receive the Line Item quantity, select the FIND
        button&mdash;or hit the ENTER key on your keyboard to select the FIND
        button.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Auto Post</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to post Line Items automatically as they are entered into
        the system. This provides the opportunity to skip the additional step
        of posting once the Receipt is complete.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without entering a Receipt, returning you to
        the application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>PRINT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to print the paperwork associated with the specified
        Order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>POST</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select this button to post the Receipt quantity to
        Inventory.</para>
        <para role="standard"><note>
            <para>When posting receipts for Lot/Serial controlled Items on a
            Return Authorization, you will be prompted to assign Lot/Serial
            Numbers for tracking purposes.</para>
          </note></para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select this button to save the Receipt quantity for posting at a
        later time. Saved Receipts may be posted later from the List Unposted
        Receipts screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>PRINT LABEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a Line Item, then select this button to print a
        Receiving Label for the specified Line Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>ENTER RECEIPT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a Line Item, then select this button to reach the
        Receipt detail screen. Double-clicking on a Line Item will also bring
        you to the Receipt entry screen. This option will be disabled if a
        Transfer Order is specified.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>RECEIVE ALL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to receive all Line Items simultaneously.</para>
        <note>
          <para>If the Item you are receiving is a <indexterm
              significance="normal">
              <primary>multiple location control</primary>
              <secondary>impact on receiving</secondary>
            </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
              <primary>receiving</primary>
              <secondary>MLC impact on</secondary>
            </indexterm>Multiple Location Control (MLC) Item, you will be
          prompted to specify the Location you want to distribute the stock
          to.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>FIND</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Compares the Bar Code entered in the "Receive Items using bar
        code" field with the Bar Codes for the listed Purchase Order Line
        Items, then receives the quantity specified in the "Qty." field. The
        FIND button may be selected using your mouse&mdash;or by hitting the
        ENTER key, which corresponds to the FIND button. Because the FIND
        button corresponds to the ENTER key, you can scan in a Bar Code and
        then hit ENTER to receive a quantity of one. If you prefer, you can
        scan in a Bar Code and then specify a different quantity before
        hitting ENTER.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <xi:include href="enterPoitemReceipt.xml" xpointer="element(/1)"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
</section>
