<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2008 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section923259">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>configuration</primary>
      <secondary>of manufacture module</secondary>
    </indexterm>Configure Manufacture</title>
  <para>To configure the Manufacture module, select the "Configure
  Manufacture" option. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/configureWO.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Configure Manufacture Module</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When configuring the Manufacture module, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>work orders</primary>
          <secondary>numbering of</secondary>
        </indexterm>Next Work Order #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The next sequentially available Work Order Number will display
        here. You may change the number&mdash;creating a new basis for the
        next Work Order Number&mdash;by typing the new number into this field.
        Any changes you make here will be reflected the next time a new Work
        Order is created.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>W/O Number Creation</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select one of the available Work Order Number creation
        methods:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Automatic</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Work Order Numbers will be automatically incremented by 1
              each time a new Work Order is created. These
              automatically-generated numbers may not be edited. They are
              read-only.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Manual</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Work Order Numbers must be entered manually whenever you
              create a new Work Order.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Automatic, Allow Override</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Work Order Numbers will be automatically generated and
              incremented, as under the "Automatic" option described above.
              However, this option also allows you to manually override the
              Work Order Number at the time of Work Order creation.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>work orders</primary>
          <secondary>automatic explosion of</secondary>
        </indexterm>Automatically Explode W/O's</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you want Work Orders to be exploded automatically.
        Work Order explosion is the process whereby Work Order Material
        Requirements and Work Order Operations are created for a Work Order.
        If this option is selected, all parent Work Order Items will be
        exploded by default. Child Work Orders will also be exploded by
        default, if the Bill of Materials for the parent Item specifies that
        child Work Orders should be created when the parent Work Order is
        exploded. If this option is not selected, Work Orders will need to be
        exploded manually.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="manufacturing">
      <term>Auto fill Post Operation Qty. to Balance</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Check this option if you want quantities to be automatically be
        populated with the quantity balance due when posting
        Operations.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Post Work Order Changes to the Change Log</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to post to the Change Log any changes made to Work
        Orders.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Explode W/O's Effective as of</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select one of the following Work Order explosion effectivity
        dates:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Date of Explosion</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Explode Work Orders effective on the date of explosion,
              incorporating Bills of Materials and Bills of Operations
              effective on that date.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>W/O Start Date</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Explode Work Orders effective on the scheduled start date,
              incorporating Bills of Materials and Bills of Operations
              effective on that date.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>Pick a default explosion level if you have not configured the W/O
    module to automatically explode Work Orders. If Work Orders are exploded
    by default, the selection of an explosion level is not relevant.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>work orders</primary>
          <secondary>default explosion levels for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Default W/O Explosion Level</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select one of the following default explosion levels, if Work
        Orders will not be exploded automatically by default:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Single Level</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>This option specifies that when Work Orders are exploded,
              requirements should be created for the parent Work Order Items
              only.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Multiple Level</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>This option specifies that requirements should be created
              for both parent and child Work Orders.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>Performing a multiple level explosion does not create child Work
    Orders. Child Work Orders must first be created before they can be
    exploded. The easiest way to ensure that child Work Orders are created for
    manufactured components is to select the "Create Child W/O at Parent W/O
    Explosion" option found on the Bill of Materials.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>work orders</primary>
          <secondary>default variance reporting for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Inventory Item Cost Defaults</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify preferences for the following defaults:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Post Material Usage Variances</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to post material usage variances whenever Work
              Order production is posted.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry role="manufacturing">
            <term>Post Labor Variances</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to post labor variances whenever Work Order
              Operations are posted.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>W/O Item Cost Recognition Defaults</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select one of the following Cost of Sales recognition defaults
        for Job Items:</para>
        <note>
          <para>The default method will be used when creating Work Orders for
          Job Items. The method may be changed manually at the Work Order
          header level.</para>
        </note>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>To Date</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>When Work Orders for Job items are shipped, all of the WIP
              costs accumulated to date will be charged to Cost of
              Sales.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Proportional</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>When Work Orders for Job items are shipped, a value up to
              the proportional value of the total quantity shipped will be
              charged to Cost of Sales. For example, if 3 Items are to be
              shipped on a Job Work Order and all the material has been
              issued&mdash;and if only 1 of the 3 is shipped&mdash;then 1/3 of
              the value charged to WIP at that point will be charged to Cost
              of Sales.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para role="manufacturing">The appropriate reporting selections must be
    made in the Bill of Operations to ensure that labor and overhead Costs
    associated with setup and run time Operations are reported.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Shop Floor Workbench Posts</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select the Work Order processing method to be used by the Shop
        Floor Workbench:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Production</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to require a Production-posting approach on the
              Shop Floor Workbench.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry role="manufacturing">
            <term>Operations</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to require an Operations-posting approach on the
              Shop Floor Workbench.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note role="manufacturing">
    <para>The Shop Floor Workbench cannot be used in a dual mode. The
    Workbench must be configured to use either a Production-posting or an
    Operations-posting approach.</para>
  </note>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Cancels any configuration settings, returning you to the
        application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Saves the configuration settings, returning you to the
        application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>