<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2008 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="location">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>site locations</primary>
      <secondary>creating new</secondary>
    </indexterm>Site Location</title>
  <para>To create a new Site Location, select the NEW button. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/location.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="NewSiteLocation">Create New Site
        Location</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When creating a new Site Location, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Site</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify Site for the Site Location.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>site locations</primary>
          <secondary>netable</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>netable</primary>
          <secondary>site location as</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>non-netable</primary>
          <secondary>site location as</secondary>
        </indexterm>Netable</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you want Items in the Location to be included in
        Quantity on Hand and Availability calculations. Not selecting means
        Items in the Location are non-netable. Items stored in a non-netable
        Location are not included in Quantity on Hand or Availability
        totals.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>When an Item is received into a non-netable Location, the Inventory
    transaction history will reflect a two-step process. First, the Quantity
    on Hand for the Item will be increased in the quantity received. Second, a
    non-netable (NN) correction will occur. This correction returns the
    Quantity on Hand to the pre-receipt levels&mdash;indicating a receipt into a
    non-netable Location. Again, quantity stored in a non-netable Location is
    considered separately. Changes in non-netable quantity do not affect
    bottom-line Quantity on Hand levels.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>site locations</primary>
          <secondary>restricted</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>restricted</primary>
          <secondary>site location as</secondary>
        </indexterm>Restricted</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if only a restricted set of Items may be placed in this
        Location. Not selecting means any Item that exists in the same
        Site as this Location may be placed into it.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>site zones</primary>
          <secondary>locations within</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>site locations</primary>
          <secondary>within zones</secondary>
        </indexterm>Zone</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the Site Zone you want to associate with the
        Location, if any. Zone selection will be activated only if Site
        Zones have been defined for the specified Site.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a name to identify the Location. The name of the Location
        will vary, depending on whether the specified Site enforces the
        aisle, rack, bin, Location (ARBL) naming convention. If the convention
        is enforced, then the name for the Location may also include aisle,
        rack, or bin information. If ARBL is not enforced, then the Location
        name will consist of only one field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>The parameters for the ARBL naming convention are set within a
    Site master. These parameters include the maximum length allowed for
    names and whether alpha characters or numeric only may be used.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Description</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering a
        description of the Location.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>allowable items</primary>
          <secondary>in site locations</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>site locations</primary>
          <secondary>allowable items in</secondary>
        </indexterm>Allowable Items</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display is only activated if the Location has been designated as
        restricted. If a Location is restricted, only certain Items are
        allowed to be stored there.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without creating the Site Location,
        returning you to the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Creates the Site Location and adds it to the master list of
        Site Locations.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to pick an Item from the master list of Items and
        designate it as allowed within the restricted Location.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>DELETE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight an Item and then select this button to remove the Item
        from the list of allowable items.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
