<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2008 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section>
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>screens</primary>
      <secondary>master list of</secondary>
    </indexterm>Screens</title>
  <para>Custom Screens are screens you can design, using QtDesigner, and then
  run within your xTuple ERP application. Essentially, a screen is a UI form
  which specifies widgets and layout information. Just like scripts, screens
  are stored in your xTuple database using the functionality described in this
  section. To take advantage of this functionality, you should have a basic
  understanding of how to program using <ulink
  url="http://www.ecma-international.org/publications/standards/Ecma-262.htm">ECMAScript</ulink>
  and create UI screens using <ulink
  url="http://trolltech.com/products/qt/features/tools/designer">QtDesigner</ulink>.</para>
  <para><tip>
      <para>You can read more about creating custom screens and scripting in
      the Development Zone of our wiki at <ulink
      url="http://www.xtuple.org">www.xtuple.org</ulink>.</para>
    </tip>When creating a new screen, the first thing to do is give it a name.
  This name is then used to find matching scripts. Screens can be enabled or
  disabled—as well as have an order. You may have several screens with the
  same name; however, only the lowest enabled screen is used. In addition, you
  must export or import the UI file (i.e., you cannot edit the UI file
  directly on the database). And, creating a screen does not automatically
  make it available to users. You must first create a <xref
  linkend="customCommandTitle" /> to makes sure the screen is added to the
  menu structure.</para>
  <note>
    <para>Because screens are very limited in what they can be made to do
    without code or scripting, it will almost always be necessary to write one
    or more scripts for a screen.</para>
  </note>
  <para>To view the master list of available custom screens, select the
  "Screens" option. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/uiforms.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Screens Master List</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>The screens master list displays information on all custom screens,
  including screen name, description, order, and enabled status.</para>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CLOSE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the window, returning you to the application
        desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Opens window for adding a new custom screen to the screens
        master list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>EDIT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enables you to edit highlighted custom screens. The edit window
        is the same as that for creating a new custom screen&mdash;except that
        when editing, the fields will contain screen information.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>DELETE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a custom screen and then select this button to remove
        the custom screen from the master list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>TEST</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a custom screen and then select this button to launch
        the screen in the xTuple ERP application. If successful, the
        highlighted screen will appear within the xTuple framework (e.g., on
        the desktop). If the screen does not appear, then check your
        settings—and be sure you have imported your source UI file into the
        database.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <xi:include href="uiform.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
              xpointer="element(/1)" />
</section>