<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<article>
  <articleinfo>
    <title>Development Environment Setup</title>
    <author>
      <firstname></firstname>
      <surname></surname>
      <affiliation>
        <orgname></orgname>
      </affiliation>
    </author>
    <pubdate></pubdate>
  </articleinfo>
  <section>
    <title>Overview</title>
    <para>This document describes the tools you need and the steps you must
    follow to create a software environment to contribute to the xTuple ERP
    development effort. It assumes that you have a software development
    background, are familiar with the operating system you will be working on,
    are comfortable downloading software and source code bundles from the Web,
    and have worked with tools similar to those described below. This document
    does not describe the only way to do things, just those we have tried with
    success.</para>
    <tip>
      <para>Read this document in its entirety before attempting this
      process.</para>
    </tip>
    <para>The following tools all have to be present to successfully create a
    binary version of the xTuple ERP application.</para>
    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Subversion</term>
        <listitem>
          <para></para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Software Development Environment</term>
        <listitem>
          <para></para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Qt</term>
        <listitem>
          <para></para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>PostgreSQL</term>
        <listitem>
          <para></para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>cURL</term>
        <listitem>
          <para></para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
    <para>In addition to the information below, you may need the following
    information from xTuple before you begin:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Subversion tags to use when checking out the source code for
        OpenRPT and xTuple ERP.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Additional information to use when checking out source code
        specific to proprietary xTuple packages.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Setup Steps</title>
    <para>Here are the steps you need to follow to create a development
    environment. Basic goals and platform-independent information are given at
    the beginning of each step. This is immediately followed by
    platform-specific information.</para>
    <section>
      <title>Basic Development Tools</title>
      <para>The GUI client is a large application built in C++. You will need
      a C++ compiler and a version of the make utility.</para>
      <section>
        <title>Microsoft Windows using MinGW</title>
        <para>xTuple recommends using MinGW for developing on Windows although
        we have also tried Microsoft Visual C++ Express. Newer versions of the
        Qt SDK include MinGW.</para>
        <para>If you need to obtain MinGW separately:</para>
        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Point your browser to
            http://sourceforge.net/projects/mingw/</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para></para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para></para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
      </section>
      <section>
        <title>Microsoft Windows using Visual C++ Express Edition</title>
        <para></para>
      </section>
    </section>
  </section>
</article>
