<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2010 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="cashReceiptItem">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>cash receipts</primary>
      <secondary>applying to balance due</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>open items</primary>
      <secondary>applying cash receipts to</secondary>
    </indexterm>Cash Receipt Application</title>
  <para>To apply a Cash Receipt to an individual open A/R Item, select the
  APPLY button. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/cashReceiptItem.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Apply Cash Receipt</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <tip>
    <para>You will not be able to post a Cash Receipt if the amount applied is
    greater than the Cash Receipt total.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>When applying a Cash Receipt to an individual open Item, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Customer #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Customer Number of the Customer selected on the
        previous screen. The Customer name and billing address will also
        display. Select the "?" symbol to view Customer information for the
        specified Customer.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Doc. Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Document Number associated with the Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Doc. Type</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Document Type of the Document.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Doc. Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Document's origination date. In the case of a Sales
        Order, the Document date is the date when the Sales Order is
        created.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Due Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the date payment is due. In the case of a Sales Order,
        billing terms are defined in the Sales Order master.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Discount</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the amount of any Discount given when cash is applied
        to an open A/R item inside the billing Discount period for that
        item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Open Amount</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the amount due for the open Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Amount to Apply</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the Cash Receipt amount to apply to the open Item. You
        may not apply more than the open amount.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without applying a new Cash Receipt, returning
        you to the application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Applies the Cash Receipt to the open Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>EDIT DISCOUNT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to edit the Discount amount for the selected open A/R
        item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>Discounts are applied automatically when using the APPLY LINE BAL. or
  APPLY TO BALANCE buttons. However, you may have cases where you want to
  manually enter or override a Discount amount. When editing the Discount for
  an open A/R item, you are presented with the following screen:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/applyARDiscount.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Apply A/R Discount</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When editing the Discount for an open A/R item, you are presented with
  the following options</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Customer</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the name of the Customer whose open A/R item you are
        applying cash to.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Doc. Type</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Document Type. Valid Document Types include posted
        Invoices and miscellaneous A/R Debit Memos.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Doc #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Document Number of the Document you are applying
        cash to.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Doc. Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Document's origination date.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Terms</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the billing Terms selected at the time the Document was
        posted.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Discount Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the expiration date for the billing Terms Discount
        period. The Discount date will display in red type once the Discount
        period has expired. Once the Discount period has expired, the system
        will no longer automatically update the Discount amount field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Discount %</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Discount percentage, as specified in the billing
        Terms.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Total Owed</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the total amount from the original Document.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Discounts Applied</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the amount of any Discounts previously applied to the
        selected Document.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Discount Amount</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the amount of the Discount to be applied to the total
        owed. As long as the Discount period has not expired, the system will
        automatically calculate the Discount amount for you. The Discount
        amount will be equal to the total owed multiplied by the Discount
        percentage. The Account used for posting Discounts to the General
        Ledger (G/L) is defined on the A/R Account Assignments screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
