<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section role="standard">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>vendor catalog</primary>
      <secondary>costs for</secondary>
    </indexterm>Vendor Catalog Costs</title>
  <para>The Vendor Catalog Costs screen allows you to manage the costs
  associated with any External Vendor Catalog items which you've converted to
  Inventory Items in xTuple. From this one screen you can both view your
  converted Items and manage their Item costing information. Changes you make
  to an Item's costing information on this screen will be transferred to the
  xTuple Items when you run the update option.</para>
  <para>To view and manage your converted Vendor Catalog Items, select the
  "Vendor Catalog Costs" option. The following screen will appear.</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/catCostList.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Vendor Catalog Costs</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>The Vendor Catalog Costs screen displays cost and pricing information
  for xTuple Inventory Items converted from your External Vendor Catalog. Item
  Master and Item Source records are both displayed here. To modify
  information for an Item, select the "Edit" option from the right-click
  menu.</para>
  <note>
    <para>If your pricing configuration is configured to "Use Wholesale Price
    for Unit Cost for Markups," then your sales commission is based on the
    Item's Wholesale Price. The <literal>catcost</literal> information can be
    used to manage those costs, as well, reflecting a true cost for
    commissions.</para>
  </note>
  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>UPDATE CATCOST</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to update your xTuple Item information with the
        information shown on the Vendor Catalog Cost screen. If the two sets
        of information are in sync, no changes will be made.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>DELETE CATCOST</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to temporarily clear all Item information from the
        Catalog Cost table. When you select the UPDATE CATCOST button, this
        information will be refreshed with the current xTuple Item information
        on file.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>UPDATE ITEMS</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to update the Catalog Cost data using information from
        your external Vendors' Price Sheet(s). If you are coordinating with
        multiple Price Sheets, you will be given the option to choose the
        provider whose updates you want to apply.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <xi:include href="catCost.xml" xpointer="element(/1)"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
</section>
