<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2008 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section942568">
  <title id="configureGLTitle"><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>configuration</primary>
      <secondary>of accounting module</secondary>
    </indexterm>Configure Accounting</title>
  <para>Setting up the default Account Number structure is one of the primary
  purposes of the General Ledger Configuration. The system uses a
  multi-segment approach to defining General Ledger accounts. The various
  segments include the following:</para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>Base Account Segment</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>Company Segment</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>Profit Center</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>Subaccount</para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>Depending on the parameters selected, the system will display General
  Ledger Account Numbers in the Profit Center-Account Number-Subaccount
  sequence. An example of this sequence would be 001-11111-001.</para>
  <tip>
    <para>It is important to realize that the system does not utilize
    sub-Accounts in the same manner that some other packaged software does. It
    does not roll-up into the base account, but allows you to define "related"
    Accounts.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>To configure the General Ledger, select the "General Ledger" tab. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/configureGL.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Configure General Ledger</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When configuring the General Ledger, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Main Segment Size</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify a main Segment size value between 3 and 10. This setting
        defines how large the base Account Number portion should be. For
        example, if you specify "4" here, then your Account Numbers would
        probably range from 1000 through 9999. Similarly, if you specify "5"
        then your Account Number range would be from 10000 though
        99999.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Use Company Segment</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to utilize a Company Segment by default. This is an
        optional setting.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Company Segment Size</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>If a Company Segment is being utilized, specify a Company
              Segment size value between 1 and 10.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Use Profit Centers</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to utilize Profit Centers by default. This is an optional
        setting.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Profit Center Segment Size</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>If Profit Centers are being utilized, specify a Profit
              Center Segment size value between 1 and 10. This segment is
              placed at the front end of the Account Number. Profit Centers
              are typically used to identify activity for different
              Sites.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Allow Free-Form Profit Centers</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to allow free-form Profit Centers. Free-form means
              the values may be edited on the Account Number master. In other
              words, you will not be required to select a predetermined Profit
              Center value from the list. Using free-form Profit Centers can
              lead to inconsistent Account Numbers if not handled
              correctly.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Use Subaccounts</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to utilize Subaccounts by default. This is an optional
        setting.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Subaccount Segment Size</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>If Subaccounts are being utilized, specify a Subaccount
              Segment size value between 1 and 10. This segment is placed at
              the back end of the Account Number. Subaccounts are typically
              used to identify activity for similar types of accounts where
              detail is important.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Allow Free-Form Subaccounts</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to allow free-form Subaccounts. Free-form means the
              values may be edited on the Account Number master. In other
              words, you will not be required to select a predetermined
              Subaccount value from the list. Using free-form Subaccounts can
              lead to inconsistent Account Numbers if not handled
              correctly.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Enforce mandatory notes for Manual G/L Entries</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you want to require users to be required to enter
        Notes when posting simple or series manual Journal entries. If this
        option is not selected, users will not be required to enter Notes when
        posting simple or series manual Journal entries.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>Try to avoid changing your Year End Equity Account if you have
    already used it to close a Fiscal Year. If you do change this Account
    after a fiscal year has been closed, be sure to consult your system
    administrator. The trial balance for the new Account will need to be
    manually updated.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Allow manual entry of G/L Account Numbers</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to enable users to manually enter G/L Account Numbers
        wherever G/L Account Numbers may be entered. If not selected, users
        will be required to use a browse button to select G/L Account Numbers
        from a list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>If Account Numbers have multiple segments separated by dashes, the
    dashes must be included when manually entering G/L Account Numbers. If the
    dashes are not included, the manual entry will not work.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Default Tax Authority</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the default Tax Authority to be used when setting up
        Sites.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Retained Earnings, Year End Account</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select a valid General Ledger Account. This is an Equity
        Account. It will be credited if retained earnings are
        positive&mdash;and debited if retained earnings are negative. The
        retained earnings calculation occurs when a Fiscal Year is closed.
        Total Expenses for the year are subtracted from total Revenues, and
        the balance is transferred to the Year End Equity Account. The system
        then automatically resets the beginning balances for Revenue and
        Expense Accounts to $0 for the start of the new Fiscal Year.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>The Currency Gain/Loss Account is needed only for databases where
    multiple Currencies are used.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Currency Gain/Loss Account</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select a valid General Ledger Account. This is an Expense
        Account. It will debited for Currency gains and credited for Currency
        losses arising from fluctuating Exchange Rates. Currency gains/losses
        may be recognized at the following points: 1) When posting a Cash
        Receipt applied to an Invoice; 2) when posting an A/P Check applied to
        a Voucher; 3) when applying an A/R Misc. Credit Memo to an Invoice;
        and 4) when applying an A/P Misc. Credit Memo to a Voucher. In each
        case, the gain or loss arises when the Exchange Rate used for the
        Apply-To document differs from the Exchange Rate used for the
        application.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>G/L Series Discrepancy Account</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select a valid General Ledger Account. This is an Expense
        Account. It will be debited or credited if rounding errors cause
        discrepancies when multiple line item (i.e., series) transactions are
        posted to the General Ledger. If used, the amounts posted to this
        Account will be miniscule, as rounding errors are fractional by
        nature.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Meaning of Currency Exchange Rates</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify how you want Exchange Rates to be implemented and also
        displayed on the Exchange Rates master list:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Base x Exchange Rate = Foreign</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>If selected, this equation will be used.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Foreign x Exchange Rate = Base</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>If selected, this equation will be used.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Cancels any configuration settings, returning you to the
        application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Saves the configuration settings, returning you to the
        application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To configure Accounts Payable options, select the "Accounts Payable"
  tab. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <screenshot>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/configureGL_ap.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption><para>Configure Accounts Payable</para></caption>
    </mediaobject>
  </screenshot>
  <para>When configuring the A/P module, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Next A/P Memo #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The next sequentially available Accounts Payable Memo Number
        will display here. You may change the number&mdash;creating a new
        basis for the next A/P Memo Number&mdash;by typing the new number into
        this field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To configure Accounts Receivable options, select the "Accounts
  Receivable" tab. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <screenshot>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/configureGL_ar.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption><para>Configure Accounts Receivable</para></caption>
    </mediaobject>
  </screenshot>
  <para>When configuring Accounts Receivable options, you are presented with
  the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Next A/R Memo #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The next sequentially available Accounts Receivable Memo Number
        will display here. You may change the number&mdash;creating a new
        basis for the next A/R Memo Number&mdash;by typing the new number into
        this field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Hide "Apply to Balance" button</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you want to hide the APPLY TO BALANCE button on the
        "Enter Cash Receipt" screen. If this option is selected, users will be
        required to apply Cash Receipts manually to individual open A/R
        items.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Enable Customer Deposits</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you want unapplied Cash Receipts from Customers to be
        handled by a Deferred Revenue Account. If selected, the A/R Account
        Assignments screen will include a Deferred Revenue Account option. Not
        selecting this option will hide the Deferred Revenue Account option on
        the A/R Account assignments screen. Also hidden will be Customer
        Deposit options on the Cash Receipts screen. If the Deferred Revenue
        approach is not being used, then unapplied Cash Receipts will be
        handled by the Asset Account for the specified Bank Account.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Remit-To Address</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The Remit-To Address is used in multiple report definitions.
        Specify details to be used for your site's default Remit-To
        Address:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Street Address</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the street Address to be used on the default
              Remit-To Address.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>City:</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the city to be used on the default Remit-To
              Address.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>State:</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the state to be used on the default Remit-To
              Address.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Postal Code</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the Postal Code for the Contact.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Country:</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the country to be used on the default Remit-To
              Address.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Phone</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the phone for the default Remit-To Address.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Credit Warn Customers when Late</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to globally enable the ability to place Customers on
        credit warning when the due dates on their A/R open items become late
        past the specified grace period. If this option is selected, you will
        have the ability to run a utility called "Update Late Customer Credit
        Status" described here: <xref
        linkend="UpdateLateCustomerCreditStatus" />. When run, this utility
        will review all late A/R open items for all Customers. Any Customers
        found to have late items falling outside the grace period will be
        placed on credit warning. These Customers will automatically be taken
        off credit warning once their late items are paid.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Default Grace Period Days</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the standard number of days beyond the A/R open
              due date which will serve as a grace period. As long as A/R open
              item due dates are within the grace period, Customers will not
              be put on credit warning when the late status utility is run.
              Once outside the grace period, they will be placed on credit
              warning.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="configureGLRecurInvBuffer">Recurring Invoice Buffer</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the number of buffer days you want to allow for when
        automatically processing recurring Invoices. This setting is used by
        the recurring Invoices utility, which is described in more detail here
        <xref linkend="CreateRecurringInvoices" />. Essentially, the buffer
        days setting tells the utility how far to look ahead. When it runs,
        the utility will create new Invoices for any recurring Invoices having
        Invoice dates within the look-ahead (i.e., buffer) days. If an Invoice
        date falls outside the buffer period, then no new Invoice will be
        created.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>