<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2010 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="configureIE">
  <title>Configure Import and Export</title>
  <para>The Import and Export configuration allows you to set a number of
  options for importing data from XML and CSV files. These data might be
  generated manually or by other database or e-commerce systems. For example
  xTuple supports importing orders from Yahoo! stores.</para>
  <para>Importing data files is a multi-step process:</para>
  <orderedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>The files have to be received from the originator and placed on a
      computer file system where the xTuple application can find them.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>Any wrapper information has to be stripped off, such as mail
      headers for files received by electronic mail.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>XML may have to be converted from its original format to one
      understood by the xTuple application.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>The file has to be read by the xTuple application and its contents
      inserted into the database.</para>
    </listitem>
  </orderedlist>
  <para role="xtconnect">The xTuple Connect extension package can be used to
  automate much of this processing, including retrieving files from remote FTP
  servers, converting XML files to a usable format, and importing the contents
  of XML and CSV files.</para>
  <para>xTuple uses <indexterm>
      <primary>XSLT</primary>
      <secondary>transforming XML documents for import</secondary>
    </indexterm><link linkend="glossary.XSLT">XSLT</link> to convert XML files
  from one format to another. XML file formats are described in DTDs. The
  <literal>xtupleimport</literal> <indexterm>
      <primary>DTD</primary>
      <secondary>xtupleapi</secondary>
    </indexterm><link linkend="glossary.DTD">DTD</link> defines an XML file
  format which can be directly imported by the xTuple application. This DTD
  defines XML tags with names that correspond exactly with the names of views
  and columns in the xTuple import API.</para>
  <para>An XSLT file for transforming Yahoo! OrderList files for import into
  an xTuple database is available from xTuple. If you need to import data
  files in other XML formats you must write your own XSLT to convert the data
  to conform to xTuple's DTD.</para>
  <para>To configure which transformations to use for XML files in various
  formats, click the XSLT Mapping tab on the Configure Import and Export
  window.</para>
  <screenshot>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/configureIE_mappingTab.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption><para>Configure XSLT Mapping</para></caption>
    </mediaobject>
  </screenshot>
  <para>When configuring XSLT Mapping, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="configureIE.defaultXSLTdirectory">Default XSLT File
      Directories</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The XSLT files used to perform the translation between XML data
        formats must be present on the file system of the computer which is
        running the xTuple application. This set of options lets you define
        one directory for each operating system platform where the application
        should look for XSLT files.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Map of XSLT import and export filters</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This is a list of document transformations recognized by the
        xTuple application. These transformations are called
        <wordasword>filters</wordasword>.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>XSLT Processor</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>XSLT is a language for transforming XML documents. To apply an
        XSLT stylesheet to a given XML document you need an XSLT processor.
        This is a program that interprets or compiles the XSLT and then
        performs the transformation on the XML file.</para>
        <note>
          <para>Each XSLT processor has its own command-line syntax.</para>
        </note>
        <para>The "XSLT Processor" field you define the command line that the
        xTuple application should execute to perform the transformation. Two
        arguments that will always be required are the name of the XSLT file
        which describes the transformation and the XML file to be transformed.
        When typing the command line that should be run to call the XSLT
        processor, put %f where the XSLT processor expects to find the name of
        the XML file and %x where the XSLT processor expects to find the name
        of the XSLT file.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To create a new XSLT Map, select the NEW button. The following screen
  will appear:</para>
  <screenshot>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/xsltMap.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption><para>XSLT Map</para></caption>
    </mediaobject>
  </screenshot>
  <para>When creating a new XSLT Map, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Map Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This is a name you choose to describe this map.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Document Type</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This is the XML document type that the application will use to
        find the correct filter to use when importing an XML document. When
        the application starts to import an XML document, it looks for the
        <literal>DOCTYPE</literal> processing directive at the top of the
        file. If the <literal>DOCTYPE</literal> is
        <literal>xtupleimport</literal> then no transformation is required.
        Otherwise it searches for a match in the Document Type and System
        Identifier columns to find the correct filter to use when importing
        the file.</para>
        <para>The Document Type of an XML file is the name of its root
        element.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>System Identifier</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This is the System Identifier that the application will use to
        find the correct filter to use when importing an XML document.</para>
        <para>The System Identifier is a URI that describes how to get the DTD
        for the XML document.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Import XSLT File Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This is the name of the XSLT file that will be used to transform
        XML files with this Document Type and System Identifier to xTuple's
        format for XML files. If the name of the file is a full path, starting
        with a drive letter on Windows or a / on Macintosh or Linux, then the
        application will look for this file using this full path
        specification. If the name is a simple filename (like
        <filename>myTransform.xsl</filename>) or a relative pathname (like
        <filename>oasis/from_ubl.xsl</filename>) then the application will
        look for it in the default XSLT directory defined on the
        <guilabel>Configure Import and Export</guilabel> window.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Export XSLT File Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This is the name of the XSLT file that will be used to transform
        XML files generated by xTuple to a file of the given Document Type and
        System Identifier.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>Exporting XML is not currently supported by xTuple. At this time the
    <guilabel>Export XSLT File Name</guilabel> on the XSLT Map window and the
    <guilabel>XML Export</guilabel> tab on the <guilabel>Configure Import and
    Export</guilabel> window are placeholders for future development.</para>
  </note>
  <para>The <guilabel>Import Settings</guilabel> tab on the
  <guilabel>Configure Import and Export</guilabel> window lets you enter
  details of how files are imported.</para>
  <screenshot>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/configureIE_dirTab.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption><para>XML Import</para></caption>
    </mediaobject>
  </screenshot>
  <para>When configuring Import processing you are presented with the
  following options on the <guilabel>Directories</guilabel> tab:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="configureIE.defaultImportDirectory">Default Import File
      Directory</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This names the directory on the current platform that the xTuple
        application will search when the user wants to import files. It is
        used to populate the <guilabel>Import Data</guilabel> window.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="xtconnect">
      <term>Transfer files from</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The xTuple Connect extension package allows retrieving files
        from remote FTP servers. This list contains information about the FTP
        servers that will be checked for files to download.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para role="xtconnect">To set up a new FTP server to check, click the NEW
  button. You will be presented with the following screen:<screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images\importsrc.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption><para>Import Source screen</para></caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para role="xtconnect">When setting up an Import Source you are presented
  with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist role="xtconnect">
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a name for this Import Source.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Host</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the host name or IP address of the FTP server.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>User Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the user name with which to log in to the FTP
        server.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Password</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the password with which to log in to the FTP
        server.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Directory</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the directory in which to look for files to download, if
        any.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Name or Pattern</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the file name or a regular expression to use to find files
        to download. For example you can leave this blank if you want to
        download all files that you find. To download all CSV files that
        contain "TTOYS" and the current year, you could enter a regular
        expression like <literal>.*TTOYS.*201[0-9].*\.csv$</literal></para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>After Successful Download</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select an option from the list of how the xTuple Connect Batch
        Manager should handle the file <emphasis>on the FTP server</emphasis>
        after the file has been downloaded successfully.</para>
        <xi:include href="../widgets/filemoveselector.xml"
                    xpointer="fileMoveSelector"
                    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Recurring</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a schedule for the xTuple Connect Batch Manager to connect
        to the FTP server and try to download files.</para>
        <xi:include href="../widgets/recurrencewidget.xml"
                    xpointer="recurrenceWidget"
                    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>From</term>
      <term>Reply To</term>
      <term>To</term>
      <term>Cc</term>
      <term>Bcc</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter email information for sending the status of download
        processing.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note role="xtconnect">
    <para>Importing downloaded files with the xTuple Connect Batch Manager is
    a two-step process. The FTP download and the file imports are scheduled
    separately. The Import Source screen lets you schedule the FTP download
    step. Use the Schedule Imports tab to schedule loading the data into the
    database.</para>
  </note>
  <para>The <guilabel>General Import Options</guilabel> tab lets you choose
  how to handle files after their contents have been imported. </para>
  <screenshot>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/configureIE_xmlImportTab.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption><para>General Import Options</para></caption>
    </mediaobject>
  </screenshot>
  <para>When defining general import options, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>After successful import</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Choose how CSV and XML files that have been successfully
        imported should be handled after the import is complete.</para>
        <xi:include href="../widgets/filemoveselector.xml"
                    xpointer="fileMoveSelector"
                    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>After error during import</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Choose how CSV and XML files that could not be successfully
        imported should be handled after the import attempt is
        complete.</para>
        <xi:include href="../widgets/filemoveselector.xml"
                    xpointer="fileMoveSelector"
                    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Save failed XML elements to a separate file</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Leave this unchecked if you want XML files to be processed in an
        all-or-none fashion. Check this option if you want those portions of
        XML files that can be imported to be saved and those portions that
        cannot be imported successfully to be written out to a separate
        file.</para>
        <para>If this option is checked, a new XML file will be created in the
        xTuple import format containing those elements that could not be
        imported. A comment will be added to the XML containing the error
        message if one is available. If the <guilabel>After error during
        import</guilabel> option is set to add a suffix or move the file after
        errors, this setting will be used to name new the error file.<note>
            <para>If this option is checked, all XML files imported will
            handled as though they were successfully imported even if every
            element failed. The failed elements will be written to a separate
            error file.</para>
            <para>The error file will have the xTuple import format, not the
            format of the original XML file before the XSLT
            transformation.</para>
          </note></para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>The <guilabel>CSV Import Options</guilabel> tab lets you define
  options specific to importing CSV files.</para>
  <screenshot>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/configureIE_csvImportTab.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption><para>CSV Import Options</para></caption>
    </mediaobject>
  </screenshot>
  <para>When defining options specific to importing CSV files, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CSV Atlas Directory</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This is where the application will look for CSV Atlas files when
        opening them for editing and when importing CSV files.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Map of CSV file properties and CSV Atlas files</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This lists how CSV Atlases are chosen automatically when
        importing CSV files.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To set up a new mapping between CSV files and the CSV Atlases to
  choose, click the NEW button. The following screen will appear:<screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images\atlasMap.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption><para>CSV File to Atlas Map</para></caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When setting up a CSV Atlas Map you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a name for this mapping between CSV files and the CSV
        Atlas to use</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Pattern</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a regular expression that uniquely describes this CSV file
        format</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Apply Pattern to</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Choose whether the <guilabel>Pattern</guilabel> should be
        applied to the name of the CSV file or the first line of the CSV
        file.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Atlas File</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Choose the Atlas File that should be applied to files matching
        the entered <guilabel>Pattern</guilabel>. This file should be placed
        in the CSV Atlas Directory or a full path to the file should be
        entered.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Map</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Choose the particular Map within the Atlas File that should be
        used for files matching the entered
        <guilabel>Pattern</guilabel>.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Treat first row as header information</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Check this if the first row of the CSV file contains column
        headers. Uncheck this if the first row of the CSV file contains data
        to be imported.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para role="xtconnect">The Schedule Imports tab lets you define a schedule
  for importing data with the xTuple Connect Batch Manager.</para>
  <screenshot>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/configureIE_scheduleTab.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption><para>Scheduling Options</para></caption>
    </mediaobject>
  </screenshot>
  <para role="xtconnect">When setting up an import schedule, you are presented
  with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist role="xtconnect">
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Recurring</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a schedule for the xTuple Connect Batch Manager to check
        the import directory and try to import the XML and CSV files found in
        that directory</para>
        <xi:include href="../widgets/recurrencewidget.xml"
                    xpointer="recurrenceWidget"
                    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>From</term>
      <term>Reply To</term>
      <term>To</term>
      <term>Cc</term>
      <term>Bcc</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter email information for sending the status of import
        processing.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note role="xtconnect">
    <para>Importing downloaded files with the xTuple Connect Batch Manager is
    a two-step process. The FTP download and the file imports are scheduled
    separately. The Import Source screen lets you schedule the FTP download
    step. Use the Schedule Imports tab to schedule loading the data into the
    database.</para>
  </note>
  <para>The <guilabel>XML Export</guilabel> tab on the <guilabel>Configure
  Import and Export</guilabel> window lets you define how the transformations
  are to be performed.</para>
  <screenshot>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/configureIE_exportTab.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption><para>XML Export</para></caption>
    </mediaobject>
  </screenshot>
  <para>When configuring XML Export processing you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Default Export File Directories</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This names the directory on each platform that the xTuple
        application will search when the user wants to export XML files. It is
        used to populate the <guilabel>Export XML</guilabel> window.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
