<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2008 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="configureIE">
  <title id="configureIE.title">Configure Import and Export</title>
  <para>The Import and Export configuration allows you to set options for
  importing data from XML files as an alternative to the CSV Import tool.
  These data might be generated manually or by other database or e-commerce
  systems. For example xTuple supports importing orders from Yahoo!
  stores.</para>
  <para>Importing data from XML files is a multi-step process:</para>
  <orderedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>The files have to be received from the originator and placed on a
      computer file system where the xTuple application can find them.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>Any wrapper information has to be stripped off, such as mail
      headers for files received by electronic mail.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>The XML has to be converted from its original format to one
      understood by the xTuple application.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>The converted file has to be read by the xTuple application and
      its contents inserted into the database.</para>
    </listitem>
  </orderedlist>
  <para>xTuple currently does not automate the first two steps in this
  process.</para>
  <para>xTuple uses <indexterm>
      <primary>XSLT</primary>
      <secondary>transforming XML documents for import</secondary>
    </indexterm><link linkend="glossary.XSLT">XSLT</link> to convert XML files
  from one format to another. XML file formats are described in DTDs. The
  <literal>xtupleimport</literal> <indexterm>
      <primary>DTD</primary>
      <secondary>xtupleapi</secondary>
    </indexterm><link linkend="glossary.DTD">DTD</link> defines an XML file
  format which can be directly imported by the xTuple application. This DTD
  defines XML tags with names that correspond exactly with the names of views
  and columns in the xTuple import API.</para>
  <para>An XSLT file for transforming Yahoo! OrderList files for import into
  an xTuple database is available from xTuple. If you need to import data
  files in other XML formats you must write your own XSLT to convert the data
  to conform to xTuple's DTD.</para>
  <para>To configure which transformations to use for XML files in various
  formats, click the XSLT Mapping tab on the Configure Import and Export
  window.</para>
  <screenshot>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/configureIE_mappingTab.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption><para>Configure XSLT Mapping</para></caption>
    </mediaobject>
  </screenshot>
  <para>When configuring XSLT Mapping, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="configureIE.defaultXSLTdirectory">Default XSLT File
      Directories</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The XSLT files used to perform the translation between XML data
        formats must be present on the file system of the computer which is
        running the xTuple application. This set of options lets you define
        one directory for each operating system platform where the application
        should look for XSLT files.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Map of XSLT import and export filters</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This is a list of document transformations recognized by the
        xTuple application. These transformations are called
        <wordasword>filters</wordasword>.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the list of import and export filters, the
  following buttons are available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Opens the screen for entering new XSLT import and export
        filters.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>EDIT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Opens the screen for editing existing XSLT import and export
        filters.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>DELETE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Delete existing XSLT import and export filters.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To create a new XSLT Map, select the NEW button. The following screen
  will appear:</para>
  <screenshot>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/xsltMap.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption><para>XSLT Map</para></caption>
    </mediaobject>
  </screenshot>
  <para>When creating a new XSLT Map, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Map Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This is a name you choose to describe this map.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Document Type</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This is the XML document type that the application will use to
        find the correct filter to use when importing an XML document. When
        the application starts to import an XML document, it looks for the
        <literal>DOCTYPE</literal> processing directive at the top of the
        file. If the <literal>DOCTYPE</literal> is
        <literal>xtupleimport</literal> then no transformation is required.
        Otherwise it searches for a match in the Document Type and System
        Identifier columns to find the correct filter to use when importing
        the file.</para>
        <para>The Document Type of an XML file is the name of its root
        element.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>System Identifier</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This is the System Identifier that the application will use to
        find the correct filter to use when importing an XML document.</para>
        <para>The System Identifier is a URI that describes how to get the DTD
        for the XML document.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Import XSLT File Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This is the name of the XSLT file that will be used to transform
        XML files with this Document Type and System Identifier to xTuple's
        format for XML files. If the name of the file is a full path, starting
        with a drive letter on Windows or a / on Macintosh or Linux, then the
        application will look for this file using this full path
        specification. If the name is a simple filename (like
        <filename>myTransform.xsl</filename>) or a relative pathname (like
        <filename>oasis/from_ubl.xsl</filename>) then the application will
        look for it in the default XSLT directory defined on the
        <guilabel>Configure Import and Export</guilabel> window.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Export XSLT File Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This is the name of the XSLT file that will be used to transform
        XML files generated by xTuple to a file of the given Document Type and
        System Identifier.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>Exporting XML is not currently supported by xTuple. At this time the
    <guilabel>Export XSLT File Name</guilabel> on the XSLT Map window and the
    <guilabel>XML Export</guilabel> tab on the <guilabel>Configure Import and
    Export</guilabel> window are placeholders for future development.</para>
  </note>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Cancels any changes to the XSLT Map and returns to the
        <guilabel>Configure Import and Export </guilabel>window.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Saves the changes to the XSLT Map and returns to the
        <guilabel>Configure Import and Export</guilabel> window.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>The <guilabel>XML Import</guilabel> tab on the <guilabel>Configure
  Import and Export</guilabel> window lets you define how the transformations
  are to be performed.</para>
  <screenshot>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/configureIE_importTab.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption><para>XML Import</para></caption>
    </mediaobject>
  </screenshot>
  <para>When configuring XML Import processing you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>XSLT Processor</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>XSLT is a language for transforming XML documents. To apply an
        XSLT stylesheet to a given XML document you need an XSLT processor.
        This is a program that interprets or compiles the XSLT and then
        performs the transformation on the XML file.</para>
        <note>
          <para>Each XSLT processor has its own command-line syntax.</para>
        </note>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Use External XSLT Processor. Commands</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Lets you define the command line that the xTuple
              application should execute to perform the transformation. Two
              arguments that will always be required are the name of the XSLT
              file which describes the transformation and the XML file to be
              transformed. When typing the command line that should be run to
              call the XSLT processor, put %f where the XSLT processor expects
              to find the name of the XML file and %x where the XSLT processor
              expects to find the name of the XSLT file.</para>
              <para>In the figure you see three different XSLT processors
              defined. Each has its own syntax, which is reflected by the
              differences in the sequence of options and the way run-time
              parameters are passed to the stylesheets. Note that
              <command>msxsl.exe</command> takes the XML and XSLT files in a
              different order than the other two processors.</para>
              <para>XSLT run-time parameters let you write a stylesheet with
              default values that can be changed when you run a transformation
              without editing the stylesheet itself. In this example, written
              to use xTuple's stylesheet for importing Yahoo! orders, the
              customer_default_tax_authority parameter is set to INET; when
              Customer records are created they will all be assigned the tax
              authority INET.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="configureIE.defaultImportDirectory">Default Import File
      Directories</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This names the directory on each platform that the xTuple
        application will search when the user wants to import XML files. It is
        used to populate the <guilabel>Import XML</guilabel> window.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>XML File Handling Options</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This set of options lets you choose what the application should
        do with XML files after they have been imported successfully. Files
        which lead to errors during import will be left in place.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term id="configureIE.filehandling.donothing">Do nothing after
            successful import</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>If you choose this option then the application will leave
              imported files unchanged in the import directory.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Rename after successful import. Append</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>If you choose this option then the application will leave
              the files in the import directory but will add a suffix to the
              file. You must give a suffix in the adjacent text field if you
              select this option.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Move after successful import to</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>If you choose this option then the application will move
              the files to the directory you name after the import is
              complete. If the directory name is a simple or relative path
              then the application assumes this is a subdirectory of or is
              relative to the Default Import Directory.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Delete after successful import</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>This will remove the files from the import directory after
              they have been imported.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>The XML Export tab is currently empty. It is a placeholder for
    future development.</para>
  </note>
</section>