<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2008 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section>
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>configuration</primary>
      <secondary>for credit cards</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>credit cards</primary>
      <secondary>configuration for</secondary>
    </indexterm>Credit Cards</title>
  <para>To configure your system to process Credit Cards, select the "Credit
  Cards" option. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/configureCC.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Configure Credit Card General Options</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <note>
    <para>The system currently supports only the YourPay and Authorize.Net
    verification services.</para>
  </note>
  <para>When establishing the general settings for your Credit Card
  configuration, you are presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Accept Credit Cards</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to indicate the system is configured to accept Credit
        Card Payments. If selected, the Credit Card processing functionality
        will be enabled throughout the system. For example, users will be able
        to store Customer Credit Card information on the Customer master—and
        receive Credit Card payments when processing Sales Orders. If this
        option is not selected, Credit Card functionality will be
        disabled.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Work in Test Mode</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if your site is testing the Credit Card configuration and
        functionality. If selected, the system will verify that the server
        specified under the "Server" tab is in fact the correct test server.
        If this option is not selected, the system will verify that the
        correct production server is specified.</para>
        <warning>
          <para>Make sure that you <emphasis>uncheck</emphasis> this option as
          soon as you are ready to put the application into production. Most
          credit card transactions will appear to succeed whether running in
          test mode or live mode but there will be no actual charges made if
          in test mode.</para>
          <para>If you are using Authorize.Net then you should also make sure
          that the Merchant Interface is configured to run in live mode
          instead of test mode. Both xTupleERP and the Authorize.Net gateway
          allow sending test transactions to the live server but both
          applications must be set to run in live mode for real transactions
          to occur.</para>
        </warning>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>credit cards</primary>
          <secondary>selecting verification service</secondary>
        </indexterm>Verification Service</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the Credit Card payment gateway you will be
        using:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Authorize.Net</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if you will be using the Authorize.Net payment
              gateway for handling Credit Card transactions. Specific
              Authorize.Net options will be enabled on the screen if you
              select this service.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>YourPay</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if you will be using the YourPay payment gateway
              for handling Credit Card transactions. Specific YourPay options
              will be enabled on the screen if you select this service.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Confirm Transaction</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify when you want to application users to confirm
        transactions before they are processed:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Pre-Authorization</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if you want confirmation before pre-authorizing
              charges on a Credit Card.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Direct Charge</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if you want confirmation before directly charging a
              Credit Card.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Charge Pre-Authorization</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if you want confirmation before posting
              pre-authorizied charges.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Credit</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if you want confirmation before crediting back
              charges on a Credit Card.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Enable Transaction on Sales Order</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select which of the following options should be enabled under
        the Payments tab of the Sales Order header. This setting does not
        affect the A/R Workbench or any other window in the
        application.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Pre-Authorization</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>If selected, only the AUTHORIZE button will be
              enabled.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Direct Charge</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>If selected, only the CHARGE button will be
              enabled.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>pre-authorizations</primary>
          <secondary>for credit card transactions</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>credit cards</primary>
          <secondary>pre-auth limits</secondary>
        </indexterm>Number of days Pre-Authorizations are valid for</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select a value between 1 and 30 using the arrow buttons located
        to the right of the field. Value entered specifies the number of days
        pre-authorizations will remain valid from the date they were entered.
        Once a pre-authorization expires, it will no longer be visible in the
        system and will be unavailable for post-authorization.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>bank accounts</primary>
          <secondary>for credit card transactions</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>credit cards</primary>
          <secondary>bank accounts and</secondary>
        </indexterm>Default Bank Account</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the default Bank Account to be used for receiving Cash
        whenever a Customer Credit Card is charged.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Cancels any configuration settings, returning you to the
        application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Saves the configuration settings, returning you to the
        application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>Fraud detection methods vary depending on the payment gateway used.
  Authorize.Net requires fraud settings to be configured on the gateway
  server. Other services, like YourPay, send fraud detection results back to
  the client software and require the client to decide whether to accept the
  transaction or void it. To configure client-side fraud detections settings,
  if required, select the "Fraud Detection" tab. The following screen will
  appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/configureCC_fraudPage.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Configure Credit Card Fraud Detection</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot><tip>
      <para>If YourPay is the service being used, the options on the "Fraud
      Detection" tab will be enabled and selections should be made. These
      options will be disabled if the Authorize.Net gateway is being used.
      Fraud detection settings for Authorize.Net must be configured through
      the Merchant Interface.</para>
    </tip>When configuring client-side fraud detection settings, if required,
  you are presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Require Card Verification Value/Code (CVV)</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you want to require users to enter a CVV code when
        processing Credit Cards.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Card Verification</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify how you want to handle Credit Card verification
        processing:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Do not check</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if the xTuple application should ignore the CVV
              result sent by the payment gateway.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Warn if failure</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if the xTuple application should tell the user if
              the CVV result sent by the payment gateway fails based on the
              criteria checked in the "Fail CVV Check If" section.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Reject if failure</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if the xTuple application should void the
              transaction and tell the user if the CVV result sent by the
              payment gateway fails based on the criteria checked in the "Fail
              CVV Check If" section.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Fail CVV Check If:</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify how you want to handle Credit Card Verification Value
        (CVV) check failures:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Code Does Not Match</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if the transaction should be treated as fraudulent
              if the CVV does not match the credit card number.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>CVV Was Not Processed</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if the transaction should be treated as fraudulent
              if the Credit Card company, such as Visa or American Express,
              could not process the CVV for the payment gateway.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Card Had No Code</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if the transaction should be treated as fraudulent
              if the Credit Card does not have a CVV but is expected to have
              one.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Card Issuer Is Not Certified</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if the transaction should be treated as fraudulent
              if the financial institution that issued the Credit Card is not
              certified.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Address Verification Service</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify how you want to handle address verification:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Do not check</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if the xTuple application should ignore the AVS
              result sent by the payment gateway.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Warn on Failed AVS Check</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if the xTuple application should tell the user if
              the AVS result sent by the payment gateway fails based on the
              criteria checked in the "Fail AVS Check If" section.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Reject on Failed AVS Check</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if the xTuple application should void the
              transaction and tell the user if the AVS result sent by the
              payment gateway fails based on the criteria checked in the "Fail
              AVS Check If" section.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Fail AVS check if:</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify how you want to handle address verification check
        failures:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Address Does Not Match</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if the transaction should be treated as fraudulent
              if the address stored by the xTuple application does not match
              the Credit Card company's recorded billing address for the
              Credit Card.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Address Comparison Not Available</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if the transaction should be treated as fraudulent
              if the Credit Card company could not process the street address
              information for the payment gateway.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>ZIP Does Not Match</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if the transaction should be treated as fraudulent
              if the postal code stored by the xTuple application does not
              match the Credit Card company's recorded billing address for the
              Credit Card.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>ZIP Comparison Not Available</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if the transaction should be treated as fraudulent
              if the Credit Card company could not process the postal code
              information for the payment gateway.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To establish the server settings for your Credit Card configuration,
  <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>servers</primary>
      <secondary>for credit card companies</secondary>
    </indexterm>select the "Server" tab. The following screen will
  appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/configureCC_serverPage.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Configure Credit Card Server Options</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When establishing the server settings for your Credit Card
  configuration, you are presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>servers</primary>
          <secondary>for credit card service</secondary>
        </indexterm>Server Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the URL for the specified Verification Service's server.
        The URL specified may vary, depending on whether you are working in
        test mode or production mode. If this is empty then the application
        will use the default URL for this Verification Service, which again
        may vary depending on whether you are working in test mode or
        production mode.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Port</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the port number for the specified Verification Service's
        server. If this is left empty then the application will use the
        default Port for this Verification Service.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Login</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>YourPay does not require login information to be entered in this
        field. For Authorize.Net, use your API Login here, not your Merchant
        Interface Login, which may differ.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Password</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>YourPay does not require login information to be entered in this
        field. Type your Transaction Key here for Authorize.Net. The label for
        this field may change if you select Authorize.Net.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Use Proxy Server</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if your site uses a proxy server.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Server Name</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the IP Address for your proxy server.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Port</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the port used by your proxy server.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Login</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the login name for your proxy server.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Password</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the password for your proxy server.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>You can leave the Server Name and Port fields blank if you desire.
    This is the easiest way to switch between test mode and production mode,
    as you won't have to change these values every time you switch
    modes.</para>
    <para>Some payment gateways, such as Authorize.Net, allow testing against
    the live, production server. If you want to run test transactions against
    the live payment gateway then you must set the Server Name explicitly to
    the live payment gateway's URL. You will get a warning from the
    application when you click the Save button if you do this.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>To establish the service option settings for your Credit Card
  configuration, select the "Service Options" tab. The options will vary
  depending on the payment gateway being used. If YourPay is being used, the
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/configureCC_optionsPage_yourPayStack.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>YourPay Service Options</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When establishing the service option settings for your YourPay
  configuration, you are presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Link Shield</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>LinkShield is a risk-scoring service provided by YourPay at an
        additional fee. If you have purchased this service then check the
        Enabled box and set the desired cut-off score.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Reject if Score Exceeds</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Set your risk tolerance by selecting a value between 0 and
              100 using the arrow buttons located to the right of the field or
              by typing a number in this field. A Link Shield score of 0
              indicates that this transaction has an extremely low risk, while
              a score of 100 indicates a high risk transaction.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Store Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the number of your YourPay store. Store numbers are
        assigned when you register with the YourPay Verification
        Service.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Digital Certificate (PEM File) Location:</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the physical location of the digital certificate (i.e.,
        PEM file) according to your operating system:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Windows</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the directory path any Windows machine on your
              system would use to access the YourPay PEM file. The PEM file
              may be stored locally for use by individual machines, or on a
              network drive for wider distribution.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Linux</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the directory path any Linux machine on your
              system would use to access the YourPay PEM file. The PEM file
              may be stored locally for use by individual machines, or on a
              network drive for wider distribution.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Mac</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the directory path any Mac machine on your system
              would use to access the YourPay PEM file. The PEM file may be
              stored locally for use by individual machines, or on a network
              drive for wider distribution.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>In Test Mode, transactions should</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The YourPay test gateway allows testing the client application's
        ability to handle failed transactions. The client application can
        build transaction messages and then indicate whether the test gateway
        should return an error or not.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Always Fail (Be Declined or Marked as Duplicates)</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>If this is selected then the test gateway will always
              return a message indicating that the transaction failed.
              Sometimes it will send a message saying the transaction was
              declined and sometimes it will send a message saying the
              transaction failed because it is a duplicate of a prior
              transaction.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Sometimes Fail</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>This is similar to "Always Fail" but about 80% of the
              transactions attempted by the application will be sent unaltered
              and should be expected to succeed. Approximately 10% of the
              transactions sent to the test server should be marked as
              declined and approximately 10% should be marked as
              duplicates.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Always Succeed If Possible</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>This option does not inject failure requests in the
              transaction stream. This allows testing normal flow of all
              credit card transactions in the application.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>If Authorize.Net is being used, the following screen will
  appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/configureCC_optionsPage_authorizeDotNetStack.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Authorize.Net Service Options</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When establishing the service option settings for your Authorize.Net
  configuration, you are presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Transaction Version</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Authorize.Net supports three different versions of the
        communications protocol at this time, with the potential for more to
        be added in the future. The xTuple application builds transaction
        requests which conform to version 3.1 of the Authorize.Net protocol.
        This field is a placeholder to allow for future expansion by both
        xTuple and Authorize.Net.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Delimiting Character</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This field allows overriding the default character used by
        Authorize.Net to separate parts of the messages sent by the gateway to
        the client application. If this field is blank then Authorize.Net will
        use the comma (,) to separate message fields. If you expect your data
        to contain commas as part of their content, such as street addresses,
        then you should change the Delimiting Character.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Encapsulating Character</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This field allows setting the character used by Authorize.Net to
        enclose individual parts of the messages sent by the gateway to the
        client application. If this field is blank then Authorize.Net will not
        use any character for this purpose.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Duplicate Window</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Use this field to indicate a time window to Authorize.Net for
        checking for duplicate transactions. If similar transactions are sent
        to Authorize.Net within this window then it may reject them as
        duplicates. This is a value in seconds.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>MD5 Hash</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>If you want an additional sense of security, set the MD5 Hash
        field to a short string and set the same value on the Merchant
        Interface. This shared secret can be used to assure that the payment
        gateway is actually Authorize.Net's server and not an imposter. The
        value of the MD5 Hash field and a few other fields in the transaction
        request are processed with the MD5 algorithm by the payment gateway
        and the resulting string is returned to the xTuple application. The
        xTuple application performs the same processing and compares the
        result with the value sent by the payment gateway.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Set on Gateway</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify how you want the gateway to respond if the MD5 hash
        fails:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Warn if MD5 check fails</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>If the comparison of the MD5 value fails then warn the
              user.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Fail if MD5 check fails</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>If the comparison of the MD5 values fails then treat the
              transaction as failed, regardless of apparent success or
              failure, and tell the user. This transaction is not
              voided.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Currency of Transactions</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify how you want to handle foreign Currency
        transactions:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Same as Order</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Always process credit card transactions using the same
              currency as the Sales Order, Cash Deposit, or Credit
              Memo.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Always Use</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to always use the Currency specified here for all
              Credit Card transactions.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Additional Options</term>
      <listitem>
        <variablelist>
          <para>You have the option to specify the following additional
          options:</para>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Using Wells Fargo SecureSource</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Check this box if you are using Authorize.Net with Wells
              Fargo SecureSource. Wells Fargo SecureSource requires that
              transaction requests be built slightly differently than pure
              Authorize.Net transactions and this configuration option tells
              the xTuple application to construct the transactions to work
              with this service.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <warning>
    <para>You should set the Encapsulating Character to a value. Otherwise
    some transactions may fail with an error reporting that the response from
    the payment gateway has the wrong number of fields.</para>
    <para>Several of these configuration options may be set through the
    Authorize.Net Merchant Interface. If you set any of these options there,
    you <emphasis>must</emphasis> use exactly the same values here in the
    Service Options tab. If you do not then most or all of your credit card
    transactions will fail, often with mysterious errors.</para>
    <para>If you want to use the MD5 Hash feature, you must set it to exactly
    the same value here and on the Merchant Interface, including spaces and
    capitalization.</para>
    <para>You may set the Delimiting Character, Encapsulating Character,
    Duplicate Window, and Currency of Transactions in the xTuple application
    without setting them through the Authorize.Net Merchant Interface.</para>
  </warning>
  <para><indexterm>
      <primary>credit cards</primary>
      <secondary>key files and</secondary>
    </indexterm>To establish the key file settings for your Credit Card
  configuration, select the "Key File" tab. The following screen will
  appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/configureCC_keyPage.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Configure Credit Card Key File Options</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <tip>
    <para>All users on your system who need access to Credit Card information
    must use the same key file. The key file can be a simple text file with
    any contents whatsoever. It should be stored at the same level as the
    xTuple executable file. For Mac users, this would be within the MacOS
    directory inside the Package Contents for your xTuple executable. The key
    file is not stored on the database.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>When establishing the key file settings for your Credit Card
  configuration, you are presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Key File Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the name of your key file. The key file is an encryption
        seed file, which enables you to read encrypted Credit Card
        information. The key file is required regardless of the Verification
        Service used at your site. The contents of the key file should be at
        least 16 characters long and use a combination of upper and lower case
        letters and numbers. Special characters should not be used.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>If you change the contents of your key file after it has already
    been in production, steps must be taken to convert any data encrypted up
    to that point. The function "alterencrypt" must be used to handle the
    conversion. Please contact your Systems Administrator for more
    information.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Windows Location</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the directory path any Windows machine on your system
        would use to access the key file. All users and machines on the system
        must use the same key file. To ensure consistency and security, the
        file should be stored in a central location.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>If you name the key file "OpenMFG.key" and place it in the
    installation directory, then you do not need to enter the path.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Linux Location</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the directory path any Linux machine on your system
        would use to access the key file. All users and machines on the system
        must use the same key file. To ensure consistency and security, the
        file should be stored in a central location.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Mac Location</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the directory path any Mac machine on your system would
        use to access the key file. All users and machines on the system must
        use the same key file. To ensure consistency and security, the file
        should be stored in a central location.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>