<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2010 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="createRecurringItems">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>incidents</primary>
      <secondary>create recurring</secondary>
    </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>to-dos</primary>
      <secondary>create recurring</secondary>
    </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>projects</primary>
      <secondary>create recurring</secondary>
    </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>invoices</primary>
      <secondary>create recurring</secondary>
    </indexterm>Create Recurring Items</title>
  <para>Several document types may be marked as recurring: Invoices,
  Incidents, To-Do Items, and Projects. Recurring means these documents have
  the capacity to be recreated over and over again on a periodic basis. To
  process recurring documents, you need to run the recurring items utility.
  When the utility is run, copies will be created of any documents marked as
  recurring. The frequency of the recurrence is defined on the parent document
  itself.</para>
  <tip>
    <para>Once the recurring flag is set on a parent document, all subsequent
    copies will be marked in the database as children of the original parent
    document. If you need to make changes to the frequency of a recurring
    document, you must go back to the original parent document and make the
    changes there. Frequency changes made at the parent level will propagate
    to the child level.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>To create recurring items, select the "Create Recurring Items" option.
  The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images\createRecurringItems.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create Recurring Items</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When creating recurring items, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Invoices</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to create recurring Invoices for any Invoices marked as
        recurring. The frequency of the recurrence is defined at the parent
        level.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Incidents</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to create recurring Incidents for any Incidents marked as
        recurring. The frequency of the recurrence is defined at the parent
        level.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>To-Do Items</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to create recurring To-Do Items for any To-Do Items
        marked as recurring. The frequency of the recurrence is defined at the
        parent level.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Projects</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to create recurring Projects for any Projects marked as
        recurring. The frequency of the recurrence is defined at the parent
        level.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without creating any recurring items,
        returning you to the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CREATE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to create recurring items for the selected document
        types.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
