<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2008 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section>
  <title id="CreateRecurringInvoices"><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>invoices</primary>
      <secondary>creating recurring</secondary>
    </indexterm> Create Recurring Invoices</title>
  <para>Some Invoices may be marked as recurring. This means the Invoices are
  designed to be recreated over and over again on a periodic basis. To process
  recurring Invoices, you need to run the recurring Invoices utility. When the
  utility is run, new unposted Invoices are created for any recurring Invoices
  having an Invoice date within the specified number of look-ahead days. The
  look ahead days, or buffer days, are specified in the Accounting Module
  configuration. You can read more about recurring Invoice buffer days here
  <xref linkend="configureGLRecurInvBuffer" />.</para>
  <para>Newly-created recurring Invoices will appear on the list of unposted
  Invoices. Their distribution date will depend on the frequency specified and
  the Invoice date on the original Invoice. For example, if the original
  Invoice is dated January 1 and the frequency is once every month, then the
  next Invoices will be dated February 1, March 1, etc.</para>
  <tip>
    <para>Once the recurring flag is set on the original Invoice, all
    subsequent, recurring Invoices will be marked in the database as children
    of the original parent Invoice. If you need to make changes to the
    frequency of a recurring Invoice (or to cancel the recurring Invoice), you
    must go back to the original parent Invoice and make the changes
    there.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>To create recurring Invoices, select the "Create Recurring Invoices"
  option. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/createRecurringInvoices.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create Recurring Invoices</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When creating recurring Invoices, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without creating recurring Invoices, returning
        you to the application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>UPDATE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Creates the recurring Invoices, using the specified
        parameters.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="standard">
      <term>SUBMIT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to submit the job to the Batch Manager.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>