<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="creditMemoItem">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>returns</primary>
      <secondary>adding line items to</secondary>
    </indexterm>Return Item</title>
  <para>To create a new Return Line Item, select the NEW button. The following
  screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/creditMemoItem.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create New Return Line Item</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When creating a new Return Line Item, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Return #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Return number for the current Return.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Line #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the line number assigned to the Return Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Type</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Indicate the Item Type for the Return Line Item, by selecting
        one of the following options:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Item</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The lookup feature located to the right of the field leads
              to a searchable list of Inventory Items. If the Return is being
              applied to a particular Invoice―and your Sales module is
              configured to restrict Returns to Items appearing on their
              apply-to document―then the Item list will show only Items on the
              original Invoice. The ITEM/ALIAS SEARCH button can also be used
              to help locate Return Items. Once an Item Number is entered, the
              Inventory Unit of Measure and Item description will
              automatically appear. Additionally, you may also specify the
              Item's receiving Site. Commercial editions of xTuple allow Items
              to be received into multiple Sites.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Miscellaneous</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter a name and description for the miscellaneous,
              non-Inventory Item you are billing the Customer for. The name
              and description fields are free-form, meaning they accept
              unlimited alphanumeric characters. You must also select a Sales
              Category. Sales Categories are used to identify the General
              Ledger (G/L) Accounts to be used when non-Inventory Sales
              transactions take place.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Reason Code</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the reason why an adjustment is being made to a
        Customer's account.</para>
        <para><note>
            <para>By default, the Reason Code on the Return header will be
            used at the Line Item level. However, you may change the Reason
            Code for individual Line Items.</para>
          </note></para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. Returned</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the quantity of the Item returned for credit. If the
        Return was created from a Return Authorization, the quantity returned
        will be zero on the Return Item screen. Return Authorization returns
        are handled separately, outside of the normal sales Return Inventory
        handling process.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Update Inventory</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if you want the quantity returned to be added back
              into Inventory when you post the Return. If not selected, your
              Inventory will not be updated.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. To Credit</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the quantity of the Item you plan to give the Customer
        credit for. The quantity entered here may equal the quantity returned.
        However, you have the flexibility to credit the Customer for a
        quantity different from the returned quantity. The quantity credited
        is multiplied by the Net Unit Price to determine the amount of the
        credit.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The unit of measure being returned and credited in.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. Shipped</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the quantity of the Item shipped to date.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Discount % from Sale</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify a percentage to reduce the credited amount by. The
        discount will be deducted from the sale Price, thereby reducing the
        amount of the credit by the specified percentage.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>returns</primary>
          <secondary>pricing of</secondary>
        </indexterm>Net Unit Price</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the Net Unit Price to assign the quantity being
        credited. If the Return is being applied to a specific Invoice, then
        the system will automatically enter the Item's Net Unit Price as it
        appeared on the referring Invoice. If no Invoice is being applied-to,
        then the system will choose the lower of the following two Prices: A)
        The most-specific Pricing Schedule Assignment or B) any Sale in effect
        at the time of Order entry. The specificity of Pricing Schedule
        Assignments is determined in the following descending order: By
        Customer Ship-To Address (most specific), by Customer, by Customer
        Type, by Customer Type pattern, by all Customers. The lookup feature
        located to the right of the field leads to a Price List screen.</para>
        <para>If your Pricing Schedule has multiple Units of Measure (UOM) on
        it (or if several Pricing Schedules share the same level of Price
        specificity, but they have different UOMs) then the UOM which matches
        the selected UOM will be chosen—that is, as long as the quantity break
        does not exceed the quantity being priced. If no entry matches the UOM
        with a quantity break less than the quantity being priced, then the
        lowest value Price for any UOM will be chosen. To make sure a specific
        UOM is always chosen at the desired level of Price specificity, then
        your Pricing Schedules should include at least one UOM with a quantity
        break of 0.</para>
        <tip>
          <para>The system can be configured to prevent users from editing the
          Net Unit Price. If your system is configured that way, the Net Unit
          Price field will not be editable.</para>
        </tip>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Pricing UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Item's Price UOM.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Extended Price</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Extended Price. The Extended Price for a Return
        Item is based on the quantity credited multiplied by the Price.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Unit Cost</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Standard Cost per unit.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>List Price</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Item's List Price per unit displays.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Sale Price</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the sold Price for the Item at the time of sale.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>returns</primary>
          <secondary>discount pricing for</secondary>
        </indexterm>List Discount %</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The default Customer discount (if any) will display here.
        Default Customer discount percentages are defined in the Customer
        master.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Tax Type</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the Tax Type for the Return Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Tax</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the amount of Tax to be charged for the Return Line
        Item quantity. To get a detailed view of the Tax calculation, click on
        the Tax link using your mouse.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>Click on the notes tab to enter notes and you will be presented with
  the following screen:</para>
  <screenshot>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/creditMemoItem_notes.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption>Create New Return Line Item Notes</caption>
    </mediaobject>
  </screenshot>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Notes</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        Notes related to the Return Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
