<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="crmaccountMerge">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>crm accounts</primary>
      <secondary>merging</secondary>
    </indexterm> Merge CRM Accounts</title>
  <para>If you are importing Customer or Vendor or any other CRM Account
  information—either through the xTuple web Portal or some other feature—it's
  possible you will encounter duplicate CRM Account records. It's also
  possible to create overlapping or duplicate CRM Account records manually by
  mistake. The Merge CRM Accounts utility is a wizard designed to help you
  resolve this scenario. Using the Merge CRM Accounts utility, you can easily
  locate duplicate records and merge them into one single CRM Account
  record.</para>
  <tip>
    <para>For practical information about how the Merge CRM Accounts utility
    can be used during an upgrade process, please see the following article
    posted on our community website here: <ulink
    url="http://www.xtuple.org/node/4479">http://www.xtuple.org/node/4479</ulink>.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>To begin using the Merge CRM Accounts utility, select the "Merge CRM
  Accounts" option. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/crmaccountMergePickTaskPage.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Identify Merge Tasks</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>Upon first opening the Merge CRM Accounts utility, you are presented
  with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Start a new merge</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to begin a new merge process.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Continue an existing merge</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to continue working on a merge that you have already
        started by not yet completed. Because you may have multiple merges in
        process at the same time, be sure to select the correct merge from the
        drop-down list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Revert a completed merge</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to reverse a merge that has already been completed.
        Again, be sure to select the correct merge from the drop-down
        list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Purge old records</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to purge old records which have been marked for purging
        during merge processes you have performed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>After specifying a task to perform, select the NEXT button to reach
  the next step. The following screenshot shows the second step for creating a
  new merge:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/crmaccountMergePickAccountsPage.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Select CRM Accounts to be Merged</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When starting a new merge, you need to identify the CRM Accounts you
  want to merge. You are presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <xi:include href="../widgets/parameterwidget.xml"
                xpointer="parameterwidget"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
    <varlistentry>
      <term>QUERY</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to refresh the CRM Account data after filters have been
        changed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Accounts to Merge</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the list of CRM Accounts found in your system. By using
        your mouse, you can click on Accounts to specify which ones you want
        to merge. The Accounts you select will appear in the "Destination
        Account" drop-down list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Destination Account</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>After the CRM Accounts have been selected, specify which of the
        Accounts is the target or destination Account. Information from the
        other selected Account(s) will be merged into the destination
        Account.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>Once you've selected CRM Accounts to merge, select the NEXT button to
  reach the next step. The following screenshot shows the next step once
  you've identified CRM Accounts to merge:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/crmaccountMergePickDataPage.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Select Data to be Merged</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>The next step is to pick which details you want to add to the target
  CRM Account from the source CRM Account(s). When merging specific data
  elements, you are presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Source CRM Accounts</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the CRM Accounts you want to merge. Any information
        displayed in blue will be added to the target CRM Account. You can
        select information (i.e., make it blue) by double-clicking on the
        information with your mouse. You can also click on the information
        once and then choose either the SELECT or DESELECT button to add or
        remove the information from the merge. Since the final result can only
        contain one piece of information per column, only one item in each
        column can be selected and blue.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SELECT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>After a cell of information has been clicked on, use this button
        to select it and add it to the merge.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>DESELECT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>After a cell of information has been clicked on, use this button
        to select it and remove it from the merge.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>COMMIT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to save the details you want to merge. At this stage, the
        merge is still in process. You may revisit the merge details and make
        changes later.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>Once you select the COMMIT button, you will be shown a preview of your
  merge results, as shown below:</para>
  <screenshot>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/crmaccountMergeResultPage.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption>Results of CRM Account Merge</caption>
    </mediaobject>
  </screenshot>
  <para>To keep the merge result, make sure the "Keep" option is chosen and
  then select the NEXT button. To undo the merge, make sure the "Undo" option
  is chosen and then select the NEXT button.</para>
  <para>Assuming you decide to keep the merge, you will be presented with the
  following purge screen:</para>
  <screenshot>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/crmaccountMergePurgePage.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption>Purge CRM Accounts</caption>
    </mediaobject>
  </screenshot>
  <para>When reviewing the purge screen, pay particular attention to the
  information shown in the "Status" column. The status information explains
  what will happen to the specified records when they are purged.</para>
  <tip>
    <para>If you decide to delete a merge you are working on, look for a
    status of "In Process." When you purge an in-process merge, you are
    effectively deleting the merge.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>PURGE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a target CRM Account and then select this button to
        complete the merge and purge the records you are not keeping.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>PURGE ALL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to purge all merges shown in the list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>FINISH</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select this button when you are done using this screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
