<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2011 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section>
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>crm accounts</primary>
      <secondary>merging</secondary>
    </indexterm> Merge CRM Accounts</title>
  <para>If you are importing Customer or Vendor or any other CRM Account
  information—either through the xTuple web Portal or or some other
  feature—it's possible you will encounter duplicate CRM Account records. It's
  also possible to create overlapping or duplicate CRM Account records
  manually by mistake. The Merge CRM Accounts utility is a wizard designed to
  help you resolve this scenario. Using the Merge CRM Accounts utility, you
  can easily locate duplicate records and merge them into one single CRM
  Account record.</para>
  <tip>
    <para>For practical information about how the Merge CRM Accounts utility
    can be used during an upgrade process, please see the following article
    posted on our community website here: <ulink
    url="http://www.xtuple.org/node/4479">http://www.xtuple.org/node/4479</ulink>.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>To begin using the Merge CRM Accounts utility, select the "Merge CRM
  Accounts" option. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/crmaccountMergePickTaskPage.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Identify Merge Tasks</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>Upon first opening the Merge CRM Accounts utility, you are presented
  with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Start a new merge</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to begin a new merge process.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Continue an existing merge</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to continue working on a merge that you have already
        started by not yet completed. Because you may have multiple merges in
        process at the same time, be sure to select the correct merge from the
        drop-down list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Revert a completed merge</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to reverse a merge that has already been completed.
        Again, be sure to select the correct merge from the drop-down
        list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Purge old records</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to purge old records which have been marked for purging
        during merge processes you have performed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>After specifying a task to perform, select the NEXT button to reach
  the next screen for the task. The following screenshot shows a new merge
  being started:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/crmaccountMergePickAccountsPage.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Select CRM Accounts to be Merged</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When starting a new merge, you first need to specify which CRM
  Accounts you want to merge. You are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <xi:include href="../widgets/parameterwidget.xml"
                xpointer="parameterwidget"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Accounts to Merge</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Using your mouse, select the CRM Accounts you want to
        merge.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Destination Account</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>After the CRM Accounts have been selected, specify which of the
        Accounts is the target or destination Account. Information from the
        other selected Account(s) will be merged into the destination
        Account.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>QUERY</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to refresh the CRM Account data after filters have been
        changed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>In addition to the basic Contact references, specific data elements of
  a source Contact may also be carried over to the merged target
  Contact—information such as the notes, phone numbers, or the email address.
  To select these specific data elements for merging, go to the "Selections"
  tab":</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/crmaccountMergePickDataPage.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Select Data to be Merged</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When merging specific data elements for selected Contacts, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Source Contacts</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays any Contact records you specified as source Contacts on
        the "Contacts" tab. If you right-click on any of the cells of the
        Source Contacts list, you can choose to merge that cell to the target
        Contact. The cell's contents will turn blue when selected.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Target Contact</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the target Contact record. When you merge Contacts, the
        target Contact record will receive the specified data elements
        selected in the source Contact(s) records.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para></para>
  <screenshot>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/crmaccountMergeResultPage.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption>Results of CRM Account Merge</caption>
    </mediaobject>
  </screenshot>
  <para></para>
  <screenshot>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/crmaccountMergePurgePage.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption>Purge CRM Accounts</caption>
    </mediaobject>
  </screenshot>
  <para></para>
</section>
