<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2010 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section656540">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>customers</primary>
      <secondary>creating new</secondary>
    </indexterm>Enter New Customer</title>
  <para>Maintaining detailed Customer information is essential to ensuring a
  successful Customer relationship. To enter a new Customer into the system,
  select the "New Customer" option. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/customer_tabAddresses.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create New Customer</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <tip>
    <para>Customers can also be created from the CRM Account screen. Simply
    enter a new CRM Account, selecting the "Customer" relationship
    option.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>When creating a new Customer, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Customer #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The Customer Number uniquely identifies the Customer. To search
        for an existing Customer, use the lookup feature located next to the
        Customer field. Use the "+" button to add a new Customer. And use the
        "!" button if you want to edit the Customer Number. If the "!" button
        is not selected, you will be prevented from editing the Customer
        Number.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Customer Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the name of the Customer or company you are doing business
        with. This field should not to be confused with the contact name of an
        individual at the company.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Customer Type</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the Customer Type the Customer belongs to.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Active</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you are actively doing business with this Customer.
        Not selecting makes the Customer inactive.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without creating the Customer, returning you
        to the application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Creates the Customer and enters the Customer into the master
        list of Customers.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>customers</primary>
      <secondary>addresses for</secondary>
    </indexterm>To enter Contact information for the Customer, select the
  "Addresses" tab and choose from the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Billing Contact</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to manually enter billing Contact information in the
        fields below&mdash;or use the lookup feature to select pre-existing
        Contact information. If a new Contact is manually entered here, that
        Contact will be added automatically to the master list of Contacts.
        For additional documentation related to creating Contacts, see <xref
        linkend="contactTitle" />.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Correspondence Contact</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to manually enter non-billing-related Contact information
        in the fields below&mdash;or use the lookup feature to select
        pre-existing Contact information. Examples of non-billing-related
        correspondence might include Price updates, holiday cards, etc. You
        may also enter additional contact information. If a new Contact is
        manually entered here, that Contact will be added automatically to the
        master list of Contacts. For additional documentation related to
        creating Contacts, see <xref linkend="contactTitle" />.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Ship-To</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to display Ship-To Addresses for the specified Customer.
        Every Customer can have multiple Ship-To Addresses, one for each of
        the destinations you ship goods to. Ship-To Addresses are specified at
        the point of Sales Order entry.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>ship-to addresses</primary>
      <secondary>creating new</secondary>
    </indexterm>To create a new Ship-To Address for a Customer, select the NEW
  button. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/shipTo.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Ship-To Address</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <tip>
    <para>The Ship-To Address screen shares many common fields with the
    Customer master&mdash;for example, shipping defaults, Sales
    Representative, etc. By default, the Customer master values will be
    pre-filled on the Ship-To Address screen. However, you can easily change
    these Customer defaults for each Ship-To Address. The specific Ship-To
    Address information will be used when the Ship-To Address is selected at
    the point of Sales Order entry.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>When creating a new Ship-To Address, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Customer #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Customer Number and Customer name.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Ship-To #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify a number or code to identify the Ship-To Address.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the name of the company that will receive shipments at
        this Ship-To Address. Customers may maintain multiple Ship-To
        Addresses with diverse destinations.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Active</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to activate the Ship-To Address. If this option is not
        selected, then the Ship-To Address will be inactive.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Default</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if this is the default Ship-To Address for the
        Customer.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Address</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Manually enter delivery Address information in the fields
        below&mdash;or use the lookup feature to select pre-existing Address
        information. If a new Address is manually entered here, that Address
        will be added automatically to the master list of Addresses. For
        additional documentation related to creating Addresses, see <xref
        linkend="Section560316" />.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>ship-to addresses</primary>
          <secondary>contact information for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Contact</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Manually enter delivery Contact information in the fields
        below&mdash;or use the lookup feature to select pre-existing Contact
        information. This field should not to be confused with the "Name"
        field that appears on the Ship-To Address label. If a new Contact is
        manually entered here, that Contact will be added automatically to the
        master list of Contacts. For additional documentation related to
        creating Contacts, see <xref linkend="contactTitle" />.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Defaults</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the following Ship-To Address defaults:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Sales Rep</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the Sales Representative for the Ship-To Address.
              When entering Orders for a Customer, the name of the Sales
              Representative specified on the Ship-To Address will be used if
              it is different from the Customer default.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Commission</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Field accepts up to 4 whole numbers and 2 decimals. Enter
              the Commission rate to be used when Sales Orders for this
              Customer are shipped to the specified Ship-To Address.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Ship Zone</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the Shipping Zone for the Ship-To Address.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Tax Zone</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify Tax Zone to be used for Ship-To Address.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Ship Via</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the default Ship Via to be used for the Ship-To
              Address. You may enter a free-form Ship Via simply by typing the
              name of the Ship Via into the field.</para>
              <tip>
                <para>The system supports up-to-date shipment tracking with
                links to the websites of many leading shipping companies
                (i.e., "Ship Vias").</para>
              </tip>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Shipping Form</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the default Shipping Form to be used for the
              Ship-To Address.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Shipping Charges</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the default Shipping Charges to be used for the
              Ship-To Address.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>General Notes</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select the "General Notes" tab to access this scrolling text
        field with word-wrapping for entering general Notes related to the
        Customer Ship-To Address. These Notes are for internal use
        only.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Shipping Notes</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select the "Shipping Notes" tab to access this scrolling text
        field with word-wrapping for entering Shipping Notes related to the
        Customer Ship-To Address. Shipping Notes are transferred to the
        "Shipping Notes" tab on the Sales Order header whenever a Sales Order
        for the specified Ship-To Address is entered. Ultimately, Shipping
        Notes may be printed on shipping paperwork.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="standard">
      <term>Transmission</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select the "Transmission" tab to associate EDI Profiles with the
        Ship-To Address. EDI Profiles are used for transmitting Orders and
        Invoices to Customers electronically&mdash;via email or FTP.
        Associating an EDI Profile with a Ship-To Address overrides the
        association of an EDI Profile with the Customer.</para>
        <note>
          <para role="standard">The buttons on the "Transmission" tab are
          disabled when creating a new Ship-To Address. If you want to set up
          EDI for a new Ship-To Address, save the Ship-To Address and edit it
          again.</para>
        </note>
        <xi:include href="../widgets/edirelation.xml"
                    xpointer="edirelationWidget"
                    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without adding Customer Address information,
        returning you to the application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Saves any new Customer Address information.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To define some of the basic Customer settings, select the "Settings"
  tab. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/customer_settingsTab.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Customer Settings Tab</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When defining basic Customer settings, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>General</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to specify the default preferences for the
        Customer.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Terms</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to specify credit-related information for the
        Customer.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Tax</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to specify the default Tax information for the
        Customer.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Credit Cards</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to enter Credit Card information for the Customer. This
        option will only be enabled if your site is configured to use and
        process Customer Credit Cards.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>The following options are available when you select the "General"
  option:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Sales Rep</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify a default Sales Representative for the Customer. When
        entering Orders for a Customer, the Sales Representative defined on
        the specified Ship-To Address will be used.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Commission</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the commission percentage for the selected Sales
        Representative.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Ship Via</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the default Ship Via to be used for the Customer. You
        may enter a free-form Ship Via simply by typing the name of the Ship
        Via into the field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Shipping Form</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the default Shipping Form to be used for the
        Customer.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Shipping Charges</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the default Shipping Charges to be used for the
        Customer. Shipping defaults specified on the Customer master will
        transfer to the Sales Order header when a new Sales Order is entered
        for a Customer.</para>
        <tip>
          <para>The system supports up-to-date shipment tracking with links to
          the websites of many leading shipping companies (i.e., "Ship
          Vias").</para>
        </tip>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>backorders</primary>
          <secondary>accepted by customer</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>customers</primary>
          <secondary>backorders accepted by</secondary>
        </indexterm>Accepts Backorders</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to indicate whether the Customer accepts Backorders. A
        backorder is defined as an unshipped Line Item on a shipped Sales
        Order. For example, if a Customer orders three Line Items, but only
        one of the Line Items is shipped, the remaining two Line Items would
        be on backorder. Not selecting this option indicates the Customer does
        not accept backorders or partial shipments.</para>
        <tip>
          <para>Sales Orders having unshipped Line Items on backorder will be
          closed at billing (i.e., when an Invoice is created) if the Customer
          in question is flagged to not accept backorders.</para>
        </tip>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>customers</primary>
                <secondary>order preferences for</secondary>
              </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>shipments</primary>
                <secondary>partial</secondary>
              </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>customers</primary>
                <secondary>partial shipments accepted by</secondary>
              </indexterm>Accepts Partial Shipments</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Accepts Partial Shipments: Select to indicate whether the
              Customer accepts partial shipments. A partial shipment is
              defined as a shipped Order having a Line Item whose full
              quantity is not included in the shipment. For example, if
              Customer ABC orders 20 units of Item XYZ, but only 10 units are
              shipped, that partial Line Item quantity ("10") would constitute
              a partial shipment of the ordered Item. Not selecting this
              option indicates the Customer does not accept partial
              shipments.</para>
              <tip>
                <para>Partially-shipped Line Items will be closed at billing
                (i.e., when an Invoice is created) if the Customer in question
                is flagged to not accept partial shipments.</para>
              </tip>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Allow Free-Form Ship-To's</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to indicate that free-form Ship-To Addresses may be
        entered when Sales Orders are created for the Customer. If not
        selected, you are indicating that free-form Ship-To's may not be
        entered for the Customer. Instead, Ship-To's must be entered using
        predefined information.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Allow Free-Form Bill-To</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to indicate that free-form Bill-To Addresses may be
        entered when Sales Orders are created for the Customer. If not
        selected, you are indicating that free-form Bill-To's may not be
        entered for the Customer. Instead, the predefined Bill-To found on the
        Customer master will be used.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="standard">
      <term>Preferred Selling Site</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the preferred selling Site, if any. This is an optional
        setting. If a preferred Site is selected, then this Site will be used
        when entering Sales Orders for the Customer. At Sales Order entry, the
        preferred Site will be the default Shipping Site for the Sales
        Order&mdash;as well as the default selling Site for Sales Order
        Items.</para>
        <note>
          <para>If there are no Item Sites matching the preferred Site at the
          point of Sales Order Line Item entry, the highest-ranked selling
          Site will be used instead.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To specify credit-related information for the Customer, select the
  "Terms" option. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/customer_settingsTab_termsButton.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Customer Terms Options</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When specifying credit-related information for the Customer, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Terms</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the default billing Terms for the Customer.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Discount</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the default discount&mdash;if any&mdash;which the Customer
        should receive. Customer discounts are applied to either a) the List
        Price for an Item if the List Price is being used or b) a specific
        Sale if a Sale is in place which the Customer is assigned to. The
        discount does not get applied to Pricing Schedules.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Currency</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the Currency to be used when transacting business with
        the Customer. With the system's multi-currency support, you can do
        business with Customer's in their Currency, using Exchange Rates to
        normalize transactions in your base Currency.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>In Good Standing</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to mark the Customer as having credit in good standing.
        Customers with credit "In Good Standing" may have Sales Orders issued
        for them. A black-colored typeface will be associated with their
        account.</para>
        <note>
          <para>Sales Orders may not be entered for Customers whose credit
          status is either "On Credit Warning" or "On Credit Hold." Credit
          Holds may be overridden, but only by users having the appropriate
          privileges.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>On Credit Warning</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to alert sales staff to possible credit problems with the
        Customer. Non-privileged users will be prevented from issuing Stock to
        Shipping for any Customers on credit warning. An orange-colored
        typeface will be associated with their account.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>On Credit Hold</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to inform sales staff that Customer's credit has been
        suspended. Non-privileged users will be prevented from issuing Stock
        to Shipping for any Customers on credit hold. A red-colored typeface
        will be associated with their account.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Uses Purchase Orders</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to indicate that the Customer uses Purchase Orders. If
        selected, users will be required to enter a Customer Purchase Order
        Number when entering a Sales Order. In addition, selecting the option
        will prevent users from entering duplicate Customer Purchase Order
        Numbers&mdash;unless the Customer is marked as using Blanket
        POs.</para>
        <note>
          <para>If the option "Uses Purchase Orders" is not selected, the
          system will place no restrictions on Customer Purchase Order
          Numbers.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>purchase orders</primary>
          <secondary>customers using blanket</secondary>
        </indexterm>Uses Blanket P/O's</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Blanket P/O"s: Select to indicate that the Customer uses blanket
        Purchase Orders. A blanket P/O is a Customer Purchase Order which may
        be used for more than one Sales Order. Selecting this option means
        users will be allowed to enter duplicate Purchase Order Numbers for
        this Customer.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Balance Method</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify one of the available methods for handling open balances
        for the Customer:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Balance Forward</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to post payments against the oldest Invoices. Used
              in Accounts Receivable only.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Open Items</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to post payments against specific Invoices,
              regardless of their age. Used in Accounts Receivable
              only.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Credit Limit</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the credit ceiling you are willing to extend to the
        Customer.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>customers</primary>
          <secondary>credit rating options for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Credit Rating</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>You have the option of assigning a credit rating to the
        Customer. Any value entered here is purely informational. The system
        does not use the credit rating in any calculations.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Place on Credit Warning when Credit Limit is Exceeded</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select this option to automatically place the Customer on Credit
        Warning if their open Accounts Receivable (A/R) balance exceeds their
        Credit Limit. This option must also be selected for a Customer's A/R
        open items to be evaluated when the Update Late Customer Credit Status
        utility is run. If a Customer is on Credit Warning, Sales Orders may
        not be entered for the Customer&mdash;except by users with override
        privileges. Once the Customer's A/R open balance falls below their
        Credit Limit, Sales Orders may once again be entered for the
        Customer.</para>
        <tip>
          <para>You must specify you want a Customer to be placed on credit
          warning to enable the late credit status utility to consider a
          Customer's A/R open items.</para>
        </tip>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Place Open S/Os on Credit Hold when Credit Limit is
      Exceeded</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select this option to place all new and existing open Sales
        Orders on Credit Hold if the Customer's Credit Limit is exceeded. The
        contents of Sales Orders placed on Credit Hold may not be issued to
        Shipping&mdash;except by users with override privileges. Once the
        Customer's Credit Limit is no longer exceeded, Sales Order contents
        may be issued to Shipping.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Alternate Late Grace Days</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to specify an alternate number of grace days for the
        Customer, to override the global grace period defined at the system
        level in the Accounting configuration. To learn more about configuring
        grace days, see <xref linkend="Section942568" />.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Grace Days</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the number of days beyond the A/R open due date
              which will serve as a grace period for the Customer. The number
              of days entered here will override the global number of grace
              days.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To specify Tax-related information for the Customer, select the "Tax"
  option. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/customer_settingsTab_taxButton.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Customer Tax Options</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>customers</primary>
      <secondary>tax information for</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>taxes</primary>
      <secondary>for customers</secondary>
    </indexterm>When adding Customer Tax information, you are presented with
  the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>tax zones</primary>
          <secondary>default for customers</secondary>
        </indexterm>Default Tax Zone</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the default Tax Zone you want to associate with the
        Customer. By default, the specified Tax Zone will be used on Sales
        Orders and Quotes for the Customer?unless a Ship-To Address in use
        specifies a different Tax Zone.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Tax Registration Numbers</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists Tax Registration Numbers for the specified
        Customer.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Opens screen for creating a new Customer Tax Registration
        Number.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>EDIT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enables you to edit highlighted Customer Tax Registration
        Numbers. The edit screen is the same as that for creating a new
        Customer Tax Registration Number&mdash;except that when editing, the
        fields will contain Customer Tax Registration Number information.
        Double-clicking on a Customer Tax Registration Number will also bring
        you to the editing screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>VIEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a Customer Tax Registration Number and then select
        this button to reach a read-only view of the "Edit" screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>DELETE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a Customer Tax Registration Number and then select
        this button to remove the Customer Tax Registration Number from the
        list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To add a new Customer Tax Registration Number, select the NEW button.
  The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/taxRegistration.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Customer Tax Registration Information</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>customers</primary>
      <secondary>tax registration for</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>taxes</primary>
      <secondary>registration for customers</secondary>
    </indexterm>When adding a new Customer Tax Registration Number, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Customer #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Customer Number for the specified Customer.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Tax Zone</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the Tax Zone the Tax Registration Number is valid
        for.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Tax Authority</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the Tax Authority associated with the Tax Registration
        Number.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Registration Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the Customer's Tax Registration Number for the specified
        Tax Authority. The registration number is used by Tax Authorities to
        identify businesses and/or individuals. An Employer Identification
        Numbers (EIN) is an example of a Tax Registration Number.</para>
        <tip>
          <para>The Customer's Tax Registration Number is used for identifying
          the Customer to relevant Tax Authorities. This information should
          not be confused with the Tax Registration Numbers, which are used to
          identify your company to relevant Tax Authorities.</para>
        </tip>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Effectivity</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the date range the Tax Registration Number is valid
        for:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Start Date</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The Tax Registration Number is valid on and after this
              date.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>End Date</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The Tax Registration Number is valid on and before this
              date.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Notes</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        Notes related to the Tax Registration Number.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without creating a new Tax Registration
        Number, returning you to the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Creates the Tax Registration Number and adds it to the master
        list of Customer Tax Registration Numbers.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>credit cards</primary>
      <secondary>adding to customer master</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>customers</primary>
      <secondary>credit cards for</secondary>
    </indexterm>To specify Credit Card information for the Customer, select
  the "Credit Cards" option. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/customer_settingsTab_creditcardsButton.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Customer Credit Cards</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <note>
    <para>Customer Credit Cards may be used when entering Sales Orders or Cash
    Receipt transactions for the Customer. When entering a Sales Order, you
    have the option to either pre-authorize or charge a Credit Card. Any
    pre-authorizations may later be post-authorized using the A/R
    Workbench.</para>
  </note>
  <para>When specifying Credit Card information for the Customer, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Credit Cards</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists Credit Card records for the Customer.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Opens screen for entering new Credit Card information for the
        Customer.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>EDIT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enables you to edit highlighted Credit Cards. The edit screen is
        the same as that for entering new Credit Card information&mdash;except
        that when editing, the fields will contain Credit Card
        information.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>VIEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a Credit Card and then select this button to reach a
        read-only view of the "Edit" screen. Double-clicking on a Credit Card
        will also bring you to the view screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>MOVE UP</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a Credit Card and then select this button to move the
        Credit Card up in the sequence of Credit Cards. Sequence numbers are
        automatically adjusted to reflect the change in position.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>MOVE DOWN</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a Credit Card and then select this button to move the
        Credit Card down the sequence of Credit Cards. Sequence numbers are
        automatically adjusted to reflect the change in position.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To create a new Credit Card record for a Customer, select the NEW
  button. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/creditCard.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create New Credit Card Record</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When creating a new Credit Card record for a Customer, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Customer #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the name of the Customer associated with the Credit
        Card record. The name of the Customer will also be displayed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Credit Card Type</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the type of Credit Card. The following Credit Card types
        are currently supported: Master Card, Visa, American Express, and
        Discover.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Credit Card Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the Credit Card Number. After the Credit Card record has
        been saved, all but the last four digits of the Credit Card Number
        will be encrypted for security purposes.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Active</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if the Credit Card record is active. Do not select this
        option if the specified Credit Card is inactive or invalid for any
        reason.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a name to describe the Credit Card record.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Address</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>By default, the Customer's Billing Address will be entered here.
        However, you may specify an alternate billing address for the Credit
        Card record using the Address lookup feature located in the lower
        right-hand corner of the screen. For additional documentation related
        to creating Addresses, see <xref linkend="Section560316" />.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Expiration Month</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the month when the specified Credit Card expires. The
        month must be saved in the format "MM". For example, the month of
        January would be represented as "01".</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Expiration Year</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the year when the specified Credit Card expires. The year
        must be saved in the format "YYYY". For example, the year 2006 would
        be represented as "2006".</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without creating the Credit Card record,
        returning you to the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Creates the Credit Card record and adds it to the list of Credit
        Card records.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>characteristics</primary>
      <secondary>creating new for customer</secondary>
    </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>characteristics</primary>
      <secondary>customers having</secondary>
    </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>customers</primary>
      <secondary>characteristics for</secondary>
    </indexterm>Customer Characteristics are user-defined definitions which
  may be used to provide additional layers of description about Customers. For
  example, Customer Characteristics might be used to specify "Order
  Preferences" or "Buying Season". These constitute static descriptions which
  are not processed by the system, but are useful for informational purposes.
  To enter Characteristics associated with a Customer, select the
  "Characteristics" tab. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/customer_tabCharacteristics.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Customer Characteristics</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot><tip>
      <para>If the Customer Type a Customer belongs to has a Characteristic
      Profile (i.e., template) defined, then every Customer in that Customer
      Type will be presented with a range of pre-defined Characteristics. You
      can select or add values for each Characteristic by right-clicking on a
      Characteristic in the list.</para>
    </tip></para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Characteristics</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists the Characteristics related to the
        Customer.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>If Characteristic Profiles are enabled for the Customer Type, you
    will not see buttons on the right-side of the screen. Values may be
    selected or added by right-clicking on a Characteristic in the
    list.</para>
  </note>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <tip>
    <para>If you do not see buttons on the right side of the Customer
    Characteristics screen, this means Characteristic Profiles are being used
    for the Customer Type the Customer belongs to. These buttons will only
    appear if Customer Type Characteristic Profiles are not being used.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Opens screen for creating a new Customer Characteristic.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>EDIT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enables you to edit highlighted Customer Characteristics. The
        edit screen is the same as that for creating a new Customer
        Characteristic&mdash;except that when editing, the fields will contain
        Customer Characteristic information. Double-clicking on a Customer
        Characteristic will also bring you to the editing screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>DELETE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a Customer Characteristic and then select this button
        to remove the Customer Characteristic from the list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To create a new Customer Characteristic, select the NEW button. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/characteristicAssignmentCustomer.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create New Customer Characteristic</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When creating a new Customer Characteristic, you are presented with
  the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Characteristic</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select a Characteristic from the list of Characteristics
        designated as being available for use as Customer
        Characteristics.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Value</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a description of the Customer Characteristic.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without creating the Customer Characteristic,
        returning you to the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Creates the Customer Characteristic and adds it to the list of
        Customer Characteristics.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>Every Customer record is linked to a CRM Account. To view information
  related to the Customer's CRM Account, select the "CRM" tab. The following
  screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/customer_crmTab.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>CRM Information</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When viewing information related to the Customer's CRM Account, you
  are presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Contacts</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to view a list of all Contacts associated with the
        Account. On this screen you can manage an Account's Contacts?either by
        adding new Contacts or attaching/detaching Contacts from the Account.
        Any changes made here also update the CRM Account record. For
        additional documentation related to managing a Contacts associated
        with a CRM Account, see <xref linkend="Section560293" />.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>To-Do List</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to view the To-Do List associated with the Account. On
        this screen you can manage all of the To-Do items and Incidents
        related to the Account. Any changes made here also update the main
        To-Do List. For additional documentation related to managing the To-Do
        List, see <xref linkend="Section560390" />.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Opportunities</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to view any Opportunities associated with the Account. On
        this screen you can manage your Customer Opportunities?either by
        adding new Opportunities or editing already-existing ones. Any changes
        made here also update the main list of Opportunities. For additional
        documentation related to managing Opportunities, see <xref
        linkend="Section574794" />.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To manage or review a Customer's sales activity, select the "Sales"
  tab. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/customer_salesTab.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Customer Sales Information</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When reviewing a Customer's sales activity, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Summary</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to view high-level sales history information for the
        Customer, including year-to-date sales, last year sales, total backlog
        value, and more. For more detailed Customer sales history, see the
        wide range of sales analysis options available in the Sales Module
        menu here: <guimenuitem>Sales &gt; Analysis</guimenuitem>.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Quotes</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to view the list of Quotes associated with the Customer.
        On this screen you can create new Quotes or edit existing ones. For
        additional documentation related to entering Quotes for Customers, see
        <xref linkend="Section528866" />.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Orders</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to view the list of Sales Orders associated with the
        Customer. On this screen you can create new Sales Orders or edit
        existing ones. For additional documentation related to entering Sales
        Orders for Customers, see <xref linkend="Section519027" />.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="standard">
      <term>Returns</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to manage Returns associated with the Customer. On this
        screen you can manage most aspects of the Returns process?from
        creating new Return Authorizations to processing Credit Memos. For
        additional documentation related to managing Return Authorizations,
        see <xref linkend="returnAuthWorkbenchTitle" />.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To manage or review accounting information for the Customer, select
  the "Accounting" tab. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/customer_accountingTab.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Customer Accounting Information</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When reviewing a Customer's accounting information, you are presented
  with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Receivables</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to view information related to the Customer's open
        Receivables. On this screen you can manage most aspects of the
        Receivables process?from creating new Receivable documents (e.g.,
        Invoices, Credit Memos, etc.) to printing out Customer statements. For
        additional documentation related to managing Customer Receivables, see
        <xref linkend="Section556338" />.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Cash Receipts</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to view information related to Cash Receipts from the
        Customer. On this screen you can view Cash Receipt and cash
        application history, as well as enter new Cash Receipts for the
        Customer. For additional documentation related to Cash Receipt
        history, see <xref linkend="Section553315" />. And for detailed
        information about entering Cash Receipts, see <xref
        linkend="Section524311" />.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Credit Cards</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to view information related to transactions involving the
        Customer's Credit Card(s). On this screen you can view Credit Card
        transaction history. You can also authorize Credit Card
        pre-authorizations. For additional documentation related to Credit
        Card history and the method for processing pre-authorizations, see
        <xref linkend="Section570079" />.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>documents</primary>
      <secondary>customers associated with</secondary>
    </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>customers</primary>
      <secondary>documents associated with</secondary>
    </indexterm>associate documents with a Customer, select the "Documents"
  tab. The following screen will appear:<mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/customer_documentsTab.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption><para>Customer Images</para></caption>
    </mediaobject></para>
  <xi:include href="../widgets/documents.xml" xpointer="documentsWidget"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
  <para>To enter remarks (e.g., Notes and Comments) related to the Customer,
  select the "Remarks" tab. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/customer_tabRemarks.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Customer Notes</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When entering remarks related to a Customer, you are presented with
  the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Notes</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to enter Notes related to the Customer. This is a
        scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering Notes related to
        the Customer. Any Notes entered on this screen are for internal
        purposes only.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Comments</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to review or add Comments related to the Customer.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <xi:include href="../widgets/comments.xml" xpointer="commentsWidget"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
  <para role="standard">The Electronic Data Interchange (EDI) system enables
  you to send Quotes, Sales Orders, Credit Memos, A/R Statements, and Invoices
  electronically to your Customers. To establish a Customer's EDI preferences,
  select the "Transmission" tab. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para role="standard"><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/customer_transmitTab.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Transmission Information for EDI</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <note role="standard">
    <para>The buttons on the "Transmission" tab are disabled when creating a
    new Customer. If you want to set up EDI for a new Customer, save the
    Customer and edit it again.</para>
  </note>
  <xi:include href="../widgets/edirelation.xml" xpointer="edirelationWidget"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
</section>
