<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2008 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section656540">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>customers</primary>
      <secondary>creating new</secondary>
    </indexterm>Enter New Customer</title>
  <para>Maintaining detailed Customer information is essential to ensuring a
  successful Customer relationship. To enter a new Customer into the system,
  select the "New Customer" option. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/customer.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create New Customer</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <tip>
    <para>Customers can also be created from the CRM Account screen. Simply
    enter a new CRM Account, selecting the "Customer" Relationship
    option.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>When creating a new Customer, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Customer #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The Customer Number uniquely identifies the Customer.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Customer Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the name of the Customer or company you are doing business
        with. This field should not to be confused with the contact name of an
        individual at the company.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Customer Type</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the Customer Type the Customer belongs to.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Active</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you are actively doing business with this Customer.
        Not selecting makes the Customer inactive.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Sales Rep</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify a default Sales Representative for the Customer.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>When entering Orders for a Customer, the Sales Representative
    defined on the specified Ship-To Address will be used.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Commission</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the commission percentage for the selected Sales
        Representative.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Defaults</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify one of the available Shipping-related defaults:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Ship Via</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the default Ship Via to be used for the Customer.
              You may enter a free-form Ship Via simply by typing the name of
              the Ship Via into the field.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Shipping Form</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the default Shipping Form to be used for the
              Customer.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Shipping Charges</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the default Shipping Charges to be used for the
              Customer.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>Shipping defaults specified on the Customer master will transfer to
    the Sales Order header when a new Sales Order is entered for a
    Customer.</para>
  </note>
  <tip>
    <para>The system supports up-to-date shipment tracking with links to the
    websites of many leading shipping companies (i.e., "Ship Vias").</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>backorders</primary>
          <secondary>accepted by customer</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>customers</primary>
          <secondary>backorders accepted by</secondary>
        </indexterm>Accepts Backorders</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to indicate whether the Customer accepts Backorders. A
        backorder is defined as an unshipped Line Item on a shipped Sales
        Order. For example, if a Customer orders three Line Items, but only
        one of the Line Items is shipped, the remaining two Line Items would
        be on backorder. Not selecting this option indicates the Customer does
        not accept backorders or partial shipments.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>Sales Orders having unshipped Line Items on backorder will be closed
    at billing (i.e., when an Invoice is created) if the Customer in question
    is flagged to not accept backorders.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>customers</primary>
          <secondary>order preferences for</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>shipments</primary>
          <secondary>partial</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>customers</primary>
          <secondary>partial shipments accepted by</secondary>
        </indexterm> Accepts Partial Shipments</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Accepts Partial Shipments: Select to indicate whether the
        Customer accepts partial shipments. A partial shipment is defined as a
        shipped Order having a Line Item whose full quantity is not included
        in the shipment. For example, if Customer ABC orders 20 units of Item
        XYZ, but only 10 units are shipped, that partial Line Item quantity
        ("10") would constitute a partial shipment of the ordered Item. Not
        selecting this option indicates the Customer does not accept partial
        shipments.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>Partially-shipped Line Items will be closed at billing (i.e., when
    an Invoice is created) if the Customer in question is flagged to not
    accept partial shipments.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Allow Free-Form Ship-To"s</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to indicate that free-form Ship-To Addresses may be
        entered when Sales Orders are created for the Customer. If not
        selected, you are indicating that free-form Ship-To's may not be
        entered for the Customer. Instead, Ship-To's must be entered using
        predefined information.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Allow Free-Form Bill-To</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to indicate that free-form Bill-To Addresses may be
        entered when Sales Orders are created for the Customer. If not
        selected, you are indicating that free-form Bill-To's may not be
        entered for the Customer. Instead, the predefined Bill-To found on the
        Customer master will be used.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Preferred Selling Site</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the preferred selling Site, if any. This is an optional
        setting. If a preferred Site is selected, then this Site will be used
        when entering Sales Orders for the Customer. At Sales Order entry, the
        preferred Site will be the default Shipping Site for the Sales
        Order&mdash;as well as the default selling Site for Sales Order
        Items.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>If there are no Item Sites matching the preferred Site at the point
    of Sales Order Line Item entry, the highest-ranked selling Site will be
    used instead.</para>
  </note>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without creating the Customer, returning you
        to the application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Creates the Customer and enters the Customer into the master
        list of Customers.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To view or enter Customer Tax information, select the "Tax" tab. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/customer_tax.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Customer Tax Information</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>customers</primary>
      <secondary>tax information for</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>taxes</primary>
      <secondary>for customers</secondary>
    </indexterm>When adding Customer Tax information, you are presented with
  the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>tax authorities</primary>
          <secondary>default for customers</secondary>
        </indexterm>Default Tax Authority</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the primary Tax Authority you want to associate with the
        Customer. By default, the specified Tax Authority will be used on the
        Sales Order header whenever entering Sales Orders or Quotes for the
        Customer.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Tax Registration Numbers</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists Tax Registration Numbers for the specified
        Customer.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Opens screen for creating a new Customer Tax Registration
        Number.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>EDIT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enables you to edit highlighted Customer Tax Registration
        Numbers. The edit screen is the same as that for creating a new
        Customer Tax Registration Number&mdash;except that when editing, the
        fields will contain Customer Tax Registration Number information.
        Double-clicking on a Customer Tax Registration Number will also bring
        you to the editing screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>VIEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a Customer Tax Registration Number and then select
        this button to reach a read-only view of the "Edit" screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>DELETE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a Customer Tax Registration Number and then select
        this button to remove the Customer Tax Registration Number from the
        list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To add a new Customer Tax Registration Number, select the NEW button.
  The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/taxRegistration.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Customer Tax Registration Information</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>customers</primary>
      <secondary>tax registration for</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>taxes</primary>
      <secondary>registration for customers</secondary>
    </indexterm>When adding a new Customer Tax Registration Number, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Customer #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Customer Number for the specified Customer.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Tax Authority</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the Tax Authority associated with the Tax Registration
        Number.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Registration Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the Customer's Tax Registration Number for the specified
        Tax Authority. The registration number is used by Tax Authorities to
        identify businesses and/or individuals. An Employer Identification
        Numbers (EIN) is an example of a Tax Registration Number.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>The Customer's Tax Registration Number is used for identifying the
    Customer to relevant Tax Authorities. This information should not be
    confused with the Tax Registration Numbers, which are used to identify
    your company to relevant Tax Authorities.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without creating a new Customer Tax
        Registration Number, returning you to the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Creates the Customer Tax Registration Number and adds it to the
        master list of Customer Tax Registration Numbers.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To view or edit Customer credit terms, select the "Credit" tab. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/customer_credit.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Customer Credit Terms</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When adding a Customer credit terms, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Default Terms</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the default billing Terms for the Customer.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Balance Method</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify one of the available methods for handling open balances
        for the Customer:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Balance Forward</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to post payments against the oldest Invoices. Used
              in Accounts Receivable only.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Open Items</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to post payments against specific Invoices,
              regardless of their age. Used in Accounts Receivable
              only.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Default Discount</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the default discount&mdash;if any&mdash;which the Customer
        should receive. Customer discounts are applied to either a) the List
        Price for an Item if the List Price is being used or b) a specific
        Sale if a Sale is in place which the Customer is assigned to. The
        discount does not get applied to Pricing Schedules.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Default Currency</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the Currency to be used when transacting business with
        the Customer. With the system's multi-currency support, you can do
        business with Customer's in their Currency, using Exchange Rates to
        normalize transactions in your base Currency.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Credit Limit</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the credit ceiling you are willing to extend to the
        Customer.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>customers</primary>
          <secondary>credit rating options for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Credit Rating</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>You have the option of assigning a credit rating to the
        Customer. Any value entered here is purely informational. The system
        does not use the credit rating in any calculations.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Credit Status</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select one from the list below by clicking on the radio button
        to the left of the option. In Good Standing: Select to mark the
        Customer as having credit in good standing. Customers with credit "In
        Good Standing" may have Sales Orders issued for them. A black-colored
        typeface will be associated with their account.</para>
        <note>
          <para>Sales Orders may not be entered for Customers whose credit
          status is either "On Credit Warning" or "On Credit Hold." Credit
          Holds may be overridden, but only by users having the appropriate
          privileges.</para>
        </note>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>On Credit Warning</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to alert sales staff to possible credit problems
              with the Customer. Non-privileged users will be prevented from
              issuing Stock to Shipping for any Customers on credit warning.
              An orange-colored typeface will be associated with their
              account.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>On Credit Hold</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to inform sales staff that Customer's credit has
              been suspended. Non-privileged users will be prevented from
              issuing Stock to Shipping for any Customers on credit hold. A
              red-colored typeface will be associated with their
              account.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Uses Purchase Orders</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to indicate that the Customer uses Purchase Orders. If
        selected, users will be required to enter a Customer Purchase Order
        Number when entering a Sales Order. In addition, selecting the option
        will prevent users from entering duplicate Customer Purchase Order
        Numbers&mdash;unless the Customer is marked as using Blanket
        POs.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>If the option "Uses Purchase Orders" is not selected, the system
    will place no restrictions on Customer Purchase Order Numbers.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>purchase orders</primary>
          <secondary>customers using blanket</secondary>
        </indexterm>Uses Blanket P/O"s</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Blanket P/O"s: Select to indicate that the Customer uses blanket
        Purchase Orders. A blanket P/O is a Customer Purchase Order which may
        be used for more than one Sales Order. Selecting this option means
        users will be allowed to enter duplicate Purchase Order Numbers for
        this Customer.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Place on Credit Warning when Credit Limit is Exceeded</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select this option to automatically place the Customer on Credit
        Warning if their open Accounts Receivable (A/R) balance exceeds their
        Credit Limit. This option must also be selected for a Customer's A/R
        open items to be evaluated when the Update Late Customer Credit Status
        utility is run. If a Customer is on Credit Warning, Sales Orders may
        not be entered for the Customer&mdash;except by users with override
        privileges. Once the Customer's A/R open balance falls below their
        Credit Limit, Sales Orders may once again be entered for the
        Customer.</para>
        <tip>
          <para>You must specify you want a Customer to be placed on credit
          warning to enable the late credit status utility to consider a
          Customer's A/R open items.</para>
        </tip>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Place Open S/Os on Credit Hold when Credit Limit is
      Exceeded</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select this option to place all new and existing open Sales
        Orders on Credit Hold if the Customer's Credit Limit is exceeded. The
        contents of Sales Orders placed on Credit Hold may not be issued to
        Shipping&mdash;except by users with override privileges. Once the
        Customer's Credit Limit is no longer exceeded, Sales Order contents
        may be issued to Shipping.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Alternate Late Grace Days</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to specify an alternate grace period for the specific
        Customer. If selected, this grace period will override the global
        grace period used when the late credit status utility is run. This
        option is only available if the "Place on Credit Warning when Credit
        Limit is Exceeded" option is selected.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Grace Days</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the number of days beyond the due date before a
              Customer's A/R open items are considered late.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To view or edit Customer contact Addresses, select the "Addresses"
  tab. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/customer_tabAddresses.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Customer Addresses</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>customers</primary>
      <secondary>addresses for</secondary>
    </indexterm>When adding contact addresses to a Customer master, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <note>
    <para>If a new Contact is manually entered here, that Contact will be
    added automatically to the master list of Contacts.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Billing Contact</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Manually enter billing Contact information in the fields
        below&mdash;or use the browse button to select pre-existing Contact
        information.</para>
        <note>
          <para>If a new Contact is manually entered here, that Contact will
          be added automatically to the master list of Contacts.</para>
        </note>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Title</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select a Title from the list of available Titles.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>First</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the Contact's first name.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Last</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the Contact's last name.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Job Title</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the Contact's job title.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Voice</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the Contact's phone number.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Fax</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the Contact's fax number.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>E-Mail</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the Contact's e-mail address. To send email to the
              Contact, simply double-click on the Contact's email address.
              This will launch your default mail application with the
              Contact's email address in the To: field.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Web</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the Contact's website address. To access the
              website, simply double-click on the Contact's website address.
              This will launch your default web browser, with the Contact's
              website address in the URL field.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Address</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Manually enter billing Address information in the fields
        below&mdash;or use the browse button to select pre-existing Address
        information.</para>
        <note>
          <para>If a new Address is manually entered here, that Address will
          be added automatically to the master list of Addresses.</para>
        </note>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Street Address</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the street Address for the Contact.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>City</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the city where the Contact is located.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>State</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the state where the Contact is located.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Postal Code</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the Postal Code for the Contact.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Country</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the country where the Contact is located.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Correspondence Contact</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Manually enter non-billing-related Contact information in the
        fields below&mdash;or use the browse button to select pre-existing
        Contact information. Examples of non-billing-related correspondence
        might include Price updates, holiday cards, etc. You may also enter
        additional contact information.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Title</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select a Title from the list of available Titles.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>First</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the Contact's first name.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Last</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the Contact's last name.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Job Title</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the Contact's job title.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Voice</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the Contact's phone number.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Fax</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the Contact's fax number.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>E-Mail</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the Contact's e-mail address. To send email to the
              Contact, simply double-click on the Contact's email address.
              This will launch your default mail application with the
              Contact's email address in the To: field.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Web</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the Contact's website address. To access the
              website, simply double-click on the Contact's website address.
              This will launch your default web browser, with the Contact's
              website address in the URL field.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Address</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Manually enter non-billing Address information in the fields
        below&mdash;or use the browse button to select pre-existing Address
        information.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Street Address</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the street Address for the Contact.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>City</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the city where the Contact is located.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>State</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the state where the Contact is located.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Postal Code</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the Postal Code for the Contact.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Country</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the country where the Contact is located.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>Customers may have multiple Addresses where they want you to ship
  their goods. To support this, the system allows you to maintain multiple
  Customer Ship-To Addresses. To view or edit Customer Ship-To Addresses,
  select the "Ship-To" tab. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/customer_tabShipto.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Ship-To Addresses</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Ship-To Addresses</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists Ship-To Addresses for the specified
        Customer.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>You can maintain multiple Ship-To Addresses for your Customers.
    Ship-To Addresses are selected at the point of Sales Order entry.</para>
  </note>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>PRINT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Runs the report associated with this screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Opens screen for creating a new Ship-To Address.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>EDIT</term>
      <listitem id="customerShipToEDIT">
        <para>Enables you to edit highlighted Ship-To Address. The edit screen
        is the same as that for creating a new Ship-To Address&mdash;except
        that when editing, the fields will contain Ship-To Address
        information. Double-clicking on a Ship-To Address will also bring you
        to the editing screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>VIEW</term>
      <listitem id="customerShipToVIEW">
        <para>Highlight a Ship-To Address and then select this button to reach
        a read-only view of the "Edit" screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>DELETE</term>
      <listitem id="customerShipToDELETE">
        <para>Highlight a Ship-To Address and then select this button to
        remove the address from the master list of Ship-To Addresses.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>Right-clicking on a Ship-To Address in the Ship-To list enables you to
  select from the following menu options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Edit</term>
      <xi:include href="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                  xpointer="element(customerShipToEDIT)" />
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>View</term>
      <xi:include href="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                  xpointer="element(customerShipToVIEW)" />
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Delete</term>
      <xi:include href="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                  xpointer="element(customerShipToDELETE)" />
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>ship-to addresses</primary>
      <secondary>creating new</secondary>
    </indexterm>To create a new Ship-To Address for a Customer, select the NEW
  button. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/shipTo.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Ship-To Address</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <tip>
    <para>The Ship-To master shares many common fields with the Customer
    master&mdash;shipping defaults, Sales Representative, etc. By default, the
    Customer master values will pre-populate the Ship-To master. However, when
    specifying a specific Ship-To Address on a Sales Order, the specific
    Ship-To details will populate the Sales Order header.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>When creating a new Ship-To Address, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Customer #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The Customer Number and Customer name specified in the Customer
        master will display here.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Ship-To #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify a number or code to identify the Ship-To Address
        by.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Active</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to activate the Ship-To Address. If option is not
        selected, then the Ship-To Address is inactive.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Default</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if this is the default Ship-To Address for the
        Customer.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the name of the company that will receive shipments at
        this Ship-To Address. Customers may maintain multiple Ship-To
        Addresses with diverse destinations.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>If a new Address is manually entered here, that Address will be
    added automatically to the master list of Addresses.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Address</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Manually enter billing Address information in the fields
        below&mdash;or use the browse button to select pre-existing Address
        information.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Street Address</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the street Address for the Contact.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>City</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the city where the Contact is located.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>State</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the state where the Contact is located.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Postal Code</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the Postal Code for the Contact.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Country</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the country where the Contact is located.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>If a new Contact is manually entered here, that Contact will be
    added automatically to the master list of Contacts.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>ship-to addresses</primary>
          <secondary>contact information for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Contact</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Manually enter Contact information in the fields below&mdash;or
        use the browse button to select pre-existing Contact information. This
        field should not to be confused with the "Name" field that appears on
        the Ship-To Address label.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Title</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select a Title from the list of available Titles.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>First</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the Contact's first name.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Last</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the Contact's last name.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Job Title</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the Contact's job title.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Voice</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the Contact's phone number.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Fax</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the Contact's fax number.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>E-Mail</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the Contact's e-mail address.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Sales Rep</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the Sales Representative for the Ship-To Address. When
        entering Orders for a Customer, the name of the Sales Representative
        specified on the Ship-To Address will be used.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Commission</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Field accepts up to 4 whole numbers and 2 decimals. Enter the
        Commission rate to be used when Sales Orders for this Customer are
        shipped to the specified Ship-To Address.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Zone</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the Zone for the Ship-To Address.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Tax Code</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify Tax Code to be used for Ship-To Address.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Defaults</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select one of the available Shipping-related defaults:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Ship Via</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the default Ship Via to be used for the Ship-To
              Address. You may enter a free-form Ship Via simply by typing the
              name of the Ship Via into the field.</para>
              <tip>
                <para>The system supports up-to-date shipment tracking with
                links to the websites of many leading shipping companies
                (i.e., "Ship Vias").</para>
              </tip>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Shipping Form</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the default Shipping Form to be used for the
              Ship-To Address.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Shipping Charges</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the default Shipping Charges to be used for the
              Ship-To Address.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>EDI Profile</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select one of the available EDI options. Different EDI
              Profiles may be specified for different Ship-To Addresses.
              However, if you want the default Profile to mirror the Customer
              master settings, select the "Use Customer Master" option.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>General Notes</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select the "General Notes" tab to access this scrolling text
        field with word-wrapping for entering general Notes related to the
        Customer Ship-To Address. These Notes are for internal use
        only.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Shipping Notes</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select the "Shipping Notes" tab to access this scrolling text
        field with word-wrapping for entering Shipping Notes related to the
        Customer Ship-To Address. Shipping Notes are transferred to the
        "Shipping Notes" tab on the Sales Order header whenever a Sales Order
        for the specified Ship-To Address is entered.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without adding Customer Address information,
        returning you to the application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Saves any new Customer Address information.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>Any Notes added to the Customer master are for internal purposes only.
  To add Notes to a Customer master, select the "Notes" tab at the bottom of
  the "Customer" screen. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/customer_tabNotes.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Add Customer Notes</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When adding Notes to a Customer master, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Notes</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        Notes related to the Customer. Any Notes entered on this screen are
        for internal purposes only.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CLOSE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without creating the Customer Note, returning
        you to the application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Creates the Customer Note and adds it to the Customer
        master.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>characteristics</primary>
      <secondary>creating new for customer</secondary>
    </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>characteristics</primary>
      <secondary>customers having</secondary>
    </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>customers</primary>
      <secondary>characteristics for</secondary>
    </indexterm>Customer Characteristics are user-defined definitions which
  may be used to provide additional layers of description about Customers. For
  example, Customer Characteristics might be used to specify "Order
  Preferences" or "Buying Season". These constitute static descriptions which
  are not processed by the system, but are useful for informational purposes.
  To enter Characteristics associated with a Customer, select the
  "Characteristics" tab from the "Item" screen. The following screen will
  appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/customer_tabCharacteristics.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Customer Characteristics</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot><tip>
      <para>If the Customer Type a Customer belongs to has a Characteristic
      Profile (i.e., template) defined, then every Customer in that Customer
      Type will be presented with a range of pre-defined Characteristics. You
      can select or add values for each Characteristic by right-clicking on a
      Characteristic in the list.</para>
    </tip></para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Characteristics</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists the Characteristics related to the
        Customer.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>If Characteristic Profiles are enabled for the Customer Type, you
    will not see buttons on the right-side of the screen. Values may be
    selected or added by right-clicking on a Characteristic in the
    list.</para>
  </note>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <tip>
    <para>If you see buttons to the right of the Customer Characteristics
    screen, then Characteristic Profiles are not enabled for the Customer Type
    the Customer belongs to.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Opens screen for creating a new Customer Characteristic.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>EDIT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enables you to edit highlighted Customer Characteristics. The
        edit screen is the same as that for creating a new Customer
        Characteristic&mdash;except that when editing, the fields will contain
        Customer Characteristic information. Double-clicking on a Customer
        Characteristic will also bring you to the editing screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>DELETE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a Customer Characteristic and then select this button
        to remove the Customer Characteristic from the list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To create a new Customer Characteristic, select the NEW button. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/characteristicAssignmentCustomer.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create New Customer Characteristic</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When creating a new Customer Characteristic, you are presented with
  the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Characteristic</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select a Characteristic from the list of Characteristics
        designated as being available for use as Customer
        Characteristics.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Value</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a description of the Customer Characteristic.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without creating the Customer Characteristic,
        returning you to the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Creates the Customer Characteristic and adds it to the list of
        Customer Characteristics.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To add Comments to a Customer master, select the "Comments" tab at the
  bottom of the "Customer" screen. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/customer_tabComments.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Customer Comments</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When adding Comments to a Customer master, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Comments</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists Comments related to the Customer.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Opens the screen for creating a new Customer Comment.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>VIEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Opens a read-only view of the Customer Comment.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To enter a new Customer Comment, select the NEW button. The following
  screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/CommentNew.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create New Comment</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Comment Type</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify one of the following Comment Types from the drop-down
        list: ChangeLog or General. Comment Types are used to categorize
        Comments. Once you have specified a Comment Type, you may type your
        Comment in the main text area. The text area features word-wrapping
        and scroll-bar support for longer Comments.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without creating the Customer Comment,
        returning you to the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Creates the Comment and adds it to the list of Customer
        Comments.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para role="standard">The Electronic Data Interchange (EDI) system enables
  you to send Sales Orders and Invoices electronically to your Customers. To
  establish a Customer's EDI preferences for Sales Orders, select the "S/O
  EDI" tab. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/customer_soEdi.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Sales Order EDI Information</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When setting up the Sales Order EDI preferences for a Customer, you
  are presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>EDI Profile</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select from the following EDI Profile options:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>No EDI</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select this option if you do not wish to use the EDI
              system.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Custom Email</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select this option if you want to bypass standard EDI
              Profiles and instead create custom email preferences for the
              Customer. These preferences will be stored solely with the
              Customer master&mdash;and will be used to send email versions of
              Sales Orders to the Customer. When this option is selected, the
              email-related fields on the Customer master will be enabled.
              Otherwise, the email-related fields will be disabled.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>EDI Profile</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select a standard EDI Profile from the list of EDI
              Profiles. The selected Profile will be used when Sales Orders
              for the Customer are scheduled for email delivery.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>EDI Email</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the Customer email address to be used as the default
        recipient address whenever Sales Orders are emailed to the Customer.
        Only applies when the "Custom Email" EDI Profile option is
        selected.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>Send Sales Orders to multiple recipients by separating email
    addresses with a comma. Be sure to omit any spaces between addresses when
    using commas to send copies to multiple recipients.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Cc</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the email address to be used as the default carbon copy
        address whenever Sales Orders are emailed to the Customer. Only
        applies when the "Custom Email" EDI Profile option is selected.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Subject</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a default email subject line to be used whenever Sales
        Orders are emailed to the Customer. Only applies when the "Custom
        Email" EDI Profile option is selected.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Filename</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>XML tags may be used in this field to dynamically generate
        filename text. In the example shown in the screenshot above, the
        filename will include the Document Type (i.e., Sales Order) and the
        Document Number (i.e., Sales Order Number). This field only applies
        when the "Custom Email" EDI Profile option is selected.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>EDI Email Body</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Use this text field to enter the default message that will
        accompany any Sales Orders sent to the Customer. Only applies when the
        "Custom Email" EDI Profile option is selected.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Send Email as HTML</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you want the body of the Email to be sent as HTML. If
        not selected, the Email will be sent as plain text.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CLOSE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without setting up a Customer to receive Sales
        Orders via email, returning you to the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enables the Customer to receive Sales Orders via email.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para role="standard">To establish a Customer's EDI preferences for
  Invoices, select the "Invoice EDI" tab. The following screen will
  appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/customer_tabEDI.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Invoice EDI Information</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <note>
    <para>EDI preferences for a Customer are implemented at the point when
    Invoices for the Customer are printed.</para>
  </note>
  <para>When setting up the Invoice EDI preferences for a Customer, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>EDI Profile</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select from the following EDI Profile options:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>No EDI</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select this option if you do not wish to use the EDI
              system.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Custom Email</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select this option if you want to bypass standard EDI
              Profiles and instead create custom email preferences for the
              Customer. These preferences will be stored solely with the
              Customer master&mdash;and will be used to send email versions of
              Invoices to the Customer when Invoices for the Customer are
              printed. When this option is selected, the email-related fields
              on the Customer master will be enabled. Otherwise, the
              email-related fields will be disabled.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>EDI Profile</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select a standard EDI Profile from the list of EDI
              Profiles. The selected Profile will be used when Invoices for
              the Customer are printed.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>EDI Email</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the Customer email address to be used as the default
        recipient address whenever Invoices are emailed to the Customer. Only
        applies when the "Custom Email" EDI Profile option is selected.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>Send Invoices to multiple recipients by separating email addresses
    with a comma. Be sure to omit any spaces between addresses when using
    commas to send copies to multiple recipients.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Cc</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the email address to be used as the default carbon copy
        address whenever Invoices are emailed to the Customer. Only applies
        when the "Custom Email" EDI Profile option is selected.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Subject</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a default email subject line to be used whenever Invoices
        are emailed to the Customer. Only applies when the "Custom Email" EDI
        Profile option is selected.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Filename</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>XML tags may be used in this field to dynamically generate
        filename text. In the example shown in the screenshot above, the
        filename will include the Document Type (i.e., Invoice) and the
        Document Number (i.e., Invoice Number). This field only applies when
        the "Custom Email" EDI Profile option is selected.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>EDI Email Body</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Use this text field to enter the default message that will
        accompany any Invoices sent to the Customer. Only applies when the
        "Custom Email" EDI Profile option is selected.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Send Email as HTML</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you want the body of the Email to be sent as HTML. If
        not selected, the Email will be sent as plain text.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CLOSE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without setting up a Customer to receive
        Invoices via email, returning you to the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enables the Customer to receive Invoices via email.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>If your system is configured to use Credit Cards, the "Credit Cards"
    tab will be visible. This tab will not be visible if your system is not
    configured to use Credit Cards.</para>
  </note>
  <para><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>credit cards</primary>
      <secondary>adding to customer master</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>customers</primary>
      <secondary>credit cards for</secondary>
    </indexterm>To add Credit Card information to a Customer master, select
  the "Credit Cards" tab at the bottom of the "Customer" screen. The following
  screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/customer_tabCreditCard.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Customer Credit Cards</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <note>
    <para>Customer Credit Cards may be used when entering Sales Orders or Cash
    Receipt transactions for the Customer. When entering a Sales Order, you
    have the option to either pre-authorize or charge a Credit Card. Any
    pre-authorizations may later be post-authorized using the A/R
    Workbench.</para>
  </note>
  <para>When adding Credit Card information to a Customer master, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Credit Cards</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists Credit Card records for the Customer.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Opens screen for entering new Credit Card information for the
        Customer.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>EDIT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enables you to edit highlighted Credit Cards. The edit screen is
        the same as that for entering new Credit Card information&mdash;except
        that when editing, the fields will contain Credit Card
        information.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>VIEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a Credit Card and then select this button to reach a
        read-only view of the "Edit" screen. Double-clicking on a Credit Card
        will also bring you to the view screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>MOVE UP</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a Credit Card and then select this button to move the
        Credit Card up in the sequence of Credit Cards. Sequence numbers are
        automatically adjusted to reflect the change in position.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>MOVE DOWN</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a Credit Card and then select this button to move the
        Credit Card down the sequence of Credit Cards. Sequence numbers are
        automatically adjusted to reflect the change in position.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To create a new Credit Card record for a Customer, select the NEW
  button. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/creditCard.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create New Credit Card Record</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When creating a new Credit Card record for a Customer, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Customer #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the name of the Customer associated with the Credit
        Card record. The name of the Customer will also be displayed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Credit Card Type</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the type of Credit Card. The following Credit Card types
        are currently supported: Master Card, Visa, American Express, and
        Discover.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Credit Card Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the Credit Card Number. After the Credit Card record has
        been saved, all but the last four digits of the Credit Card Number
        will be encrypted for security purposes.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Active</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if the Credit Card record is active. Do not select this
        option if the specified Credit Card is inactive or invalid for any
        reason.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a name to describe the Credit Card record.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Address</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>By default, the Customer's Billing Address will be entered here.
        However, using the browse button associated with the Address fields,
        you have the ability to specify an alternate billing address for the
        Credit Card record.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Country</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the country associated with the billing address.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Expiration Month</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the month when the specified Credit Card expires. The
        month must be saved in the format "MM". For example, the month of
        January would be represented as "01".</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Expiration Year</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the year when the specified Credit Card expires. The year
        must be saved in the format "YYYY". For example, the year 2006 would
        be represented as "2006".</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without creating the Credit Card record,
        returning you to the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Creates the Credit Card record and adds it to the list of Credit
        Card records.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>