<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2008 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section636366">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>costing</primary>
      <secondary>for summarized BOMs</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>bills of materials</primary>
      <secondary>costed summarized view of</secondary>
    </indexterm>Costed Summarized BOM</title>
  <para>A summarized Bill of Materials shows all the material requirements for
  an Item. The components for subassemblies are included in this view;
  however, the top-level subassemblies themselves are excluded. To view a
  Costed summarized Bill of Materials, select the "Costed Summarized BOM"
  option. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/dspCostedSummarizedBOM.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Costed Summarized Bill of Materials</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When displaying a Costed summarized Bill of Materials, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the Item Number of the manufactured Item you would like to
        view a Costed summarized Bill of Materials for.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Inventory Unit of Measure.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Revision</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>If Revision Control is enabled at your site, specify the Bill of
        Materials Revision Number you want to view. If none exists, simply
        enter a value to create one. The status of the Revision will also be
        displayed. The following statuses apply to Revisions:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Active</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>This is the current, default Revision used for costing and
              Material Requirements Planning (MRP). Only one Revision can be
              active at the same time. Active Revisions may be modified.
              However, once a Revision becomes inactive, it may no longer be
              changed.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Show Expired Components</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to cause expired components to be listed in the "Bill of
        Materials" display.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Threshold Days</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select a number using the arrow buttons, or manually enter
              a value up to a maximum of 999. Components that have been
              expired from the Bill of Materials within the specified number
              of days will be included in the display.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Show Future Components</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to cause future components to be listed in the "Bill of
        Materials" display.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Threshold Days</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select a number using the arrow buttons, or manually enter
              a value up to a maximum of 999. Components that will be added in
              future to the Bill of Materials within the specified number of
              days will be included in the display.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Use Standard Costs</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to display Standard Costs for the specified Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>When Labor and Overhead are posted to the General Ledger, they are
    posted using their Actual Cost. This is a departure from the rule which
    governs materials&mdash;namely, that materials are always posted using
    their Standard Cost. Differences between Actual and Standard Labor and
    Overhead Costs will be reflected in Inventory Cost Variances when Work
    Order Production or Operations are posted. You can address these variances
    if and when they occur by posting your Actual Costs to Standard.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Use Actual Costs</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to display Actual Costs for the specified Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Bill of Materials</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists summarized Bill of Materials components, using the
        specified parameters.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CLOSE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen, returning you to the application
        desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>QUERY</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to generate the display, using the specified
        parameters.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>PRINT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Runs the report associated with this screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>