<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2008 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section520014">
  <title>
<indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>costing</primary>
      <secondary>for indented BOMs</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>bills of materials</primary>
      <secondary>costed indented view of</secondary>
    </indexterm>Costed Indented BOM</title>
  <para>The difference between the indented view and the single level view is
  that the indented view displays Costs for all subcomponents if there is a
  manufactured component listed on the Bill of Materials list. To view
  associated Item Costs using an indented Bill of Materials, select the
  "Costed Indented BOM" option. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para>
<screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/dspCostedIndentedBOM.png"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Costed Indented Bill of
        Materials</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
</para>
  <para>When displaying Costs for an indented Bill of Materials, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the Item Number of the manufactured Item whose associated
        Costs you would like to view using an indented Bill of
        Materials.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Inventory Unit of Measure.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Use Standard Costs</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to display Standard Costs for component Items in the
        specified Item's Bill of Materials. Both the Unit Cost and Extended
        Cost for each component Item, expressed in terms of Standard Cost,
        will display&mdash;assuming Standard Costs have been defined for each
        component Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>When Labor and Overhead are posted to the General Ledger, they are
    posted using their Actual Cost. This is a departure from the rule which
    governs materials&mdash;namely, that materials are always posted using their
    Standard Cost. Differences between Actual and Standard Labor and Overhead
    Costs will be reflected in Inventory Cost Variances when Work Order
    Production or Operations are posted. You can address these variances if
    and when they occur by posting your Actual Costs to Standard.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Use Actual Costs</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to display Actual Costs for component Items in the
        specified Item's Bill of Materials. Both the Unit Cost and Extended
        Cost for each component Item, expressed in terms of Actual Cost, will
        display&mdash;assuming Actual Costs have been defined for each component
        Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>The totals displayed on the screen are derived as follows:</para>
    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Total Cost</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>This total is pulled from the Extended Cost column. The total
          may vary, depending on whether "Use Standard Costs" or "Use Actual
          Costs" is selected.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Actual Cost</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>This value represents the Actual Cost for the parent Item
          whose Costed Indented BOM is being displayed.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Standard Cost</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>: This value represents the Standard Cost for the parent Item
          whose Costed Indented BOM is being displayed.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Costed Bill of Materials</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists Costed Indented Bill of Materials components,
        using the specified parameters. The difference between the indented
        view and the single level view is that the indented view displays all
        subcomponents if there is a manufactured component listed on the Bill
        of Materials. The Total Cost, Actual Cost, and Standard Cost will be
        calculated automatically at the bottom of the display.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the display are the following buttons and display
  fields:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CLOSE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen, returning you to the application
        desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>PRINT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Runs the report associated with this screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>Right-clicking on a component in the Costed Bill of Materials list
  enables you to select from the following menu options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="../supportfiles/rightclick.xml" xpointer="element(rightclickMaintainItemCosts)"/>
    <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="../supportfiles/rightclick.xml" xpointer="element(rightclickViewItemCosting)"/>
    <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="../widgets/xtreewidget.xml" xpointer="element(xtreewidget.menu.exportcontents)"/>
  </variablelist>
</section>
