<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2011 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section531394">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>general ledger</primary>
      <secondary>viewing transaction series in</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>series</primary>
      <secondary>viewing g/l transactions in</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>transactions</primary>
      <secondary>viewing in general ledger</secondary>
    </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>journals</primary>
      <secondary>viewing transaction series for</secondary>
    </indexterm>Journal Series</title>
  <para>When transactions are posted in the system?either to the General
  Ledger or intermediate Journals, depending on your accounting
  configuration?the grouping of debits and credits associated with the
  transaction is considered to be a Journal Series. Each series is categorized
  by module and assigned a unique Journal Number. </para>
  <para>From the Journal Series screen you can review your transaction
  series?and also take action, when needed.</para>
  <note>
    <para>The following transaction series types may be reversed: Simple
    Journal Entry, Series Journal Entry, Standard Journal, and Standard
    Journal Group. The same transaction series types may also be deleted
    (Simple and Series Journal entries may also be edited)?but only if they
    were posted directly to the General Ledger. You cannot edit or delete
    transactions posted to intermediate Journals.</para>
  </note>
  <tip>
    <para>When a transaction has been deleted, it remains in the database and
    may still be viewed using the "Show Deleted" option on the General Ledger
    Transactions screen. Similarly, when you edit a Simple or Series Journal
    transaction, the original transaction is marked as deleted?and the new,
    edited version is posted in its place. Transactions found in closed or
    frozen periods?or if they were part of a Bank Reconciliation?may not be
    modified.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>To view transaction series for either the General Ledger or Journals
  (depending on your configuration), select the "Journal Series" option. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/dspGLSeries.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Journal Series</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When displaying transaction series for either the General Ledger or
  Journals, you are presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>All Sources</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to display transaction series from all source
        modules.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Selected</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify source module whose transaction series you want to
        display.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Journal Number Range</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you want to search for a specific range of Journal
        Numbers within the time frame you specify.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Start</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the first Journal Number in the range you want to
              display.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>End</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the last Journal Number in the range you want to
              display.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Start Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Transaction series posted on and after this date will be
        displayed. This is a required field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>End Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Transaction series posted on and before this date will be
        displayed. This is a required field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Type</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>If your system is configured to post transactions to
        intermediate Journals, then you will see the "Type" option on this
        screen. However, you will not see this option if your system is
        configured to post transactions directly to the General Ledger. For
        more information on the system's accounting configuration, please see
        <xref linkend="Section942568" />.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>General Ledger</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if you want to review transaction series posted to
              the General Ledger.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Journal</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if you want to review transaction series posted to
              Journals.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Journal Transactions</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists transaction series based on the specified
        parameters. This display is a nested list, with a plus ("+") sign
        located to the far left of the display next to each transaction that
        may be expanded to lower levels. By clicking your mouse on a plus
        sign, you reveal lower levels of information related to the
        transaction series.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
