<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2010 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="dspRecurringInvoices">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>invoices</primary>
      <secondary>recurring list of</secondary>
    </indexterm>List Recurring Invoices</title>
  <para>Invoices may be set as recurring on the "Advanced" tab of the Invoice
  screen. On that tab you can specify how frequently you want an Invoice to
  recur&mdash;and for how long. For more information, see <xref
  linkend="invoiceAdvancedTab" />. Once an Invoice has been made recurring,
  you can monitor and manage these Invoices on the Recurring Invoices screen.
  To view the complete list of your recurring Invoices, select the "List
  Recurring Invoices" option. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/dspRecurringInvoices.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>List Recurring Invoices</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>The recurring Invoices list displays information on all your recurring
  Invoices, including the Invoice Number, Customer, date, interval, type,
  duration, and amount.</para>
  <tip>
    <para>Using the "Edit" option on the right-click menu, you can change the
    frequency of an Invoice's recurrence. You can also turn off the recurring
    option on the "Advanced" tab of the Invoice.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CLOSE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen, returning you to the application
        desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Opens screen for creating a new Invoice.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>EDIT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enables you to edit highlighted recurring Invoices. The edit
        screen is the same as that for selecting a new Invoice&mdash;except
        that when editing, the fields will contain recurring Invoice
        information. Double-clicking on a recurring Invoice will also bring
        you to the editing screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>VIEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a recurring Invoice and then select this button to
        reach a read-only view of the "Edit" screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
