<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2011 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section571902">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>trial balances</primary>
      <secondary>reporting on</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>financial reports</primary>
      <secondary>trial balances</secondary>
    </indexterm>View Trial Balances</title>
  <para>To view the Trial Balances for General Ledger Accounts, select the
  "View Trial Balances" option. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/dspTrialBalances.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>View Trial Balances</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <tip>
    <para>The system will automatically reset the beginning balances for
    Revenue and Expense Accounts to $0 at the start of a new Fiscal Year.
    However, for the Year-End Equity Account, the beginning balance for the
    first Period of the Fiscal Year will be equal to the ending balance for
    the previous year. In addition, the Credit and Debit columns will
    summarize the revenue and expense account activity for the previous year,
    and the ending balance will be the actual year-end equity value for the
    just-closed Fiscal Year.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>When viewing Trial Balances, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <xi:include href="../widgets/parameterwidget.xml" xpointer="parameterwidget"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
  <note>
    <para>The Trial Balance query builder includes options for displaying
    Accounts having a zero balance.</para>
    <para role="xtprjaccnt">Also included is an option for showing Accounts
    with a Project Number as the last segment. If the "Show Project Detail"
    option is not used, balances will roll up into the parent Account
    total.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Trial Balances</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists Trial Balances based on the specified parameters.
        A "CR" may display after the following columns: Beg. Bal., Difference,
        and End. Bal. The "CR" indicates the balance is a Credit balance. If
        no "CR" appears, then the balance is a Debit balance. Ending balances
        will display in orange type if either of the following conditions is
        true: 1) The ending balance has not been forward-updated, or 2) the
        ending balance has been forward-updated, but the account in question
        has no activity during the specified Period.</para>
        <note>
          <para>Trial Balances will be automatically forward-updated unless
          your system is configured to manually forward-update Trial Balances.
          Ending balances cannot be forward-updated into future Periods. For
          more information see <xref linkend="Section942568" />.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Show Trial Balances with Zero</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to display Trial Balances with a zero balance for the
        specified Period(s). If not selected, zero-balance Trial Balances will
        be hidden.</para>
        <note>
          <para>If a specific Account is selected using the Selected Account
          option, the Account will appear regardless of whether the Trial
          Balance is zero.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <xi:include href="../widgets/fliterManager.xml" xpointer="filterManager"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
</section>
