<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2008 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="enterPoitemReceipt">
  <title>Enter Receipt Item</title>
  <para>To enter Receipt details, highlight a Line Item and select the ENTER
  RECEIPT button. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para>
<screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/enterPoitemReceipt.png"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Enter Purchase Order Item
        Receipt</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
</para>
  <para>When entering Receipt details, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>P/O Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Purchase Order Number specified on the previous
        screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Line #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the line number for the specified Purchase Order
        Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Item Number for the Purchase Order Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Inventory Unit of Measure.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Vend. Item Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Vendor's Item number for the specified Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Vendor Item Description</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays Vendor's description of specified Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Vendor UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Vendor's Item UOM for the specified Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Inv./Vendor UOM Ratio</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the ratio between Inventory and Vendor Units of
        Measure.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Date Received</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the date you want the receiving transaction to be posted
        to the General Ledger. By default, receipts will be posted on the
        current day. However, this feature gives you the option to post
        transactions on an alternate date.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Due Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the date the Item is due to be received.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. Ordered</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the quantity ordered of the specified Item</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. Received</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the quantity received of the specified Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. to Receive</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the Line Item quantity you want to receive into
        Inventory. Depending on how your system is configured, you may or may
        not be allowed to receive more than the quantity ordered.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Freight</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>If Line Item freight charges were specified when the Line Item
        was created, then those charges will automatically appear here. If you
        receive a partial quantity and decrease the Freight amount
        accordingly, the system will automatically show the remaining Freight
        balance due when you go to receive the remaining quantity.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Notes</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        Notes related Items being received into Inventory.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without receiving any of the Line Item
        quantity.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>RECEIVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to receive the specified Line Item quantity.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
