<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2008 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="invoiceItem">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>invoices</primary>
      <secondary>adding line items to</secondary>
    </indexterm>Invoice Item</title>
  <para>To add a new Invoice Line Item, select the NEW button. The following
  screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/invoiceItem.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create Invoice Line Item</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When creating a new Invoice Line Item, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Invoice #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Invoice Number specified in the "Invoice"
        screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Line #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Line Item Number for the current Line Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Type</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Indicate the Item Type for the Invoice Line Item, by selecting
        one of the following options:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Item</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The browse button located to the right of the field leads
              to a searchable list of Inventory Items. The list will contain
              sold Items available for purchase by the specified Customer. The
              list of available Items may vary from Customer to Customer,
              depending on how Pricing Schedules are implemented at your site.
              Once an Item Number is entered, the Inventory Unit of Measure
              and Item description will automatically appear. Additionally,
              you may also specify the Item's supplying Site. Items may
              be supplied from multiple Sites. Sites designated as
              "Sold from" Sites in the Item Site master for an Item are
              considered "Supplying Sites" on this screen. By default,
              the Item Site with the highest Ranking will be selected as the
              supplying Site. If more than one Item Site share a Ranking
              of "1", the default supplying Site will be selected in
              alphabetical order. Item Sites are ranked using the Ranking
              mechanism on the Item Site master.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Miscellaneous</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter a name and description for the miscellaneous,
              non-Inventory Item you are billing the Customer for. The name
              and description fields are free-form, meaning they accept
              unlimited alphanumeric characters. You must also select a Sales
              Category. Sales Categories are used to identify the General
              Ledger (G/L) Accounts to be used when non-Inventory Sales
              transactions take place.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Customer P/N</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>If applicable, enter a Customer Part Number to further identify
        the Item you are billing the Customer for. In the case of Inventory
        Items, the Customer Part Number will display automatically if you
        enter an Item Alias in the Item Number field. To enter an Item Alias,
        place the cursor in the Item Number field and then use the keyboard
        shortcut "CTRL + A". After you have entered a valid Item Alias, hit
        the TAB key. A list of Items that use the specified Item Alias will be
        displayed. Select the desired Item from the list. The Item Alias will
        display as the Customer Part Number. Item Aliases are defined on the
        Item master.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. Ordered</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the quantity of the Item you are billing for. The quantity
        ordered for Inventory Items is measured in the Item's Inventory
        UOM.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>The Quantity Ordered for Inventory Items is based on the Inventory
    UOM. But the Price is based on the Price UOM. Whenever these two UOMs are
    not identical, the Extended Price for a Line Item will be based on the
    following formula:</para>
    <informalexample>
      <para>(Qty. Ordered) x (Price/Inv. Ratio) x (Net Unit Price)</para>
    </informalexample>
    <para>If for some reason the Prices don"t look correct, check the Item
    master for the Line Item in question. It may be that the Inventory and
    Price UOMs do not exist in a 1:1 relationship.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. Billed</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the quantity of ordered Items you are billing
        for.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the Unit of Measure to be used when selling the Line
        Item. Sold Items may be assigned multiple Selling UOMs. These
        alternate UOMs may be defined on the Item master. If a Line Item has
        no Selling UOM defined, then the Inventory UOM will be used here by
        default.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>invoices</primary>
          <secondary>line item pricing for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Net Unit Price</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>For Inventory Items having assigned Pricing Schedules, the Net
        Unit Price will be automatically calculated. For miscellaneous Items,
        the Net Unit Price must be entered manually.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Pricing UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The Price Unit of Measure is the same as the Selling UOM. If an
        Item has Selling UOMs defined, then the Item may be sold and priced in
        these alternate UOMs. If no Selling UOMs are defined, then the
        Inventory UOM will be used here by default.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Extended Price</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Extended Price. The Extended Price for a Line Item
        is based on the quantity ordered multiplied by the Net Unit
        Price.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To view Costing and Tax information related to the Invoice Item,
  select the "Detail" tab. You will be presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Unit Cost (Inv. UOM)</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Standard Cost per unit in the Item's Inventory Unit
        of Measure.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>List Price</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Item's List Price per Inventory UOM.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Customer Price</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Price (per Inventory UOM) given to the specified
        Customer for the specified Item. Special Customer Prices can be set
        for individual Customers or Customer Groups by using a Pricing
        Schedule.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Tax</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The following Tax-related information is available:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Type</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the Tax Type for the Invoice Item. By default, the
              Item's Tax Type corresponding to the Invoice's Tax Authority
              will be presented here. The link between Tax Types and Tax
              Authorities is made on the Item master. If the Item master does
              not have a Tax Type for the Invoice's Tax Authority, then no Tax
              will be charged.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Code</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the Tax Code to be applied to the Invoice Item. By
              default, the Tax Code specified in the Tax Selection matrix will
              be displayed here. For a Tax Code to be used, the matrix must
              have an entry which matches both the Item's Tax Type definition
              and the Tax Authority specified on the Invoice header. If no Tax
              Selection match exists, then no Tax Code will be
              used&mdash;meaning no Tax will be charged.</para>
              <tip>
                <para>The relationship between Tax Authorities, Tax Types, and
                Tax Codes is established in the Tax Selection matrix.</para>
              </tip>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Tax</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the amount of Tax to be charged for the Invoice
              Line Item quantity. Sales Tax is calculated at the Invoice Line
              Item level. To get a detailed view of the Tax calculation, click
              on the Tax link using your mouse.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To add Notes to an Invoice Line Item, select the "Notes" tab at the
  bottom of the screen. If the Invoice was created from a Sales Order, any
  Sales Order Line Item Notes will be transfered to the Invoice. The following
  screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/invoiceItem_tab.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Invoice Line Item Notes</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When entering Invoice Line Item Notes, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Notes</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        general Notes related to the Invoice Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>