<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2008 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section574190">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>invoices</primary>
      <secondary>creating new</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>accounts receivable</primary>
      <secondary>creating invoices for</secondary>
    </indexterm>New Invoice</title>
  <para>When you post a Sales Order that has been selected for billing, an
  Invoice is created for that Order. This is the standard flow for creating
  Invoices tied to Sales Orders. However, you also have the option of creating
  miscellaneous Invoices&mdash;that is, Invoices which are not tied to Sales
  Orders. For example, you might use a miscellaneous Invoice to bill for
  non-Inventory Items you have sold. To create a miscellaneous Invoice, select
  the "Create Invoice" option. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/invoice.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create New Invoice</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When creating an Invoice, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Invoice #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Next available Invoice Number will automatically display, unless
        your system requires you to enter Invoice Numbers manually. Default
        values and input parameters for Invoice Numbers are configurable at
        the system level.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Order #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Will display the relevant Sales Order Number for Invoices
        generated from the Select for Billing process flow. If the Invoice is
        miscellaneous and was not generated by the Select for Billing process,
        then use this field for informational or reference purposes. Possible
        references might include Sales Order Number or Customer Purchase Order
        Number.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Invoice Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>By default, the current day's date will be entered.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Order Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>By default, the current day's date will be entered.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Ship Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>By default, the current day's date will be entered.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Customer #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the Customer Number of the Customer to be billed. The
        browse button located to the right of the field leads to a searchable
        Customers list. You may also access this list using the keyboard
        shortcut "CTRL + L". Once a Customer Number is entered, the Customer
        name and billing address will display. Select the "?" or "$" symbol
        next to the browse button to view Customer information for the
        specified Customer. If a Customer's credit is "In Good Standing," the
        button will feature a black question mark ("?") icon. If the icon
        turns to an orange dollar sign ("$"), the Customer's credit Status is
        "On Credit Warning." A red dollar sign ("$") indicates the Customer's
        credit Status is "On Credit Hold."</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>A valid Customer Number must be entered in the "Customer #" field
    before Line Items can be added to an Invoice. If no valid Customer Number
    is entered, you will not be able to add Line Items to the Invoice.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>invoices</primary>
          <secondary>billing information for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Billing Address</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the Customer address where bills should be sent. By
        default, the billing address defined on the Customer master will be
        entered here.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Copy to Ship-to</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to copy contents of billing address into Ship-To address
        field. This option is enabled if the Customer master for the specified
        Customer indicates that free-form Ship-To's are allowed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales representatives</primary>
          <secondary>commissions for</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>invoices</primary>
          <secondary>commissions on</secondary>
        </indexterm>Sales Rep.</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the Sales Representative for the Invoice. By default,
        the Customer's designated Sales Representative will appear in the
        field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Commission</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>By default, the commission percentage recorded on the Customer
        master will be automatically entered in this field. If for some reason
        you select a non-default Sales Representative at Order entry, the
        commission rate will not change. To adjust the commission rate, you
        must make the change manually.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Tax Authority</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the Tax Authority for the Invoice. By default, the main
        Tax Authority for the Customer will appear in the field. The Ship-To
        Addresss Tax Authority will be shown if a Ship-To Address is being
        used.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>invoices</primary>
          <secondary>setting terms for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Terms</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the billing Terms for the Invoice. By default, the
        Customer's standard billing terms will appear in the field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Recurring</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to indicate you want the Invoice to be a recurring
        Invoice, using the frequency settings you specify below. This feature
        enables you to automatically generate Invoices on a recurring basis
        (e.g., the same day of every month). Recurring Invoices are generated
        when you run the recurring Invoices utility, which is described in
        more detail here <xref linkend="CreateRecurringInvoices" />.
        Newly-created recurring Invoices will appear on the list of unposted
        Invoices. Their distribution date will depend on the frequency
        specified and the Invoice date on the original Invoice. For example,
        if the original Invoice is dated January 1 and the frequency is once
        every month, then the next Invoices will be dated February 1, March 1,
        etc.</para>
        <tip>
          <para>Once the recurring flag is set on the original Invoice, all
          subsequent, recurring Invoices will be marked in the database as
          children of the original parent Invoice. If you need to make changes
          to the frequency of a recurring Invoice (or to cancel the recurring
          Invoice), you must go back to the original parent Invoice and make
          the changes there.</para>
        </tip>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Every</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify how frequently you want the Invoice to recur. For
              example, once (1) per month, six (6) times per year, etc.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Until</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify when the recurrence should stop. For example, on
              the last day of the year, at the end of six months, etc.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Ship-To #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the number of the preferred Ship-To Address. Customers may
        maintain multiple Ship-To Addresses. If the Customer master for the
        specified Customer indicates that free-form Ship-To's are allowed,
        then any address may be entered. If free-form Ship-To's are not
        allowed, then the Ship-To Address must be entered using the browse
        button located to the right of the field. The browse button leads to a
        searchable Ship-To Addresses list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Cust. PO #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>PO #: Enter a Customer Purchase Order Number, as needed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>F.O.B.</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter free on board (FOB) terms for the Invoice.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Ship Via</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The preferred Ship Via method for the Customer will appear in
        the field. You may change the Ship Via using the list.</para>
        <tip>
          <para>The Ship Via field supports free-form Ship Vias. If you want
          to enter a free-form Ship Via, simply type the name of the Ship Via
          into the field.</para>
        </tip>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Project #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select a Project Number to associate with the Invoice. If the
        Invoice was created from a Sales Order&mdash;and the Sales Order had a
        Project Number associated with it&mdash;then the Project Number from
        the originating Sales Order will automatically be entered here. Once a
        Project Number is associated with a Sales Order, any Work Orders or
        Purchase Orders created by the Sales Order demand will automatically
        be linked to the same Project Number as the Sales Order. In this way,
        Sales Orders, Work Orders, and Purchase Orders may be linked to the
        same Project.</para>
        <tip>
          <para>If your site is configured to create Projects automatically
          whenever new Sales Orders or Quotes are entered, the Projects
          generated in this way will assume the number of the Sales Order or
          Quote which caused their creation.</para>
        </tip>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Creates the new Invoice.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CLOSE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without creating a new Invoice, returning you
        to the application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>sales orders</primary>
      <secondary>adding line items to</secondary>
    </indexterm>To create or modify Invoice Line Items, select the "Line
  Items" tab at the top of the "Invoice" screen. The following screen will
  appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/invoice_lineItemsTab.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Miscellaneous Invoice Line Items</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When creating or modifying Invoice Line Items, you are presented with
  the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Line Items</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists Line Items for this Invoice. A valid Customer
        Number must be entered in the "Customer #" field before Line Items can
        be added to the Order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Subtotal</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the subtotal for the Invoice Line Items.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Tax</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Tax is not calculated automatically when creating a
        miscellaneous Invoice&mdash;as it is when an Invoice is generated from
        a Sales Order. You must manually enter a Tax amount if you want to add
        Tax to a miscellaneous Invoice. To get a detailed view of the Tax
        calculation, click on the Tax link using your mouse.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Misc. Charge Amount</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the amount of any miscellaneous charge. Examples of
        miscellaneous charges include palletization costs, co-op refund, etc.
        Before entering a miscellaneous charge amount, you must first assign
        the charge to a Sales Account and also enter a description of the
        charge.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Misc. Charge Description</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a description to identify the miscellaneous charge.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Misc. Charge Sales Account</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a Sales Account to assign the miscellaneous charge
        to.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>freight</primary>
          <secondary>on invoices</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>invoices</primary>
          <secondary>freight charges on</secondary>
        </indexterm>Freight</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the amount of freight charge to be added to the
        Invoice.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Total</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays total amount of the Invoice.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Payment Received</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the amount of payment received against the specified Sales
        Order, if any. This amount will appear on the Invoice, but will not be
        posted as a credit against the Invoice.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>The Payment Received field is an optional field which may be used to
    provide visibility into prepaid amounts. Because the field exists for
    visual purposes only, entering an amount in this field will not affect the
    amount due. The only way an Invoice may be offset is through the
    application of a Cash Receipt or a Credit Memo.</para>
  </note>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Saves the Invoice Line Item information.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CLOSE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without creating a new Invoice, returning you
        to the application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Opens screen for creating a new Invoice Line Item. Mac users may
        use COMMAND + N to enter a new Line Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>EDIT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enables you to edit highlighted Invoice Line Items. The edit
        screen is the same as that for creating a new Invoice Line
        Item&mdash;except that when editing, the fields will contain Invoice
        Line Item information. Double-clicking on an Invoice Line Item will
        also bring you to the editing screen. Mac users may use COMMAND + E to
        edit an existing Line Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>VIEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight an Invoice Line Item and then select this button to
        reach a read-only view of the "Edit" screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>DELETE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight an Invoice Line Item and then select this button to
        remove the Invoice Line Item from the list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To add Notes to an Invoice, select the "Notes" tab at the top of the
  "Invoice" screen. If the Invoice was created from a Sales Order, any Sales
  Order Notes will be transfered to the Invoice. The following screen will
  appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/invoice_notesTab.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Invoice Notes</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When adding Notes to an Invoice, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Notes</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        Notes related to the Invoice. Notes entered on this screen will follow
        the Invoice through the billing process. For example, you may view
        notes associated with a posted Invoice within the Invoice Information
        report.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Saves the Invoice Notes.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without creating a Note, returning you to the
        application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <xi:include href="invoiceItem.xml"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
              xpointer="element(/1)" />
</section>