<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2008 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="itemPricingScheduleItem">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>pricing schedules</primary>
      <secondary>creating new</secondary>
    </indexterm>Pricing Schedule Item</title>
  <para>To create a new Pricing Schedule Item, select the NEW button. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/itemPricingScheduleItem.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Pricing Schedule for Item</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When creating a new Pricing Schedule Item, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Type</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify which type of Pricing Schedule Item you want to
        create:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Item</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if the Pricing Schedule is for an individual
              Item.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Product Category</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if the Pricing Schedule is for a Product
              Category.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
        <tip>
          <para>The screen options will differ depending on whether the
          Pricing Schedule is for an Item or a Product Category.</para>
        </tip>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the Item Number of the Item you want to add to the Pricing
        Schedule. The browse button located to the right of the field leads to
        a searchable sold Items list. Multiple sold Items may be assigned to a
        single Pricing Schedule.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Inventory Unit of Measure.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To define the base Pricing Schedule details for non-configured Items,
  select the "Base" tab. The "Characteristics" tab is only available for
  configured Items (i.e., Job and Reference Items).</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>quantity breaks</primary>
          <secondary>in pricing schedules</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>pricing schedules</primary>
          <secondary>quantity breaks in</secondary>
        </indexterm>Qty. Break</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the lowest quantity of the specified Item that must be
        purchased to receive the specified Price. The Quantity Break is
        measured in the Inventory Unit of Measure. Multiple Quantity Breaks
        may be assigned to a single Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>pricing schedules</primary>
          <secondary>pricing detail for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Price</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the Price the specified Item may be purchased for if the
        specified Quantity Break is met. The Price is measured in the Price
        Unit of Measure.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the Unit of Measure you want to use for the Quantity
        Break. By default, the Inventory UOM will appear here. However, if you
        have Selling UOMs defined for the specified Item, you may also select
        one of these. Selling UOMs are defined on the Item master.</para>
        <tip>
          <para>When using a Selling UOM for the Quantity Break, you may not
          select an alternate Price UOM. The reason for this is that selling
          UOMs use the same UOM for both quantity and pricing.</para>
        </tip>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Price UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the Price Unit of Measure to be used with the specified
        Quantity Break UOM. If you select a Selling UOM for the Qty. UOM, you
        will not be able to select a Price UOM. For Selling UOMs, the Selling
        UOM and the Price UOM are the same.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>List Price</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the List Price for the specified Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Price/Inv. Ratio</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the ratio between the Price and Inventory Units of
        Measure for the specified Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Cost (Pricing UOM)</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays Standard Cost and Actual Cost for the specified
        Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Margin</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The margin is determined by the following formula: Price - Cost
        / Price.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>pricing schedules</primary>
      <secondary>configured item pricing and</secondary>
    </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>configuration</primary>
      <secondary>pricing for</secondary>
    </indexterm>If the specified Item is a configured Item (i.e., Job and
  Reference Items), then the "Characteristics" tab will be available.
  Characteristics for configured Items can carry their own List Prices. These
  Characteristic Prices may be added to the Base Price when configured Items
  are sold. To define Characteristic pricing for configured Items, select the
  "Characteristics" tab. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/itemPricingScheduleItem_configuredPrices.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption>Configured Item Pricing</caption>
    </mediaobject>When defining Characteristic pricing for configured Items,
  you are presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Characteristic</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>List displays all the Characteristic Prices which have been
        associated with the Pricing Schedule Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Opens screen for creating a new Characteristic pricing
        Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>EDIT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enables you to edit highlighted Characteristic pricing Item. The
        edit screen is the same as that for creating a new Characteristic
        pricing Item&mdash;except that when editing, the fields will contain
        Characteristic pricing Item information. Double-clicking on a
        Characteristic pricing Item will also bring you to the editing
        screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>DELETE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a Characteristic pricing Item and then select this
        button to remove the Characteristic pricing Item from the list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To add a new Characteristic pricing Item, select the NEW button. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/characteristicPrice.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption>Characteristic Pricing</caption>
    </mediaobject>When adding a new Characteristic pricing Item, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Characteristic</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select a Characteristic from the list of Item Characteristics
        defined for the specified Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Value</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select a Value from the list of Values defined for the specified
        Item Characteristic.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Price</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a new Price for the Characteristic and Value combination.
        This alternate Price will be used in place of the standard
        Characteristic List Price when the Pricing Schedule is used.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>List Price</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the default List Price for the Item Characteristic. The
        List Price for Characteristics is added to the Base Price of Sales
        Order Items when the Characteristic is specified at Sales Order entry
        time. Pricing Schedules are designed to override standard List
        Prices.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without creating the Pricing Schedule Item,
        returning you to the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Creates the Pricing Schedule Item and adds it to the Pricing
        Schedule.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>pricing schedules</primary>
      <secondary>by product category</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>product categories</primary>
      <secondary>pricing schedules for</secondary>
    </indexterm>If you are creating a new Pricing Schedule for a Product
  Category, the following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/SO_IP_pricingSchedPCat.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Pricing Schedule for Product Category</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When creating a new Pricing Schedule for a Product Category, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Product Category</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the Product Category you want to add to the Pricing
        Schedule. All Items in the Product Category will be subject to the
        specified Quantity Break and Discount. Multiple Product Categories may
        be assigned to a single Pricing Schedule.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>quantity breaks</primary>
          <secondary>in pricing schedules</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>pricing schedules</primary>
          <secondary>quantity breaks in</secondary>
        </indexterm>Qty. Break (Inventory UOM)</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the lowest quantity that must be purchased to receive the
        specified Discount. The Quantity Break applies to all Items in the
        specified Product Category. Multiple Quantity Breaks may be assigned
        to a single Product Category.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>pricing schedules</primary>
          <secondary>discount percentage for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Discount Percent (List Price)</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the Discount percentage off List Price to be used when the
        specified Quantity Break is reached. The List Prices for all Items in
        the Product Category will be reduced by the specified
        percentage.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>