<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2008 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section518698">
  <title id="Anchor54109"><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>locales</primary>
      <secondary>master list of</secondary>
    </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>locales</primary>
      <secondary>linguistic flexibility using</secondary>
    </indexterm>Locales</title>
  <para>Locales are associated with users and define the format for date,
  time, and numbers. Locales are also used to search for translation files and
  to specify decimal precision and some of the colors that the user sees on
  the screen. This is a powerful feature that allows each user to interact
  with the application in their native language and formats.</para>
  <para>Part of defining a Locale is setting the language and, optionally, the
  Country. It is the combination of language and Country that determines date
  and numeric formats and which translation file will be used. For example, a
  Locale that references English and the United States will display as
  follows:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>M/D/YY</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Time</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>12 hour format</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Numbers</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>1,999.00</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>A Locale that refers to German and Germany will display like
  this:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>DD.MM.YY</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Time</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>12 hour format</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Numbers</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>1.999,00</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>Translation information is stored in .qm files, which xTuple uses to
  display the user interface in a different language. When a Language is
  selected in a Locale and the Country is left as "Default," the xTuple client
  expects to find the file <filename>xTuple.xx.qm</filename> (where
  <filename>xx</filename> is the ISO two letter language code) located in the
  directory where the xTuple client is located. The U.S. Library of Congress
  is the ISO registration authority for language codes and makes the list of
  languages available on its <ulink
  url="http://www.loc.gov/standards/iso639-2/php/code_list.php">language codes
  website</ulink>. Please contact xTuple for more information about the
  availability of .qm files for various languages.</para>
  <para>When both a Language and a Country are selected, the xTuple client
  looks for the file <filename>xTuple.xx_yy.qm</filename> located in the
  directory where the xTuple client is installed. The <filename>xx</filename>
  is the ISO two letter language code and <filename>yy</filename> is the two
  letter country code. You can find country codes in xTuple by navigating to
  System &gt; Master Information &gt; Countries and observing the abbreviation
  column. If the xTuple client does not find a file that matches both Language
  and Country (<filename>xTuple.xx_yy.qm</filename>) it next looks for a file
  that contains the Language only (e.g.,
  <filename>xTuple.xx.qm</filename>).</para>
  <para>If no .qm translation file is found, the xTuple client will report the
  error and continue the logon. The user will be presented the screens in the
  default language, which is English. The conventions established for the
  Locale that define date, time, decimal precision, and color will be
  presented based on the Locale associated with the User. If you don't want to
  see this error message again, go to the Preferences window and check the
  Ignore Missing Translations check box.</para>
  <para>Numbers are generally formatted by the application in accordance with
  the conventions associated with the selected language and Country. These
  conventions mostly concern the character used to distinguish the fractional
  part of a number from the integer part, commonly called the "decimal point"
  or decimal separator, and the character used as the "group separator" or, at
  least in the U.S., the "thousands separator." In addition to the core
  numeric format, the xTuple application lets you choose the precision of
  numeric display and data entry for different kinds of number.</para>
  <para>To access the master list of Locales, select the "Locales" option. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/locales.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Locales Master List</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>The "Locales" screen displays information on all existing Locales,
  including Locale name and Locale description.</para>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CLOSE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen, returning you to the application
        desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Opens screen for creating a new Locale.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>EDIT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enables you to edit highlighted Locale definitions. The edit
        screen is the same as that for creating a new Locale definition—except
        that when editing, the fields will contain Locale information.
        Double-clicking on a Locale master will also bring you to the editing
        screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>COPY</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a Locale and then select this button to reach a screen
        for copying the Locale's definition.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>DELETE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a Locale definition and then select this button to
        remove the Locale from the list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <xi:include href="locale.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
              xpointer="element(/1)" />
</section>