<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2008 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="locale">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>locales</primary>
      <secondary>creating new</secondary>
    </indexterm>Locale</title>
  <para>Locales are used to present information to users in the formats and
  language appropriate for their site. For example, the formatting of dates,
  times, and Currency are controlled by Locales. Translation of the
  application into a user's local language is also controlled by
  Locales.</para>
  <tip>
    <para>Make the link between users and their Locales on the Maintain Users
    screen.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>The xTuple Locale functionality is designed to coordinate with the
  settings in your local operating system. Because of this, it should only be
  necessary to specify the "Default" language and country value--and xTuple
  ERP will follow your operating system settings. For example, let's say you
  are located in China, running an operating system configured for China. In
  that scenario, using the default xTuple Locale values should result in
  xTuple ERP being formatted appropriately for China.</para>
  <para>While in most cases using the default values will work, you may have
  the need to modify your Locale settings for specific cases. To create a new
  Locale, select the NEW button. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/locale.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create New Locale</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When creating a new Locale, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Code</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a code to uniquely identify the specified Locale setting.
        This code is referenced in the Maintain Users section, where Locales
        are associated with individual users.</para>
        <note>
          <para>If you plan to use the Default Locale, then it may not be
          necessary to define any additional Locales. By using the Default
          Locale you allow your operating system settings to govern the
          presentation of xTuple ERP.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Description</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a brief description to further define the specified
        Locale.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>locales</primary>
          <secondary>language setting for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Language</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select a language from the list of languages--or specify
        "Default" to indicate you want your operating system to define
        language option for you. The language selection impacts date and time
        formatting. It also tells the system which language translation file
        to load (if any). xTuple ERP supports multi-language translations of
        the product interface through the use of .QM files. If a .QM
        translation file is installed next to your xTuple ERP executable file,
        then the system will load the translation file at run
        time--automatically translating the application into your desired
        language. As long as your .QM file follows the standard ISO-derived
        naming convention (e.g., <filename>xTuple.cn.qm</filename> = Chinese
        and <filename>xTuple.es.qm</filename> = Spanish), then the system will
        successfully find it based on your Locale language selection. </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>locales</primary>
          <secondary>country setting for</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>countries</primary>
          <secondary>defined in locales</secondary>
        </indexterm>Country</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select a country from the list of countries--or specify "Any" to
        indicate you want your operating system to define country option for
        you. The available countries will vary depending on the language
        selection. The country selection combined with the language selection
        impacts date and time formatting.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>The following date and time formatting will be used, based on your
  language and country selections. If you are using the "Default" language and
  country selections, then the formatting will be inherited from your
  operating system.</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>locales</primary>
          <secondary>data formats for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Date Format</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the format used for dates within the
        application.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Time Format</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the format used for times within the
        application.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Timestamp Format</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the timestamp format used to display any "timestamp"
        data within the application. Timestamps are typically used in
        transaction logs that record the specific date and time when an
        activity occurs within the system.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Interval Format</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the format used for intervals within the application.
        The interval format is used to define how Work Order
        clock-in/clock-out times and effort are displayed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>While date and time formatting are governed by the language and
  country selections, you do have the ability to manually determine the number
  of supported decimal places for various formats. The following formatting
  options are available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Currency</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The currency format is used to display any currency data within
        the application.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Sales Price</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The sales Price format is used to display any sales Price data
        within the application.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Purch. Price</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The purchase Price format is used to display any purchase Price
        data within the application.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Ext. Price</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The Extended Price format is used to display any Extended Price
        data within the application.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Cost</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The Cost format is used to display costing data within the
        application.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty.</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The quantity format is used to display quantity data within the
        application.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. Per</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The quantity per format is used to display quantities per within
        the application.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>UOM Ratio</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The Unit of Measure ratio format is used to display Unit of
        Measure ratios within the application.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Color Coding</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify RGB values, or use any of the color names found in the
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>You have the ability to define the colors used by the application to
  emphasize special cases in the data. When entering color choices, you can
  either use standard RGB values or any of the color names found on the <ulink
  url="http://www.w3.org/TR/SVG/types.html#ColorKeywords">available colors
  list</ulink>. Colors may be defined for any of the following cases:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Error</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the color-coding for errors.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Warning</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the color-coding for warnings.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Emphasis</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the color-coding for emphasis.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Alternate</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the color-coding for alternate text.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Expired</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the color-coding to indicate the expired
        condition.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Future</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the color-coding to indicate the future
        condition.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To enter Comments related to the Locale, use the Comments
  field:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Comments</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        Comments related to the Locale.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen, returning you to the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Creates the Locale setting and adds it to the master list of
        Locales.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>