<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2010 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="metasqlEditor">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>metasql</primary>
      <secondary>editor for</secondary>
    </indexterm>MetaSQL Editor</title>
  <para>To create a new MetaSQL Statement, select the NEW button. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/metasqlEditor.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create New MetaSQL Statement</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>The MetaSQL Editor can be used to create new MetaSQL Statements or
  edit those already found on the MetaSQL Statements master list. Once
  created, new MetaSQL Statements can be added to the master list, making them
  available for use in the application. To edit an existing MetaSQL Statement,
  simply load the statement into the editor from the Database you are
  currently connected to. Then edit the statement and save it back to the
  Database once editing is complete.</para>
  <para>The body of a MetaSQL Statement is an SQL <literal>SELECT</literal>,
  <literal>UPDATE</literal> or <literal>DELETE</literal> statement. (The user
  must have been granted the <literal>ExecuteMetaSQL</literal> privilege to
  run the <literal>UPDATE</literal> or <literal>DELETE</literal> statement.)
  Passed parameters can be utilized to control how the statement operates
  (using an <literal>IF</literal>, <literal>ELSE</literal>,
  <literal>ENDIF</literal> construct) and their values can be inserted. The
  core xTuple PostBooks Edition contains many statements that can be used as
  examples.</para>
  <para>The MetaSQL Editor toolbar has icon shortcuts for New, Open, Save,
  Undo, Cut, Copy, and Paste. The Editor menu has many options to simplify the
  development of MetaSQL Statements, including viewing and editing the
  Parameter List, executing the query, and viewing the query results.</para>
  <para>When saving a new MetaSQL Statement, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Database and File</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Saves the MetaSQL Statement into the Database you are currently
        connected to and to a file.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>File Only</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Saves the MetaSQL Statement to a file.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Cancel</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Cancels the save operation.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Database Only</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Saves the MetaSQL Statement into the Database you are currently
        connected to.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>After defining the save options, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Schema</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>You would normally select the "public" schema. However, there
        are situations where you may want to define the MetaSQL Statement in a
        different schema.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Group</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the Group for the MetaSQL Statement. This is the major
        grouping for statements and normally reflects the type or source of
        information. Some examples are <literal>arHistory</literal>,
        <literal>purchaseOrders</literal>, etc.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the Name for the MetaSQL Statement. This is detailed name
        for the statement within the Group.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Grade</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the Grade number for the MetaSQL Statement. If there are
        multiple MetaSQL Statements with the same Group/Name, the one with the
        highest Grade number will be used. It is a good idea to save changes
        to statements with a higher Grade number so, if necessary, you can
        refer to the original statement before implementing the changes. Use
        the menu option <guimenuitem>File &gt; Save As Database</guimenuitem>
        to change the Grade of a statement.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Notes</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter any notes or comments related to the MetaSQL
        Statement.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
