<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2008 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section541038">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>checks</primary>
      <secondary>creating miscellaneous</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>miscellaneous checks</primary>
      <secondary>creating new</secondary>
    </indexterm>Create Miscellaneous Check</title>
  <para>For payments related to non-Inventory goods or services, you have the
  ability to create miscellaneous A/P Checks. You can write Checks to Vendors,
  Customers, or Tax Authorities. To create a miscellaneous Check, select the
  "Create Miscellaneous Check" option. The following screen will
  appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/miscCheck.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Miscellaneous Check</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When creating a miscellaneous Check, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Write Check To:</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify which type of recipient you want to write the
        miscellaneous Check to. Your options will vary depending on which type
        you select.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Vendor</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if you want to write a Check to a Vendor. Once
              selected, you must also specify the Vendor.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Customer</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if you want to write a Check to a Customer. Once
              selected, you must also specify the Customer.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Tax Authority</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if you want to write a Check to a Tax Authority.
              Once selected, you must also specify the Tax Authority.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Charge To:</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify how you want to handle the accounting for the
        miscellaneous Check. Your options will vary depending on the recipient
        type you choose.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Expense Category</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the Expense Category you want to distribute the
              payment to. This option is available for all recipient
              types.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Apply to Credit Memo</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>This option is available only for Checks to Customers. If
              selected, you can choose a Credit Memo from the Customer's open
              balance. Then, when the miscellaneous Check is posted, the open
              Credit Memo will automatically be closed. Use this feature for
              paying off and closing open Customer balances.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Create Credit Memo</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>This option is available only for Checks to Vendors. Once
              the miscellaneous Check is posted, a Credit Memo in the Check
              amount will be created. This Credit Memo will offset your
              Accounts Payable for the specified Vendor. You would use this
              option, for example, to handle prepayments made to
              Vendors.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Create Debit Memo</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>This option is available only for Checks to Customers. You
              would use this in the case where you lent a Customer money, with
              the expectation of billing them later.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the date to appear on the miscellaneous Check.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Amount</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the amount of the miscellaneous Check.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Memo</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a Memo line to be included on the bottom portion of the
        printed miscellaneous Check.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Bank Account</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the Bank Account you want to use for the miscellaneous
        Check.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Check Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the next available Check Number.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Notes</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        Notes related to the miscellaneous Check.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without creating a miscellaneous Check,
        returning you to the application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CREATE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Creates the miscellaneous Check, using the specified
        parameters.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>