<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2008 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section>
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>packages</primary>
      <secondary>master list of</secondary>
    </indexterm>Packages</title>
  <para>Packages are compressed files which may contain either a) custom
  software designed to extend the functionality of xTuple ERP without touching
  the core xTuple ERP source code or b) upgrade bundles designed to migrate
  xTuple ERP databases from one version to the next. Using Packages,
  third-party software developers can add features without needing C++
  programming skills. And these features can be integrated seamlessly into
  xTuple ERP independent of the release cycles and source code requirements
  defined by xTuple. In short, Packages are flexible. And they make it easy
  for software developers to add new features—or even just simple tweaks—to
  customize and enhance the xTuple ERP experience. For additional information,
  please see the <ulink
  url="http://wiki.xtuple.org/CreateUpdaterPackages">CreateUpdaterPackages</ulink>
  wiki page.</para>
  <para>To view the complete list of Packages loaded into your xTuple ERP
  system, select the "Packages" option. The following screen will
  appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/packages.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Packages Master List</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>The "List Packages" screen displays information on all existing
  Packages.</para>
  <para>To the far right of the list, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CLOSE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen, returning you to the application
        desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>PRINT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Runs the report associated with this screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>LOAD</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Opens the Updater utility to allow loading a new Package. If the
        application cannot find the Updater then the user is given a dialog to
        find the Updater. This option will only be available to xTuple ERP
        administrators.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>VIEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a Package and then select this button to reach a
        read-only view of the "Edit" screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>ENABLE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a Package and then select this button to enable a
        Package which has been disabled. This option will only be available to
        xTuple ERP administrators.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>DISABLE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a Package and then select this button to disable a
        Package which has been enabled. This option will only be available to
        xTuple ERP administrators.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>DELETE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a Package and then select this button to remove the
        Package from the list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Automatically Update</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to have the Packages master list automatically update
        whenever there are changes to the information shown on the
        screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <xi:include href="package.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
              xpointer="element(/1)" />
</section>