<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2008 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section519291" role="openmfg">
  <title>Post Operation</title>
  <para>Work Order progress can be posted in terms of materials used or
  Operations completed. When you post Operations, you are using the
  Operations-driven process for reporting progress. To post Work Order
  Operations, select the "Post Operations" option. The following screen will
  appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/postOperations.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Post Work Order Operations</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When posting a Work Order's Operations, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Work Order #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the Work Order Number of the Work Order whose Operations
        you want to post. You may also scan into this field a Work Order
        Operation barcode as defined for the Shop Floor Workbench
        screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Site</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays Site code automatically when Work Order Number is
        entered into "Work Order #" field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays Item Number automatically when Work Order Number is
        entered into "Work Order #" field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Inventory Unit of Measure.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>If your site combines Operations posting with WIP Location tracking
    for Multiple Location Control (MLC) Items, then you may be prompted to
    relocate Inventory during the Operations posting process.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Status</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays Work Order Status automatically when Work Order Number
        is entered into "Work Order #" field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>W/O Operation</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select the individual Operation you want to post from the list
        of Work Order Operations for the specified Item. After selecting an
        Operation, specify details for that Operation. To post Operations for
        another Operation, simply select that Operation from the sequential
        list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. to Post</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the quantity you want to post.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>work orders</primary>
          <secondary>posting options</secondary>
        </indexterm>Post in Production UOMs</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to post the Operations quantity in Production Units of
        Measure. Operations may be posted using either the Inventory or
        Production UOM. In addition, different Operations in a single Bill of
        Operations may use different Production UOMs. For example, if you are
        producing soup, you might mix the soup in one Operation using UOM =
        BATCH. But when canning the soup, the canning Operation might use UOM
        = CAN. If you post Operations using the Production UOM, the
        Inventory/Production UOM ratio defined at the Operation level
        normalizes the posting so that the Inventory impact is recorded using
        the Inventory UOM.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Post in Inventory UOMs</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to post the Operations quantity in Inventory Units of
        Measure.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>W/O Qty. Ordered</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Ordered: Indicates the quantity of material, measures in the
        Item's Inventory UOM, that the selected Work Order is due to
        produce.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Operation Qty. Received</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Indicates the quantity, measured in the Item's Inventory UOM,
        that has been completed by this Operation.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Operation Balance Due</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Indicates the quantity remaining to be produced by the specified
        Operation.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Work Center</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the name of the Work Center where the Operations were
        performed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Issue Components</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Indicates that linked component materials will be issued
        automatically (i.e., backflushed) when the specified Operation is
        posted. Option will be enabled only if component materials are linked
        to the specified Operation within the parent Item's Bill of Materials.
        If such linkages exist, only components with "Pull" or "Mixed" issue
        methods will be displayed. Components having the "Push" issue method
        will not appear in the list, as these must be issued manually to a
        Work Order. If this option is selected, the General Ledger will show
        the component materials being removed from Inventory when this
        Operation is posted.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Receive Inventory</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Indicates that finished goods will be received into Inventory
        when the specified Operation is posted. Enabled only when the selected
        Operation is the receiving Operation for the selected Work Order. Only
        one Work Order Operation may have this flag set. If this option is
        selected, the General Ledger will show the finished goods being
        received into Inventory when the Operation is posted.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Close W/O</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select this option to close the Work Order. The option will be
        selected automatically at the point when you are posting all quantity
        complete.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Post Setup Time</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to post setup time.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Mark Setup as Complete</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to mark setup as complete.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Post Standard Setup Time</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to post standard setup time. Typically, standard times
        will not be used if Operations are being posted using the Shop Floor
        Workbench. Instead, labor times will be calculated based on clock-in
        and clock-out times. Only users with privileges to override the
        Production Time Clock will be able to post standard times.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Post Specified Setup Time</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the non-standard amount of setup time required. The
        amount of time entered will be posted. If you are posting Operations
        from the Shop Floor Workbench, the setup time entered will be
        automatically deducted from the run-time total.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Post Run Time</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to post run time.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Mark Operation as Complete</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to mark Operation as complete. An Operation may not be
        marked as "Complete" until all users are clocked-out of the Operation.
        Users clock-in to and clock-out of Work Orders using the Shop Floor
        Workbench.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Post Standard Run Time</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to post the standard run time for specified Item.
        Typically, standard times will not be used if Operations are being
        posted using the Shop Floor Workbench. Instead, labor times will be
        calculated based on clock-in and clock-out times. Only users with
        privileges to override the Production Time Clock will be able to post
        standard times.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Post Specified Run Time</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the non-standard amount of run time required. The amount
        of time entered will be posted. If you are posting Operations from the
        Shop Floor Workbench, run time will be automatically calculated based
        on the accumulated time elapsed between clock-ins and
        clock-outs.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Setup Performed By</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the name of the user who performed the set up. Since this
        is a text field, user names may also be scanned into the field using a
        Bar Code scanner.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Run Performed By</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the name of the user who performed the production run.
        Since this is a text field, user names may also be scanned into the
        field using a Bar Code scanner.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without posting Operations, returning you to
        the application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SCRAP MATERIALS</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to open the "Scrap Work Order Material from W/O"
        screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>POST OPERATION</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Posts the specified Operation using the values entered in the
        screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>