<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2010 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="postJournals">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>journals</primary>
      <secondary>posting to g/l</secondary>
    </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>general ledger</primary>
      <secondary>posting journals to</secondary>
    </indexterm>Post Journals to Ledger</title>
  <para>If your system is configured to post transactions to intermediate
  Journals (sometimes also referred to as "day books"), it is important that
  you periodically post transactions from the Journals to the General Ledger.
  The reason for this is that the trial balance and other financial reports
  draw their information solely from the General Ledger. If Journal
  transactions are not posted to the General Ledger, then they will not be
  included in the system's financial reports.</para>
  <para>One advantage to using intermediate Journals is that transactions are
  summarized when they are posted over to the General Ledger. In this way,
  transaction detail remains in the Journals, with the summarized version of
  that detail residing in the General Ledger. You can post Journals to the
  General Ledger on a daily, monthly, or weekly basis. It's up to you how you
  want to implement this feature. But again, keep in mind that financial
  reports will only be updated when Journal transactions are posted over to
  the General Ledger.</para>
  <para>To review and post Journals to the General Ledger, select the "Post
  Journals to Ledger" option. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/postJournals.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Post Journals to General Ledger</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When reviewing Journals for posting to the General Ledger, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Transaction Dates</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify a date range for the Journals you want to review and
        post.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Start Date</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Journal transactions posted on and after this date will be
              included in the display.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>End Date</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Journal transactions posted on and before this date will
              be included in the display.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Preview Posting</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you want to review the transaction detail for the
        Journals before posting. You will not be able to post Journals while
        in preview mode.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>General Ledger Distribution</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify a distribution date:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Date</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the date when you want the selected Journals to be
              posted to the General Ledger.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Eligible Sources</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists unposted Journals available for posting to the
        General Ledger. You may select one or multiple Journals for posting
        using your mouse and the SHIFT or CTRL keys. To select all Journals
        for posting, select the SELECT ALL button.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Print on Post</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you want to print a report of the posted Journals
        after the POST button has been pushed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>POST</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to post the selected Journals to the General Ledger,
        using the specified distribution date. Only selected Journals will be
        posted.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SELECT ALL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to include all available Journals for posting to the
        General Ledger.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
