<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2010 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section528862">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>packing lists</primary>
      <secondary>printing of</secondary>
    </indexterm>Print Packing List</title>
  <para>To print a Packing List or Sales Order (S/O) Pick List, select the
  "Print Packing List" option. If the order has a Shipment Number, the Packing
  List form should be used. If there is no Shipment Number&mdash;that is, if
  no Line Item quantity has been issued to shipping&mdash;then the S/O Pick
  List form should be used. Both forms are defined under <guimenuitem>Sales
  &gt; Master Information &gt; Customer Form Assignments</guimenuitem>.</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/printPackingList.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Print Packing List</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When printing a Packing List, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Form</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify which type of Packing List form you want to
        print:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Auto Select</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to have the system automatically determine which
              form should be used, based on the state of the Order at the time
              the report is printed.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Packing List</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to have the defined Packing List form printed. This
              form is used if an Order has a Shipment Number.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Pick List</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to have the S/O Pick List form printed. If the
              Order does not have a Shipment Number, this form is used.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Reprint</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select this option if you want to print a Packing List which has
        already been printed. Once a Packing List has been printed, you must
        use this option if you want to print it again.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Order #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the Order Number of the Order whose Packing List you want
        to print. The Order may be either a Sales Order or a Transfer
        Order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Shipment #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the Shipment Number you want to print a Packing List
        for. Shipment Numbers are assigned to Orders when Line Item quantity
        is issued to Shipping. A single Order may have multiple Shipments
        associated with it. If no stock has ever been issued to Shipping for
        an Order, then no Shipment Number will be associated with it.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Customer Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Customer's name.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Customer Phone</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Customer's phone number.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Purchase Order Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Customer's Purchase Order Number.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Order Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Order date for the Sales Order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen, returning you to the application
        desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>PRINT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Prints a copy of either the Packing List or Sales Order Pick
        List for the specified Order. A Sales Order Pick List will be printed
        if the Sales Order does not yet have a Shipment Number associated with
        it&mdash;that is, if no Line Item quantity has been issued to
        shipping. If stock has been issued to Shipping, then the Packing List
        report definition will be used.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>The system includes two alternate S/O Pick List report
    definitions:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>PickingListSOClosedLines.xml</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>PickingListNoClosedLines.xml</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>The first includes already closed Sales Order Line Items in the
    report; the other excludes closed Line Items.</para>
  </tip>
</section>
