<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="printCheck">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>payments</primary>
      <secondary>printing individual</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>accounts payable</primary>
      <secondary>printing payments for</secondary>
    </indexterm>Print Payment</title>
  <para>To print an individual Payment, select the "Print Payment" option. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/printCheck.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Print Payment</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <tip>
    <para>If Payments being printed contain reference lines which spill over
    and exceed one standard page, then consider using the report definition
    CheckMultiPage.xml. This Payment Form is designed to support multiple
    pages for one Payment number.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>When printing an individual Payment, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Bank Account</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the Bank Account for the Payment you want to print. Only
        Bank Accounts which require printing will have Payments to print. If
        the specified Bank Account is configured to use Electronic Funds
        Transfer (EFT), the CREATE EFT FILE button will be enabled on this
        screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Payment</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the Payment Number you want to print. Menu will list
        Payments from prepared Payment Runs associated with the specified Bank
        Account.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Next Payment #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the next Payment number.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>ALREADY PRINTED/PAID</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you want to mark the Payment as already printed or
        paid. By marking a Payment in this way, you can manually bypass the
        print requirement and move straight to posting the Payment.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CREATE EFT FILE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to create an Electronic Funds Transfer (EFT) file. This
        button will be enabled only for Bank Accounts which are configured to
        use EFT.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
