<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2008 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="transferOrderItem" role="standard">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>transfer orders</primary>
      <secondary>adding line items to</secondary>
    </indexterm>Transfer Order Item</title>
  <para>To add a new Transfer Order Line Item, select the NEW button. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/IM_IT_transferOrdItemNew.png"
                     />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create New Transfer Order Line
        Item</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When creating a new Transfer Order Line Item, you are presented with
  the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Order #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Transfer Order Number specified on the Transfer
        Order header screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Line #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Line Item Number for the current Line Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the Item Number of the Item you want to sell. The Item
        list will contain Items having valid Item Sites in the From (i.e.,
        Source) Site.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sites</primary>
          <secondary>source for transfer orders</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales orders</primary>
          <secondary>selling sites for</secondary>
        </indexterm>From Site</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Source Site specified on the Transfer Order
        header screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. Ordered</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the quantity of the specified Item to be
        transferred.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Scheduled Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The scheduled date is the date when the Line Item should be
        Shipped. The user who enters the Line Item is responsible for
        determining the scheduled date. After entering the scheduled date, hit
        the TAB key on your keyboard to display values in the remaining
        display only fields.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>The Transfer Order Item having the earliest scheduled date will
    determine the ship date for the Transfer Order.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales orders</primary>
          <secondary>availability of items for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Show Availability</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to display Availability information for the Transfer
        Order Item in the following categories:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>On Hand</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the current Quantity on Hand value.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Allocated</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the quantity allocated to current Sales Orders,
              Transfer Orders, and/or Work Orders in the system. An Item is
              considered allocated to a Sales Order/Transfer Order if a
              Transfer Order Line Item exists for the Item&mdash;and that Line Item
              has not yet been issued to Shipping. An Item is considered
              allocated to a Work Order if the Item is a material
              requirement&mdash;and the material has not yet been issued to the
              Work Order. Once the current Transfer Order Line Item is saved,
              the "Allocated" value will increase by the quantity
              ordered.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Unallocated</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the Quantity on Hand remaining after allocations
              have been accounted for, as in: QOH - Allocated Qty. =
              Unallocated Qty.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>On Order</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>If the Transfer Order Item is a manufactured Item, the
              quantity ordered by current Work Orders will be displayed. If
              the Transfer Order Item is a purchased Item, the quantity
              ordered by current Purchase Orders will be displayed.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Available</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the available quantity. Available quantity is
              determined using the following formula: Unallocated Qty. + On
              Order Qty. = Available Qty.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Standard Cost</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Standard Cost per unit.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Line Item Freight</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the amount of freight charges for the entire Line Item
        quantity.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Tax</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the amount of Tax to be charged for the Transfer Order
        Line Item quantity. Sales Tax is calculated at the Transfer Order Line
        Item level. To get a detailed view of the Tax calculation, click on
        the Tax link using your mouse.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. Shipped to Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Shipped to Date: Displays the total quantity shipped of the
        specified Line Item to date.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>You can link Characteristics and Values to an Item by using the Item
    master. Once entered, these Characteristics and Values will be available
    to users entering Transfer Order Line Items.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>When selecting or editing Characteristics for a Transfer Order Line
  Item, you are presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the name of any Item Characteristics associated with
        the Item. Characteristics defined as Item Characteristics may be
        associated with Items on the Item master.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Value</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the default Value associated with an Item
        Characteristic, but permits you to specify an alternate Value. When
        associating Characteristic Values with a Transfer Order Line Item, you
        have four options: 1) Select the default Value; 2) select an alternate
        pre-defined Value from the list; 3) manually enter a new Value in
        place of the pre-defined Value; or 4) make no selection. Making no
        selection means the Characteristics will not be associated with the
        Transfer Order Line Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CLOSE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without creating a new Transfer Order Line
        Item, returning you to the Transfer Order header.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Creates the new Transfer Order Line Item and adds it to the list
        of Transfer Order Line Items.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>If there is no Item Site for the Item in the Destination Site,
    you will automatically be presented with an Item Site screen. Simply enter
    the required information to create an Item Site in the Destination
    Site. An Item Site must exist in the Destination Site before
    material can be received successfully.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>PREVIOUS</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to view previous Line Items associated with the Transfer
        Order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to create a new Transfer Order Line Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL ITEM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to cancel the current Transfer Order Line Item. Records
        of canceled Line Items will be retained for informational purposes. To
        view canceled Line Items associated with a Transfer Order, select the
        "Show Canceled Line Items" option on the Transfer Order header's "Line
        Items tab.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To enter Notes related to a Transfer Order Line Item, select the
  "Notes" tab at the bottom of the screen, as shown below:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/IM_IT_transferOrdItemNotes.png"
                     />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Transfer Order Line Item Notes</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When adding Notes to a Transfer Order Line Item, you are presented
  with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Notes</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        general Notes related to the Transfer Order Line Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To add Comments related to a Transfer Order Line Item, select the
  "Comments" tab. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/IM_IT_transferOrdItemComm.png"
                     />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Transfer Order Line Item
        Comments</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <note>
    <para>Whenever Transfer Order Line Items are created or their quantities
    are changed, the system will automatically generate a Comment, which will
    appear in the list of Line Item Comments.</para>
  </note>
  <para>When adding Comments related to a Transfer Order Line Item, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Comments</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists Comments for the specified Line Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Opens screen for creating a new Comment. Transfer Order Line
        Item Comments may only be added after the Line Item has been saved to
        the Transfer Order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>VIEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a Comment and then select this button to reach a
        read-only view of the Comment.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To create a Transfer Order Line Item Comment, select the NEW button.
  The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/CommentNew.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create New Comment</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Comment Type</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify one of the following Comment Types from the drop-down
        list: ChangeLog or General. Comment Types are used to categorize
        Comments. Once you have specified a Comment Type, you may type your
        Comment in the main text area. The text area features word-wrapping
        and scroll-bar support for longer Comments.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without creating a new Comment, returning you
        to the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Creates the Comment and adds it to the list of Order
        Comments.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>If the Transfer Order Line Item is a manufactured Item, you have the
  ability to view Pending Availability for any of its component Items. To view
  the Pending Availability for Transfer Order Line Item component Items,
  select the "Pending Availability" tab, as shown below:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/IM_IT_transferOrdItemPend.png"
                     />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Pending Availability for Component
        Items</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When displaying Pending Availability for Transfer Order component
  Items, you are presented with the following options:</para>
  <note>
    <para>The "Pending Availability" tab features details related to component
    Items and so only applies if a Transfer Order Line Item is a manufactured
    Item. If a Line Item is not manufactured, Pending Availability does not
    apply.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Show Pending Availability as Indented BOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to display Pending Availability as an indented Bill of
        Materials.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Pending Availability</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays Pending Availability for component Items associated
        with sold manufactured Items. If you choose the "Show Pending
        Availability as Indented BOM" option, the information will be
        displayed in a nested list&mdash;with a plus ("+") sign located to the far
        left of the screen next to each line that may be expanded to lower
        levels. By clicking your mouse on a plus sign, you reveal lower levels
        of information related to the Line Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>Keep in mind that Pending Availability in this case is not the same
    as Available to Promise. This view to Pending Availability reflects
    current Inventory Levels&mdash;it is not a time-phased view of
    Availability.</para>
  </tip>
</section>
