<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="user">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>user accounts</primary>
      <secondary>creating new</secondary>
    </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>xtuple administrators</primary>
      <secondary>new user accounts created by</secondary>
    </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>administrators</primary>
      <see>xtuple administrators</see>
    </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>system administrators</primary>
      <see>xtuple administrators</see>
    </indexterm>User Account</title>
  <para>To create a new User Account, select the NEW button. The following
  screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/user.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>User Account Information</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When creating a new User Account, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>usernames</primary>
          <secondary>creating for users</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>user accounts</primary>
          <secondary>creating usernames for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Username</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a unique username to clearly distinguish the new User
        Account from existing User Accounts. The username is case-sensitive.
        This is a required field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Active</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to mark the User Account as Active. Not selecting marks
        the User Account as Inactive. User Accounts cannot be deleted from the
        system; however, marking them Inactive prevents them from logging into
        the application. In some cases, inactive User Accounts may still be
        associated with valid documents in the system. Whenever that is the
        case, the User Account's name will appear with horizontal lines
        striking through it. Re-saving documents with this inactive User
        Account relationship may cause the username to be dropped from the
        record.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Proper Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the User Account's first name and last name (e.g., John
        Smith).</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Initials</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the User Account's initials.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>user accounts</primary>
          <secondary>passwords for</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>xtuple administrators</primary>
          <secondary>passwords created by</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>passwords</primary>
          <secondary>created by administrators</secondary>
        </indexterm>Password</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>User Account passwords are established to ensure application and
        system security. Passwords are case-sensitive. As you can see in the
        example, this field does not display the values entered on the screen.
        Instead, individual keystrokes are replaced by asterisks (*) to
        protect the password from being viewed. Once the User Account's
        password is entered, it can only be reset by an system administrator
        who must overwrite the existing password.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Verify</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Verify the accuracy of the User Account's password by retyping
        it in this field. Again, individual keystrokes will be replaced by
        asterisks (*) to protect the password from being viewed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Dept.</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select a Department to associate with the specified User
        Account. This is an optional setting.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="manufacturing">
      <term>Shift</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select a Shift to associate with the specified User Account.
        This is an optional setting.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>locales</primary>
          <secondary>user specific</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>xtuple administrators</primary>
          <secondary>user locales established by</secondary>
        </indexterm>Locale</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select one of the available Locales. Use the
        <option>Default</option> option if you want the operating system to
        determine the correct Locale for the User Account. Locale settings
        affect how information is formatted and displayed on a User Account's
        screen. Only User Accounts who have been granted the "MaintainLocales"
        privilege can define and maintain Locale settings. For more
        information on Locales and Locale settings, see <xref
        linkend="locales" />.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Employee</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>If the User Account is an Employee, then the Employee Code will
        be displayed here. The link between the User Account and Employee
        records will be made automatically if the username matches the
        Employee Code.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>user accounts</primary>
          <secondary>privileges for</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>xtuple administrators</primary>
          <secondary>user account privileges defined by</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>privileges</primary>
          <secondary>for user accounts</secondary>
        </indexterm>Purchasing Agent</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if the User Accounts is authorized to make purchases. Not
        selecting means the User Account is not authorized to make
        purchases.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Can Create System User Accounts</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if the User Account is authorized to create new User
        Accounts. Not selecting means the User Account is not authorized to
        create new User Accounts.</para>
        <note>
          <para>System administrators are able to assign and/or revoke
          privileges on a module-by-module basis. The application provides
          granular security settings for each module, down to the submenu
          level.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Disable Export Display Contents</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to prevent User Account from exporting display contents.
        The "Export Contents" option can be found on right-click menus
        throughout the application. If selected, the User Account will be
        blocked from using the "Export Contents" option.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Use Enhanced Authentication</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to require User Accounts to use enhanced authentication
        when they log in to the application. Enhanced authentication adds a
        layer to the authentication process used to log in to the system. When
        this feature is turned on, User Account passwords are stored in the
        database in a modified form. The end result is that User Accounts may
        only log in to the database using the xTuple Client. If User Accounts
        try to access the database using a tool other than an xTuple
        application, they will not be able to connect. User Account passwords
        entered when logging in via the xTuple Client will not be recognized
        if the xTuple Client is not used. If enhanced authentication is
        specified for a User Account, that User Account must also select the
        "Use Enhanced Authentication" flag in their log in options. If
        enhanced authentication is not specified, User Accounts will be
        permitted to log in to the database using database tools other than
        the xTuple Client.</para>
        <note>
          <para>The enhanced authentication option will only affect User
          Accounts whose passwords are created or updated after the option is
          enabled/disabled. Legacy User Accounts will not be affected if the
          option is not used. Legacy User Accounts may continue logging in as
          before this feature was implemented.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="manufacturing">
      <term>May only use Shop Floor Workbench</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you want the User Account to have access only to the
        Shop Floor Workbench—and to no other screens. If selected, the Shop
        Floor Workbench will be the only screen the User Account will have
        access to when they log in to the database. The log in screen for this
        User Account will be the same as for all User Accounts. However, once
        logged in, the User Account will only be able to see and use the Shop
        Floor Workbench. This option will override any other privileges which
        may have been assigned previously to the User Account. For more
        information on related privileges and other aspects of using and
        configuring the Shop Floor Workbench, please see <xref
        linkend="woTimeClock" />.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Module</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select an individual module to assign privileges for that
        module. Assign privileges to the User Account on a module-by-module
        basis. Select one module, assign the appropriate privileges, and then
        repeat for each subsequent module the User Account will need access
        to. All application modules are included in the list.</para>
        <tip>
          <para>You can dramatically speed up the process of adding new User
          Accounts by adding privileges by User Account role.</para>
        </tip>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>privileges</primary>
          <secondary>list of available</secondary>
        </indexterm>Available Privileges</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select appropriate privileges from the list of available
        privileges. Descriptions of each privilege will be shown. The
        privileges listed in this column represent the full range of
        privileges available for the specified module. The list of available
        privileges will change as different modules are specified. To grant
        privileges to a User Account, highlight an available privilege and
        then click the ADD button. The highlighted privilege will be added to
        the User Account's list of granted privileges. Double-clicking on a
        privilege will also move it to the granted privileges column. You can
        grant all privileges for a specified module by clicking on the ADD ALL
        button.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>privileges</primary>
          <secondary>list of granted</secondary>
        </indexterm>Granted Privileges</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays granted privileges for the specified User Account. To
        remove a User Account's granted privileges for a specified module,
        highlight a granted privilege and then click the REVOKE button. The
        highlighted privilege will be removed from the User Account's list of
        granted privileges. Double-clicking on a privilege will also remove it
        from the granted privileges column. You can remove all granted
        privileges for a specified module by clicking on the REVOKE ALL
        button.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>Many of the available privileges govern User Accounts' ability to
  either view or edit information. In some cases, however, it may be possible
  to perform editing tasks on screens where only view privileges have been
  granted. Take Item Sites, for example. Item Sites exist as their own objects
  with their own privileges independent of Items. When you edit an Item Site,
  you are not editing the Item itself, but an object associated with the Item.
  By contrast, when you edit Item notes, Item transformations, or Item
  aliases, you are editing things which belong exclusively and intrinsically
  to Item records. On the Item screen, there is an option to view/edit Item
  Sites for the Item. Let's imagine a User Account has privileges to edit Item
  Sites but to only view Items. Following this example, xTuple would allow the
  User Account to edit Item Sites from the Item record, even when in view
  mode.</para>
  <para>Here are some examples of independent objects which may be editable
  from a parent window, even in view mode:</para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>Sales Orders when viewing a Customer</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>Item Sources when viewing an Item</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>Contacts when viewing a CRM Account</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>Documents from any screen that supports them</para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>Conversely, here are examples of attributes that belong exclusively to
  and are editable only from a parent window in edit mode:</para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>Number</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>Name</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>Notes</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>Characteristics</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>Alarms</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>Comments</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>Transformations (Item)</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>Ship-to Addresses (Customer)</para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>The following buttons are located between the Available Privileges and
  Granted Privileges columns:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>ADD-&gt;</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a specific privilege in the available privileges
        column, then select this button to transfer the privilege to the
        granted privileges column. Double-clicking on an available privilege
        will also transfer it to the granted privileges column.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>ADD ALL-&gt;&gt;</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select this button to automatically transfer all available
        privileges to the granted privileges column.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>&lt;-REVOKE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a specific privilege in the granted privileges column,
        then select this button to remove the privilege from the granted
        privileges column. Double-clicking on a granted privilege will also
        remove it from the granted privileges column.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>&lt;&lt;-REVOKE ALL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select this button to automatically remove all granted
        privileges from the granted privileges column.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>ACCOUNT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to open the User Account's CRM Account.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>While you may assign individual privileges by User Account, you also
  have the option to add User Account privileges by User Account role. Adding
  User Account privileges by User Account role can dramatically speed up the
  process of adding new User Accounts. You can learn more about User Account
  roles here <xref linkend="groupsTitle" />.</para>
  <tip>
    <para>If individual User Account privileges appear to be disabled, that
    means the User Account is assigned to a User Account role. The only way to
    change individual privileges in this case is to remove the User Account
    from the role.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>To add User Account role privileges to a User Account profile, select
  the "Roles" tab, as shown in the following screen:</para>
  <para><mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/user_groupTab.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption>User Account Role Information</caption>
    </mediaobject>When adding User Account role privileges to a User Account
  profile, you are presented with the following options:</para>
  <tip>
    <para>Don't forget to select the ADD button when you have finished
    entering a User Account's information.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Available Roles</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select an available User Account role from the list. To grant
        User Account role privileges to a User Account, highlight an available
        role and then click the ADD button. The highlighted role will be added
        to the User Account's list of granted roles. Double-clicking on a role
        will also move it to the granted roles column.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Granted Roles</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays granted roles for the specified User Account. To remove
        a granted role from the User Account, highlight a granted role and
        then click the REVOKE button. The highlighted role will be removed
        from the User Account's list of granted roles. Double-clicking on a
        role will also remove it from the granted roles column.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>The following buttons are located between the Available Privileges and
  Granted Privileges columns:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>ADD-&gt;</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a specific role in the available roles column, then
        select this button to transfer the role to the granted roles column.
        Double-clicking on an available role will also transfer it to the
        granted roles column.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>&lt;-REVOKE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a specific role in the granted roles column, then
        select this button to remove the role from the granted roles column.
        Double-clicking on a granted role will also remove it from the granted
        roles column.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para role="standard">Multiple Site installations have the option of
  defining User Account site security. User Account site security provides a
  method for restricting a User Account to a single or multiple Sites. All of
  the screens in the application will honor this restriction. On the multiple
  site documents, such as Purchase Orders and Sales Orders, the User Account
  will be able to view restricted Sites, however, they will not be able to
  edit restricted Sites. To add User Account site security to a User Account
  profile, select the "Sites" tab, as shown in the following screen:</para>
  <para role="standard"><mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/user_siteTab.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption>User Account Site Security</caption>
    </mediaobject></para>
  <para role="standard">When adding User Account site security to a User
  Account profile, you are presented with the following options:</para>
  <para role="standard"><variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Grant Access to all Sites</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>Select this option if the User Account has full unrestricted
          access to all Sites defined in the application.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Grand Access only to Selected Sites</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>Select this option if the User Account has restricted access
          to the Sites defined in the application.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Available Sites</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>Select an available Site from the list. To grant access
          privileges to a User Account, highlight an available Site and then
          click the ADD button. The highlighted Site will be added to the User
          Account's list of granted Sites. Double-clicking on a Site will also
          move it to the granted Sites column.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Granted Sites</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>Displays granted Sites for the specified User Account. To
          remove a granted Site from the User Account, highlight a granted
          Site and then click the REVOKE button. The highlighted Site will be
          removed from the User Account's list of granted Sites.
          Double-clicking on a Site will also remove it from the granted Sites
          column.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist></para>
  <para role="standard">The following buttons are located between the
  Available Sites and Granted Sites columns:</para>
  <para role="standard"><variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>ADD-&gt;</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>Highlight a specific Site in the available Sites column, then
          select this button to transfer the Site to the granted Sites column.
          Double-clicking on an available Site will also transfer it to the
          granted Sites column.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>&lt;-REVOKE</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>Highlight a specific Site in the granted Sites column, then
          select this button to remove the Site from the granted Sites column.
          Double-clicking on a granted Site will also remove it from the
          granted Sites column.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist></para>
</section>
