<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2010 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<chapter>
  <title>System Administration</title>

  <para>Before you can begin processing Time and Expense Sheets, you must
  first set up the system with Expense Items and the appropriate User
  Permissions. These activities could be completed by a manager responsible
  for time and expense or dedicated information technology professional. In
  this chapter we'll cover the following topics:</para>

  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>Setting up Expense Items</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para>Configuring User Permissions</para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>

  <para>Once these configurations are complete, you can begin entering Time
  and Expense Sheets!</para>

  <section>
    <title>Expense Item Setup</title>

    <para>The processing of Sheets is handled by the Open Sheets screen. For
    this scenario, we'll need to review the open sheets to begin. To open a
    Sheet, follow these steps: Click on the Expense tab to view expense setup.
    The following screen will appear:</para>

    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Follow this path: <guimenuitem>Products &gt; Item &gt;
        List...</guimenuitem></para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select an existing Reference item, or create a new Reference
        item. For this example, we'll select the MILEAGE item.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>The following screen will appear:</para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>

    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/expenseItem.png" />
          </imageobject>

          <caption>Expense Item Setup</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>NOTE: The Expense tab is only available for Reference item
    types.</para>

    <para></para>

    <para>The Expense tab provides the ability to select a related Account or
    Expense Category.</para>

    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>ACCOUNT</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>Identify a General Ledger (G/L) Account to be used for
          expensing Purchasing Expenses to. This is an Expense Account. This
          Account will be used to create distributions when Vouchering expense
          lines. The account will be debited when the Voucher is
          posted.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term>EXPENSE CATEGORY</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>Identify an Expense Category to distribute Purchasing Expenses
          to. The Expense Category is used to define a set of General Ledger
          (G/L) Accounts related to an expense. This Account will be used to
          create distributions when Vouchering expense lines. The account will
          be debited when the Voucher is posted.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term>DELETE EXPENSE ITEM SETUP</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>Select this button to remove the relationship between the item
          and the specified General Ledger (G/L) Account or Expense
          Category.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Configuring User Permissions</title>

    <para>xTuple ERP has the powerful ability to manage user permissions,
    enabling you to allow or disallow access to various functional areas of
    the system. For example, a clerk may enter time and expense, while a
    manager may have the ability to Approve entries.</para>

    <para>There are several options available to you when managing system
    users. You can either A) assign individual permissions to users B) create
    preconfigured groups of permissions and assign individuals to these groups
    or C) a combination of A and B.</para>

    <para>The following path will get you to the screen for maintaining system
    users: <guimenuitem>System &gt; Maintain Users</guimenuitem>.</para>

    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/tepermissions.png" />
      </imageobject>

      <caption>List Users</caption>
    </mediaobject>

    <para>In this scenario, let's say we have a new employee whose permissions
    we want to review. To begin, follow these steps:</para>

    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight the user whose permissions we want to review</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select the EDIT button (or double-click on the user)</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>The following screen will appear:</para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>

    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/tepermissions2.png" />
      </imageobject>

      <caption>User Privileges</caption>
    </mediaobject>

    <para>As you can see, the basic user information—such as name and email
    address—has already been entered. The user has the ability to enter their
    own time and expenses, which you can see under the "Granted Privileges"
    section. We can add or remove privileges (by module) simply by selecting a
    specific privilege, and then choosing either the ADD or REVOKE button.
    .</para>

    <tip>
      <para>Use the ADD ALL and REVOKE ALL buttons to move all the privileges
      at once for the specified module</para>
    </tip>

    <para>The user role feature makes it easy to define logical sets of
    privileges defined according to standard job roles. The following path
    takes you to the screen for defining role privileges: <guimenuitem>System
    &gt; Maintain Roles</guimenuitem>. More information regarding Role setup,
    please consult the xTuple ERP <ulink
    url="http://www.xtuple.org/docs/reference-guide">Reference
    Guide</ulink>.</para>

    <para></para>

    <tip>
      <para>Time and Expense entry is closely integrated with Projects and
      Tasks. Users that are granted privileges to Time and Expense entry
      should also be granted MaintainProjects and ViewProjects in the CRM
      module.</para>
    </tip>
  </section>
</chapter>
