<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section role="openmfg">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>inventory</primary>
      <secondary>reservation utility for</secondary>
    </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>sales orders</primary>
      <secondary>reservation utility for</secondary>
    </indexterm>Allocate Reservations</title>
  <para>The Allocate Reservations utility enables you to allocate Inventory to
  batches of open Sales Orders. This can be a more efficient method for
  quickly making hard Inventory allocations, as compared to allocating
  Inventory one-at-a-time at the individual Sales Order Line Item level. You
  can allocate Inventory to batches of Sales Orders using the following
  screen:</para>
  <screenshot>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/allocateReservations.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption>Allocate Sales Order Reservations</caption>
    </mediaobject>
  </screenshot>
  <note>
    <para>Only Sales Order Line Items that can be completely reserved using
    actual Quantity on Hand will be affected when this utility is run. If a
    Line Item cannot be completely reserved, it will be skipped.</para>
  </note>
  <para>When allocating Inventory to batches of open Sales Orders, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Selected Customer</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to allocate Inventory to an individual Customer's open
        Sales Orders.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Customer #</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the Customer Number of the Customer whose open
              Sales Orders you want to allocate Inventory to. The browse
              button located to the right of the field leads to a searchable
              Customers list. You may also access this list using the keyboard
              shortcut "CTRL + L". Once a Customer Number is entered, the
              Customer name and billing address will display. Select the "?"
              or "$" symbol next to the browse button to view Customer
              information for the specified Customer. If a Customer's credit
              is "In Good Standing," the button will feature a black question
              mark ("?") icon. If the icon turns to an orange dollar sign
              ("$"), the Customer's credit Status is "On Credit Warning." A
              red dollar sign ("$") indicates the Customer's credit Status is
              "On Credit Hold."</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Selected Customer Ship-To</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the Customer Ship-To Address whose open Sales Orders you
        want to allocate Inventory to. This is an optional setting which may
        be used in conjunction with the "Selected Customer" setting. The
        Ship-To option gives you the added flexibility of being able to assign
        multiple Pricing Schedules to a single Customer based on separate
        Ship-To Addresses.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Selected Cust. Ship-To Pattern</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a Ship-To Address pattern to select a range of Ship-To
        Addresses for the selected Customer. Refine your search using Regular
        Expressions, as described in <xref linkend="Anchor77806" />.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Selected Customer Type</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the Customer Type you want to assign a Pricing Schedule
        to.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Customer Type Pattern</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a Customer Type pattern to select a range of Customer
        Types. Refine your search using Regular Expressions, as described in
        <xref linkend="Anchor77806" />.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Start Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Open Sales Orders having a due date on and after this date will
        have Inventory allocated to them. Start date and end date must be
        entered for calculation to proceed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>End Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Open Sales Orders having a due date on and before this date will
        have Inventory allocated to them. Start date and end date must be
        entered for calculation to proceed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Automatically Add to Packing List Batch</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to automatically add affected Sales Orders to the Packing
        List Batch.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen, returning you to the application
        desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>ALLOCATE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to run the batch allocation process, using the specified
        parameters.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>