<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section937769" role="openmfg">
  <title>Batch Manager</title>

  <para id="Para971523">The Batch Manager is an application which connects to
  one or more databases and waits for and then processes batched jobs that
  need to be run. These batched jobs are submitted from various places within
  the application. Often the type of jobs that can be submitted are jobs that
  either take long periods of time to run or jobs that you would want to run
  periodically at a given time. When you submit a job to the Batch Manager,
  you specify a time for the job to start running. This job and others like it
  are stored on the database, waiting for the Batch Manager to process them.
  You can see a list of jobs submitted to the Batch Manager by selecting the
  "Batch Manager" option from the System module.</para>

  <note>
    <para id="Para971480">For details on installing and setting up the Batch
    Manager at your site, please see the Batch Manager documentation available
    in the Downloads area of the xTuple community website.</para>
  </note>

  <para>To access the system interface to the Batch Manager, select the "Batch
  Manager" option. The following screen will appear:</para>

  <para id="Para938610"><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/Sys_batchMgrList.png" id="Graphic938608" />
        </imageobject>

        <caption id="Caption954099">Batch Manager</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <note>
    <para id="Para954176">When a report or other job is submitted to the Batch
    Manager with a scheduled time of ASAP, the Batch Manager sets the
    scheduled time to the current time. However, a job will not necessarily be
    run immediately if it is scheduled for the current time. Any pre-existing
    jobs with scheduled times prior to the current time must be completed
    first. In other words, ASAP jobs will not necessarily be run immediately.
    Previously scheduled jobs will be run first.</para>
  </note>

  <para id="Para954101">When managing Batch Items using the system interface
  to the Batch Manager, you are presented with the following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para938674">Submitted by</term>

      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e2acc">
        <para>Specify the user(s) whose Batch Items you want to
        display.</para>

        <para id="Para938750">Current User: Select to display Batch Items for
        the current user.</para>

        <para id="Para938754">All Users: Select to display Batch Items for all
        users.</para>

        <para id="Para938755">Selected User: Specify the user whose Batch
        Items you want to display.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para938678">Show Completed Actions</term>

      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e2b14">
        <para>Select to include completed Batch Items in the display.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para938679">Batch</term>

      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e2b5c">
        <para>Displays Batch Items using the specified parameters.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para938684">Automatically Update</term>

      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e2ba4">
        <para>Select to automatically update the display every five
        minutes.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para id="Para938697">To the far right of the screen, the following buttons
  are available:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para938709">CLOSE</term>

      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18eb400">
        <para>Closes the screen, returning you to the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para938699">RESCHEDULE</term>

      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18eb448">
        <para>Highlight a Batch Item and then select this button to reschedule
        the Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para938705">CANCEL</term>

      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18eb490">
        <para>Highlight a Batch Item and then select this button to remove the
        Item from the Batch Manager list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <xi:include href="batchItem.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
              xpointer="element(/1)" />
</section>