<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="bomItem">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>bills of materials</primary>
      <secondary>adding new components to</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>components</primary>
      <secondary>adding to BOMs</secondary>
    </indexterm>Bill of Materials Item</title>
  <para>To add new components to a Bill of Materials, select the NEW button.
  The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/bomItem.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption519345">Add New Bill of Materials Component
        Item</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <tip>
    <para>Bill of Materials component Items must have an Item Site defined to
    be valid.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>When adding a new component Item to a Bill of Materials, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the Item Number of the Item you want to add to the Bill of
        Materials.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Inventory Unit of Measure.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>effectivity</primary>
          <secondary>in BOMs</secondary>
        </indexterm>Effectivity</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the component's effectivity, using the following
        parameters:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Effective</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The system enables you to specify when a component can be
              used in a Bill of Materials. For example, the company's
              engineering department may be working on a new design for an
              existing Item--but that new design will not be available for use
              until a given date in the future. In this case, you can specify
              a future "effective" date to indicate when the component will be
              available for use.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Expires</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The system also enables you to specify when a component is
              planned to be obsoleted from (i.e., no longer used in) a Bill of
              Materials. As mentioned above, the company's engineering
              department may be working on a new design for an existing
              Item--but that new design will not be available for use until a
              given date in the future. In this case, the old component Item
              must be marked for "expiration" on the date when the new Item
              becomes effective. Setting this parameter will instruct the
              system to stop using the specified component on the date entered
              into this field.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. Per</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Per: Specify the quantity of the component Item required per
        Bill of Materials. This is a required field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Issue UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the Unit of Measure (UOM) you want to use when issuing
        Item quantity to Work Orders. Unless you specifiy an alternate UOM,
        the Inventory UOM will be used by default.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Scrap %</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Number entered should represent a percentage of material
        quantity that is additionally consumed as Scrap. This is a required
        field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>Using the "Create Child W/O at Parent W/O Explosion" option can
    greatly simplify the processing of Work Orders. If this option is not
    selected, child Work Orders will need to be created independently.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Create Child W/O at Parent W/O Explosion</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to create Work Orders for manufactured components when
        their parent Items are exploded. This option applies only to
        manufactured Items appearing as components on a Bill of Materials. If
        selected, a Work Order will automatically be created for the
        manufactured component when the parent Item is exploded.The impact on
        Work Order numbers will be visible. For example, a "-1" will be
        appended to the parent level Work Order and a "-2" to the child level
        Work Order--as in, #1061-1 and #1061-2. If this option is not
        selected, a child Work Order will not be created when the parent Item
        is exploded.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>The "Create Child W/O at Parent W/O Explosion" option will cause the
    creation of lower level Work Orders BOTH at Work Order explosion and also
    during the explosion that takes place during Master Production Scheduling
    (MPS) and Material Requirements Planning (MRP) runs.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>issue methods</primary>
          <secondary>within BOMs</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>bills of materials</primary>
          <secondary>issue methods for</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>push</primary>
          <secondary>issue method defined</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>pull</primary>
          <secondary>issue method defined</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>mixed</primary>
          <secondary>issue method defined</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>issue methods</primary>
          <secondary>push as</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>issue methods</primary>
          <secondary>pull as</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>issue methods</primary>
          <secondary>mixed as</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>issue methods</primary>
          <secondary>backflush as</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>backflush</primary>
          <secondary>as issue method</secondary>
        </indexterm>Issue Method</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Method: Select one of the available issue methods:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Push</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if you want the component Item to be issued to Work
              Orders by a specific material issue transaction. Because a
              specific material issue transaction must be used, "Push" Items
              enable you to monitor material usage variances. Standard issue
              quantities are not automatically backflushed to Work Orders, as
              is true for "Pull" Items. If a component Item uses the "Push"
              issue method, you must manually issue quantities to Work
              Orders.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Pull</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if you want the component Item to be issued to Work
              Orders by a material backflush. "Pull" Items are automatically
              issued to Work Orders when Work Order Production is posted.
              Using the "Pull" issue method saves time, since materials do not
              need to be manually issued to Work Orders by a specific material
              issue transaction.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Mixed</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if you want the component Item to take upon itself
              the issue method applied to it initially--that is, either "Pull"
              or "Push." Assigning the "Mixed" issue method to a component
              Item gives you the flexibility of deciding on a
              Work-Order-by-Work-Order basis whether you want to assign the
              "Pull" or "Push" method to the component Item.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>You can define a default issue method for new Bill of Materials
    component Items at the system level.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Used At</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify which Operation the component is used at. Using the
        browse button located to the right of the field, select a Bill of
        Operations sequence number to identify which Operation the component
        is used at. Linking a component with an Operation will have certain
        effects. First, when posting Operations, components that are linked to
        a given Operation will be backflushed if the issue method for the
        components is either "Pull" or "Mixed" and the Operation is set to
        Auto Issue components. Secondly, Work Order paperwork, such as
        Routings, will show the relationship between linked Work Order
        Material Requirements and Work Order Operations.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>If an Operation happens to have been expired on the current day, the
    Operation will still appear as an option when selecting "Used At"
    Operations. Once a day passes, however, the expired Operation will no
    longer appear as a "Used At" option on the BOM.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Schedule w/ W/O Operation</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to indicate that this component is not due until the Work
        Order Operation that will consume it is scheduled to begin. The
        scheduling of Operations is handled by the Execution Day indicator on
        the Bill of Operations item screen. For example, let's say we have an
        Operation with an Execution Day = 5. This means the Operation is
        scheduled to begin five days after the start date of the Work Order.
        Components scheduled with this Operation are due the day before the
        Operation starts--that is, on day four after the Work Order start
        date--to ensure they will be available when the Operation is scheduled
        to begin. If this option is not selected, then the component
        scheduling will be governed by the start and due dates set on the Work
        Order header.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>engineering change notices</primary>
          <secondary>in BOMs</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>ECN</primary>
          <see>engineering change notices</see>
        </indexterm>ECN #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the Engineering Change Notice Number--if applicable--for
        the specified component Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>BOM-defined Substitutions are the only Substitutes which may be
    implemented during Work Order processing. To substitute a component Item
    on a Work Order, use the "Substitute" option found on the right-click menu
    of the Maintain Work Order Material Requirements screen.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Substitutions</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Choose one of the following Item Substitution options:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>No Substitutions</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if no Substitutions exist for the component
              Item.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Item-Defined Substitutions</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if Substitutions are defined on the Item master for
              the component Item. Selecting this option will not cause
              Item-defined Substitutions to display here. You are simply
              indicating that Item master level Substitutions do exist.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>BOM-Defined Substitutions</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to define Item Substitutions at the Bill of
              Materials level.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>To ensure Availability, a BOM-defined Substitution must be located
    in the same Warehouse as the component Item it replaces. If the Substitute
    is located in a different Warehouse, it will not be available for
    substitution.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without inserting the component Item into the
        Bill of Materials, returning you to the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Inserts the component Item into the Bill of Materials,
        automatically assigning it a sequence number.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Opens screen for creating a new BOM-defined Substitution.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>EDIT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enables you to edit a BOM-defined Substitution. Highlight the
        Item Substitute you want to edit and then hit the EDIT button--or
        double-click on the Item Substitute to enter the edit mode. The edit
        screen is the same as that for creating a new Item Substitute--except
        that when editing, the fields will contain existing
        information.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>DELETE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight an Item Substitute and then select this button to
        remove the Item Substitute from the list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>substitutions</primary>
      <secondary>creating new bom-defined</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>bom-defined substitutions</primary>
      <secondary>creating new</secondary>
    </indexterm>To create a new BOM-defined Substitution, select the NEW
  button. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/itemSubstitute.png" id="Graphic638143" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption638146">Add New BOM-Defined Substitution</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When adding a new BOM-defined Substitution, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Number (Root Item)</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays Item Number of specified component Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Inventory Unit of Measure.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Number (Substitution)</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the Item Number of the Substitute Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Inventory Unit of Measure.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Substitute/Parent UOM Ratio</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Indicate the ratio between the Issue UOM for the specified BOM
        Item and the corresponding Issue UOM for the Substitute Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Ranking</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select a number using the arrow buttons, or manually enter a
        value up to a maximum of 9. Enter the specified ranking order of the
        Item Substitute. You may assign the same ranking to multiple Items, if
        this is appropriate.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CLOSE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen, returning you to the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Inserts the Item Substitution into the list of BOM-defined
        Substitutions.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To add Comments to a component Item, select the "Comments" tab at the
  bottom of the "Bill of Materials Item" screen. The following screen will
  appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/bomItem_Comments.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption638487">Add Comment to Bill of Materials Component
        Item</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Comments</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists the date Comment entered, Comment Type, user who
        entered Comment, and a content preview.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Opens screen for creating a new Comment.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>VIEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a Comment and then select this button to reach a
        read-only view of the Comment.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To create a new Comment, select the NEW button. The following screen
  will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/CommentNew.png" id="Graphic638427" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption638430">Create New Comment</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Comment Type</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify one of the following Comment Types from the drop-down
        list: ChangeLog or General.</para>
        <para>Comment Types are used to categorize Comments. Once you have
        specified a Comment Type, you may type your Comment in the main text
        area. The text area features word-wrapping and scroll-bar support for
        longer Comments.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without creating the Comment, returning you to
        the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Creates the Comment and adds it to the list of Comments.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>bills of materials</primary>
      <secondary>linking to BOOs</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>bills of operations</primary>
      <secondary>linking to BOMs</secondary>
    </indexterm>link a Bill of Materials component to a Bill of Operations
  Item, select the browse button located to the right of the "Used At" field.
  The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/booItemList.png" id="Graphic563019" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption519404">Bill of Operations Items</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When linking Bill of Materials components to Bill of Operations Items,
  you are presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The component Item selected on the Bill of Materials screen will
        display here.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Inventory Unit of Measure.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Bill of Operation Items</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists Bill of Operations Items for the same manufactured
        Item whose Bill of Materials is being specified. Highlight the
        Operation you want to link the Bill of Materials Item to, then hit the
        SELECT button.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without linking the Bill of Materials
        component to a Bill of Operations Item, returning you to the
        application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CLEAR</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Removes the link between a Bill of Materials component and a
        Bill of Operations Item if such a link has been made.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SELECT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Links the Bill of Operations Item to the specified Bill of
        Materials component. Highlight the desired Bill of Operations Item
        before selecting the SELECT button.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
