<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="booItem" role="openmfg">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>bills of operations</primary>
      <secondary>creating new operation in</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>operations</primary>
      <secondary>adding new to BOOs</secondary>
    </indexterm>Bill of Operations Item</title>
  <para>To add a new Operation to a Bill of Operations, select the NEW button.
  The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/PD_BOO_newBOOItem.png" id="Graphic563108" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption519546">Add New Operation to Bill of
        Operations</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When adding a new Operation to a Bill of Operations, you are presented
  with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Number</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b2938">
        <para>Displays Item Number specified in "Bill of Operations"
        screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>UOM</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b2980">
        <para>Inventory Unit of Measure.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Oper. Seq.#</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b29c8">
        <para>Displays Operation sequence number.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>execution days</primary>
          <secondary>in BOOs</secondary>
        </indexterm>Execution Day</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b9448">
        <para>Select a number using the arrow buttons, or manually enter a
        value up to a maximum of 99. This feature enables you to schedule Work
        Order Materials with Work Order Operations. For example, let's say we
        have an Operation with an Execution Day = 5. This means the Operation
        is scheduled to begin five days after the start date of the Work
        Order. Components scheduled with this Operation are due the day before
        the Operation starts--that is, on day four after the Work Order start
        date--to ensure they will be available when the Operation is scheduled
        to begin. If this option is not selected, then the component
        scheduling will be governed by the start and due dates set on the Work
        Order header. Based on the values entered for all listed Operations,
        whichever Execution Day value is the maximum, that value will be
        displayed as the production Lead Time for the Bill of
        Operations.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>effectivity</primary>
          <secondary>in BOOs</secondary>
        </indexterm>Effectivity</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b94d8">
        <para>Specify the operation's effectivity, using the following
        parameters:</para>
        <para>Effective: The system enables you to specify when an operation
        can be used in a Bill of Materials. For example, the company's
        engineering department may be working on a new design for an existing
        Item--but that new design will not be available for use until a given
        date in the future. In this case, you can specify the "effective" date
        when the component will be available for use.</para>
        <para>Expires: The system also enables you to specify when an
        operation is planned to be obsoleted from (i.e., no longer used in) a
        Bill of Materials. As mentioned above, the company's engineering
        department may be working on a new design for an existing Item--but
        that new design will not be available for use until a given date in
        the future. In this case, the old component Item must be marked for
        "expiration" on a given date. This expiration date will most likely
        coincide with the effective date of the replacement part. Setting this
        parameter will instruct the system to stop using the specified
        component on the date entered into this field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>Standard Operations are intended as initial templates used to set up
    Bill of Operations (BOO) Items. Any changes made to a Standard Operation
    will not automatically ripple throughout all your BOO Items that use the
    Standard Operation.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Standard Oper.</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b9568">
        <para>: Select a Standard Operation to use for the Operation, if
        any.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Description</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b95b0">
        <para>Enter a description to further identify the Operation.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Work Center</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b95f8">
        <para>Specify Work Center to be used for the specified
        Operation.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Tooling Reference</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b9640">
        <para>Use this field to briefly describe any tooling required for the
        Operation. For example, if you are making plastic products, the
        tooling reference might refer to the mold used to form the
        plastic.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>units of measure</primary>
          <secondary>in BOOs</secondary>
        </indexterm>Production UOM</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b96d0">
        <para>Select a Unit of Measure (UOM)--or enter a free-form UOM.
        Specify a UOM to be used optionally when Work Order Operations are
        posted for the specified Operation. Different Operations in a single
        Bill of Operations may use different Production UOMs. For example, if
        you are producing soup, you might mix the soup in one Operation using
        UOM = BATCH. But when canning the soup, the canning Operation might
        use UOM = CAN.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>When posting Work Order Operations, you are given the option to post
    Operations using Production UOMs or Inventory UOMs.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Production UOM/Inventory Ratio</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b9760">
        <para>This is the ratio that normalizes quantities to create a
        Production UOM for use when posting Work Order Operations. The ratio
        is set up in the same way as the Capacity/Inventory UOM ratio
        described in the <xref endterm="Anchor13555" linkend="Anchor13555" />
        FINDME "Enter New Item" section.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>Labor and <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>overhead</primary>
        <secondary>in BOOs</secondary>
      </indexterm>overhead Costs associated with setup and run times must be
    reported if they are to be tracked in the G/L and elsewhere. To report
    setup and run times, select the appropriate boxes in the Operations
    screen.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>setup time</primary>
          <secondary>in BOOs</secondary>
        </indexterm>Setup Time (min)</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b9880">
        <para>Amount entered represents the number of minutes required to set
        up the Work Center for the Operation.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Report Cost as (Setup Time)</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b98c8">
        <para>Specify whether you want to report Setup Costs as "Direct
        Labor," "Overhead," or "None." Specify the "None" option if you would
        do not want to track Setup Time as part of the Operation's
        Cost.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Report Setup Time</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b9910">
        <para>Select to report setup time. Must be selected for labor Costs
        associated with setup to be tracked in the G/L and elsewhere. If not
        selected, these Costs will not be reported.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>run time</primary>
          <secondary>in BOOs</secondary>
        </indexterm>Run Time (min)</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b99a0">
        <para>Amount entered represents the number of minutes required to run
        the Production UOM.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>per</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b99e8">
        <para>Specify the standard quantity that will be produced during a
        typical run-time period. The value entered here is equivalent to a run
        size, batch size, or Economic Order Quantity (EOQ) for this particular
        Operation. Because Work Order Operations roll into the Actual and
        Standard Costs for manufactured Items, you should specify a per
        quantity which accurately reflects your normal batch size for the
        Operation. Specifying a standard batch size helps ensure your
        Operations Costs are evenly distributed. For an example of how the
        batch size can help distribute Costs from Operations, see <xref
        endterm="Anchor15267" linkend="Anchor15267" /> FINDME Table
        5.1.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para><table id="Table646345">
      <title><anchor id="Anchor15267" role="Cross-Ref"
      xreflabel="15267: Figure: Figure 5.51:  Affect of Batch Size on Manufactured Item Costing" />
      Affect of Batch Size on Manufactured Item Costing</title>
      <tgroup cols="8">
        <thead>
          <row>
            <entry><para> Setup </para> <para> Time </para> <para> (Mins)
            </para></entry>
            <entry><para> Run </para> <para> Time </para> <para> (Mins)
            </para></entry>
            <entry><para> Units </para> <para> in Run </para> <para> ("per")
            </para></entry>
            <entry><para> Total </para> <para> Mins </para></entry>
            <entry><para> Mins </para> <para> Per </para></entry>
            <entry><para> Cost @ </para> <para> .10c per </para> <para> Min
            </para></entry>
            <entry><para> Material </para> <para> Cost </para> <para> per Unit
            </para></entry>
            <entry><para> Total Mfg. Cost per Run </para></entry>
          </row>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
          <row>
            <entry><para> 60 </para></entry>
            <entry><para> 100 </para></entry>
            <entry><para> 10 </para></entry>
            <entry><para> 160 </para></entry>
            <entry><para> 16 </para></entry>
            <entry><para> $1.60 </para></entry>
            <entry><para> $5.00 </para></entry>
            <entry><para> </para> <para> $66.00 </para></entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry><para> 60 </para></entry>
            <entry><para> 1000 </para></entry>
            <entry><para> 100 </para></entry>
            <entry><para> 1060 </para></entry>
            <entry><para> 10.6 </para></entry>
            <entry><para> $1.06 </para></entry>
            <entry><para> $5.00 </para></entry>
            <entry><para> </para> <para> $606.00 </para></entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry><para> 60 </para></entry>
            <entry><para> 10 </para></entry>
            <entry><para> 1 </para></entry>
            <entry><para> 70 </para></entry>
            <entry><para> 70 </para></entry>
            <entry><para> $7.00 </para></entry>
            <entry><para> $5.00 </para></entry>
            <entry><para> </para> <para> $12.00 </para></entry>
          </row>
        </tbody>
      </tgroup>
    </table></para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Report Cost as (Run Time)</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18ba03c">
        <para>Specify whether you want to report Setup Costs as "Direct
        Labor," "Overhead," or "None." Specify the "None" option if you would
        do not want to track Setup Time as part of the Operation's
        Cost.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Report Run Time</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to report run time</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Report Run Time</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to report run time. Must be selected for labor Costs
        associated with run time to be tracked in the G/L and elsewhere. If
        not selected, these Costs will not be reported.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>When Operations are posted, Inventory transaction records will be
    posted to the General Ledger if at least one of the Operations in the list
    of Work Order Operations has either or both of the Inventory handling
    options selected. If Items are backflushed at an Operation, select the
    "Auto. Issue Components" option. If finished Items are received into
    Inventory at an Operation, select the "Receive Inventory" option.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Receive Inventory at this Operation</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18ba114">
        <para>Select to indicate that the manufactured Item should be received
        into Inventory at this Operation. The manufactured Item will be
        received into Inventory via a Receive from Manufacturing (RM)
        transaction, when the Operation is posted.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>The "Receive Inventory" option may only be selected once per Bill of
    Operations. Finished Items may only be received into Inventory once in the
    Operations sequence.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Auto. Issue Components at this Operation</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18ba1a4">
        <para>Issue Components at this Operation: Select to automatically
        issue components used at this Operation. This setting will only affect
        component Items whose issue method is either "Pull" or "Mixed".
        Component Items using the "Push" issue method must be issued to Work
        Orders using a specific material issue transaction.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>May Overlap with Preceding Operation</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18ba1ec">
        <para>Select to allow the Operation to overlap with the preceding
        Operation. If selected, you are indicating that this Operation may be
        posted before the preceding Operation is complete. If not selected,
        the Operation may not be posted before the preceding Operation is
        complete.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>work in process</primary>
          <secondary>boo-defined locations for</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>bills of operations</primary>
          <secondary>wip locations and</secondary>
        </indexterm>WIP Location</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18bfeb4">
        <para>Select a work-in-process (WIP) Location.</para>
        <para>This is an optional selection which may be used for tracking the
        Warehouse Locations of finished goods Inventory as it moves through
        the manufacturing process. The feature applies only to top-level,
        Multiple Location Control (MLC) Items whose production is posted
        through Work Order Operations posting. If you choose to track finished
        MLC goods using this feature, then the WIP Location entered here is
        the Location where Inventory will be located when the preceding
        Operation for the Work Order is posted. A proceeding Operation must
        exist for the Location entered here to be used. If you do not wish to
        track WIP Locations for finished MLC goods, then you can ignore this
        option.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>throughput</primary>
          <secondary>at operation level</secondary>
        </indexterm>Throughput</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18bff44">
        <para>Indicates the number of units, in the given Item's Inventory
        UOM, that can be produced in a minute--and also the number of minutes
        that are required to produce 1 unit, expressed in the given Item's
        Inventory UOM.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18bffb0">
        <para>Closes the screen without inserting an Operation into the Bill
        of Operations, returning you to the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18bfff8">
        <para>Inserts the Operation into the Bill of Operations, automatically
        assigning it a sequence number.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To associate instructions with an Operation, select the "Instructions"
  tab. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/PD_BOO_BOOInstruct.png"
                     id="Graphic651101" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption651104">Operational Instructions</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When associating instructions with an Operation, you are presented
  with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Instructions</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c00d0">
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        instructions related to the Operation.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Use Fixed-Width Font</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c0118">
        <para>Select to display text in the "Instructions" field in
        fixed-width font. This is a useful feature for displaying tables,
        matrixes, and other format-driven texts.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>You may associate Images with an Operation, thereby making these
  Images available to be printed on Routings. To associate an Image with an
  Operation, select the "Images" tab. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/PD_BOO_BOOImages.png" id="Graphic651113" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption651116">Operation Images</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When associating Images with an Operation, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Images</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c01f0">
        <para>Display lists stored Images available for association with the
        specified Operation.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c025c">
        <para>Opens screen for adding a new Image to the list of Operation
        Images.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>EDIT</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c02a4">
        <para>Enables you to edit highlighted Operation Image definitions. The
        edit screen is the same as that for creating a new Operation Image
        definition--except that when editing, the fields will contain
        Operation Image information. Double-clicking on an Operation Image
        definition will also bring you to the editing screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>DELETE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c02ec">
        <para>Highlight an Operation Image definition and then select this
        button to remove the Item Image from the list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To add a new Image to the list of Operation Images, select the NEW
  button. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/PD_BOO_BOOImageNew.png"
                     id="Graphic651160" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption651163">Associate Image with Operation</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When adding a new Image to the list of Images associated with an
  Operation, you are presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Purpose</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c03c4">
        <para>Select one of the available purposes the Image might
        serve:</para>
        <para>Inventory Description: Select if the Operation Image describes
        Inventory.</para>
        <para>Product Description: Select if the Operation Image describes a
        Product.</para>
        <para>Engineering Reference: Select if the Operation Image serves as
        an engineering reference.</para>
        <para>Miscellaneous: Select if the Operation Image is a miscellaneous
        Image.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>An Operation may have multiple Images associated with it, but only
    one Image per purpose.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Images</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c0454">
        <para>Display lists stored Images available for association with the
        specified Operation.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CLOSE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c04c0">
        <para>Closes the screen, returning you to the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c0508">
        <para>Highlight an Image, then select the SAVE button to associate the
        Image with the specified Operation and purpose.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c0550">
        <para>Opens screen for adding a new Image to the master list of stored
        Images.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>images</primary>
      <secondary>adding new</secondary>
    </indexterm>To add a new Image to the master list of stored Images, select
  the NEW button. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/Sys_imageNew.png" id="Graphic651417" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption651420">Create New Image</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When adding a new Image to the master list of stored Images, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>File Name</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c0670">
        <para>Enter the physical directory location of the Image. The browse
        button enables you to search your system for the physical directory
        location of the Image file. Once you locate the file, simply select it
        to have it entered into the "File Name" field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Name</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c06b8">
        <para>Enter a unique name for the Image.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Description</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c0700">
        <para>Enter a description to further identify the Image.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c076c">
        <para>Closes the screen without adding a new Image to the master list
        of stored Images.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c07b4">
        <para>Creates the Image and adds it to the master list of stored
        Images.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>