<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section942568">
    <title>
      <anchor id="Anchor942567" role="Index" xreflabel="configuration:of g/l module"/> 
      <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>configuration</primary>

        <secondary>of g/l module</secondary>
      </indexterm>Configure G/L</title>

    <para id="Para964155">The system uses a multi-segment approach to defining
    General Ledger accounts. The various segments include the
    following:</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18bab6c">
        <para id="Para964156">Base Account Segment</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18bab90">
        <para id="Para964157">Company Segment</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18babb4">
        <para id="Para964158">Profit Center</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18babd8">
        <para id="Para964159">Subaccount</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <para id="Para964183">Depending on the parameters selected, the system
    will display General Ledger Account Numbers in the Profit Center-Account
    Number-Subaccount sequence. An example of this sequence would be
    001-11111-001.</para>

    <tip>
      <para id="Para964198">It is important to realize that the system does
      not utilize sub-Accounts in the same manner that some other packaged
      software does. It does not roll-up into the base account, but allows you
      to define "related" Accounts.</para>
    </tip>

    <para id="Para964166"/>

    <para id="Para942569">To configure the General Ledger (G/L) module, select
    the "Configure G/L" option. The following screen will appear:</para>

    <para id="Para942573">
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
               <imagedata fileref="images/Sys_configGL.png" id="Graphic942571"/>
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption942574">Configure G/L Module</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
   </para>

    <para id="Para942575">When configuring the G/L module, you are presented
    with the following options:</para>

    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para942868">Main Segment Size</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18bacd4">
            <para>Specify a main Segment size value between 3 and 10.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>

    <para id="Para964201"/>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18bad1c">
        <para id="Para964212">This setting defines how large the base Account
        Number portion should be. For example, if you specify "4" here, then
        your Account Numbers would probably range from 1000 through 9999.
        Similarly, if you specify "5" then your Account Number range would be
        from 10000 though 99999.</para>

        <para id="Para964215">Use Company Segment: Select to utilize a Company
        Segment by default. This is an optional setting.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18bad40">
        <para id="Para948929">Company Segment Size: If a Company Segment is
        being utilized, specify a Company Segment size value between 1 and
        10.</para>

        <para id="Para942743">Use Profit Centers: Select to utilize Profit
        Centers by default. This is an optional setting.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18bad64">
        <para id="Para964240">Profit Center Segment Size: If Profit Centers
        are being utilized, specify a Profit Center Segment size value between
        1 and 10. This segment is placed at the front end of the Account
        Number. Profit Centers are typically used to identify activity for
        different Warehouses.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18bad88">
        <para id="Para948946">Allow Free-Form Profit Centers: Select to allow
        free-form Profit Centers. Free-form means the values may be edited on
        the Account Number master. In other words, you will not be required to
        select a predetermined Profit Center value from the list. Using
        free-form Profit Centers can lead to inconsistent Account Numbers if
        not handled correctly.</para>

        <para id="Para942745">Use Subaccounts: Select to utilize Subaccounts
        by default. This is an optional setting.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18badac">
        <para id="Para942746">Subaccount Segment Size: If Subaccounts are
        being utilized, specify a Subaccount Segment size value between 1 and
        10. This segment is placed at the back end of the Account Number.
        Subaccounts are typically used to identify activity for similar types
        of accounts where detail is important.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18badd0">
        <para id="Para948955">Allow Free-Form Subaccounts: Select to allow
        free-form Subaccounts. Free-form means the values may be edited on the
        Account Number master. In other words, you will not be required to
        select a predetermined Subaccount value from the list. Using free-form
        Subaccounts can lead to inconsistent Account Numbers if not handled
        correctly.</para>

        <para id="Para958769">Enforce mandatory notes for Manual G/L Entries:
        Select if you want to require users to be required to enter Notes when
        posting simple or series manual Journal entries.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18badf4">
        <para id="Para958781">If this option is not selected, users will not
        be required to enter Notes when posting simple or series manual
        Journal entries.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <tip>
      <para id="Para961607">Try to avoid changing your Year End Equity Account
      if you have already used it to close a Fiscal Year. If you do change
      this Account after a fiscal year has been closed, be sure to consult
      your system administrator. The trial balance for the new Account will
      need to be manually updated.</para>
    </tip>

    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para973515">Allow manual entry of G/L Account Numbers</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18bae84">
            <para>Select to enable users to manually enter G/L Account Numbers
          wherever G/L Account Numbers may be entered.</para>

            <para id="Para973590">If not selected, users will be required to use
          a browse button to select G/L Account Numbers from a list.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>

    <note>
      <para id="Para973597">If Account Numbers have multiple segments
      separated by dashes, the dashes must be included when manually entering
      G/L Account Numbers. If the dashes are not included, the manual entry
      will not work.</para>
    </note>

    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para973523">Default Tax Authority</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18baf14">
            <para>Specify the default Tax Authority to be used when setting up
          Warehouses.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para958569">Retained Earnings, Year End Account</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18baf5c">
            <para>Select a valid General Ledger Account.</para>

            <para id="Para967578">This is an Equity Account. It will be credited
          if retained earnings are positive--and debited if retained earnings
          are negative. The retained earnings calculation occurs when a Fiscal
          Year is closed. Total Expenses for the year are subtracted from
          total Revenues, and the balance is transferred to the Year End
          Equity Account. The system then automatically resets the beginning
          balances for Revenue and Expense Accounts to $0 for the start of the
          new Fiscal Year.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>

    <note>
      <title>Note</title>

      <para id="Para967562">The Currency Gain/Loss Account is needed only for
      databases where multiple Currencies are used.</para>
    </note>

    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para967539">Currency Gain/Loss Account</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c3800">
            <para>Select a valid General Ledger Account.</para>

            <para id="Para967540">This is an Expense Account. It will debited
          for Currency gains and credited for Currency losses arising from
          fluctuating Exchange Rates. Currency gains/losses may be recognized
          at the following points: 1) When posting a Cash Receipt applied to
          an Invoice; 2) when posting an A/P Check applied to a Voucher; 3)
          when applying an A/R Misc. Credit Memo to an Invoice; and 4) when
          applying an A/P Misc. Credit Memo to a Voucher. In each case, the
          gain or loss arises when the Exchange Rate used for the Apply-To
          document differs from the Exchange Rate used for the
          application.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para967115">G/L Series Discrepancy Account</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c3848">
            <para>Select a valid General Ledger Account.</para>

            <para id="Para967116">This is an Expense Account. It will be debited
          or credited if rounding errors cause discrepancies when multiple
          line item (i.e., series) transactions are posted to the General
          Ledger. If used, the amounts posted to this Account will be
          miniscule, as rounding errors are fractional by nature.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para967123">Meaning of Currency Exchange Rates</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c3890">
            <para>Specify how you want Exchange Rates to be implemented and also
          displayed on the Exchange Rates master list:</para>

            <para id="Para967127">Base x Exchange Rate = Foreign: If selected,
          this equation will be used.</para>

            <para id="Para967131">Foreign x Exchange Rate = Base: If selected,
          this equation will be used.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>

    <para id="Para967435">To the far right of the screen, the following
    buttons are available:</para>

    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para942749">CANCEL</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c38fc">
            <para>Cancels any configuration settings, returning you to the
          application desktop.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para942750">SAVE</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c3944">
            <para>Saves the configuration settings, returning you to the
          application desktop.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
  </section>