<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Anchor19758">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>configuration</primary>
      <secondary>of inventory module</secondary>
    </indexterm>Configure Inventory</title>
  <para>To configure the Inventory module, select the "Configure Inventory"
  option. The following screen will appear</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/configureIM.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Configure Inventory Module</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When configuring the Inventory module, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>event fences</primary>
          <secondary>default for item sites</secondary>
        </indexterm>Defaults</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify a default Event Fence:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Event Fence</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select a value between 0 and 999 using the arrow buttons
              located to the right of the field. Indicates the Event Fence
              value that will appear by default whenever a new Item Site is
              created. The value is measured in days.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Post Item Site Changes to the Change Log</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to post to the Change Log any changes made to Item Site
        masters.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Post Warehouse Changes to the Change Log</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to post to the Change Log any changes made to Warehouse
        masters.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="openmfg">
      <term>Enable Multiple Warehouses</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to allow more than one Warehouse to be entered in the
        system. If multiple Warehouses are not enabled, your system will be
        single Warehouse only. Users will be prevented from creating more than
        one Warehouse. If your system has multiple Warehouses defined, this
        option will be hidden.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="openmfg">
      <term>Transfer Order # Generation</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>If multiple Warehouses are enabled, select one of the available
        Transfer Order Number generation methods:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Automatic</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Transfer Order Numbers will be automatically incremented
              by 1 each time a new Transfer Order is created. These
              automatically-generated numbers may not be edited. They are
              read-only.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Manual</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Transfer Order Numbers must be entered manually whenever
              you create a new Transfer Order.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Automatic, Allow Override</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Transfer Order Numbers will be automatically generated and
              incremented, as under the "Automatic" option described above.
              However, this option also allows you to manually override the
              Transfer Order Number at the time of Transfer Order
              creation.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="openmfg">
      <term>Next #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The next sequentially available Transfer Order Number will
        display here. You may change the number--creating a new basis for the
        next Transfer Order Number--by typing the new number into this field.
        Any changes you make here will be reflected the next time a new
        Transfer Order is created.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="openmfg">
      <term>Default Transit Warehouse</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>If multiple Warehouses are enabled, specify the default Transit
        Warehouse. The specified Warehouse will be pre-selected by default
        whenever Transfer Orders are entered.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="openmfg">
      <term>Enable Lot/Serial Control</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to enable Lot/Serial tracking capability in the system.
        If not selected, users will be prevented from creating Item Sites
        having either the Lot or Serial control method. Without the ability to
        create Lot/Serial Item Sites, the Lot/Serial tracking capability is
        disabled. If your system has Lot/Serial Item Sites defined, this
        option will be hidden.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>count tags</primary>
          <secondary>count slip discrepancies and</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>count slips</primary>
          <secondary>count tag discrepancies and</secondary>
        </indexterm>When Count Tag Qty. exceeds Slip Qty</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select one of the following options for handling discrepancies
        in count quantities:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Post Difference to Default Location, if any</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to post excess Count Tag quantity to an Item's
              default location if the Item's Count Tag quantity exceeds its
              Count Slip quantity. Applies only if a default location has been
              defined for the Item. Default locations are defined for an Item
              in the Item Site record.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Do Not Post Count Tag</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to prevent Count Tag quantity from being posted if
              it exceeds the Item's Count Slip quantity.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>By default, the system allows only one unposted Count Tag per Item
    Site. If an unposted Count Tag already exists for an Item Site, then an
    additional duplicate Count Tag may not be added.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>count slips</primary>
          <secondary>auditing of</secondary>
        </indexterm>Count Slip # Auditing</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select one of the following Count Slip number auditing
        methods:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>No Slip # Checks, allow Duplications</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Allows any Count Slip numbers to be used. Duplicate Count
              Slip numbers will also be allowed.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Disallow Unposted Slip # Duplications within a
            Warehouse</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Prevents duplicate "Unposted" Count Slip numbers from
              existing within a given Warehouse. However, duplicate "Unposted"
              Count Slip numbers may exist within multiple Warehouses.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Disallow All Unposted Slip # Duplications</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Prevents duplicate "Unposted" Count Slip numbers from
              existing within multiple Warehouses.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Disallow All Slip # Duplications within a Warehouse</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Prevents duplicate Count Slip numbers from existing within
              a given Warehouse. However, duplicate Count Slip numbers may
              exist within multiple Warehouses.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Disallow All Slip # Duplications</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Prevents duplicate Count Slip Numbers from existing within
              multiple Warehouses.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To configure the Inventory Shipping and Receiving options, select the
  "Shipping and Receiving" tab. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <screenshot>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/configureIM_tab_2.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption>Configure Shipping and Receiving</caption>
    </mediaobject>
  </screenshot>
  <para>When configuring Shipping and Receiving, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Shipment # Generation</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>By default, Shipment Numbers are generated automatically.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Next #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the next Shipment Number to be used. The system assigns
        Shipment Numbers to Sales Order Line Item quantities when stock is
        issued to Shipping. All stock at Shipping for an individual Sales
        Order is assigned the same Shipment Number. If no stock is already at
        Shipping, then a new Shipment Number will be used.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Disallow P/O Receipt of Qty greater than ordered</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to ensure the maximum receiving quantity does not exceed
        the quantity ordered. If selected, the system will prevent users from
        receiving more Purchase Order Line Item quantity than the quantity
        ordered. Not selecting this option means users will be allowed to
        receive quantity in excess of the quantity ordered.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Warn if P/O Receipt Qty differs from receivable Qty</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to generate a warning message if the entered quantity to
        receive does not match the quantity remaining to be received. The
        warning message will alert users that a difference exists. However, it
        will not prevent users from continuing.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>By the following amount:</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the percentage difference between Receipt quantity
              and receivable quantity which when reached should trigger a
              warning message.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Default Shipping Form Copies</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Indicate the number of Shipping Form copies you want to print by
        default:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term># of Copies</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the number of miscellaneous copies you want to
              print. Information about the specified copies will display
              below. To add a Watermark, double-click on a copy line.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Cancels any configuration settings, returning you to the
        application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Saves the configuration settings, returning you to the
        application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>