<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
  <section id="Section923250">
    <title><anchor id="Anchor76275" role="Cross-Ref"
    xreflabel="76275: Heading2: Configure S/O" /> <anchor id="Anchor932292"
    role="Index" xreflabel="configuration:of s/o module" /> <indexterm
        significance="normal" zone="Anchor932292">
        <primary>configuration</primary>

        <secondary>of s/o module</secondary>
      </indexterm>Configure S/O</title>

    <para id="Para519161">To configure the Sales Order (S/O) module, select
    the "Configure S/O" option. The following screen will appear:</para>

    <para id="Para519165"><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Sys_configSO.png" id="Graphic522127" />
          </imageobject>

          <caption id="Caption519166">General S/O Configuration
          Options</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>

    <para id="Para519167">When configuring the S/O module, you are presented
    with the following options:</para>

    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para519168"><anchor id="Anchor934406" role="Index"
        xreflabel="sales orders:numbering of" /> <indexterm
            significance="normal" zone="Anchor934406">
            <primary>sales orders</primary>

            <secondary>numbering of</secondary>
          </indexterm>Sales Order # Generation</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18a62a8">
          <para>Select one of the available Sales Order Number generation
          methods:</para>

          <para id="Para519169">Automatic - Sales Order Numbers will be
          automatically incremented by 1 each time a new Sales Order is
          created. These automatically-generated numbers may not be edited.
          They are read-only.</para>

          <para id="Para519170">Manual - Sales Order Numbers must be entered
          manually whenever you create a new Sales Order.</para>

          <para id="Para519171">Automatic, Allow Override - Sales Order
          Numbers will be automatically generated and incremented, as under
          the "Automatic" option described above. However, this option also
          allows you to manually override the Sales Order Number at the time
          of Sales Order creation.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para519175">Next #</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18a62f0">
          <para>The next sequentially available Sales Order Number will
          display here. You may change the number--creating a new basis for
          the next Sales Order Number--by typing the new number into this
          field. Any changes you make here will be reflected the next time a
          new Sales Order is created in the S/O module.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para519177"><anchor id="Anchor934407" role="Index"
        xreflabel="quotes:numbering of" /> <indexterm significance="normal"
            zone="Anchor934407">
            <primary>quotes</primary>

            <secondary>numbering of</secondary>
          </indexterm>Quote # Generation</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18a6380">
          <para>Select one of the available Quote Number generation
          methods:</para>

          <para id="Para519178">Manual - Quote Numbers must be entered
          manually whenever you create a new Quote.</para>

          <para id="Para519179">Automatic, Use Quote #'s - Quote Numbers will
          be automatically incremented by 1 each time a new Quote is created.
          These automatically-generated numbers may not be edited. They are
          read-only.</para>

          <para id="Para519180">Automatic, Use Quote #"s, Allow Override -
          Quote Numbers will be automatically generated and incremented, as
          under the "Automatic" option described above. However, this option
          also allows you to manually override the Quote Number at the time of
          Quote creation.</para>

          <para id="Para917128">Automatic, Use S/O #'s - Quote Numbers will be
          automatically incremented by 1 each time a new Quote is created,
          using the same number generation method specified for the creation
          of Sales Order Numbers. These automatically-generated numbers may
          not be edited. They are read-only.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para917132">Next #</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18a63c8">
          <para>The next sequentially available Quote Number will display
          here. You may change the number--creating a new basis for the next
          Quote Number--by typing the new number into this field. Any changes
          you make here will be reflected the next time a new Quote is created
          in the S/O module.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para519187"><anchor id="Anchor934408" role="Index"
        xreflabel="credit memos:numbering of" /> <indexterm
            significance="normal" zone="Anchor934408">
            <primary>credit memos</primary>

            <secondary>numbering of</secondary>
          </indexterm>Credit Memo # Generation</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b1848">
          <para>Select one of the available Credit Memo Number generation
          methods:</para>

          <para id="Para519188">Manual - Credit Memo Numbers must be entered
          manually whenever you create a new Credit Memo.</para>

          <para id="Para519189">Automatic, Use C/M #'s - Credit Memo Numbers
          will be automatically incremented by 1 each time you issue a new
          Credit Memo. These automatically-generated numbers may not be
          edited. They are read-only.</para>

          <para id="Para519190">Automatic, Use C/M #"s, Allow Override -
          Credit Memo Numbers will be automatically generated and incremented,
          as under the "Automatic" option described above. However, this
          option also allows you to manually override the Credit Memo Number
          at the time of Credit Memo creation.</para>

          <para id="Para519191">Automatic, Use S/O #'s - Credit Memo Numbers
          will be automatically incremented by 1 each time a new Credit Memo
          is created, using the same number generation method specified for
          the creation of Sales Order Numbers. These automatically-generated
          numbers may not be edited. They are read-only.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para519195">Next #</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b1890">
          <para>The next sequentially available Credit Memo Number will
          display here. You may change the number--creating a new basis for
          the next Credit Memo Number--by typing the new number into this
          field. Any changes you make here will be reflected the next time you
          issue a new Credit Memo within the S/O module.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para519197"><anchor id="Anchor934409" role="Index"
        xreflabel="invoices:numbering of" /> <indexterm significance="normal"
            zone="Anchor934409">
            <primary>invoices</primary>

            <secondary>numbering of</secondary>
          </indexterm>Invoice # Generation</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b1920">
          <para>By default, Invoice Numbers are automatically generated. This
          system setting cannot be changed.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para519204">Next #</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b1968">
          <para>The next sequentially available Invoice Number will display
          here. You may change the number--creating a new basis for the next
          Invoice Number--by typing the new number into this field. Any
          changes you make here will be reflected the next time you create a
          new Invoice within the S/O module.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>

    <para id="Para961816">To establish general settings for the S/O module,
    select the "General" tab. The following options will appear:</para>

    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para917201"><anchor id="Anchor934410" role="Index"
        xreflabel="sales orders:discount defaults for" /> <indexterm
            significance="normal" zone="Anchor934410">
            <primary>sales orders</primary>

            <secondary>discount defaults for</secondary>
          </indexterm>Allow Price Discounts</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b1a1c">
          <para>Check this option to allow pricing discounts for select
          customers.</para>

          <para id="Para924399">This option instructs the system to verify
          whether any Pricing Discounts have been established for a Customer,
          prior to calculating the Line Item Price for of an Item within a
          Sales Order. If this option is unchecked, then the system will apply
          the full List Price for an Item within a Sales Order.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para917202">Allow ASAP Schedule Dates</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b1a64">
          <para>Selecting this option will cause Sales Order Line Items to
          become immediately past due if no schedule date is entered.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para948823">Post Customer Changes to the Change Log</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b1aac">
          <para>Select to post to the Change Log any changes made to Customer
          masters.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para948816">Post Sales Order Changes to the Change
        Log</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b1af4">
          <para>Select to post to the Change Log any changes made to Sales
          Orders.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para953457">Restrict Credit Memos to Items that appear on
        their Apply-To Document</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b1b3c">
          <para>Select if you want to restrict Credit Memo Items to their
          Apply-To Document.</para>

          <para id="Para953461">Selecting this option narrows the Credit Memo
          Item selection process to only those Items which appeared on the
          Invoice the Credit Memo is being applied to. If not selected, a sold
          Item master list will appear instead when selecting Credit Memo
          Items for Credit Memos applied to a specific Invoice. This setting
          has no bearing on unapplied Credit Memos.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para958801">Automatically check "Select for Billing" option
        on Ship Order screen</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b1b84">
          <para>Select if you want the "Select for Billing" option to be
          selected by default whenever you ship Sales Order Line Items.</para>

          <para id="Para958812">Selecting this option reduces steps in the
          billing process. Specifically, if an Order is selected for billing
          when it is shipped, you do not then have to take the extra step of
          independently selecting the Order for billing. This can save time
          and also ensure your shipped Orders are selected for billing at the
          time of shipment.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para958838">Always show "Save and Add to Packing List"
        button on Sales Order screen</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b1bcc">
          <para>Select if you want the SAVE AND ADD TO PACKING LIST button to
          always be displayed on the Sales Order header screen.</para>

          <para id="Para958842">If this option is not selected, the SAVE AND
          ADD TO PACKING LIST button will only be displayed for newly-entered
          Sales Orders which have not yet been saved.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para959014">Disallow Override of Sales Price on Sales Order
        Entry</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b1c14">
          <para>Select to prevent all users from overriding the Sales Price
          when entering Sales Order Line Items.</para>

          <para id="Para959023">This is a system-wide setting, affecting all
          users. Do not select this option if you want to selectively prevent
          users from overriding Sales Prices. Individual users may be granted
          the ability to override Sales Prices, use the S/O module's
          OverridePrice privilege.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para962053">Automatically Allocate Credit Memos to New Sales
        Order on Save</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b1c5c">
          <para>Select to have open Credit Memos for a Customer automatically
          allocated to any new Sales Orders entered for that Customer.</para>

          <para id="Para962380">This functionality helps reduce Customer
          credit balances by ensuring that Customer credits are consumed when
          new Sales Orders are entered. Any available, open Credit Memos are
          eligible for allocation. The allocation of available Credit Memos
          occurs only once--when a Sales Order is saved for the first time.
          Subsequent saves will not result in additional allocations. Credit
          Memos which have been allocated to a Sales Order are applied at the
          point when the Invoice resulting from the Sales Order is posted.
          Once the full balance of a Credit Memo has been applied, the Credit
          Memo is then closed. The printed Invoice the Customer receives will
          indicate whether Credit Memos have been applied. In addition, the
          total due from the Customer will be automatically adjusted to
          reflect any applied credits.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>

    <note>
      <para id="Para962390">The allocation of available Credit Memos occurs
      only once--when a Sales Order is saved for the first time. Subsequent
      saves will not result in additional allocations.</para>
    </note>

    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para961846">Hide Misc. Charges on Sales Order screen</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b1cec">
          <para>Select to hide all fields related to Miscellaneous Charges on
          the Sales Order Line Item tab.</para>

          <para id="Para962036">If your site does not use Misc. Charges when
          entering Sales Orders, it may make sense to hide this functionality
          to avoid confusion.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para961899">Enable Shipping interface from Sales Order
        screen</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b1d34">
          <para>Select to enable the performance of limited Shipping
          functionality from the Sales Order header.</para>

          <para id="Para962154">If selected, users will be able to issue Stock
          to Shipping and also return Stock from Shipping directly from the
          Sales Order header. If not selected, these Shipping options will not
          be available on the Sales Order header.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para977157">Check Print S/O on Save by Default</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b1d7c">
          <para>Select to prompt users to print Sales Orders whenever Sales
          Orders are saved.</para>

          <para id="Para977164">If selected, users will be presented with a
          Sales Order print screen whenever a Sales Order is saved. To bypass
          this feature, do not select this option.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para962155">Pricing on Editing Line Items</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b1dc4">
          <para>Select one of the following as your preferred response when
          users change Sales Order Line Item quantity on EDIT:</para>

          <para id="Para971346">Update Price on Line Item Edit: If selected,
          the system will automatically update the Net Unit Price for the Line
          Item, adjusting to accommodate the newly-entered quantity.</para>

          <para id="Para971352">Prompt before Updating Price: If selected, the
          system will ask users if they want to update the Net Unit Price
          (YES/NO). If they answer "YES" because they do want to update the
          Price, then they will have to manually make the Price
          adjustment.</para>

          <para id="Para971353">Do not Update Price on Line Edit: If selected,
          the Net Unit Price will not be changed when Line Item quantity is
          changed on EDIT--and users will not be prompted to consider changing
          the Price.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>

    <note>
      <para id="Para971372">The Sales Order Line Item pricing options apply
      only when editing Line Item quantity.</para>
    </note>

    <para id="Para971368">To the far right of the screen, the following
    buttons are available:</para>

    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para962156">CANCEL</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b1e54">
          <para>Cancels any configuration settings, returning you to the
          application desktop.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para913767">SAVE</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b1e9c">
          <para>Saves the configuration settings, returning you to the
          application desktop.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>

    <para id="Para962212">To establish Invoice and Credit Memo settings,
    select the "Invoice" tab. The following screen will appear:</para>

    <para id="Para961972"><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Sys_configSOInvoice.png"
                       id="Graphic961970" />
          </imageobject>

          <caption id="Caption961973">Invoice Configuration Options</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>

    <para id="Para961965">When establishing Invoice and Credit Memo settings,
    you are presented with the following options:</para>

    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para961966">Invoice Date Source</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b1f74">
          <para>Select one of the following Invoice date options:</para>

          <para id="Para961863">Shipped Date: If selected, the Invoice date on
          the Invoice header will be the same date as the Sales Order ship
          date.</para>

          <para id="Para961864">Scheduled Date: If selected, the Invoice date
          on the Invoice header will be the same date as the Sales Order
          scheduled date.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para961865">Default Invoice Copies</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b1fbc">
          <para>Indicate how you want invoice copies to print.</para>

          <para id="Para961866"># of Copies: Indicate the number of copies you
          want to print. Information about the specified copies will display
          below.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para961867">Default Credit Memo Copies</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b2004">
          <para>Indicate how you want credit memo copies to print.</para>

          <para id="Para961868"># of Copies: Indicate the number of copies you
          want to print. Information about the specified copies will display
          below.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>

    <para id="Para962239">To establish default settings to be used whenever
    new Customers are entered, select the "Customer Defaults" tab. The
    following screen will appear:</para>

    <para id="Para962010"><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Sys_configSODefaults.png"
                       id="Graphic962009" />
          </imageobject>

          <caption id="Caption962011">Default Customer Configuration
          Options</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>

    <para id="Para962005">When establishing Customer master default settings,
    you are presented with the following options:</para>

    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para962325">Shipping Form</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b20dc">
          <para>Specify a default Shipping Form.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para961872">Ship Via</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b2124">
          <para>Specify a default Ship Via.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para961873">Balance Method</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b216c">
          <para>Specify a default procedure for handling cash receipts from
          Customers.</para>

          <para id="Para962315">This notation is informational only. Balance
          Forward: Select to apply cash receipts to the Customer's current
          balance due.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para962345">Customer Type</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b21b4">
          <para>Specify a default Customer Type to be used whenever new
          Customers are created.</para>

          <para id="Para962319">The default Customer Type may be overridden by
          users having the appropriate privileges.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para961878">Credit Limit</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b21fc">
          <para>Specify the default credit limit to be used for all
          Customers.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para961882">Credit Rating</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b2244">
          <para>Specify the default credit rating to be used for all
          Customers.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para961883">Accepts Partial Shipments</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b228c">
          <para>Select to indicate Customers accept partial shipments by
          default.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para962349">Accepts Backorders</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b22d4">
          <para>Select to indicate Customers accept backorders by
          default.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para961884">Allow Free Form Ship-Tos</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b231c">
          <para>Select to indicate Customers allow free-form Ship-Tos by
          default. This default appears on the Customer master.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
  </section>