<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="configurePO">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>configuration</primary>
      <secondary>of purchase module</secondary>
    </indexterm>Configure Purchase</title>
  <para>To configure the Purchase module, select the "Configure Purchase"
  option. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/configurePO.png" id="Graphic924091" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption924094">Configure Purchase Module</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When configuring the Purchase module, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>purchase orders</primary>
          <secondary>numbering of</secondary>
        </indexterm>Order # Generation</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify one of the available Purchase Order Number generation
        methods:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Automatic</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Purchase Order Numbers will be automatically incremented
              by 1 each time a new Purchase Order is created. These
              automatically-generated numbers may not be edited. They are
              read-only.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Manual</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Purchase Order Numbers must be entered manually whenever
              you create a new Purchase Order.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Automatic, Allow Override</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Purchase Order Numbers will be automatically generated and
              incremented, as under the "Automatic" option described above.
              However, this option also allows you to manually override the
              Purchase Order Number at the time of Purchase Order
              creation.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Next #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The next sequentially available Purchase Order Number will
        display here. You may change the number--creating a new basis for the
        next Purchase Order Number--by typing the new number into this field.
        Any changes you make here will be reflected the next time a new
        Purchase Order is created in the P/O module.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>vouchers</primary>
          <secondary>numbering of</secondary>
        </indexterm>Voucher # Generation</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>By default, Voucher Numbers are automatically generated. This
        system setting cannot be changed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Next #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The next sequentially available Voucher Number will display
        here. You may change the number--creating a new basis for the next
        Voucher Number--by typing the new number into this field. Any changes
        you make here will be reflected the next time a new Voucher is created
        in the P/O module.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>purchase requests</primary>
          <secondary>numbering of</secondary>
        </indexterm>P/R # Generation</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select one of the available Purchase Request Number generation
        methods:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Automatic</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Purchase Request Numbers will be automatically incremented
              by 1 each time a new Purchase Request is created. These
              automatically-generated numbers may not be edited. They are
              read-only.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Manual</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Purchase Request Numbers must be entered manually whenever
              you create a new Purchase Order.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Automatic, Allow Override</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Purchase Request Numbers will be automatically generated
              and incremented, as under the "Automatic" option described
              above. However, this option also allows you to manually override
              the Purchase Request Number at the time of Purchase Request
              creation.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Next #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The next sequentially available Purchase Request Number will
        display here. You may change the number--creating a new basis for the
        next Purchase Request Number--by typing the new number into this
        field. Any changes you make here will be reflected the next time you
        issue a new Purchase Request within the P/O module.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Default P/O Copies</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Indicate the copies you want to print.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Vendor</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to print one Vendor copy.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Internal</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to print a specified number of internal copies.
              When you select this option, the "# of Copies" field will be
              enabled.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term># of Copies</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the number of copies you want to print.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Post P/O Changes to the Change Log</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to post to the Change Log any changes made to Purchase
        Orders.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Post Vendor Changes to the Change Log</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to post to the Change Log any changes made to Vendor
        masters.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Use Earliest Avail. as Due Date for P/O Item</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to use Item Source Earliest Available dates as the
        default due date when entering manual Purchase Order Line Items. If
        not selected, the due date field will be left blank when entering
        Purchase Order Line Items--requiring users to enter the date manually.
        Earliest Available dates are determined by adding Item Source Lead
        Times to the current date.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>The "Use Earliest Avail." option applies only to Purchase Orders
    entered manually. This option does not impact the scheduling of POs
    generated from MRP Planned Orders.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Prevent P/O Items when no Std. Cost Exists</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you want to prevent users from entering Purchase Order
        Line Items for Items which have no Standard Cost. If selected, users
        will be shown a message stating the problem. The solution is to add
        Standard Cost to the Item(s) in question.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Check Print P/O on Save by Default</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to prompt users to print Purchase Orders whenever
        Purchase Orders are saved. If selected, users will be presented with a
        Purchase Order print screen whenever a Purchase Order is saved. To
        bypass this feature, do not select this option.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>vendors</primary>
          <secondary>default settings for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Vendor Defaults</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the following Vendor defaults:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Ship Via</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the default Ship Via to be used for Purchase
              Orders.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Cancels any configuration settings, returning you to the
        application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Saves the configuration settings, returning you to the
        application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
