<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section923250">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>configuration</primary>
      <secondary>of sales module</secondary>
    </indexterm>Configure Sales</title>
  <para>To configure the Sales module, select the "Configure Sales" option.
  The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/configureSO.png"
                     id="configureSO.imagedata" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="configureSO.caption">General Sales Configuration
        Options</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When configuring the S/O module, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales orders</primary>
          <secondary>numbering of</secondary>
        </indexterm>Sales Order # Generation</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select one of the available Sales Order Number generation
        methods:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Automatic</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Sales Order Numbers will be automatically incremented by 1
              each time a new Sales Order is created. These
              automatically-generated numbers may not be edited. They are
              read-only.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Manual</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Sales Order Numbers must be entered manually whenever you
              create a new Sales Order.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Automatic, Allow Override</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Sales Order Numbers will be automatically generated and
              incremented, as under the "Automatic" option described above.
              However, this option also allows you to manually override the
              Sales Order Number at the time of Sales Order creation.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Next #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The next sequentially available Sales Order Number will display
        here. You may change the number--creating a new basis for the next
        Sales Order Number--by typing the new number into this field. Any
        changes you make here will be reflected the next time a new Sales
        Order is created in the S/O module.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>quotes</primary>
          <secondary>numbering of</secondary>
        </indexterm>Quote # Generation</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select one of the available Quote Number generation
        methods:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Manual</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Quote Numbers must be entered manually whenever you create
              a new Quote.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Automatic, Use Quote #'s</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Quote Numbers will be automatically incremented by 1 each
              time a new Quote is created. These automatically-generated
              numbers may not be edited. They are read-only.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Automatic, Use Quote #'s, Allow Override</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Quote Numbers will be automatically generated and
              incremented, as under the "Automatic" option described above.
              However, this option also allows you to manually override the
              Quote Number at the time of Quote creation.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Automatic, Use S/O #'s</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Quote Numbers will be automatically incremented by 1 each
              time a new Quote is created, using the same number generation
              method specified for the creation of Sales Order Numbers. These
              automatically-generated numbers may not be edited. They are
              read-only.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Next #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The next sequentially available Quote Number will display here.
        You may change the number--creating a new basis for the next Quote
        Number--by typing the new number into this field. Any changes you make
        here will be reflected the next time a new Quote is created in the S/O
        module.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>return authorizations</primary>
          <secondary>numbering of</secondary>
        </indexterm>Return Auth. # Generation</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select one of the available Return Authorization Number
        generation methods:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Manual</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Return Authorization Numbers must be entered manually
              whenever you create a new Return Authorization.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Automatic, Use R/A #'s</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Return Authorization Numbers will be automatically
              incremented by 1 each time a new Return Authorization is
              created. These automatically-generated numbers may not be
              edited. They are read-only.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Automatic, Use R/A #s, Allow Override</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Return Authorization Numbers will be automatically
              generated and incremented, as under the "Automatic" option
              described above. However, this option also allows you to
              manually override the Return Authorization Number at the time of
              Return Authorization creation.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>credit memos</primary>
          <secondary>numbering of</secondary>
        </indexterm>Credit Memo # Generation</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select one of the available Credit Memo Number generation
        methods:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Manual</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Credit Memo Numbers must be entered manually whenever you
              create a new Credit Memo.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Automatic, Use C/M #'s</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Credit Memo Numbers will be automatically incremented by 1
              each time you issue a new Credit Memo. These
              automatically-generated numbers may not be edited. They are
              read-only.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Automatic, Use C/M #"s, Allow Override</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Credit Memo Numbers will be automatically generated and
              incremented, as under the "Automatic" option described above.
              However, this option also allows you to manually override the
              Credit Memo Number at the time of Credit Memo creation.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Automatic, Use S/O #'s</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Credit Memo Numbers will be automatically incremented by 1
              each time a new Credit Memo is created, using the same number
              generation method specified for the creation of Sales Order
              Numbers. These automatically-generated numbers may not be
              edited. They are read-only.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Next #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The next sequentially available Credit Memo Number will display
        here. You may change the number--creating a new basis for the next
        Credit Memo Number--by typing the new number into this field. Any
        changes you make here will be reflected the next time you issue a new
        Credit Memo within the S/O module.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>invoices</primary>
          <secondary>numbering of</secondary>
        </indexterm>Invoice # Generation</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>By default, Invoice Numbers are automatically generated. This
        system setting cannot be changed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Next #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The next sequentially available Invoice Number will display
        here. You may change the number--creating a new basis for the next
        Invoice Number--by typing the new number into this field. Any changes
        you make here will be reflected the next time you create a new Invoice
        within the S/O module.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To establish general settings for the S/O module, select the "General"
  tab. The following options will appear:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales orders</primary>
          <secondary>discount defaults for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Allow Price Discounts</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Check this option to allow pricing discounts for select
        customers. This option instructs the system to verify whether any
        Pricing Discounts have been established for a Customer, prior to
        calculating the Line Item Price for of an Item within a Sales Order.
        If this option is unchecked, then the system will apply the full List
        Price for an Item within a Sales Order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Allow ASAP Schedule Dates</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Selecting this option will cause Sales Order Line Items to
        become immediately past due if no schedule date is entered.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Restrict Credit Memos to Items that appear on their Apply-To
      Document</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you want to restrict Credit Memo Items to their
        Apply-To Document. Selecting this option narrows the Credit Memo Item
        selection process to only those Items which appeared on the Invoice
        the Credit Memo is being applied to. If not selected, a sold Item
        master list will appear instead when selecting Credit Memo Items for
        Credit Memos applied to a specific Invoice. This setting has no
        bearing on unapplied Credit Memos.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Automatically check "Select for Billing" option on Ship Order
      screen</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you want the "Select for Billing" option to be
        selected by default whenever you ship Sales Order Line Items.
        Selecting this option reduces steps in the billing process.
        Specifically, if an Order is selected for billing when it is shipped,
        you do not then have to take the extra step of independently selecting
        the Order for billing. This can save time and also ensure your shipped
        Orders are selected for billing at the time of shipment.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Always show "Save and Add to Packing List" button on Sales Order
      screen</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you want the SAVE AND ADD TO PACKING LIST button to
        always be displayed on the Sales Order header screen. If this option
        is not selected, the SAVE AND ADD TO PACKING LIST button will only be
        displayed for newly-entered Sales Orders which have not yet been
        saved.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Disallow Override of Sales Price on Sales Order Entry</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to prevent all users from overriding the Sales Price when
        entering Sales Order Line Items. This is a system-wide setting,
        affecting all users. Do not select this option if you want to
        selectively prevent users from overriding Sales Prices. Individual
        users may be granted the ability to override Sales Prices, use the S/O
        module's OverridePrice privilege.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Automatically Allocate Credit Memos to New Sales Order on
      Save</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to have open Credit Memos for a Customer automatically
        allocated to any new Sales Orders entered for that Customer. This
        functionality helps reduce Customer credit balances by ensuring that
        Customer credits are consumed when new Sales Orders are entered. Any
        available, open Credit Memos are eligible for allocation. The
        allocation of available Credit Memos occurs only once--when a Sales
        Order is saved for the first time. Subsequent saves will not result in
        additional allocations. Credit Memos which have been allocated to a
        Sales Order are applied at the point when the Invoice resulting from
        the Sales Order is posted. Once the full balance of a Credit Memo has
        been applied, the Credit Memo is then closed. The printed Invoice the
        Customer receives will indicate whether Credit Memos have been
        applied. In addition, the total due from the Customer will be
        automatically adjusted to reflect any applied credits.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>The allocation of available Credit Memos occurs only once--when a
    Sales Order is saved for the first time. Subsequent saves will not result
    in additional allocations.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Hide Misc. Charges on Sales Order screen</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to hide all fields related to Miscellaneous Charges on
        the Sales Order Line Item tab. If your site does not use Misc. Charges
        when entering Sales Orders, it may make sense to hide this
        functionality to avoid confusion.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Enable Shipping interface from Sales Order screen</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to enable the performance of limited Shipping
        functionality from the Sales Order header. If selected, users will be
        able to issue Stock to Shipping and also return Stock from Shipping
        directly from the Sales Order header. If not selected, these Shipping
        options will not be available on the Sales Order header.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="standard">
      <term>Enable S/O Reservations</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to enable the Sales Order Reservations functionality
        system-wide. This feature allows for the hard allocation of quantity
        to Sales Orders. If not selected, the Sales Order reservation options
        will be hidden from view.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Check Print S/O on Save by Default</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to prompt users to print Sales Orders whenever Sales
        Orders are saved. If selected, users will be presented with a Sales
        Order print screen whenever a Sales Order is saved. To bypass this
        feature, do not select this option.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Enable Promise Dates</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to display a Promised Date field on the Sales Order Line
        Item screen, by default. If not selected, there will be no Promised
        Date field shown on that screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Post Customer Changes to the Change Log</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to post to the Change Log any changes made to Customer
        masters.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Post Sales Order Changes to the Change Log</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to post to the Change Log any changes made to Sales
        Orders.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Pricing on Editing Line Items</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select one of the following as your preferred response when
        users change Sales Order Line Item quantities:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Update Price on Line Item Edit</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>If selected, the system will automatically update the Net
              Unit Price for the Line Item, adjusting to accommodate the
              newly-entered quantity.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Prompt before Updating Price</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>If selected, the system will ask users if they want to
              update the Net Unit Price (YES/NO). If they answer "YES" because
              they do want to update the Price, then they will have to
              manually make the Price adjustment.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Do not Update Price on Line Edit</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>If selected, the Net Unit Price will not be changed when
              Line Item quantity is changed on EDIT--and users will not be
              prompted to consider changing the Price.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>The Sales Order Line Item pricing options apply only when editing
    Line Item quantity.</para>
  </note>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Cancels any configuration settings, returning you to the
        application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Saves the configuration settings, returning you to the
        application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To establish Invoice and Credit Memo settings, select the "Invoice"
  tab. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/configureSO_invoice.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Invoice Configuration Options</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When establishing Invoice and Credit Memo settings, you are presented
  with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Invoice Date Source</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select one of the following Invoice date options:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Shipped Date</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>If selected, the Invoice date on the Invoice header will
              be the same date as the Sales Order ship date.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Scheduled Date</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>If selected, the Invoice date on the Invoice header will
              be the same date as the Sales Order scheduled date.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Default Invoice Copies</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Indicate how you want invoice copies to print.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term># of Copies</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Indicate the number of copies you want to print.
              Information about the specified copies will display
              below.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Default Credit Memo Copies</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Indicate how you want credit memo copies to print.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term># of Copies</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Indicate the number of copies you want to print.
              Information about the specified copies will display
              below.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>customers</primary>
      <secondary>default configuration for</secondary>
    </indexterm>To establish default settings to be used whenever new
  Customers are entered, select the "Customer Defaults" tab. The following
  screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/configureSO_customerDefault.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Default Customer Configuration Options</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When establishing Customer master default settings, you are presented
  with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Customer Type</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify a default Customer Type to be used whenever new
        Customers are created. The default Customer Type may be changed when
        entering or editing new Customers.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Sales Rep</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify a default Sales Representative to be used whenever new
        Customers are created. The Sales Rep may be changed when entering or
        editing new Customers.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Ship Via</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify a default Ship Via.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Shipping Form</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify a default Shipping Form.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Terms</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the default billing Terms to be used whenever new
        Customers are created. The default Terms may be changed when entering
        or editing new Customers.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Balance Method</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify a default procedure for handling cash receipts from
        Customers. This notation is informational only. Balance Forward:
        Select to apply cash receipts to the Customer's current balance
        due.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Credit Limit</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the default credit limit to be used for all
        Customers.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Credit Rating</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the default credit rating to be used for all
        Customers.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Accepts Partial Shipments</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to indicate Customers accept partial shipments by
        default.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Accepts Backorders</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to indicate Customers accept backorders by
        default.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Allow Free Form Ship-Tos</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to indicate Customers allow free-form Ship-Tos by
        default. This default appears on the Customer master.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para role="standard"><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>return authorizations</primary>
      <secondary>configuration for</secondary>
    </indexterm>To define your system's Return Authorization configuration,
  select the "Return" tab. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <screenshot role="standard">
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/configureSO_returns.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption><para>Returns Configuration Options</para></caption>
    </mediaobject>
  </screenshot>
  <para role="standard">When configuring Return Authorization settings, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist role="standard">
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Enable Return Authorizations</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to enable the system's Return Authorizations capability.
        If not selected, users will be prevented from performing any tasks
        related to Return Authorizations--and related functionality will be
        hidden from view. For systems where Return Authorizations are enabled,
        this option will be hidden.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Post Return Authorization Changes to the Change Log</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to record changes made to Return Authorizations in the
        Return Authorization change log. If not selected, the Return
        Authorization changelog will not contain change information.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Default Disposition</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify one of the following default methods for handling Return
        Authorizations:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Credit</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if, by default, you want to issue credit to
              Customers for authorized Line Items and quantities. No return is
              required or expected. Return Authorization Line Items will close
              when an associated Credit Memo is posted.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Return</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if, by default, you want to authorize returns from
              Customers. Return Authorization Items will close when an
              associated Credit Memo is posted, or when all Items on a line
              have been returned, whichever comes last.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Replace</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if, by default, you want to replace Items returned
              by Customers. Authorized quantities will be added as additional
              order quantity to an associated Sales Order line, which in turn
              should be reopened if closed. Return Authorization Items will
              close when all Items on the line have been returned or all
              authorized Items on the line have been shipped, whichever comes
              last. No money should be involved when invoicing replacement
              Items.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Service</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if, by default, you want to repair or service Items
              returned by Customers. Service or repair items will first be
              received by a Return Authorization. Then a new Sales Order with
              linked Work Order(s) will be created to track work and shipping
              on the repair or service. The new Sales Order will be on RMA
              Hold until Items have been received by the Return
              Authorization.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Substitute</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if, by default, you want to authorize the
              substitution of Items returned by Customers. Under this option,
              when an original Sales Order is imported into the Return
              Authorization, the Return Authorization Line Items will default
              to the Return disposition. Any new Line Items added beyond the
              original ones will have a default disposition of Ship.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Credit/Ship</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the default timetable for Customer credits and/or
        returns:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Immediately</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to issue credit or send returns to Customers
              immediately by default.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Upon Receipt</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to issue credit or send returns to Customers only
              after you have received returned goods from them by
              default.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Default Credit Method</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify one of the following default credit method
        options:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>None</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if, by default, you do not issue credit for
              Customer returns.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Credit Memo</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if, by default, you credit Customer returns with a
              Credit Memo to the Customer's account. This option will result
              in the automatic creation of a sales Credit Memo.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Check</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if, by default, you credit Customer returns by
              sending them a Check. This option will create a Credit Memo,
              then a Misc. Check that applies to the Credit Memo.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Credit Card</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if, by default, you credit Customer returns with a
              refund on their Credit Card.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
