<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="costCategory">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>cost categories</primary>
      <secondary>creating new</secondary>
    </indexterm>Cost Category</title>
  <para>To create a new Cost Category, select the NEW button. The following
  screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/costCategory.png" id="Graphic677973" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption677976">Create New Cost Category</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <tip>
    <para>The Account Numbers assigned to Cost Categories should not all be
    the Inventory Account. Instead, they should be individual accounts
    selected specifically for each Cost-tracking purpose. This will increase
    your visibility into your Inventory Costs and valuation.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>When creating a new Cost Category, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Category</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the Cost Category name.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Description</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a brief description of the Cost Category.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Inventory Asset</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Identify a General Ledger (G/L) Account to distribute Inventory
        assets to. This is an Asset Account. It will be debited when Inventory
        is received and credited whenever Inventory Items are removed from
        Inventory.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>WIP Asset</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Identify a General Ledger (G/L) Account to distribute
        work-in-process (WIP) assets to. This is an Asset Account. It will be
        credited and/or debited with labor, material, and <indexterm
            significance="normal">
            <primary>overhead</primary>
            <secondary>linking to wip assets</secondary>
          </indexterm>overhead Costs while a Work Order is in-process. The
        sense of the transaction record depends on the circumstances of the
        transaction.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Inventory Cost Variance</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Identify a General Ledger (G/L) Account to distribute Inventory
        Cost variances to. This is an Asset Account. It is used in several
        scenarios: 1) If there is a difference between new Actual Cost and old
        Standard Cost when posting Actual Costs to Standard; 2) during Work
        Order processing if too many materials are issued to a Work Order, or
        if a Work Order is closed without the full quantity being posted; or
        3) when posting cycle counts there is a difference between the new
        counted quantity and the quantity recorded in the system. The sense of
        the transaction record depends on the circumstances of the
        transaction.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Transform Clearing</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Identify a General Ledger (G/L) Account to distribute Transform
        transactions to. This is an Asset Account. It will be credited when a
        source Item quantity is transformed, and debited for an equal amount
        when the target Item quantity is received into Inventory.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Purchase Price Variance</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Identify a General Ledger (G/L) Account to distribute purchase
        Price variances to. This is an Asset Account. It will be credited or
        debited with the value of any variance that may arise when a Voucher
        is posted. The sense of the transaction record depends on the
        circumstances of the transaction.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Inventory Adjustment</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Identify a General Ledger (G/L) Account to distribute Inventory
        adjustments to. This is an Expense Account. It will be credited or
        debited with the value of any variance that may arise when a
        Miscellaneous Adjustment transaction or Cycle Count transaction is
        posted against an Item. The sense of the transaction record depends on
        the circumstances of the transaction.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Inventory Scrap</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Identify a G/L Account to distribute Inventory Scrap to. This is
        an Expense Account. It will be credited when a Scrap transaction is
        posted against an Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Manufacturing Scrap</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Identify a G/L Account to distribute Manufacturing Scrap to.
        This is an Expense Account. It will be credited when Work Order
        Material Requirements are scrapped from a Work Order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="openmfg">
      <term>Labor and Overhead Costs</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Overhead Costs: Identify a General Ledger (G/L) Account to
        distribute labor and overhead Costs to. This is a Liability Account.
        It will be debited and/or credited with labor and overhead Costs when
        Work Orders are in-process or posted. The sense of the transaction
        record depends on the circumstances of the transaction.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>P/O Liability Clearing</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Identify a General Ledger (G/L) Account to distribute Purchase
        Order liability clearing to. This is a Liability Account. It will be
        credited when a Purchase Order Receipt is posted and debited when a
        Voucher is posted.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Shipping Asset</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Identify a General Ledger (G/L) Account to distribute shipping
        assets to. This is an Asset Account. It will be debited with the
        Standard Cost of a Sales Order Item when the Item is issued to
        Shipping and credited once the Item has been shipped.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Line Freight Expense</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Identify a General Ledger (G/L) Account to distribute Purchase
        Order or Transfer Order Line Item freight expenses to. This is an
        Expense Account. It will be debited when Purchase Order or Transfer
        Order Line Items are received. The Account may be debited or credited
        when correcting Purchase Order Receipts.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Transfer Order Liability Clearing</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Identify a General Ledger (G/L) Account to distribute Transfer
        Order Liability Clearing to. This is a Liability Account. It is used
        for recognizing liability related to transportation costs related to
        Transfer Orders. It will be credited when Transfer Orders receipts
        having freight charges are posted. It should be debited when the
        Freight (or other Vendor) is paid by Miscellaneous Check.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without creating a Cost Category, returning
        you to the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Creates the Cost Category and adds it to the master list of Cost
        Categories.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
