<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section567098">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>item sites</primary>
      <secondary>creating new by class code</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>class codes</primary>
      <secondary>creating item sites for</secondary>
    </indexterm>Create Item Sites by Class Code</title>
  <para>When setting up a new Warehouse, you have the ability to create
  batches of Item Sites--rather than having to create them one-at-a-time. To
  create Item Sites by Class Code, select the "Create Item Sites by Class
  Code" option. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/createItemSitesByClassCode.png"
                     id="Graphic567101" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption567104">Create Item Sites by Class Code</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <tip>
    <para>Use the Create Item Sites by Class Code utility when setting up a
    new Warehouse.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>When creating Item Sites by Class Code, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Warehouse</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19be1e0">
        <para>Specify Warehouse where Item Site is located.</para>
        <para>Use this selection in conjunction with the additional Warehouse
        settings found on the Item Site screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>order parameters</primary>
          <secondary>enforcement of</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>item sites</primary>
          <secondary>enforcing order parameters in</secondary>
        </indexterm>Enforce Order Parameters</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19be2b8">
        <para>Order Parameters: Select to enforce Order Parameters.</para>
        <para>If this option is selected, then Material Requirements Planning
        (MRP) will follow the Order Parameters defined below when generating
        Planned Replenishment Orders. If you want to enforce Order Parameters
        on manual Orders as well, select the "on Manual Orders" option. For
        more information on how Order Parameters interact with MRP, see <xref
        endterm="Anchor14508" linkend="Anchor14508" />.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>Running Material Requirements Planning (MRP) on your system consists
    entirely of running the Create Planned Replenishment Orders
    screens--either by Item or by Planner Code. As MRP runs, the Planned
    Replenishment Orders are generated automatically.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Reorder Level</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19be348">
        <para>The Reorder Level specifies when a Planned Replenishment Order
        should be created for an Item Site. If Planned Availability minus
        Safety Stock falls below the Reorder Level, then a Replenishment Order
        will be created when Material Requirements Planning (MRP) is run. The
        Replenishment Order quantity will be equal to the quantity required to
        return Planned Availability to either the Reorder Level or the Order
        Up To quantity--whichever is greater. For more information, see <xref
        endterm="Anchor14508" linkend="Anchor14508" />.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>Planned Availability differs from Quantity on Hand (QOH). The
    difference is that Planned Availability considers both QOH and also the
    time-phased demands placed on Inventory by Sales Orders and Work Orders.
    MRP uses Planned Availability when calculating which Item Sites require
    Planned Replenishment Orders.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Order Up To</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19be3d8">
        <para>The Order Up To (OUT) Level indicates the level of Planned
        Availability an Item Site should be replenished up to when Material
        Requirements Planning (MRP) is run. In cases where the Reorder Level
        for an Item Site exceeds the Order Up To Level, MRP will replenish the
        Item Site up to the Reorder Level. For more information, see <xref
        endterm="Anchor14508" linkend="Anchor14508" />.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>Setting the Order Up To Level to "0" removes any restrictions on
    maximum Order quantities. Removing quantity restrictions can be an
    effective strategy to help ensure that all Order demands are satisfied
    when MRP is run. Order demands may not be met if Order Up To Levels are
    set below the demand threshold.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Minimum Order</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19be468">
        <para>Value entered indicates the minimum quantity that may be entered
        for a Planned Replenishment Order when MRP is run. If the "on Manual
        Orders" option is selected above, manually-created Work Orders will
        recognize the Minimum Order value.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Maximum Order</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19be4b0">
        <para>This is a special setting which regulates the maximum quantity
        for Planned Replenishment Orders when MRP is run. The setting does not
        apply to manual Orders, but to Planned Orders only. When a maximum
        Order quantity is specified, MRP will ignore Order multiples and
        minimum Order specifications--focusing instead solely on the maximum
        Order setting. For example, if the maximum Order quantity is set to 10
        and there is demand for 17, then Planned Orders of 10 and 7 would be
        generated when MRP is run.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>Setting the maximum order quantity too low has been shown to slow
    performance when MRP is run. Unless you have special needs (i.e., crate
    packaging limits) which require you to set a low maximum order quantity,
    you should consider setting the maximum order value to "0".</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Order Multiple</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19be540">
        <para>Value entered indicates the quantity multiple that should be
        used for Planned Replenishment Orders when MRP is run. If the "on
        Manual Orders" option is selected above, manually-created Work Orders
        will recognize the Order Multiple value.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>on Manual Orders</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19be588">
        <para>Select to enforce Order Parameters on manually-created Work
        Orders.</para>
        <para>If this option is selected, Order Parameters will also be
        enforced whenever Work Orders are manually created. This option
        applies only to the following two parameters: Minimum Order and Order
        Multiple. The other Order Parameters listed below do not apply to
        manually-created Work Orders. For manual Purchase Orders, the Minimum
        Order and Order Multiple parameters are determined on a
        Vendor-by-Vendor basis, using Item Source masters.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="openmfg">
      <term>Group MPS/MRP Orders Every</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19be5ac">
        <para>Specify the length of a periodmeasured in days--within which MPS
        or MRP Planned Orders will be grouped together (i.e, consolidated) to
        meet scheduled demand for the period.</para>
        <para>This functionality serves to limit the total number of Planned
        Replenishment Orders, thereby simplifying order processing. For
        example, to consolidate demand for an Item Site into 30-day buckets,
        set the value to "30." When MRP is run, the system will automatically
        consolidate all demand falling within the 30-day horizon into a single
        Planned Purchase Order or Planned Work Order. The grouping of Planned
        Orders moves forward in time, meaning the system will create as many
        buckets as will fit within the cutoff date specified when MRP is
        run.</para>
        <para>The initial grouping of Planned Orders is handled differently
        than subsequent buckets. The following formula specifies how the date
        range for the initial period is determined:</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>Start Date = Today's Date</para>
  <para>End Date = Today's Date + Lead Time</para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19be5f4">
      <para>All subsequent periods are determined using the following
      calculations:</para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>Start Date = End Date of Previous Period + 1</para>
  <para>End Date = Start Date of Current Period + Group Value</para>
  <tip>
    <para>To enforce <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>just-in-time</primary>
        <secondary>delivery of planned orders</secondary>
      </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>planned orders</primary>
        <secondary>just-in-time delivery and</secondary>
      </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>material requirements planning</primary>
        <secondary>just-in-time delivery and</secondary>
      </indexterm>Just-In-Time (JIT) delivery methods, set the MRP group value
    to "0." This will ensure that Planned Order due dates are the same as the
    demand due dates to which they correspond. If the MRP Order grouping value
    is set to "0", the initial period will be determined in the same way as
    for all Planned Order groups:</para>
    <para>Start Date = Today's Date</para>
    <para>End Date = Today's Date + Lead Time</para>
    <para>However, the date range for all subsequent JIT Planned Orders will
    be based on the following calculations:</para>
    <para>Start Date = Demand Due Date - Lead Time</para>
    <para>End Date = Demand Due Date</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry role="openmfg">
      <term>MPS Time Fence</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19be738">
        <para>Specify the length of the Demand Time Fence by using the arrow
        buttons or manually entering a value up to a maximum of 999. The
        Demand Time Fence is used by the Master Production Scheduling (MPS)
        system to evaluate when forecasted demand (i.e., from Production
        Plans) should be used in place of actual demand (i.e., from Sales
        Orders)--and vice versa. Measured in days, the Demand Time Fence is
        the period of time extending from the current day to the number of
        days into the future as specified in this field. The Demand Time Fence
        option applies only to those Items which currently appear on a
        released Production Plan. If demand for these Items falls within the
        Demand Time Fence period, then the Forecast will be ignored. If demand
        falls outside the Demand Time Fence, then the larger of actual or
        forecasted demand will be used. MPS responds to the demand it locates
        by creating firm Planned Orders for the required quantities.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Safety Stock</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19be780">
        <para>Specify the quantity of Stock for the Item you want to keep in
        Inventory to protect against unplanned, unforeseeable trends in your
        Order forecasts. When Material Requirements Planning (MRP) is run, the
        system considers the Safety Stock value when determining whether to
        create Planned Replenishment Orders. If Planned Availability minus
        Safety Stock is below the Reorder Level, then Planned Orders will be
        created. If not below the Reorder Level, then no Planned Orders will
        be created. The system's calculation effectively creates a buffer
        Inventory (if needed) to handle unexpected fluctuations in demand. If
        you do not want to use the Safety Stock functionality, set the Safety
        Stock value to "0".</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>ABC Class</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19be7c8">
        <para>Specify the ABC classification for the specified Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Allow Automatic Updates</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19cd600">
        <para>Select to allow the ABC Class setting for the Item Site to be
        updated whenever the ABC Class update utility is run. Not selecting
        indicates the ABC Class for the Item Site should not be updated
        whenever the ABC Class update utility is run.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Cycl. Cnt. Freq.</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19cd648">
        <para>Cnt. Freq.: Select a number using the arrow buttons, or manually
        enter a value up to a maximum of 999. A Cycle Count is a periodic
        issue of a Count Tag to count Inventory quantity within an Item Site.
        The Cycle Count frequency defines the length of that period, measured
        in days.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>To monitor the frequency of Item Site Cycle Counts, view the "Last
    Counted" column in any of the Item Site Reports: by Item, by Class Code,
    etc. The Last Counted date represents the date a Count Tag was last posted
    (not simply issued) for the Item Site.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Lead Time</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19cd6d8">
        <para>Select a number using the arrow buttons, or manually enter a
        value up to a maximum of 999. Specifies the Lead Time for the
        specified Item, measured in days. If the Item is a manufactured Item,
        then the Lead Time refers to the production Lead Time. If the Item is
        a purchased Item, then the Lead Time refers to the planning Lead Time.
        The procurement Lead Time for purchased Items is determined on a
        Vendor-by-Vendor basis, using Item Source masters. Material
        Requirements Planning (MRP) will consider Lead Times when calculating
        Planned Order start dates when MRP is run.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>event fences</primary>
          <secondary>in item sites</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>item sites</primary>
          <secondary>event fences in</secondary>
        </indexterm>Event Fence</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19cd7b0">
        <para>Select a number using the arrow buttons, or manually enter a
        value up to a maximum of 99. Specify the period of time, measured in
        days, within which relevant Event notifications should be issued. If
        an Event affecting the Item Site occurs within the Event Fence, then
        the system will issue a notification. Consider the case of a
        manufactured Item whose Event Fence is set to five (5) days. Assume
        that a Work Order exists for this Item and that the scheduled start
        date for that Work Order is three (3) days from the current date. If
        someone were to change the quantity of that Work Order, the Event
        "WoQtyChanged" would be triggered. And because the Work Order start
        date falls within the Event Fence for the Item Site, an Event
        notification would be issued.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Planner Code</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19cd7f8">
        <para>Specify Planner Code you want to assign the Item Site to.
        Assigning a Planner Code to an Item Site makes it possible to group
        Item Sites by Planner Code for the purposes of Planning.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Supplied at this Warehouse</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19cd840">
        <para>Select if Item is supplied at specified Warehouse. If selected,
        "Supplied at" means that Purchase Orders may be issued for this Item
        in this Warehouse if the Item is a purchased Item, and Work Orders may
        be issued for this Item in this Warehouse if the Item is a
        manufactured Item. These rules apply also to Planned Orders generated
        when Material Requirements Planning (MRP) is run. Planned Orders may
        only be released to "Supplied at" Item Sites.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Create P/Rs to Meet Demands</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19cd888">
        <para>Select to create Purchase Requests whenever Sales Orders or Work
        Orders demand quantities from the Item Site. This option pertains to
        purchased and outside-process Items. If you select this option, you
        are indicating that you want Purchase Requests to be generated for the
        Item in question whenever quantities are demanded by either Sales
        Orders or Work Orders. For Sales Orders, the "Create Purchase Request"
        flag on the Sales Order Item screen will automatically be selected.
        For Work Orders using a purchased or outside process Item, Purchase
        Requests will be generated automatically.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>Purchase Requests created, as specified above, to meet Sales Order
    and Work Order demands will be created regardless of an Item's
    Availability--and also regardless of whether Material Requirements
    Planning (MRP) is being run in parallel.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Create W/Os to Meet Demand</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19cd918">
        <para>Select to create Work Orders whenever Sales Orders demand
        quantities from the Item Site. This option pertains to manufactured
        Items. If you select this option, you are indicating that you want
        Work Orders to be generated for the Item in question whenever
        quantities are demanded by a Sales Order. Selecting this option will
        cause the "Create Work Order" flag to be checked whenever you enter
        Sales Order Line Items for the Item Site.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>Work Orders created, as specified above, to meet Sales Order demand
    will be created regardless of an Item's Availability--and also regardless
    of whether Material Requirements Planning (MRP) is being run in
    parallel.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Sold from this Warehouse</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19cd9a8">
        <para>Select if Item is sold from specified Warehouse. If selected,
        "Sold from" means that Sales Orders Line Items may request to Ship
        from the Warehouse. When adding Sales Order Line Items to a Sales
        Order, a "Sold from" Warehouse appears as the "Supplying
        Warehouse."</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>ranking</primary>
          <secondary>of item sites</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sold ranking</primary>
          <secondary>for item sites</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>item sites</primary>
          <secondary>sold ranking of</secondary>
        </indexterm>Ranking</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19cdac8">
        <para>Select a number using the arrow buttons, or manually enter a
        value up to a maximum of 10. Value entered specifies the order in
        which Item Sites will be chosen during Sales Order and Sales Quote
        creation. If an Item is located in more than one "Sold from"
        Warehouse, the Item Site with the highest ranking will be chosen
        first. If two Item Sites happen to share the same ranking, selection
        will be based on alphabetical order. The highest ranking an Item Site
        can have is one (1).</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Stocked</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19cdb10">
        <para>Select if Item is stocked at specified Warehouse. This option
        pertains to manufactured Items. If you select this option, you are
        indicating that the Item is a make-to-stock Item. If not selected, the
        Item will be identified as a make-to-order Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>control methods</primary>
          <secondary>at item site level</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>item sites</primary>
          <secondary>control methods in</secondary>
        </indexterm>Control Method</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19cdbe8">
        <para>Specify the Item Site control method by selecting one of the
        available options:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>None</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if you don"t care to see Inventory history
              transactions for the Item Site.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Regular</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to monitor Inventory history transactions for the
              Item Site using a Regular method. Regular means without Lot
              Number or Serial Number control.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Lot #</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to impose Lot Number control methods on the Item
              Site. Item Sites using Lot Number control are subject to unique
              processing requirements whenever Inventory is received or
              distributed. For additional information on some of the unique
              methods required to handle Lot-controlled Items, see <xref
              endterm="Anchor58321" linkend="Anchor58321" />.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Serial #</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to impose Serial Number control methods on the Item
              Site. Item Sites using Serial Number control are subject to
              unique processing requirements whenever Inventory is received or
              distributed. For additional information on some of the unique
              methods required to handle Serial-controlled Items, see <xref
              endterm="Anchor58321" linkend="Anchor58321" />.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="openmfg">
      <term>Perishable</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19cdc0c">
        <para>Select if the Item is perishable. For Item Sites whose control
        method is either Lot Number or Serial Number, you have the option of
        also designating the Item Site as Perishable. Materials received into
        a Perishable Item Site are required to specify an expiration date,
        thereby increasing your ability to monitor the status of the
        goods.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>multiple location control</primary>
          <secondary>establishing in item sites</secondary>
        </indexterm>Multiple Location Control</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19cdc9c">
        <para>Select if the specified Item is to be stored in multiple
        Locations within a single Warehouse. Items designated as Multiple
        Location Control (MLC) Items require special processing whenever Item
        quantities are distributed. For more information on distributing MLC
        Item quantities, see <xref endterm="Anchor81167"
        linkend="Anchor81167" />.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>default locations</primary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>locations</primary>
          <secondary>default</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>item sites</primary>
          <secondary>setting default locations in</secondary>
        </indexterm>Use Default Location</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19cdd98">
        <para>Default Location: Select to designate one Location within a
        Warehouse as the default Location for the specified Item. This option
        may be used for single Location and Multiple Location Control (MLC)
        Items alike. You may find that Inventory distributions for MLC Items
        are greatly simplified if you designate a default Location.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Location</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19cdde0">
        <para>Specify the Warehouse Location to be used as the default
        Location. The list will show all valid Warehouse Locations for the
        specified Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>User-Defined</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19cde28">
        <para>This is a free-form field for describing storage areas with a
        Warehouse not specifically designated as Warehouse Locations.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Location Comment</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19cde70">
        <para>Enter any free-form Comment related to the Warehouse Location.
        This is additional information which may be placed on a Pick List or a
        Pack List.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>item sites</primary>
          <secondary>cost categories in</secondary>
        </indexterm>Cost Category</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19cdf00">
        <para>Specify the Cost Category you want to associate with the Item
        Site(s). Item Sites are required to have Cost Categories associated
        with them. This requirement helps ensure that all Inventory
        transactions involving an Item Site will be properly tracked and
        recorded in the General Ledger.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CLOSE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19cdf6c">
        <para>Closes the screen without creating Item Sites for the specified
        Class Code(s), returning you to the application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19cdfb4">
        <para>Creates the Item Sites and enters them into the master list of
        Item Sites.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>