<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section519249">
  <title>
<indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>cycle count tags</primary>
      <secondary>creating by warehouse</secondary>
    </indexterm>
<indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>cycle counts</primary>
      <secondary>creating tags for</secondary>
    </indexterm>
<indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>physical inventory</primary>
      <secondary>creating cycle count tags</secondary>
    </indexterm>Create Cycle Count Tags by Warehouse</title>
  <para>Cycle Count Tags are used to count Inventory on a
  frequent basis, with the rate of frequency defined in the Item Site master.
  The following criteria are used to determine the order in which Cycle Count
  Tags will be created for a specified Warehouse(s):</para>
  <orderedlist continuation="restarts" inheritnum="ignore">
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18fa57c">
      <para>The system scans the Item Site masters in the
      specified Warehouse(s), specifically targeting Cycle Count frequency
      settings.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18fa5a0">
      <para>The frequency settings are then compared to the
      last counted dates for each Item Site to determine which Item Sites have
      last counted dates most out of sync with their count frequency rate;
      Item Sites whose last counted dates are most out of sync with their
      stated frequency rate will have Cycle Count Tags created for them
      first.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18fa5c4">
      <para>After frequency and last counted date parameters
      have been considered, the Item Site's ABC Class is used--with A Class
      Item Sites having Cycle Count Tags created first.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18fa5e8">
      <para>Then, finally, Cycle Count Tags are created based
      on the Item Numbers for the Item Sites in ascending order (i.e., 1, 2, 3
      ... A, B, C).</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18fa60c">
      <para>The total number of Cycle Count Tags to be created
      is determined beforehand.</para>
    </listitem>
  </orderedlist>
  <para>The difference between Cycle Count Tags and Count Tags
  is that Cycle Count Tags are generated dynamically, using the criteria
  listed above. Count Tags are generated manually, on demand.</para>
  <tip>
    <para>To monitor the frequency of Item Site Cycle Counts,
    view the "Last Counted" column in any of the Item Site Reports: by Item,
    by Class Code, etc. The Last Counted date represents the date a Count Tag
    was last posted (not simply issued) for the Item Site.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>To create Cycle Count Tags by Warehouse, select the
  "Create Cycle Count Tags by Warehouse" option. The following screen will
  appear:</para>
  <para>
<screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/IM_PI_createCycleCTByWareho.png" id="Graphic526024"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption519255">Create Cycle Count Tags by
        Warehouse</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
</para>
  <para>When creating Cycle Count Tags by Warehouse, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Warehouse</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18fa708">
        <para>Specify Warehouse where Cycle Count will be conducted.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Mark Created Count Tag as Priority</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18fa750">
        <para>Select to give priority status to Count Tag.</para>
        <para>Count Tags marked as having priority status are
        listed first in any prioritized lists. For example, priority Count
        Tags will appear at the top of the Count Tag Edit List; whereas,
        non-priority Count Tags will appear at the bottom of the list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>
<indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>freezing</primary>
          <secondary>of inventory</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>inventory</primary>
          <secondary>freezing during cycle counts</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>cycle counts</primary>
          <secondary>freezing inventory during</secondary>
        </indexterm>Freeze Inventory</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18fa870">
        <para>Select to freeze Inventory.</para>
        <para>The Quantity on Hand value is not updated when a
        transaction is posted against a frozen Item Site. Instead, Inventory
        transactions are pooled and then posted later when the Item Site is
        unfrozen--or thawed. The Quantity on Hand is updated when the Item
        Site is thawed. For a detailed explanation of these concepts, see the
        <xref endterm="Anchor80983" linkend="Anchor80983"/>
    FINDME
  "Topic: Freezing and Thawing"
        section.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>When an Item Site is frozen, any Warehouse activity
    entered against that Item Site--including Work Orders--will use the
    Quantity on Hand shown at the time of freezing.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Ignore Zero Balance Item Sites</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18fa900">
        <para>Select to ignore Item Sites which have a Quantity on Hand
        balance of zero.</para>
        <para>If selected, Count Tags will not be created for
        any Item Site having a Quantity on Hand balance of zero.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Maximum Number of Tags to Create</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18fa948">
        <para>Select a number using the arrow buttons, or manually enter a
        value up to a maximum of 1,000.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Sites in</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18fa990">
        <para>Specify which of the following codes you want to have Cycle
        Count Tags created for:</para>
        <para>Class Code: If selected, you will be presented
        with Class Code options.</para>
        <para>Planner Code: If selected, you will be presented
        with Planner Code options.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Only for Specified Location</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18fa9d8">
        <para>Select if you want to create Count Tags for an individual
        Warehouse Location.</para>
        <para>If selected, you will have the option to specify
        which Warehouse Location you want to have Count Tags created for. This
        option enables you to count individual Warehouse Locations separately,
        without having to post counts for an entire Warehouse all at
        once.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>
<indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>cycle counters</primary>
          <secondary>creating instructions for</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>cycle counts</primary>
          <secondary>creating instructions for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Comments</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18faab0">
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        Comments related to the Cycle Count. Use the Comments field to enter
        any instructions or other Comments that need to reach and be read by
        the cycle counters.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons
  are available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CLOSE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18fab1c">
        <para>Closes the screen without creating a Count Tag, returning you to
        the application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CREATE TAGS</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18fab64">
        <para>Creates Cycle Count Tags.</para>
        <para>Cycle Count Tag Numbers are generated
        automatically in an ordered sequence.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
