<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section537828" role="openmfg">
   <title>Run MRP by Item</title>
   <para>When you run MRP by Item, you are running the
    Material Requirements Planning (MRP) system. This utility creates Planned
    Replenishment Orders to meet existing Sales Order and Work Order demand.
    Replenishment Orders will be created whenever a Planned Availability for
    an Item Site falls below its Reorder Level. The quantity of the
    Replenishment Order will be enough to restore Planned Availability back to
    the Reorder Level--or to the Order Up To (OUT) Level, if the OUT Level is
    greater.</para>
   <tip>
      <para>When running MRP by Item for manufactured Items,
      the system generates Planned Work Orders only. If you want to also
      generate Planned Orders for purchased requirements, you should run MRP
      by Planner Code. Only Items designated as MRP Items will be affected by
      an MRP run.</para>
   </tip>
   <para>To run MRP for an individual Item, select the "Run
    MRP by Item" option. The following screen will appear:</para>
   <para>
      <screenshot>
         <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
               <imagedata fileref="images/MS_Sched_createPlanOrdByItem.png" id="Graphic537834"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption id="Caption537837">Run MRP by Item</caption>
         </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
   </para>
   <note>
      <para>The system deletes any non-firmed Planned Orders
      when MRP is run. If demand for the deleted Planned Orders still exists,
      the Orders will be replaced by new Replenishment Orders having new
      Planned Order Numbers. Order quantities will also be updated if demand
      levels have changed since MRP was last run.</para>
   </note>
   <para>When running MRP by Item, you are presented with the
    following options:</para>
   <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
         <term>Item Number</term>
         <listitem>
            <para>Enter the Item Number of the Item you want to create a Planned
          Order for.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
         <term>UOM</term>
         <listitem>
            <para>Inventory Unit of Measure.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
         <term>Warehouse</term>
         <listitem>
            <para>Specify Warehouse Planned Replenishment Orders should be
          created for.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
         <term>Cutoff Date</term>
         <listitem>
            <para>Specify how far into the future the MPS run should look for
          demand.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
         <term>
             
            <indexterm significance="normal">
               <primary>firmed orders</primary>
               <secondary>deletion of</secondary>
            </indexterm>Delete Existing Firmed MRP Orders</term>
         <listitem>
            <para>Firmed MRP Orders: Select to delete existing Firmed
          Orders.</para>
            <para>A firm Planned Order is a Planned Order that
          has been solidified in the schedule. By default, firm Planned Orders
          are not deleted when MRP is run. Selecting this option overrides
          that default behavior. If firm Planned Orders are deleted when MRP
          is run, they will automatically be replaced by soft (i.e.,
          non-firmed) Planned Orders, assuming the demand for the requirements
          still exists.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
   </variablelist>
   <tip>
      <para>Unposted Purchase Orders and Purchase Requests are
      considered as valid sources of supply when MRP is run.</para>
   </tip>
   <para>To the far right of the screen, the following
    buttons are available:</para>
   <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
         <term>CANCEL</term>
         <listitem>
            <para>Closes the screen without creating Planned Replenishment
          Orders by Item, returning you to the application desktop.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
         <term>CREATE</term>
         <listitem>
            <para>Creates Planned Replenishment Orders by Item, using the
          specified parameters.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
   </variablelist>
</section>
