<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section537991" role="openmfg">
    <title>Run Buffer Status by Item</title>

    <para>When you run buffer status by Item, you are running
    the Buffer Management system. This utility, when it is run, scans through
    your data and then updates the buffer status for the specified Item using
    the most current information.</para>

    <para>Because buffer status information is time-sensitive,
    you must run the system frequently (i.e., daily) to keep your statuses
    up-to-date. In fact, the various buffer status displays will not even show
    status information if Buffer Management has not been run on the day when
    you"re trying to view buffer status information. This built-in requirement
    prevents you from using information that is not current.</para>

    <note>
      <para>The critical buffer status in the Buffer
      Management system is 66%. In other words, any time you consume 66% of a
      buffer, then it\qs time to act immediately to resolve the situation. The
      66% value is a percentage that is widely used in academic research and
      practical real-world implementations of the Theory of Constraints--a
      theory pioneered by Eliyahu Goldratt.</para>
    </note>

    <para>After the buffer status utility has been run, you
    may view the Buffer Management displays which pertain to the Item--and
    then decide whether to take immediate action based on the newly-updated
    status value.</para>

    <para>To run buffer status by Item, select the "Run Buffer
    Status by Item" option. The following screen will appear:</para>

    <para>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
               <imagedata fileref="images/MS_Buff_runByItem.png" id="Graphic542042"/>
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption542045">Run Buffer Status by Item</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
   </para>

    <para>When running buffer status by Item, you are
    presented with the following options:</para>

    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Item Number</term>

        <listitem>
            <para>Enter the Item Number of the Item whose buffer status you want
          to update.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term>UOM</term>

        <listitem>
            <para>Inventory Unit of Measure.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term>Warehouse</term>

        <listitem>
            <para>Specify Warehouse where buffer status update should
          occur.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>

    <para>To the far right of the screen, the following
    buttons are available:</para>

    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>CANCEL</term>

        <listitem>
            <para>Closes the screen without updating buffer status by Item,
          returning you to the application desktop.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term>CREATE</term>

        <listitem>
            <para>Runs the buffer status update by Item, using the specified
          parameters.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term>SUBMIT</term>

        <listitem>
            <para>Select to submit the buffer status update to the Batch
          Manager. For additional information, see the <xref endterm="Anchor61009" linkend="Anchor61009"/>
    FINDME
  "Topic:
          Submitting Reports and Jobs to the Batch Manager".</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
  </section>
