<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.3//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.3/docbookx.dtd">

  <section id="Section537996" role="openmfg">
    <title>Run Buffer Status by Planner Code</title>

    <para id="Para542188">When you run buffer status by Planner Code, you are
    running the Buffer Management system. This utility, when it is run, scans
    through your data and then updates the buffer status for Items in the
    specified Planner Code(s) using the most current information.</para>

    <para id="Para543856">Because buffer status information is time-sensitive,
    you must run the system frequently (i.e., daily) to keep your statuses
    up-to-date. In fact, the various buffer status displays will not even show
    status information if Buffer Management has not been run on the day when
    you"re trying to view buffer status information. This built-in requirement
    prevents you from using information that is not current.</para>

    <note>
      <para id="Para542190">The critical buffer status in the Buffer
      Management system is 66%. In other words, any time you consume 66% of a
      buffer, then it\qs time to act immediately to resolve the situation. The
      66% value is a percentage that is widely used in academic research and
      practical real-world implementations of the Theory of Constraints--a
      theory pioneered by Eliyahu Goldratt.</para>
    </note>

    <para id="Para542191">After the buffer status utility has been run, you
    may view the Buffer Management displays which pertain to the affected
    Items--and then decide whether to take immediate action based on the
    newly-updated status values.</para>

    <para id="Para542192">To run buffer status by Planner Code, select the
    "Run Buffer Status by Planner Code" option. The following screen will
    appear:</para>

    <para id="Para542068"><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/MS_Buff_runByPCode.png"
                       id="Graphic542066" />
          </imageobject>

          <caption id="Caption542069">Run Buffer Status by Planner
          Code</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>

    <para id="Para542070">When running buffer status by Planner Code, you are
    presented with the following options:</para>

    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para542296">All Planner Codes</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>Select to update the buffer status for Item Sites in all
          Planner Codes.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para542297">Selected</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>Specify Planner Code whose Item Site buffer statuses you want
          to update.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para542298">Pattern</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>Enter a Planner Code pattern to select a range of Planner
          Codes.</para>

          <para id="Para554618">Refine your search using Regular Expressions,
          as described in <link endterm="Anchor77806" id="XRef554617"
          linkend="Anchor77806"> Pattern Matching with Regular
          Expressions</link>"Topic: Pattern Matching with Regular
          Expressions".</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para542306">All Warehouses</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>Select to update buffer statuses by Planner Code in all
          Warehouses.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para542307">Selected</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>Specify Warehouse where buffer status updates should
          occur.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>

    <para id="Para542415">To the far right of the screen, the following
    buttons are available:</para>

    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para542416">CANCEL</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>Closes the screen without updating buffer statuses by Planner
          Code, returning you to the application desktop.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para542417">CREATE</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>Runs the buffer status update by Planner Code, using the
          specified parameters.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para542418">SUBMIT</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>Select to submit the buffer status update to the Batch
          Manager. For additional information, see the <link
          endterm="Anchor61009" id="XRef547882" linkend="Anchor61009">
          Submitting Reports and Jobs to the Batch Manager</link>"Topic:
          Submitting Reports and Jobs to the Batch Manager".</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
  </section>
