<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.3//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.3/docbookx.dtd">

  <section id="Section551404" role="openmfg">
    <title>Run MRP by Planner Code</title>

    <para id="Para534797">When you run MRP by Planner Code, you are running
    the Material Requirements Planning (MRP) system. This utility creates
    Planned Replenishment Orders to meet existing Sales Order and Work Order
    demand. Replenishment Orders will be created whenever a Planned
    Availability for an Item Site falls below its Reorder Level. The quantity
    of the Replenishment Order will be enough to restore Planned Availability
    back to the Reorder Level--or to the Order Up To (OUT) Level, if the OUT
    Level is greater.</para>

    <note>
      <para id="Para536592">Running MRP by Planner Code may be used to
      generate Planned Orders for both parent-level manufactured Items and
      also lower level purchased Items. Only Items designated as MRP Items
      will be affected by an MRP run.</para>
    </note>

    <para id="Para536576">To run MRP by Planner Code, select the "Run MRP by
    Planner Code" option. The following screen will appear:</para>

    <para id="Para518624"><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/MS_Sched_createPlanByPCode.png"
                       id="Graphic520460" />
          </imageobject>

          <caption id="Caption518625">Run MRP by Planner Code</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>

    <note>
      <para id="Para535638">The system deletes any non-firmed Planned Orders
      when MRP is run. If demand for the deleted Planned Orders still exists,
      the Orders will be replaced by new Replenishment Orders having new
      Planned Order Numbers. Order quantities will also be updated if demand
      levels have changed since MRP was last run.</para>
    </note>

    <para id="Para518626">When running MRP by Planner Code, you are presented
    with the following options:</para>

    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para531702">All Planner Codes</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>Select to create Planned Replenishment Orders for all Planner
          Codes.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para518627">Selected</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>Specify Planner Code you want to create Planned Replenishment
          Orders for.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para526322">Pattern</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>Enter a Planner Code pattern to select a range of Planner
          Codes.</para>

          <para id="Para554575">Refine your search using Regular Expressions,
          as described in <link endterm="Anchor77806" id="XRef554574"
          linkend="Anchor77806"> Pattern Matching with Regular
          Expressions</link>"Topic: Pattern Matching with Regular
          Expressions".</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para518631">All Warehouses</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>Select to create Planned Replenishment Orders by Planner Code
          for all Warehouses.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para518633">Selected</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>Specify Warehouse Planned Replenishment Orders should be
          created for.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para531497">Cutoff Date</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>Specify how far into the future the MRP run should look for
          demand.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>

    <tip>
      <para id="Para546248">If you schedule an MRP or MPS job submitted to the
      Batch Manager to run on a periodic basis--daily, weekly, monthly--the
      cutoff date used for the run will automatically be updated by the number
      of days in the specified reschedule interval (Day = +1, Week = +7, and
      Month = +30).</para>
    </tip>

    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para518640"><anchor id="Anchor528692" role="Index"
        xreflabel="firmed orders:deletion of" /> <indexterm
            significance="normal" zone="Anchor528692">
            <primary>firmed orders</primary>

            <secondary>deletion of</secondary>
          </indexterm>Delete Existing Firmed MRP Orders</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>Firmed MRP Orders: Select to delete existing Firmed
          Orders.</para>

          <para id="Para534842">A firm Planned Order is a Planned Order that
          has been solidified in the schedule. By default, firm Planned Orders
          are not deleted when MRP is run. Selecting this option overrides
          that default behavior. If firm Planned Orders are deleted when MRP
          is run, they will automatically be replaced by soft (i.e.,
          non-firmed) Planned Orders, assuming the demand for the requirements
          still exists.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>

    <tip>
      <para id="Para545155">Unposted Purchase Orders and Purchase Requests are
      considered as valid sources of supply when MRP is run.</para>
    </tip>

    <para id="Para545151">To the far right of the screen, the following
    buttons are available:</para>

    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para518643">CANCEL</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>Closes the screen without creating Planned Replenishment
          Orders by Planner Code, returning you to the application
          desktop.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para535752">CREATE</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>Creates Planned Replenishment Orders by Planner Code, using
          the specified parameters.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para537096">SUBMIT</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>Select to submit the MRP run to the Batch Manager. For
          additional information, see the <link endterm="Anchor61009"
          id="XRef547857" linkend="Anchor61009"> Submitting Reports and Jobs
          to the Batch Manager</link>"Topic: Submitting Reports and Jobs to
          the Batch Manager" section in the <link endterm="Anchor30917"
          id="XRef537101" linkend="Anchor30917"> System Module</link>System
          Module.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
  </section>
