<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section551404" role="openmfg">
  <title>Run MRP by Planner Code</title>
  <para>When you run MRP by Planner Code, you are running the Material
  Requirements Planning (MRP) system. This utility creates Planned
  Replenishment Orders to meet existing Sales Order and Work Order demand.
  Replenishment Orders will be created whenever a Planned Availability for an
  Item Site falls below its Reorder Level. The quantity of the Replenishment
  Order will be enough to restore Planned Availability back to the Reorder
  Level--or to the Order Up To (OUT) Level, if the OUT Level is
  greater.</para>
  <note>
    <para>Running MRP by Planner Code may be used to generate Planned Orders
    for both parent-level manufactured Items and also lower level purchased
    Items. Only Items designated as MRP Items will be affected by an MRP
    run.</para>
  </note>
  <para>To run MRP by Planner Code, select the "Run MRP by Planner Code"
  option. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para>
<screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata id="Graphic520460" fileref="images/createPlannedOrdersByPlannerCode.png"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption518625">Run MRP by Planner Code</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
</para>
  <note>
    <para>The system deletes any non-firmed Planned Orders when MRP is run. If
    demand for the deleted Planned Orders still exists, the Orders will be
    replaced by new Replenishment Orders having new Planned Order Numbers.
    Order quantities will also be updated if demand levels have changed since
    MRP was last run.</para>
  </note>
  <para>When running MRP by Planner Code, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>All Planner Codes</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to create Planned Replenishment Orders for all Planner
        Codes.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Selected</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify Planner Code you want to create Planned Replenishment
        Orders for.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Pattern</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a Planner Code pattern to select a range of Planner Codes.
        Refine your search using Regular Expressions, as described in <xref linkend="Anchor77806"/>.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>All Warehouses</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to create Planned Replenishment Orders by Planner Code
        for all Warehouses.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Selected</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify Warehouse Planned Replenishment Orders should be created
        for.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Cutoff Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify how far into the future the MRP run should look for
        demand.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>If you schedule an MRP or MPS job submitted to the Batch Manager to
    run on a periodic basis--daily, weekly, monthly--the cutoff date used for
    the run will automatically be updated by the number of days in the
    specified reschedule interval (Day = +1, Week = +7, and Month =
    +30).</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>
<indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>firmed orders</primary>
          <secondary>deletion of</secondary>
        </indexterm>Delete Existing Firmed MRP Orders</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Firmed MRP Orders: Select to delete existing Firmed Orders. A
        firm Planned Order is a Planned Order that has been solidified in the
        schedule. By default, firm Planned Orders are not deleted when MRP is
        run. Selecting this option overrides that default behavior. If firm
        Planned Orders are deleted when MRP is run, they will automatically be
        replaced by soft (i.e., non-firmed) Planned Orders, assuming the
        demand for the requirements still exists.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>Unposted Purchase Orders and Purchase Requests are considered as
    valid sources of supply when MRP is run.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without creating Planned Replenishment Orders
        by Planner Code, returning you to the application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CREATE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Creates Planned Replenishment Orders by Planner Code, using the
        specified parameters.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SUBMIT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to submit the MRP run to the Batch Manager. For
        additional information, see <xref linkend="Anchor61009"/>.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
