<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section>
  <title>
<indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>credit memos</primary>
      <secondary>adding line items to</secondary>
    </indexterm>Credit Memo Item</title>
  <para>To create a new Credit Memo Line Item, select the NEW button. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para>
<screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata id="Graphic551869" fileref="images/creditMemoItem.png"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption551872">Create New Credit Memo Line Item</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
</para>
  <para>When creating a new Credit Memo Line Item, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Order #</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1930d44">
        <para>Displays the Credit Memo number for the current Credit
        Memo.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Line #</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1930d8c">
        <para>Displays the line number assigned to the Credit Memo
        Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Number</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1930dd4">
        <para>Enter the Item Number of the Item you want to add to the Credit
        Memo. If the Credit Memo is being applied to an Invoice, only those
        Line Items which appeared on the Invoice will be available for
        selection--that is, if the appropriate setting is selected at the
        system level. Invoices are selected for application by a Credit Memo
        using the "Apply To" feature on the Credit Memo header screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>The system-level configuration which determines whether Credit Memo
    Items will be restricted to relevant Invoice Items is the setting
    "Restrict Credit Memos to Items that appear on their Apply-To Document."
    Selecting this option narrows the Credit Memo Item selection process to
    only those Items which appeared on the Invoice the Credit Memo is being
    applied to. If not selected, a sold Item master list will appear instead
    when selecting Credit Memo Items for Credit Memos applied to a specific
    Invoice. This setting has no bearing on unapplied Credit Memos.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>UOM</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1930e64">
        <para>Inventory Unit of Measure.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. Shipped</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1930eac">
        <para>Displays the quantity of the Item shipped to date.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. Returned</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1930ef4">
        <para>Enter the quantity of the Item returned for credit.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. To Credit</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1930f3c">
        <para>Enter the quantity of the Item you plan to give the Customer
        credit for. The quantity entered here may equal the quantity returned.
        However, you have the flexibility to credit the Customer for a
        quantity different from the returned quantity. The quantity credited
        is multiplied by the Net Unit Price to determine the amount of the
        credit.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>
<indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>credit memos</primary>
          <secondary>pricing of</secondary>
        </indexterm>Net Unit Price</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1930fcc">
        <para>Specify the Net Unit Price to assign the quantity being
        credited. If the Credit Memo is being applied to a specific Invoice,
        then the system will automatically enter the Item's Net Unit Price as
        it appeared on the referring Invoice. If no Invoice is being
        applied-to, then select the appropriate Net Unit Price from the Price
        list, using the browse button located to the right of the
        field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>If there is only one Unit Price available for the Item, then that
    Price will be entered automatically when you select the browse button
    located to the right of the field.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Extended Price</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x193105c">
        <para>Displays the Extended Price. The Extended Price for a Credit
        Memo Item is based on the quantity credited multiplied by the
        Price.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Tax Type</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19310a4">
        <para>Specify the Tax Type for the Credit Memo Item. By default, the
        Item's Tax Type corresponding to the Credit Memo's Tax Authority will
        be presented here. The link between Tax Types and Tax Authorities is
        made on the Item master. If the Item master does not have a Tax Type
        for the Credit Memo's Tax Authority, then no Tax will be
        charged.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Tax Code</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19310ec">
        <para>Specify the Tax Code to be applied to the Credit Memo Item. By
        default, the Tax Code specified in the Tax Selection matrix will be
        displayed here. For a Tax Code to be used, the matrix must have an
        entry which matches both the Item's Tax Type definition and the Tax
        Authority specified on the Credit Memo header. If no Tax Selection
        match exists, then no Tax Code will be used--meaning no Tax will be
        charged.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>The relationship between Tax Authorities, Tax Types, and Tax Codes
    is established in the Tax Selection matrix.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Tax</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x193117c">
        <para>Displays the amount of Tax to be charged for the Credit Memo
        Line Item quantity. Sales Tax is calculated at the Credit Memo Line
        Item level. To get a detailed view of the Tax calculation, click on
        the Tax link using your mouse.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Reason Code</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19311c4">
        <para>Specify the reason why an adjustment is being made to a
        Customer's account.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>By default, the Reason Code on the Credit Memo header will be used
    at the Line Item level. However, you may change the Reason Code for
    individual Line Items.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Pricing UOM</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1931254">
        <para>Displays the Item's Price UOM.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Ratio</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x193129c">
        <para>Displays the Item's Price/Inventory UOM ratio.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Unit Cost</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19312e4">
        <para>Displays the Standard Cost per unit.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>List Price</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x193132c">
        <para>Displays the Item's List Price per unit displays.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Sale Price</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1931374">
        <para>Displays the sold Price for the Item at the time of sale.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>
<indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>credit memos</primary>
          <secondary>discount pricing for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Discount % from List</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1931404">
        <para>The default Customer discount (if any) will display here.
        Default Customer discount percentages are defined in the Customer
        master.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Discount % from Sale</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x193144c">
        <para>Specify a percentage to reduce the credited amount by. The
        discount will be deducted from the sale Price, thereby reducing the
        amount of the credit by the specified percentage.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Receiving Whse</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1931494">
        <para>Specify the Warehouse returned Inventory will be received into.
        Items designated as Multiple Location Control Items may be received
        into multiple Warehouses. If this is the case, be sure to specify the
        correct receiving Warehouse when entering a Credit Memo Line Item. The
        receiving Warehouse will not necessarily be the same Warehouse as the
        Warehouse the Item was shipped from.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Notes</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19314dc">
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        Notes related to the Credit Memo Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1931548">
        <para>Closes the screen without creating a new Credit Memo Item,
        returning you to the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1931590">
        <para>Creates the new Credit Memo Item and adds it to the list of
        Credit Memo Line Items.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
