<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section590528">
  <title id="Anchor94106"><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>credit memos</primary>
      <secondary>creating new</secondary>
    </indexterm> New Credit Memo</title>
  <para>To create a Credit Memo, select the "New Credit Memo" option. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/SO_Bill_creditMemoNew.png"
                     id="Graphic523497" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption519389">Create New Credit Memo</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Memo #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Next available Credit Memo Number will automatically display,
        unless your system requires you to enter Credit Memo Numbers
        manually.</para>
        <para>Default values and input parameters for Credit Memo Numbers are
        configurable at the system level.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Memo Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a date representing the date when you want the Credit Memo
        to be distributed. When a Credit Memo is posted, it is posted
        effective as of the Memo date.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Status</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Indicates whether Credit Memo is posted or unposted.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>The quickest way to fill in the Credit Memo screen may be to select
    the Invoice you intend to credit using the "Apply To" feature. If you use
    this feature, most of the fields in the Credit Memo screen will
    automatically populate with the needed Customer information.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>credit memos</primary>
          <secondary>customers associated with</secondary>
        </indexterm>Customer #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the Customer Number of the Customer you want to issue the
        Credit Memo to. The browse button located to the right of the field
        leads to a searchable Customers list. You may also access this list
        using the keyboard shortcut "CTRL + L". Once a Customer Number is
        entered, the Customer name and billing address will display. Select
        the "?" or "$" symbol next to the browse button to view Customer
        information for the specified Customer. If a Customer's credit is "In
        Good Standing," the button will feature a black question mark ("?")
        icon. If the icon turns to an orange dollar sign ("$"), the Customer's
        credit Status is "On Credit Warning." A red dollar sign ("$")
        indicates the Customer's credit Status is "On Credit Hold."</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>Credit Memos may be entered for inactive Customers. The same does
    not hold true for Sales Orders.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>credit memos</primary>
          <secondary>billing information for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Bill-To Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Customer's Bill-To name.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Bill-To Phone</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Customer's Bill-To phone number.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Address</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Customer's Bill-To Address. You may manually
        override the displayed Address information in the fields below--or use
        the browse button to select another Address.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Street Address</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The Customer's Bill-To street Address.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>City</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The Customer's Bill-To city.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>State:</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The Customer's Bill-To state.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Postal Code</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The Customer's Bill-To Postal Code.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Country</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The Customer's Bill-To country.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Copy to Ship-to -\&gt;</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to copy contents of billing address into Ship-To address
        field. This option is enabled if the Customer master for the specified
        Customer indicates that free-form Ship-To's are allowed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Ship-To #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the number of the preferred Ship-To Address. Customers may
        maintain multiple Ship-To Addresses. If the Customer master for the
        specified Customer indicates that free-form Ship-To's are allowed,
        then any address may be entered. If free-form Ship-To's are not
        allowed, then the Ship-To Address must be entered using the browse
        button located to the right of the field. The browse button leads to a
        searchable Ship-To Addresses list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>credit memos</primary>
          <secondary>ship-to details for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Ship-To Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the name for the specified Ship-To.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Ship-To Phone</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the phone number for the specified Ship-To.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Address</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the specified Ship-To Address. You may manually
        override the displayed Address information in the fields below--or use
        the browse button to select another Address.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Street Address</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The specified Ship-To street Address.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>City</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The specified Ship-To city.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>State</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The specified Ship-To state.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Postal Code</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The specified Ship-To Postal Code.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Country</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The specified Ship-To country.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Apply To</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the Invoice Number of the Invoice you want to apply the
        Credit Memo to, using the browse button located to the right of the
        field. The list will include Invoices for the specified Customer. If a
        Credit Memo is applied to a specific Invoice, the Credit Memo may only
        credit Items which appeared on the chosen Invoice. If for some reason
        the Credit Memo is applied to a closed Invoice, the Credit Memo will
        be listed as an unapplied Credit Memo.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>You are not required to apply a Credit Memo to a specific Invoice.
    If a Credit Memo is applied to an Invoice, any Credit Memo Items will be
    returned to Inventory when the Credit Memo is posted.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Sales Rep.</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the Sales Representative associated with the Order. By
        default, the Customer's designated Sales Representative will appear in
        the field--except if you have selected an Invoice to apply the Credit
        Memo to. In that case, the Sales Representative credited with the
        Invoice will be selected.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Commission</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>By default, the commission percentage recorded on the Customer
        master will be automatically entered in this field. If for some reason
        you select a non-default Sales Representative at Credit Memo entry,
        the commission rate will not change. To adjust the commission rate,
        you must make the change manually.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>tax authorities</primary>
          <secondary>for credit memos</secondary>
        </indexterm>Tax Authority</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the Tax Authority associated with the Credit Memo. The
        Tax Authority for the specified Ship-To Address will be entered here
        by default. Otherwise, the primary Tax Authority for the Customer will
        be entered. Ultimately, Tax is applied at the Line Item level--so the
        Tax Authority associated with an Item's Tax Type will be used.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Ship-To #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the number of the preferred Ship-To Address.</para>
        <para>Customers may maintain multiple Ship-To Addresses. If Pricing
        Schedules by Ship-To are maintained for the Customer, the Ship-To
        Address must match the Pricing Schedule to successfully issue credit
        for Items linked exclusively to the Pricing Schedule. The browse
        button located to the right of the field leads to a searchable Ship-To
        Addresses list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>Make sure the Ship-To Address on the Credit Memo matches the Ship-To
    Address on the Customer's Pricing Schedule. If they don"t match, you won"t
    be able to issue credit for exclusively sold Items.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Cust. PO #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>By default, the Customer Purchase Order Number associated with
        the Invoice being credited will display here. If no Customer Purchase
        Order Number was entered at the time of the original Sales Order--or
        if the Credit Memo is not being applied to a specific Invoice--the
        field will remain blank. Enter or edit a Customer Purchase Order
        Number as necessary.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Reason Code</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the reason why an adjustment is being made to a
        Customer's account.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>credit memos</primary>
          <secondary>hold options for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Place on Hold</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to place Credit Memo on hold. If a Credit Memo is placed
        on hold, it cannot be posted. You would place a Credit Memo on hold,
        for example, to allow time for producing and processing a Return
        Material Authorization (RMA) document. To remove a hold and allow
        posting of a Credit Memo, de-select this option.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Creates the new Credit Memo and saves the Credit Memo
        information.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without creating a new Credit Memo, returning
        you to the application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>credit memos</primary>
      <secondary>adding line items to</secondary>
    </indexterm>To create or modify Credit Memo Line Items, select the "Line
  Items" tab at the top of the "Credit Memo" screen. The following screen will
  appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/SO_Bill_credMemLineItems.png"
                     id="Graphic551633" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption551636">Credit Memo Line Items</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When creating or modifying Credit Memo Line Items, you are presented
  with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Line Items</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists Sales Order Line Item quantities that have been
        returned and selected for credit. Line Items are added to a Credit
        Memo using the NEW ITEM button.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>Before creating a new Credit Memo Line Item, be sure to specify an
    Invoice to apply the Credit Memo to. The "Apply To" feature is found on
    the Credit Memo header screen.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Subtotal</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the subtotal for the Credit Memo Line Items.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>credit memos</primary>
          <secondary>charges related to</secondary>
        </indexterm>Misc. Charge Amount</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the amount of the miscellaneous charge. Before entering a
        miscellaneous charge amount, you must first assign the charge to a
        Sales Account and also enter a description of the charge.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Misc. Charge Description</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a description to identify the miscellaneous charge.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Misc. Charge Credit Account</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a Credit Account to assign the miscellaneous charge
        to.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Freight</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the amount of freight charge to be added to the specified
        Order. The freight charge may be entered during the creation or
        modification of a Credit Memo--or at the time of shipment.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Tax</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the total amount of Tax to be charged on the Credit
        Memo. Sales Tax is calculated at the Credit Memo Line Item level. The
        Tax amount displayed here represents the total for all Line Item Tax
        amounts. To get a detailed view of the Tax calculation, click on the
        Tax link using your mouse.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Total</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the total amount of the Credit Memo.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Saves new Credit Memo Line Items and updates any changes made to
        existing Line Items.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without creating a new Credit Memo Line Item
        or saving any changes, returning you to the application
        desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW ITEM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Opens screen for creating a new Credit Memo Line Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>EDIT ITEM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enables you to edit highlighted Credit Memo Line Item. The edit
        screen is the same as that for creating a new Credit Memo Line
        Item--except that when editing, the fields will contain Line Item
        information. Double-clicking on a Line Item will also bring you to the
        editing screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>DELETE ITEM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a Credit Memo Line Item and then select this button to
        remove the Line Item from the Credit Memo list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To add Notes to a Credit Memo, select the "Notes" tab at the top of
  the "Credit Memo" screen. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/SO_Bill_credMemNotes.png"
                     id="Graphic551698" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption551701">Credit Memo Notes</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When adding Notes to a Credit Memo, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Notes</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        Notes related to the Credit Memo. Notes entered on this screen will
        follow the Credit Memo through the billing process. For example, you
        may view notes associated with a posted Credit Memo within the
        Customer History report.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Saves the Credit Memo Notes.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without creating a Credit Memo Notes,
        returning you to the application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <xi:include href="creditMemoItem.xml"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
              xpointer="element(/1)" />
</section>
