<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section967998">
   <title>
      
      <indexterm significance="normal">
         <primary>custom commands</primary>
         <secondary>master list of</secondary>
      </indexterm> 
      <indexterm significance="normal">
         <primary>menus</primary>
         <secondary>customizing</secondary>
      </indexterm> 
      <indexterm significance="normal">
         <primary>commands</primary>
         <secondary>adding custom</secondary>
      </indexterm>List Custom Commands</title>
   <para id="Para968011">If you want to execute external programs from within
  the menu structure, you can do so using the Custom Commands utility. This
  utility enables you to create custom menu options, which users may then
  select to launch specified programs. Custom Commands are well-suited for
  running custom reports. However, they may be used to execute a wide range of
  programs, for a variety of purposes. To access the master list of Custom
  Commands, select the "Custom Commands" option. The following screen will
  appear:</para>
   <para id="Para967782">
      <screenshot>
         <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
               <imagedata fileref="images/Sys_custCommList.png" id="Graphic967780"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption id="Caption967783">Custom Commands List</caption>
         </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
   </para>
   <note>
      <para id="Para969525">There is no limit to the number of Custom Commands
    which may be added to a module. Executable programs may be launched from
    local or network drives.</para>
   </note>
   <para id="Para967958">The Custom Commands master list displays information
  on all Custom Commands, including module name and menu label.</para>
   <para id="Para967959">To the far right of the list, the following buttons
  are available:</para>
   <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para967786">CLOSE</term>
         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1890b84">
            <para>Closes the screen, returning you to the application
        desktop.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para967788">NEW</term>
         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1890bcc">
            <para>Opens screen for adding a new Custom Command to the master list
        of Custom Commands.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para967789">EDIT</term>
         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1890c14">
            <para>Enables you to edit highlighted Custom Command definitions. The
        edit screen is the same as that for creating a new Custom Command
        definition--except that when editing, the fields will contain Custom
        Command information. Double-clicking on a Custom Command definition
        will also bring you to the editing screen.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para967791">DELETE</term>
         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1890c5c">
            <para>Highlight a Custom Command definition and then select this
        button to remove the Custom Command from the master list.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
   </variablelist>
</section>