<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section>
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>customer types</primary>
      <secondary>creating new</secondary>
    </indexterm>Customer Type</title>
  <para id="Para573436">To create a new Customer Type, select the NEW button.
  The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para id="Para573440"><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/customerType.png" id="Graphic573438" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption573441">Create New Customer Type</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <tip>
    <para id="Para573443">Create your Customer Types using a logical,
    hierarchical structure. This will make it easier to retrieve Customer Type
    information in the future. For more information on matching patterns using
    Regular Expressions, see <xref linkend="Anchor77806" />.</para>
  </tip>
  <para id="Para573447">When creating a new Customer Type, you are presented
  with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para573448">Code</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a code number to identify the Customer Type.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para573449">Description</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a description to identify the Customer Type.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Enable Characteristics Profile</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to enforce the use of a Characteristics template for any
        Customer assigned to the specified Customer Type. If Characteristics
        Profiles are used, the full slate of Characteristics and corresponding
        Values will be presented in the Characteristics Tab of the Customer
        master for every Customer assigned to the Customer Type. If not
        selected, the template approach will not be used--and users will have
        the ability to create ad hoc Characteristics for Customers.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para id="Para573450">To the far right of the screen, the following buttons
  are available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para573451">CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without creating a Customer Type, returning
        you to the application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para573452">SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Creates the Customer Type and adds it to the master list of
        Customer Types.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Opens screen for creating a new Customer Characteristic to be
        added to the Profile.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>EDIT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enables you to edit highlighted Customer Characteristics. The
        edit screen is the same as that for creating a new Customer
        Characteristic--except that when editing, the fields will contain
        Customer Characteristic information. Double-clicking on a Customer
        Characteristic will also bring you to the editing screen. </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>DELETE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a Customer Characteristic and then select this button
        to remove the Characteristic from the list. </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To create a new Customer Characteristic, select the NEW button. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <screenshot>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/characteristicAssignmentCustomer.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption><para>Create New Customer Characteristic</para></caption>
    </mediaobject>
  </screenshot>
  <para>When creating a new Customer Characteristic, you are presented with
  the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Characteristic</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select a Characteristic from the list of Characteristics
        designated as being available for use as Customer
        Characteristics.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Value</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a description of the Customer Characteristic.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without creating the Customer Characteristic,
        returning you to the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Creates the Customer Characteristic and adds it to the list of
        Customer Characteristics.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>