<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section656540">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>customers</primary>
      <secondary>creating new</secondary>
    </indexterm>Enter New Customer</title>
  <para>Maintaining detailed Customer information is essential to ensuring a
  successful Customer relationship. To enter a new Customer into the system,
  select the "New Customer" option. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/SO_MI_custCreateNew.png"
                     id="Graphic656543" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption656546">Create New Customer</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <tip>
    <para>Customers can also be created from the CRM Account screen. Simply
    enter a new CRM Account, selecting the "Customer" Relationship
    option.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>When creating a new Customer, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Customer #</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x181a0d0">
        <para>The Customer Number uniquely identifies the Customer.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Customer Type</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x181a118">
        <para>Specify the Customer Type the Customer belongs to.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Customer Name</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x181a160">
        <para>Enter the name of the Customer or company you are doing business
        with. This field should not to be confused with the contact name of an
        individual at the company.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Active</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x181a1a8">
        <para>Select if you are actively doing business with this
        Customer.</para>
        <para>Not selecting makes the Customer inactive.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Sales Rep</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x181a1f0">
        <para>Specify a default Sales Representative for the Customer.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>When entering Orders for a Customer, the Sales Representative
    defined on the specified Ship-To Address will be used.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Commission</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x181a280">
        <para>Specify the commission percentage for the selected Sales
        Representative.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Defaults</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x181a2c8">
        <para>Specify one of the available Shipping-related defaults:</para>
        <para>Ship Via: Specify the default Ship Via to be used for the
        Customer. You may enter a free-form Ship Via simply by typing the name
        of the Ship Via into the field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>The system supports up-to-date shipment tracking with links to the
    websites of many leading shipping companies (i.e., "Ship Vias").</para>
  </tip>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x181a334">
      <para>Shipping Form: Specify the default Shipping Form to be used for
      the Customer.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x181a358">
      <para>Shipping Charges: Specify the default Shipping Charges to be used
      for the Customer.</para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <note>
    <para>Shipping defaults specified on the Customer master will transfer to
    the Sales Order header when a new Sales Order is entered for a
    Customer.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>backorders</primary>
          <secondary>accepted by customer</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>customers</primary>
          <secondary>backorders accepted by</secondary>
        </indexterm>Accepts Backorders</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x181a478">
        <para>Select to indicate whether the Customer accepts
        Backorders.</para>
        <para>A backorder is defined as an unshipped Line Item on a shipped
        Sales Order. For example, if a Customer orders three Line Items, but
        only one of the Line Items is shipped, the remaining two Line Items
        would be on backorder. Not selecting this option indicates the
        Customer does not accept backorders or partial shipments.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>Sales Orders having unshipped Line Items on backorder will be closed
    at billing (i.e., when an Invoice is created) if the Customer in question
    is flagged to not accept backorders.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>customers</primary>
          <secondary>order preferences for</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>shipments</primary>
          <secondary>partial</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>customers</primary>
          <secondary>partial shipments accepted by</secondary>
        </indexterm> Accepts Partial Shipments</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x181a5e0">
        <para>Accepts Partial Shipments: Select to indicate whether the
        Customer accepts partial shipments.</para>
        <para>A partial shipment is defined as a shipped Order having a Line
        Item whose full quantity is not included in the shipment. For example,
        if Customer ABC orders 20 units of Item XYZ, but only 10 units are
        shipped, that partial Line Item quantity ("10") would constitute a
        partial shipment of the ordered Item. Not selecting this option
        indicates the Customer does not accept partial shipments.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>Partially-shipped Line Items will be closed at billing (i.e., when
    an Invoice is created) if the Customer in question is flagged to not
    accept partial shipments.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Allow Free-Form Ship-To"s</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x181a670">
        <para>Select to indicate that free-form Ship-To Addresses may be
        entered when Sales Orders are created for the Customer.</para>
        <para>If not selected, you are indicating that free-form Ship-To's may
        not be entered for the Customer. Instead, Ship-To's must be entered
        using predefined information.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Allow Free-Form Bill-To</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x181a6b8">
        <para>Select to indicate that free-form Bill-To Addresses may be
        entered when Sales Orders are created for the Customer.</para>
        <para>If not selected, you are indicating that free-form Bill-To's may
        not be entered for the Customer. Instead, the predefined Bill-To found
        on the Customer master will be used.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Preferred Selling Whs.</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x181a700">
        <para>Specify the preferred selling Warehouse, if any.</para>
        <para>This is an optional setting. If a preferred Warehouse is
        selected, then this Warehouse will be used when entering Sales Orders
        for the Customer. At Sales Order entry, the preferred Warehouse will
        be the default Shipping Warehouse for the Sales Order--as well as the
        default selling Warehouse for Sales Order Items.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>If there are no Item Sites matching the preferred Warehouse at the
    point of Sales Order Line Item entry, the highest-ranked selling Warehouse
    will be used instead.</para>
  </note>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x181a790">
        <para>Closes the screen without creating the Customer, returning you
        to the application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x181a7d8">
        <para>Creates the Customer and enters the Customer into the master
        list of Customers.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To view or enter Customer Tax information, select the "Tax" tab. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/SO_MI_custTaxReg.png" id="Graphic656590" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption656593">Customer Tax Information</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>customers</primary>
      <secondary>tax information for</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>taxes</primary>
      <secondary>for customers</secondary>
    </indexterm>When adding Customer Tax information, you are presented with
  the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>tax authorities</primary>
          <secondary>default for customers</secondary>
        </indexterm>Default Tax Authority</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x181a988">
        <para>Specify the primary Tax Authority you want to associate with the
        Customer.</para>
        <para>By default, the specified Tax Authority will be used on the
        Sales Order header whenever entering Sales Orders or Quotes for the
        Customer.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Tax Registration Numbers</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x181a9d0">
        <para>Display lists Tax Registration Numbers for the specified
        Customer.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x181aa3c">
        <para>Opens screen for creating a new Customer Tax Registration
        Number.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>EDIT</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x181aa84">
        <para>Enables you to edit highlighted Customer Tax Registration
        Numbers. The edit screen is the same as that for creating a new
        Customer Tax Registration Number--except that when editing, the fields
        will contain Customer Tax Registration Number information.
        Double-clicking on a Customer Tax Registration Number will also bring
        you to the editing screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>VIEW</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x181aacc">
        <para>Highlight a Customer Tax Registration Number and then select
        this button to reach a read-only view of the "Edit" screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>DELETE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x181ab14">
        <para>Highlight a Customer Tax Registration Number and then select
        this button to remove the Customer Tax Registration Number from the
        list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To add a new Customer Tax Registration Number, select the NEW button.
  The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/SO_MI_custTaxRegNew.png"
                     id="Graphic656607" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption656610">Customer Tax Registration
        Information</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>customers</primary>
      <secondary>tax registration for</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>taxes</primary>
      <secondary>registration for customers</secondary>
    </indexterm>When adding a new Customer Tax Registration Number, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Customer #</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x182d86c">
        <para>Displays the Customer Number for the specified Customer.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Tax Authority</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x182d8b4">
        <para>Specify the Tax Authority associated with the Tax Registration
        Number.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Registration Number</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x182d8fc">
        <para>Enter the Customer's Tax Registration Number for the specified
        Tax Authority.</para>
        <para>The registration number is used by Tax Authorities to identify
        businesses and/or individuals. An Employer Identification Numbers
        (EIN) is an example of a Tax Registration Number.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>The Customer's Tax Registration Number is used for identifying the
    Customer to relevant Tax Authorities. This information should not be
    confused with the Tax Registration Numbers, which are used to identify
    your company to relevant Tax Authorities.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x182d98c">
        <para>Closes the screen without creating a new Customer Tax
        Registration Number, returning you to the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x182d9d4">
        <para>Creates the Customer Tax Registration Number and adds it to the
        master list of Customer Tax Registration Numbers.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To view or edit Customer credit terms, select the "Credit" tab. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/SO_MI_custCredit.png" id="Graphic656624" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption656627">Customer Credit Terms</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When adding a Customer credit terms, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Default Terms</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x182daac">
        <para>Specify the default billing Terms for the Customer.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Balance Method</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x182daf4">
        <para>Specify one of the available methods for handling open balances
        for the Customer:</para>
        <para>Balance Forward - Select to post payments against the oldest
        Invoices. Used in Accounts Receivable only.</para>
        <para>Open Items - Select to post payments against specific Invoices,
        regardless of their age. Used in Accounts Receivable only.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Default Discount</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x182db3c">
        <para>Enter the default discount--if any--which the Customer should
        receive.</para>
        <para>Customer discounts are applied to either a) the List Price for
        an Item if the List Price is being used or b) a specific Sale if a
        Sale is in place which the Customer is assigned to. The discount does
        not get applied to Pricing Schedules.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Credit Limit</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x182db84">
        <para>Specify the credit ceiling you are willing to extend to the
        Customer.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>customers</primary>
          <secondary>credit rating options for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Credit Rating</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x182dc14">
        <para>You have the option of assigning a credit rating to the
        Customer. Any value entered here is purely informational. The system
        does not use the credit rating in any calculations.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Credit Status</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x182dc5c">
        <para>Select one from the list below by clicking on the radio button
        to the left of the option.</para>
        <para>In Good Standing: Select to mark the Customer as having credit
        in good standing. Customers with credit "In Good Standing" may have
        Sales Orders issued for them. A black-colored typeface will be
        associated with their account.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>Sales Orders may not be entered for Customers whose credit status is
    either "On Credit Warning" or "On Credit Hold." Credit Holds may be
    overridden, but only by users having the appropriate privileges.</para>
  </note>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x182dcc8">
      <para>On Credit Warning: Select to alert sales staff to possible credit
      problems with the Customer. Customers with credit "On Credit Warning"
      may not have Sales Orders issued for them. An orange-colored typeface
      will be associated with their account.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x182dcec">
      <para>On Credit Hold: Select to inform sales staff that Customer's
      credit has been suspended. Customers with credit "On Credit Hold" may
      not have Sales Orders issued for them. A red-colored typeface will be
      associated with their account.</para>
      <para>Uses Purchase Orders: Select to indicate that the Customer uses
      Purchase Orders.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x182dd10">
      <para>If selected, users will be required to enter a Customer Purchase
      Order Number when entering a Sales Order. In addition, selecting the
      option will prevent users from entering duplicate Customer Purchase
      Order Numbers--unless the Customer is marked as using Blanket
      POs.</para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <note>
    <para>If the option "Uses Purchase Orders" is not selected, the system
    will place no restrictions on Customer Purchase Order Numbers.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>purchase orders</primary>
          <secondary>customers using blanket</secondary>
        </indexterm>Uses Blanket P/O"s</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x182dde8">
        <para>Blanket P/O"s: Select to indicate that the Customer uses blanket
        Purchase Orders.</para>
        <para>A blanket P/O is a Customer Purchase Order which may be used for
        more than one Sales Order. Selecting this option means users will be
        allowed to enter duplicate Purchase Order Numbers for this
        Customer.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Place on Credit Warning when Credit Limit is Exceeded</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x182de30">
        <para>Select this option to automatically place the Customer on Credit
        Warning if their open Accounts Receivable (A/R) balance exceeds their
        Credit Limit.</para>
        <para>If a Customer is on Credit Warning, Sales Orders may not be
        entered for the Customer--except by users with override privileges.
        Once the Customer's A/R open balance falls below their Credit Limit,
        Sales Orders may once again be entered for the Customer.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Place Open S/Os on Credit Hold when Credit Limit is
      Exceeded</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x182de78">
        <para>Select this option to place all new and existing open Sales
        Orders on Credit Hold if the Customer's Credit Limit is
        exceeded.</para>
        <para>The contents of Sales Orders placed on Credit Hold may not be
        issued to Shipping--except by users with override privileges. Once the
        Customer's Credit Limit is no longer exceeded, Sales Order contents
        may be issued to Shipping.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To view or edit Customer Addresses, select the "Addresses" tab. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/SO_MI_custAddresses.png"
                     id="Graphic656657" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption656660">Customer Addresses</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>customers</primary>
      <secondary>addresses for</secondary>
    </indexterm>When adding addresses to a Customer master, you are presented
  with the following options:</para>
  <note>
    <para>If a new Contact is manually entered here, that Contact will be
    added automatically to the master list of Contacts.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Billing Contact</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x182dfbc">
        <para>Manually enter billing Contact information in the fields
        below--or use the browse button to select pre-existing Contact
        information.</para>
        <para>Title: Select a Title from the list of available Titles.</para>
        <para>First: Enter the Contact's first name.</para>
        <para>Last: Enter the Contact's last name.</para>
        <para>Job Title: Enter the Contact's job title.</para>
        <para>Voice: Enter the Contact's phone number.</para>
        <para>Fax: Enter the Contact's fax number.</para>
        <para>E-Mail: Enter the Contact's e-mail address.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>If a new Address is manually entered here, that Address will be
    added automatically to the master list of Addresses.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Address</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x182e04c">
        <para>Manually enter billing Address information in the fields
        below--or use the browse button to select pre-existing Address
        information.</para>
        <para>Street Address: Enter the street Address for the Contact.</para>
        <para>City: Enter the city where the Contact is located.</para>
        <para>State: Enter the state where the Contact is located.</para>
        <para>Postal Code: Enter the Postal Code for the Contact.</para>
        <para>Country: Enter the country where the Contact is located.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Correspondence Contact</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x182e094">
        <para>Manually enter non-billing-related Contact information in the
        fields below--or use the browse button to select pre-existing Contact
        information. Examples of non-billing-related correspondence might
        include Price updates, holiday cards, etc. You may also enter
        additional contact information.</para>
        <para>Title: Select a Title from the list of available Titles.</para>
        <para>First: Enter the Contact's first name.</para>
        <para>Last: Enter the Contact's last name.</para>
        <para>Job Title: Enter the Contact's job title.</para>
        <para>Voice: Enter the Contact's phone number.</para>
        <para>Fax: Enter the Contact's fax number.</para>
        <para>E-Mail: Enter the Contact's e-mail address.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Address</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x182e0dc">
        <para>Manually enter non-billing Address information in the fields
        below--or use the browse button to select pre-existing Address
        information.</para>
        <para>Street Address: Enter the street Address for the Contact.</para>
        <para>City: Enter the city where the Contact is located.</para>
        <para>State: Enter the state where the Contact is located.</para>
        <para>Postal Code: Enter the Postal Code for the Contact.</para>
        <para>Country: Enter the country where the Contact is located.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Ship-To Addresses</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x182e124">
        <para>Display lists Ship-To Addresses for the specified
        Customer.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>You can maintain multiple Ship-To Addresses for your Customers.
    Ship-To Addresses are selected at the point of Sales Order entry.</para>
  </note>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>PRINT</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x182e1b4">
        <para>Runs the report associated with this screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x182e1fc">
        <para>Opens screen for creating a new Ship-To Address.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>EDIT</term>
      <listitem id="customerShipToEDIT">
        <para>Enables you to edit highlighted Ship-To Address. The edit screen
        is the same as that for creating a new Ship-To Address--except that
        when editing, the fields will contain Ship-To Address information.
        Double-clicking on a Ship-To Address will also bring you to the
        editing screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>VIEW</term>
      <listitem id="customerShipToVIEW">
        <para>Highlight a Ship-To Address and then select this button to reach
        a read-only view of the "Edit" screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>DELETE</term>
      <listitem id="customerShipToDELETE">
        <para>Highlight a Ship-To Address and then select this button to
        remove the address from the master list of Ship-To Addresses.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>Right-clicking on a Ship-To Address in the Ship-To list enables you to
  select from the following menu options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Edit</term>
      <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                  xpointer="element(customerShipToEDIT)" />
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>View</term>
      <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                  xpointer="element(customerShipToVIEW)" />
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Delete</term>
      <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                  xpointer="element(customerShipToDELETE)" />
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>ship-to addresses</primary>
      <secondary>creating new</secondary>
    </indexterm>To create a new Ship-To Address for a Customer, select the NEW
  button. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/SO_MI_ship-ToCreate.png"
                     id="Graphic656712" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption656715">Create New Ship-To Address</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <tip>
    <para>The Ship-To master shares many common fields with the Customer
    master--shipping defaults, Sales Representative, etc. By default, the
    Customer master values will pre-populate the Ship-To master. However, when
    specifying a specific Ship-To Address on a Sales Order, the specific
    Ship-To details will populate the Sales Order header.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>When creating a new Ship-To Address, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Customer #</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x182e55c">
        <para>The Customer Number and Customer name specified in the Customer
        master will display here.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Ship-To #</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x182e5a4">
        <para>Specify a number or code to identify the Ship-To Address
        by.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Active</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x182e5ec">
        <para>Select to activate the Ship-To Address.</para>
        <para>If option is not selected, then the Ship-To Address is
        inactive.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Default</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1842a24">
        <para>Select if this is the default Ship-To Address for the
        Customer.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Name</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1842a6c">
        <para>Enter the name of the company that will receive shipments at
        this Ship-To Address. Customers may maintain multiple Ship-To
        Addresses with diverse destinations.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>If a new Address is manually entered here, that Address will be
    added automatically to the master list of Addresses.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Address</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1842afc">
        <para>Manually enter billing Address information in the fields
        below--or use the browse button to select pre-existing Address
        information.</para>
        <para>Street Address: Enter the street Address for the Contact.</para>
        <para>City: Enter the city where the Contact is located.</para>
        <para>State: Enter the state where the Contact is located.</para>
        <para>Postal Code: Enter the Postal Code for the Contact.</para>
        <para>Country: Enter the country where the Contact is located.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>If a new Contact is manually entered here, that Contact will be
    added automatically to the master list of Contacts.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>ship-to addresses</primary>
          <secondary>contact information for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Contact</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1842bd4">
        <para>Manually enter Contact information in the fields below--or use
        the browse button to select pre-existing Contact information. This
        field should not to be confused with the "Name" field that appears on
        the Ship-To Address label.</para>
        <para>Title: Select a Title from the list of available Titles.</para>
        <para>First: Enter the Contact's first name.</para>
        <para>Last: Enter the Contact's last name.</para>
        <para>Job Title: Enter the Contact's job title.</para>
        <para>Voice: Enter the Contact's phone number.</para>
        <para>Fax: Enter the Contact's fax number.</para>
        <para>E-Mail: Enter the Contact's e-mail address.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Sales Rep</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1842c1c">
        <para>Specify the Sales Representative for the Ship-To Address.</para>
        <para>When entering Orders for a Customer, the name of the Sales
        Representative specified on the Ship-To Address will be used.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Commission</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1842c64">
        <para>Field accepts up to 4 whole numbers and 2 decimals</para>
        <para>Enter the Commission rate to be used when Sales Orders for this
        Customer are shipped to the specified Ship-To Address.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Zone</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1842cac">
        <para>Specify the Zone for the Ship-To Address.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Tax Code</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1842cf4">
        <para>Specify Tax Code to be used for Ship-To Address.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Defaults</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1842d3c">
        <para>Select one of the available Shipping-related defaults:</para>
        <para>Ship Via: Specify the default Ship Via to be used for the
        Ship-To Address. You may enter a free-form Ship Via simply by typing
        the name of the Ship Via into the field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>The system supports up-to-date shipment tracking with links to the
    websites of many leading shipping companies (i.e., "Ship Vias").</para>
  </tip>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1842da8">
      <para>Shipping Form: Specify the default Shipping Form to be used for
      the Ship-To Address.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1842dcc">
      <para>Shipping Charges: Specify the default Shipping Charges to be used
      for the Ship-To Address.</para>
      <para>EDI Profile: Select one of the available EDI options:</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1842df0">
      <para>Different EDI Profiles may be specified for different Ship-To
      Addresses. However, if you want the default Profile to mirror the
      Customer master settings, select the "Use Customer Master"
      option.</para>
      <para>General Notes: Select the "General Notes" tab to access this
      scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering general Notes
      related to the Customer Ship-To Address. These Notes are for internal
      use only.</para>
      <para>Shipping Notes: Select the "Shipping Notes" tab to access this
      scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering Shipping Notes
      related to the Customer Ship-To Address. Shipping Notes are transferred
      to the "Shipping Notes" tab on the Sales Order header whenever a Sales
      Order for the specified Ship-To Address is entered.</para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1842e5c">
        <para>Closes the screen without adding Customer Address information,
        returning you to the application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1842ea4">
        <para>Saves any new Customer Address information.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>Any Notes added to the Customer master are for internal purposes only.
  To add Notes to a Customer master, select the "Notes" tab at the bottom of
  the "Customer" screen. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/SO_MI_custNotes.png" id="Graphic656768" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption656771">Add Customer Notes</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When adding Notes to a Customer master, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Notes</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1842f7c">
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        Notes related to the Customer. Any Notes entered on this screen are
        for internal purposes only.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CLOSE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1842fe8">
        <para>Closes the screen without creating the Customer Note, returning
        you to the application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1843030">
        <para>Creates the Customer Note and adds it to the Customer
        master.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>Customer Characteristics are user-defined definitions which may be
  used to provide additional layers of description about Customers. For
  example, Customer Characteristics might be used to specify "Order
  Preferences" or "Buying Season". These constitute static descriptions which
  are not processed by the system, but are useful for informational purposes.
  To enter <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>characteristics</primary>
      <secondary>creating new for customer</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>characteristics</primary>
      <secondary>customers having</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>customers</primary>
      <secondary>characteristics for</secondary>
    </indexterm>Characteristics associated with a Customer, select the
  "Characteristics" tab from the "Item" screen. The following screen will
  appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/SO_MI_custChar.png" id="Graphic656780" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption656783">Customer Characteristics</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Characteristics</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18431e0">
        <para>Display lists the Characteristics related to the
        Customer.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x184324c">
        <para>Opens screen for creating a new Customer Characteristic.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>EDIT</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1843294">
        <para>Enables you to edit highlighted Customer Characteristics. The
        edit screen is the same as that for creating a new Customer
        Characteristic--except that when editing, the fields will contain
        Customer Characteristic information. Double-clicking on a Customer
        Characteristic will also bring you to the editing screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>DELETE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18432dc">
        <para>Highlight a Customer Characteristic and then select this button
        to remove the Customer Characteristic from the list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To create a new Customer Characteristic, select the NEW button. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/SO_MI_custCharNew.png" id="Graphic656791" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption656794">Create New Customer
        Characteristic</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Characteristic</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18433b4">
        <para>Select a Characteristic from the list of Characteristics
        designated as being available for use as Customer
        Characteristics.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Value</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18433fc">
        <para>Enter a description of the Customer Characteristic.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1843468">
        <para>Closes the screen without creating the Customer Characteristic,
        returning you to the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18434b0">
        <para>Creates the Customer Characteristic and adds it to the list of
        Customer Characteristics.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To add Comments to a Customer master, select the "Comments" tab at the
  bottom of the "Customer" screen. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/SO_MI_custComment.png" id="Graphic656802" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption656805">Customer Comments</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When adding Comments to a Customer master, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Comments</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1843588">
        <para>Display lists Comments related to the Customer.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18435f4">
        <para>Opens the screen for creating a new Customer Comment.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>VIEW</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x184363c">
        <para>Opens a read-only view of the Customer Comment.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To enter a new Customer Comment, select the NEW button. The following
  screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/CommentNew.png" id="Graphic656813" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption656816">Create New Comment</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Comment Type</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1843714">
        <para>Specify one of the following Comment Types from the drop-down
        list: ChangeLog or General.</para>
        <para>Comment Types are used to categorize Comments. Once you have
        specified a Comment Type, you may type your Comment in the main text
        area. The text area features word-wrapping and scroll-bar support for
        longer Comments.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1843780">
        <para>Closes the screen without creating the Customer Comment,
        returning you to the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18437c8">
        <para>Creates the Comment and adds it to the list of Customer
        Comments.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para role="openmfg">The Electronic Data Interchange (EDI) system enables
  you to send Sales Orders and Invoices electronically to your Customers. To
  establish a Customer's EDI preferences for Sales Orders, select the "S/O
  EDI" tab. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/SO_MI_custSOEDI.png" id="Graphic656828" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption656831">Add Customer Sales Order EDI
        Information</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When setting up the Sales Order EDI preferences for a Customer, you
  are presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>EDI Profile</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x184bc90">
        <para>Select from the following EDI Profile options:</para>
        <para>No EDI: Select this option if you do not wish to use the EDI
        system.</para>
        <para>Custom Email: Select this option if you want to bypass standard
        EDI Profiles and instead create custom email preferences for the
        Customer. These preferences will be stored solely with the Customer
        master--and will be used to send email versions of Sales Orders to the
        Customer. When this option is selected, the email-related fields on
        the Customer master will be enabled. Otherwise, the email-related
        fields will be disabled.</para>
        <para>EDI Profile: Select a standard EDI Profile from the list of EDI
        Profiles. The selected Profile will be used when Sales Orders for the
        Customer are scheduled for email delivery.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>EDI Email</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x184bcd8">
        <para>Enter the Customer email address to be used as the default
        recipient address whenever Sales Orders are emailed to the Customer.
        Only applies when the "Custom Email" EDI Profile option is
        selected.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>Send Sales Orders to multiple recipients by separating email
    addresses with a comma. Be sure to omit any spaces between addresses when
    using commas to send copies to multiple recipients.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Cc</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x184bd68">
        <para>Enter the email address to be used as the default carbon copy
        address whenever Sales Orders are emailed to the Customer. Only
        applies when the "Custom Email" EDI Profile option is selected.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Subject</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x184bdb0">
        <para>Enter a default email subject line to be used whenever Sales
        Orders are emailed to the Customer. Only applies when the "Custom
        Email" EDI Profile option is selected.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Filename</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x184bdf8">
        <para>XML tags may be used in this field to dynamically generate
        filename text. In the example shown in the screenshot above, the
        filename will include the Document Type (i.e., Sales Order) and the
        Document Number (i.e., Sales Order Number). This field only applies
        when the "Custom Email" EDI Profile option is selected.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>EDI Email Body</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x184be40">
        <para>Use this text field to enter the default message that will
        accompany any Sales Orders sent to the Customer. Only applies when the
        "Custom Email" EDI Profile option is selected.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CLOSE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x184beac">
        <para>Closes the screen without setting up a Customer to receive Sales
        Orders via email, returning you to the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x184bef4">
        <para>Enables the Customer to receive Sales Orders via email.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para role="openmfg">To establish a Customer's EDI preferences for Invoices,
  select the "Invoice EDI" tab. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/SO_MI_custInvEDI.png" id="Graphic656853" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption656856">Add Customer Invoice EDI
        Information</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <note>
    <para>EDI preferences for a Customer are implemented at the point when
    Invoices for the Customer are printed.</para>
  </note>
  <para>When setting up the Invoice EDI preferences for a Customer, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>EDI Profile</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x184bff0">
        <para>Select from the following EDI Profile options:</para>
        <para>No EDI: Select this option if you do not wish to use the EDI
        system.</para>
        <para>Custom Email: Select this option if you want to bypass standard
        EDI Profiles and instead create custom email preferences for the
        Customer. These preferences will be stored solely with the Customer
        master--and will be used to send email versions of Invoices to the
        Customer when Invoices for the Customer are printed. When this option
        is selected, the email-related fields on the Customer master will be
        enabled. Otherwise, the email-related fields will be disabled.</para>
        <para>EDI Profile: Select a standard EDI Profile from the list of EDI
        Profiles. The selected Profile will be used when Invoices for the
        Customer are printed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>EDI Email</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x184c038">
        <para>Enter the Customer email address to be used as the default
        recipient address whenever Invoices are emailed to the Customer. Only
        applies when the "Custom Email" EDI Profile option is selected.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>Send Invoices to multiple recipients by separating email addresses
    with a comma. Be sure to omit any spaces between addresses when using
    commas to send copies to multiple recipients.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Cc</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x184c0c8">
        <para>Enter the email address to be used as the default carbon copy
        address whenever Invoices are emailed to the Customer. Only applies
        when the "Custom Email" EDI Profile option is selected.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Subject</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x184c110">
        <para>Enter a default email subject line to be used whenever Invoices
        are emailed to the Customer. Only applies when the "Custom Email" EDI
        Profile option is selected.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Filename</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x184c158">
        <para>XML tags may be used in this field to dynamically generate
        filename text. In the example shown in the screenshot above, the
        filename will include the Document Type (i.e., Invoice) and the
        Document Number (i.e., Invoice Number). This field only applies when
        the "Custom Email" EDI Profile option is selected.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>EDI Email Body</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x184c1a0">
        <para>Use this text field to enter the default message that will
        accompany any Invoices sent to the Customer. Only applies when the
        "Custom Email" EDI Profile option is selected.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CLOSE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x184c20c">
        <para>Closes the screen without setting up a Customer to receive
        Invoices via email, returning you to the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x184c254">
        <para>Enables the Customer to receive Invoices via email.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>If your system is configured to use Credit Cards, the "Credit Cards"
    tab will be visible. This tab will not be visible if your system is not
    configured to use Credit Cards.</para>
  </note>
  <para><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>credit cards</primary>
      <secondary>adding to customer master</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>customers</primary>
      <secondary>credit cards for</secondary>
    </indexterm>To add Credit Card information to a Customer master, select
  the "Credit Cards" tab at the bottom of the "Customer" screen. The following
  screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/SO_MI_custCC.png" id="Graphic656879" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption656882">Customer Credit Cards</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <note>
    <para>Customer Credit Cards may be used when entering Sales Orders or Cash
    Receipt transactions for the Customer. When entering a Sales Order, you
    have the option to either pre-authorize or charge a Credit Card. Any
    pre-authorizations may later be post-authorized using the A/R
    Workbench.</para>
  </note>
  <para>When adding Credit Card information to a Customer master, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Credit Cards</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x184c404">
        <para>Display lists Credit Card records for the Customer.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x184c470">
        <para>Opens screen for entering new Credit Card information for the
        Customer.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>EDIT</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x184c4b8">
        <para>Enables you to edit highlighted Credit Cards. The edit screen is
        the same as that for entering new Credit Card information--except that
        when editing, the fields will contain Credit Card information.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>VIEW</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x184c500">
        <para>Highlight a Credit Card and then select this button to reach a
        read-only view of the "Edit" screen. Double-clicking on a Credit Card
        will also bring you to the view screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>MOVE UP</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x184c548">
        <para>Highlight a Credit Card and then select this button to move the
        Credit Card up in the sequence of Credit Cards.</para>
        <para>Sequence numbers are automatically adjusted to reflect the
        change in position.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>MOVE DOWN</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x184c590">
        <para>Highlight a Credit Card and then select this button to move the
        Credit Card down the sequence of Credit Cards.</para>
        <para>Sequence numbers are automatically adjusted to reflect the
        change in position.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To create a new Credit Card record for a Customer, select the NEW
  button. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/SO_MI_custCCNew.png" id="Graphic656897" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption656900">Create New Credit Card Record</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When creating a new Credit Card record for a Customer, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Customer #</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x184c668">
        <para>Displays the name of the Customer associated with the Credit
        Card record.</para>
        <para>The name of the Customer will also be displayed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Credit Card Type</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x184c6b0">
        <para>Specify the type of Credit Card.</para>
        <para>The following Credit Card types are currently supported: Master
        Card, Visa, American Express, and Discover.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Credit Card Number</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x184c6f8">
        <para>Enter the Credit Card Number.</para>
        <para>After the Credit Card record has been saved, all but the last
        four digits of the Credit Card Number will be encrypted for security
        purposes.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Active</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x184c740">
        <para>Select if the Credit Card record is active.</para>
        <para>Do not select this option if the specified Credit Card is
        inactive or invalid for any reason.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Name</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x184c788">
        <para>Enter a name to describe the Credit Card record.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Address</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x184c7d0">
        <para>Specify the billing address associated with the Credit Card
        record.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Country</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x184c818">
        <para>Specify the country associated with the billing address.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Expiration Month</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x184c860">
        <para>Enter the month when the specified Credit Card expires.</para>
        <para>The month must be saved in the format "MM". For example, the
        month of January would be represented as "01".</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Expiration Year</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x184c8a8">
        <para>Enter the year when the specified Credit Card expires.</para>
        <para>The year must be saved in the format "YYYY". For example, the
        year 2006 would be represented as "2006".</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x184c914">
        <para>Closes the screen without creating the Credit Card record,
        returning you to the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x184c95c">
        <para>Creates the Credit Card record and adds it to the list of Credit
        Card records.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>