<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section932714" role="standard">
  <title>Schedule P/O for Email Delivery</title>
  <para>To schedule a Purchase Order for email delivery, select the "Schedule
  P/O for Email Delivery" option. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para>
<screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/deliverPurchaseOrder.png"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Schedule Purchase Order for Email
        Delivery</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
</para>
  <para>When scheduling a Purchase Order for email delivery, you are presented
  with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>P/O #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the Purchase Order Number of the Purchase Order you want
        to schedule for email delivery.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>Vendors are set up to receive email deliveries of information using
    the Electronic Data Interchange (EDI) tab on the Vendor master. For more
    information, see <xref linkend="Anchor55000"/>.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>From</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The default address appearing in the "From" field will
        automatically be pre-populated with the email address of the user who
        is currently logged in to the application. User email addresses are
        stored with customer records at the system level. You may change the
        address in this field manually at run time.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Send To</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>If the Vendor associated with the selected Purchase Order has
        been set up to receive email, then the default email address for that
        Vendor will be automatically pre-populated here. Because this is an
        editable field, you may change the email address.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Subject</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>If EDI is set up for the Vendor, then the default subject line
        found on the Vendor master will be automatically pre-populated here.
        Because this is an editable field, you may modify the subject
        line.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Filename</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>If EDI is set up for the Vendor, then the default filename found
        on the Vendor master will be automatically pre-populated here. Because
        this is an editable field, you may modify the filename line. XML tags
        may be used in this field to dynamically generate filename text. In
        the example shown in the screenshot above, the filename will include
        the Document Type (i.e., Purchase Order) and the Document Number
        (i.e., Purchase Order Number).</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Email Body</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>If EDI is set up for the Vendor, then the default email body
        found on the Vendor master will be automatically pre-populated here.
        This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping. You may edit the
        default email body.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Mark Purchase Order as having been Printed</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to mark highlighted Invoice as having been
        printed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without scheduling a Purchase Order for email
        delivery, returning you to the application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SUBMIT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to submit requested action to the Batch Manager for
        processing. For additional information, see <xref linkend="Anchor61009"/>.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
