<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section520014">
   <title>
      
      <indexterm significance="normal">
         <primary>costing</primary>
         <secondary>for indented BOMs</secondary>
      </indexterm> 
      <indexterm significance="normal">
         <primary>bills of materials</primary>
         <secondary>costed indented view of</secondary>
      </indexterm>Costed Indented BOM</title>
   <para id="Para520015">The difference between the indented view and the
    single level view is that the indented view displays Costs for all
    subcomponents if there is a manufactured component listed on the Bill of
    Materials list. To view associated Item Costs using an indented Bill of
    Materials, select the "Costed Indented BOM" option. The following screen
    will appear:</para>
   <para id="Para520019">
      <screenshot>
         <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
               <imagedata fileref="images/PD_Cost_dispIndentedBOM.png" id="Graphic563436"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption id="Caption520020">Costed Indented Bill of
          Materials</caption>
         </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
   </para>
   <para id="Para520026">When displaying Costs for an indented Bill of
    Materials, you are presented with the following options:</para>
   <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para520027">Item Number</term>
         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x191b024">
            <para>Enter the Item Number of the manufactured Item whose
          associated Costs you would like to view using an indented Bill of
          Materials.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para663300">UOM</term>
         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x191b06c">
            <para>Inventory Unit of Measure.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para520031">Use Standard Costs</term>
         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x191b0b4">
            <para>Select to display Standard Costs for component Items in the
          specified Item's Bill of Materials.</para>
            <para id="Para626495">Both the Unit Cost and Extended Cost for each
          component Item, expressed in terms of Standard Cost, will
          display--assuming Standard Costs have been defined for each
          component Item.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
   </variablelist>
   <tip>
      <para id="Para654644">When Labor and Overhead are posted to the General
      Ledger, they are posted using their Actual Cost. This is a departure
      from the rule which governs materials--namely, that materials are always
      posted using their Standard Cost. Differences between Actual and
      Standard Labor and Overhead Costs will be reflected in Inventory Cost
      Variances when Work Order Production or Operations are posted. You can
      address these variances if and when they occur by posting your Actual
      Costs to Standard.</para>
   </tip>
   <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para520032">Use Actual Costs</term>
         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x191b144">
            <para>Select to display Actual Costs for component Items in the
          specified Item's Bill of Materials.</para>
            <para id="Para626510">Both the Unit Cost and Extended Cost for each
          component Item, expressed in terms of Actual Cost, will
          display--assuming Actual Costs have been defined for each component
          Item.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
   </variablelist>
   <note>
      <para id="Para626462">The totals displayed on the screen are derived as
      follows:</para>
      <para id="Para626538">Total Cost: This total is pulled from the Extended
      Cost column. The total may vary, depending on whether "Use Standard
      Costs" or "Use Actual Costs" is selected.</para>
      <para id="Para626550">Actual Cost: This value represents the Actual Cost
      for the parent Item whose Costed Indented BOM is being displayed.</para>
      <para id="Para626551">Standard Cost: This value represents the Standard
      Cost for the parent Item whose Costed Indented BOM is being
      displayed.</para>
   </note>
   <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para520033">Costed Bill of Materials</term>
         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x191b1d4">
            <para>Display lists Costed Indented Bill of Materials components,
          using the specified parameters.</para>
            <para id="Para664256">The difference between the indented view and
          the single level view is that the indented view displays all
          subcomponents if there is a manufactured component listed on the
          Bill of Materials. The Total Cost, Actual Cost, and Standard Cost
          will be calculated automatically at the bottom of the
          display.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
   </variablelist>
   <para id="Para520041">To the far right of the display are the following
    buttons and display fields:</para>
   <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para520042">CLOSE</term>
         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x191b240">
            <para>Closes the screen, returning you to the application
          desktop.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para663949">PRINT</term>
         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x191b288">
            <para>Runs the report associated with this screen.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
   </variablelist>
   <para id="Para552056">Right-clicking on a component in the Costed Bill of
    Materials list enables you to select from the following menu
    options:</para>
   <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para520045">Maintain Item Costs</term>
         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x191b2f4">
            <para/>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para592092">View Item Costing</term>
         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x191b33c">
            <para/>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="../widgets/xtreewidget.xml"
                  xpointer="element(xtreewidget.menu.exportcontents)"/>
   </variablelist>
</section>