<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section600352">
   <title>
       
      <indexterm significance="normal">
         <primary>financial reports</primary>
         <secondary>viewing of</secondary>
      </indexterm>View Financial Report</title>
   <para>Once a Financial Report has been created using the
    Financial Reporting Engine, you may then generate it using time-phased
    information. To view a Financial Report, select the "View Financial
    Report" option. The following screen will appear:</para>
   <para>
      <screenshot>
         <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
               <imagedata id="Graphic534303" fileref="images/dspFinancialReport.png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption id="Caption534306">View Financial Report</caption>
         </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
   </para>
   <para>When viewing a Financial Report, you are presented
    with the following options:</para>
   <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
         <term>Financial Report</term>
         <listitem>
            <para>Specify the Financial Report you want to generate.</para>
            <para>The list will include both system-defined
          Financial Reports (e.g., basic Income Statement and basic Balance
          Sheet) and also any other reports you may have created.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
         <term>Report Type</term>
         <listitem>
            <para>Displays the report type for the Financial Report you select:
          Balance Sheet, Income Statement, Cash Flow, or Ad Hoc.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
   </variablelist>
   <note>
      <para>The options available on the screen will vary,
      depending on the report type selected. For example, column layouts are
      not available for Ad Hoc reports.</para>
   </note>
   <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
         <term>Column Layout</term>
         <listitem>
            <para>Select the column layout you want the Financial Report to use.
          This feature may not be used in conjunction with the "Trend Report"
          option.</para>
            <para>When defining a Financial Report using one of
          the standard report types (i.e., Balance Sheet, Income Statement, or
          Cash Flow), you must define a column layout to specify the time
          buckets financial information will be sorted into. A standard
          Financial Report may have any number of column layouts defined for
          it. Each layout will be linked to either a pre-defined report
          definition or a custom report definition you create yourself. This
          option will be disabled for Ad Hoc reports, which do not use column
          layouts.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
         <term>Periods</term>
         <listitem>
            <para>Specify the Accounting Period(s) whose details you want to
          display.</para>
            <para>For Financial Reports created using one of the
          standard report types (i.e., Balance Sheet, Income Statement, or
          Cash Flow), you can only select a single Accounting Period--unless
          you are running a Trend Report, in which case multiple Periods may
          be chosen. Ad Hoc reports may always use either single or multiple
          Periods. To select an individual Period, highlight the Period using
          your mouse button. The Period is now selected. To select a sequence
          of Periods, highlight the first in the sequence using your mouse
          button. Then, holding down the SHIFT key on your keyboard, highlight
          the last Period in the sequence. The entire sequence is now
          selected. To select Periods that are out of sequence (e.g., January,
          April, July, October), highlight the first Period in the group.
          Then, holding down the CTRL key on your keyboard, highlight the next
          Period you want to select. Continue highlighting Periods with the
          CTRL key depressed until all desired Periods are selected. The
          entire group is now selected.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
   </variablelist>
   <tip>
      <para>You can export the generated financial data in
      tab-delimited format using the "Export Contents" option from the
      right-click menu.</para>
   </tip>
   <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
         <term>Show Columns</term>
         <listitem>
            <para>For Ad Hoc reports (which do not use column layouts), specify
          the columns of information you want to include in the Financial
          Report. To be successful, these selections must also match the Ad
          Hoc report layout. If a column is not selected, it will not be
          included in the report. This option will be disabled for non-Ad Hoc
          reports, whose column choices are defined by column layouts.</para>
            <variablelist>
               <varlistentry>
                  <term>Beg. Bal</term>
                  <listitem>
                     <para>Select to include a beginning balance column in the
                report. An alternate label may also be used to identify this
                field.</para>
                  </listitem>
               </varlistentry>
               <varlistentry>
                  <term>Beg. Bal. %</term>
                  <listitem>
                     <para>Select to include a beginning balance percentage column
                in the report. An alternate label may also be used to identify
                this field.</para>
                  </listitem>
               </varlistentry>
               <varlistentry>
                  <term>Debits</term>
                  <listitem>
                     <para>Select to include a Debits column in the report. An
                alternate label may also be used to identify this
                field.</para>
                  </listitem>
               </varlistentry>
               <varlistentry>
                  <term>Debits %</term>
                  <listitem>
                     <para>Select to include a Debits percentage column in the
                report. An alternate label may also be used to identify this
                field.</para>
                  </listitem>
               </varlistentry>
               <varlistentry>
                  <term>Credits</term>
                  <listitem>
                     <para>Select to include a Credits column in the report. An
                alternate label may also be used to identify this
                field.</para>
                  </listitem>
               </varlistentry>
               <varlistentry>
                  <term>Credits %</term>
                  <listitem>
                     <para>Select to include a Credits percentage column in the
                report. An alternate label may also be used to identify this
                field.</para>
                  </listitem>
               </varlistentry>
               <varlistentry>
                  <term>End. Bal.</term>
                  <listitem>
                     <para>Select to include an ending balance column in the
                report. An alternate label may also be used to identify this
                field.</para>
                  </listitem>
               </varlistentry>
               <varlistentry>
                  <term>End. Bal. %</term>
                  <listitem>
                     <para>Select to include an ending balance percentage column in
                the report. An alternate label may also be used to identify
                this field.</para>
                  </listitem>
               </varlistentry>
               <varlistentry>
                  <term>Budget</term>
                  <listitem>
                     <para>Select to include a Budget column in the report. An
                alternate label may also be used to identify this
                field.</para>
                  </listitem>
               </varlistentry>
               <varlistentry>
                  <term>Budget %</term>
                  <listitem>
                     <para>Select to include a Budget percentage column in the
                report. An alternate label may also be used to identify this
                field.</para>
                  </listitem>
               </varlistentry>
               <varlistentry>
                  <term>Difference</term>
                  <listitem>
                     <para>Select to include a column showing the difference
                between Debits and Credits in the report. An alternate label
                may also be used to identify this field.</para>
                  </listitem>
               </varlistentry>
               <varlistentry>
                  <term>Difference %</term>
                  <listitem>
                     <para>Select to include a difference percentage column in the
                report. An alternate label may also be used to identify this
                field.</para>
                  </listitem>
               </varlistentry>
               <varlistentry>
                  <term>Custom</term>
                  <listitem>
                     <para>Select to include a Custom column in the report. An
                alternate label may also be used to identify this
                field.</para>
                  </listitem>
               </varlistentry>
               <varlistentry>
                  <term>Custom %</term>
                  <listitem>
                     <para>Select to include a Custom column percentage column in
                the report. An alternate label may also be used to identify
                this field.</para>
                  </listitem>
               </varlistentry>
            </variablelist>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
         <term>Trend Report</term>
         <listitem>
            <para>Select to generate a Financial Report which groups information
          across multiple time periods. This option may be used regardless of
          report type--and if used for one of the standard report types (i.e.,
          Balance Sheet, Income Statement, or Cash Flow), the column layout
          option will be disabled. If selected, the following options will be
          available:</para>
            <variablelist>
               <varlistentry>
                  <term>Month</term>
                  <listitem>
                     <para>If selected, you may group together any number of
                Accounting Periods to include in your report. Use your mouse
                and a combination of the SHIFT and CTRL keys to select
                multiple Periods.</para>
                  </listitem>
               </varlistentry>
               <varlistentry>
                  <term>Quarter</term>
                  <listitem>
                     <para>If selected, you may group together any number of
                Quarters to include in your report. Use your mouse and a
                combination of the SHIFT and CTRL keys to select multiple
                Quarters.</para>
                  </listitem>
               </varlistentry>
               <varlistentry>
                  <term>Year</term>
                  <listitem>
                     <para>If selected, you may group together any number of Fiscal
                Years to include in your report. Use your mouse and a
                combination of the SHIFT and CTRL keys to select multiple
                Fiscal Years.</para>
                  </listitem>
               </varlistentry>
            </variablelist>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
   </variablelist>
   <tip>
      <para>There is no relationship between the selected
      Periods in a column layout and the Trend Report options available when
      viewing a Financial Report. Trend Reporting ignores column
      layouts.</para>
   </tip>
   <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
         <term>Options</term>
         <listitem>
            <para>You may optionally select one or both of the following
          options:</para>
            <variablelist>
               <varlistentry>
                  <term>Show Account Numbers</term>
                  <listitem>
                     <para>Select to include Account Numbers for each row in the
                Group/Account Name column. If not selected, only Account
                descriptions will be shown.</para>
                  </listitem>
               </varlistentry>
               <varlistentry>
                  <term>Show Accounts with Zero Amounts</term>
                  <listitem>
                     <para>Select to include Accounts with zero amounts for each
                row in the Group/Account Name column. If not selected, only
                Accounts with non-zero amounts will be shown.</para>
                  </listitem>
               </varlistentry>
            </variablelist>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
         <term>Layout</term>
         <listitem>
            <para>Display lists Financial Report details for the selected
          Financial Report, using the specified parameters. This display is a
          nested list, with a plus ("+") sign located to the far left of the
          display next to each Financial Report Group that may be expanded to
          lower levels. By clicking your mouse on a plus sign, you reveal
          lower levels of information related to the group.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
   </variablelist>
   <para>To the far right of the screen, the following
    buttons are available:</para>
   <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
         <term>CLOSE</term>
         <listitem>
            <para>Closes the screen, returning you to the application
          desktop.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
         <term>QUERY</term>
         <listitem>
            <para>Select to generate the display, using the specified
          parameters.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
         <term>
             
            <indexterm significance="normal">
               <primary>financial reports</primary>
               <secondary>printing of</secondary>
            </indexterm>PRINT</term>
         <listitem>
            <para>Runs the report associated with this screen.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
   </variablelist>
</section>
