<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section518794" role="openmfg">
  <title>MPS Detail</title>

  <para id="Para533463">To view the Master Production Schedule (MPS), select
  the "MPS Detail" option. The following screen will appear:</para>

  <para id="Para520715">
      <screenshot>
         <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
               <imagedata fileref="images/MS_Disp_mpsDetail.png" id="Graphic520713"/>
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption520716">MPS Detail</caption>
         </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
   </para>

  <para id="Para518801">When viewing the Master Production Schedule, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para518802">All Warehouses</term>

         <listitem>
            <para>Select to display MPS detail for all Warehouses.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para518804">Selected</term>

         <listitem>
            <para>Specify Warehouse whose MPS detail you want to display.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para518806">All Planner Codes</term>

         <listitem>
            <para>Select to display MPS detail for all Planner Codes.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para518807">Selected</term>

         <listitem>
            <para>Specify Planner Code whose MPS detail you want to
        display.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para526352">Pattern</term>

         <listitem>
            <para>Enter a Planner Code pattern to select a range of Planner
        Codes.</para>

            <para id="Para554638">Refine your search using Regular Expressions, as
        described in <link endterm="Anchor77806" id="XRef554637" linkend="Anchor77806"> Pattern Matching with Regular
        Expressions</link>"Topic: Pattern Matching with Regular
        Expressions".</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para552712">Calendar</term>

         <listitem>
            <para>Select the Calendar you want to use for the report.</para>

            <para id="Para552713">By default, the Calendar defined at the system
        level will be used. Associated Calendar periods will be
        displayed.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <tip>
      <para id="Para522398">When setting up a planning Calendar, be sure to
    include past due information in the first period of the Calendar.</para>
  </tip>

  <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para523296">Name/Selected Periods</term>

         <listitem>
            <para>Select as many periods as you want to display. Selected periods
        correspond to Calendar specified in the "Calendar" field.</para>

            <para id="Para526711">Select individual periods or groups of periods
        together. To select an individual period, highlight the period using
        your mouse button. The period is now selected. To select a sequence of
        periods, highlight the first in the sequence using your mouse button.
        Then, holding down the SHIFT key on your keyboard, highlight the last
        period in the sequence. The entire sequence is now selected. To select
        periods that are out of sequence (e.g., January, April, July,
        October), highlight the first period in the group. Then, holding down
        the CTRL key on your keyboard, highlight the next period you want to
        select. Continue highlighting periods with the CTRL key depressed
        until all desired periods are selected. The entire group is now
        selected.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para518815">Item Sites</term>

         <listitem>
            <para>Display lists Item Sites for Items matching the specified
        parameters.</para>

            <para id="Para553860">When you have selected a Calendar type and
        corresponding Calendar period(s), highlight an Item Site to display
        MPS detail for the Item Site in the "MPS Detail" display below.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para518817">MPS Detail</term>

         <listitem>
            <para>Display lists MPS detail for the Item Site you selected in the
        "Item Sites" display above.</para>

            <para id="Para553968">MPS detail will include the following rows:
        Forecast (based on MPS reading of Production Plans); Allocations
        (requirements from Customer Orders or Work Orders); Orders (based on
        Work Orders or Purchase Orders); Projected Quantity on Hand (based on
        Allocations and Orders for specified future periods); Planned Orders
        (system-generated Orders showing requirements needed to meet negative
        Availability); Availability (based on current Allocations and Orders);
        Available to Promise (uncommitted quantity available to support new
        Sales Orders).</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para id="Para541548">To the far right of the screen, the following buttons
  are available:</para>

  <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para541549">CLOSE</term>

         <listitem>
            <para>Closes the screen, returning you to the application
        desktop.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para553772">PRINT</term>

         <listitem>
            <para>Runs the report associated with this screen.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para id="Para525749">Right-clicking on a Line Item in the MPS Detail
  display enables you to select from the following context-sensitive
  options.</para>

  <variablelist>
      <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="../supportfiles/rightclick.xml"
                  xpointer="element(/1/8/2/18)"/>

      <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="../supportfiles/rightclick.xml"
                  xpointer="element(/1/8/2/24)"/>

      <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="../widgets/xtreewidget.xml"
                  xpointer="element(xtreewidget.menu.exportcontents)"/>
  </variablelist>

  <para id="Para525753">You will only be able to view Allocations if
  Allocations are showing a positive value in the period where you right-click
  your mouse. Similarly, you will only be able to view Orders if Orders are
  showing a positive value in the period where you right-click your
  mouse.</para>

  <para id="Para525755">If the Line Item is a purchased Item, the following
  additional options will be available:</para>

  <variablelist>
      <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="../supportfiles/rightclick.xml"
                  xpointer="element(/1/8/2/11)"/>

      <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="../supportfiles/rightclick.xml"
                  xpointer="element(/1/8/2/10)"/>
  </variablelist>

  <para id="Para530194">If the Line Item is a manufactured Item, the following
  additional option will be available:</para>

  <variablelist>
      <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="../supportfiles/rightclick.xml"
                  xpointer="element(/1/8/2/13)"/>
  </variablelist>
</section>