<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.3//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.3/docbookx.dtd">

  <section id="Section555646" role="openmfg">
    <title>P/O Items by Buffer Status</title>

    <para id="Para555647">The Purchase Order buffer status displays provide
    information on your current stock and time buffer levels for those Items
    having current Purchase Orders. Stock buffers apply to make-to-stock
    Items; whereas time buffers apply to Items which are make-to-order. Keep
    in mind that buffer status information will only be displayed on days when
    the Buffer Management system is run. If you find your displays show no
    information, this probably means Buffer Management has not been
    run.</para>

    <para id="Para555648">To view Purchase Order Item buffer statuses, select
    the "P/O Items by Buffer Status" option. The following screen will
    appear:</para>

    <para id="Para555652"><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/MS_Buff_poItemsByBuffStatus.png"
                       id="Graphic555650" />
          </imageobject>

          <caption id="Caption555653">Purchase Order Items by Buffer
          Status</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>

    <note>
      <para id="Para555655">When the buffer status for an Item hits 66 or
      higher, the status number will become red. By highlighting Items which
      are "red hot," the system is informing you which Items should be acted
      on immediately. The best remedy for red hot Item Sites is to expedite
      any associated Work Orders or Purchase Orders.</para>
    </note>

    <para id="Para555656">When displaying Purchase Order Item buffer statuses,
    you are presented with the following options:</para>

    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para555657">All Warehouses</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>Select to display Purchase Order Item buffer statuses for all
          Warehouses.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para555658">Selected</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>Specify Warehouse whose Purchase Order Item buffer statuses
          you want to display.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para555659">All Purchasing Agents</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>Select to display Purchase Order Item buffer statuses for all
          Purchasing Agents.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para555660">Selected</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>Specify Purchasing Agent whose Purchase Order Item buffer
          statuses you want to display.</para>

          <para id="Para555661">Users may be designated as Purchasing Agents
          at the system level.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>

    <note>
      <para id="Para555663">By default, the display will sort Purchase Order
      Items by buffer status in descending order. In other words, Purchase
      Order Items with the highest buffer status will appear at the top of the
      list; Purchase Order Items with the lowest buffer status will appear at
      the bottom.</para>
    </note>

    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para555664">P/O Items</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>Display lists buffer statuses for open Purchase Order Items,
          using the specified parameters.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>

    <para id="Para555665">To the far right and at the bottom of the screen,
    the following buttons are available:</para>

    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para555666">CLOSE</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>Closes the screen, returning you to the application
          desktop.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para555667">QUERY</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>Select to generate the display, using the specified
          parameters.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para555668">PRINT</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>Runs the report associated with this screen.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
  </section>
