<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.3//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.3/docbookx.dtd">

  <section id="Section518859" role="openmfg">
    <title>Time-Phased Rough Cut Capacity Plan by Work Center</title>

    <para id="Para518860">To view a rough cut Capacity Plan by Work Center
    showing detail over Calendar periods you define, select the "Time-Phased
    Rough Cut Capacity Plan by Work Center" option. The following screen will
    appear:</para>

    <para id="Para518864"><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/MS_Disp_tpPlanRoughByWCente.png"
                       id="Graphic520795" />
          </imageobject>

          <caption id="Caption518865">Time-Phased Rough Cut Capacity Plan by
          Work Center</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>

    <para id="Para518866">When displaying a time-phased rough cut Capacity
    Plan by Work Center, you are presented with the following options:</para>

    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para518867">All Work Centers</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>Select to display time-phased rough cut Capacity Plan by Work
          Center for all Work Centers.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para518868">Selected</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>Specify Work Center whose time-phased rough cut Capacity Plan
          you want to display.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para518870">All Warehouses</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>Select to display time-phased rough cut Capacity Plan by Work
          Center for all Warehouses.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para518872">Selected</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>Specify Warehouse whose time-phased rough cut Capacity Plan by
          Work Center you want to display.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para552733">Calendar</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>Select the Calendar you want to use for the report.</para>

          <para id="Para552734">Associated Calendar periods will be
          displayed.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para523266">Name/Selected Periods</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>Select as many periods as you want to display. Selected
          periods correspond to Calendar specified in the "Calendar"
          field.</para>

          <para id="Para526675">Select individual periods or groups of periods
          together. To select an individual period, highlight the period using
          your mouse button. The period is now selected. To select a sequence
          of periods, highlight the first in the sequence using your mouse
          button. Then, holding down the SHIFT key on your keyboard, highlight
          the last period in the sequence. The entire sequence is now
          selected. To select periods that are out of sequence (e.g., January,
          April, July, October), highlight the first period in the group.
          Then, holding down the CTRL key on your keyboard, highlight the next
          period you want to select. Continue highlighting periods with the
          CTRL key depressed until all desired periods are selected. The
          entire group is now selected.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para518878">Rough Cut</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>Display lists time-phased rough cut Capacity Plan by Work
          Center, using the specified parameters.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>

    <para id="Para518880">To the far right of the screen, the following
    buttons are available:</para>

    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para518881">CLOSE</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>Closes the screen, returning you to the application
          desktop.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para531402">QUERY</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>Select to generate the display, using the specified
          parameters.</para>

          <para id="Para518883">Start date and end date must be entered for
          calculation to proceed. Results will be displayed in the "Rough Cut"
          display.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para553785">PRINT</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>Runs the report associated with this screen.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
  </section>
