<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section518743" role="openmfg">
  <title>Time-Phased Demand by Planner Code</title>
  <para>To view time-phased demand by Planner Code, select the
  "Time-Phased Demand by Planner Code" option. The following screen will
  appear:</para>
  <para>
<screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/CP_Disp_tpDemandByPCode.png" id="Graphic519943"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption519946">Time-Phased Demand by Planner
        Code</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
</para>
  <para>When displaying time-phased demand by Planner Code,
  you are presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>All Warehouses</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to display time-phased demand by Planner Code for all
        Warehouses.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Selected</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify Warehouse whose time-phased demand by Planner Code you
        want to display.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>All Planner Codes</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to display time-phased demand for all Planner
        Codes.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Selected</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify Planner Code whose time-phased demand you want to
        display.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Pattern</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a Planner Code pattern to select a range of Planner
        Codes.</para>
        <para>Refine your search using Regular Expressions, as
        described in <xref endterm="Anchor77806" linkend="Anchor77806"/>
    FINDME
  "Topic: Pattern Matching with Regular
        Expressions".</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Inventory Units</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to display Inventory Units of Measure.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Capacity Units</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to display Capacity Units of Measure.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Alt. Capacity Units</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Capacity Units: Select to display Alternate Capacity Units of
        Measure.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Calendar</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select the Calendar you want to use for the report.</para>
        <para>Associated Calendar periods will be
        displayed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Name/Selected Periods</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select as many periods as you want to display. Selected periods
        correspond to Calendar specified in the "Calendar" field.</para>
        <para>Select individual periods or groups of periods
        together. To select an individual period, highlight the period using
        your mouse button. The period is now selected. To select a sequence of
        periods, highlight the first in the sequence using your mouse button.
        Then, holding down the SHIFT key on your keyboard, highlight the last
        period in the sequence. The entire sequence is now selected. To select
        periods that are out of sequence (e.g., January, April, July,
        October), highlight the first period in the group. Then, holding down
        the CTRL key on your keyboard, highlight the next period you want to
        select. Continue highlighting periods with the CTRL key depressed
        until all desired periods are selected. The entire group is now
        selected.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Demand</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists time-phased demand by Planner Code, using the
        specified parameters.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons
  are available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CLOSE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen, returning you to the application
        desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>QUERY</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to generate the display, using the specified
        parameters.</para>
        <para>Start date and end date must be entered for
        calculation to proceed. Results will be displayed in the "Demand"
        display.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>PRINT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Runs the report associated with this screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="openmfg">
      <term>SUBMIT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to submit report to the Batch Manager. For additional
        information, see the <xref endterm="Anchor61009" linkend="Anchor61009"/>
    FINDME
  "Topic: Submitting Reports and Jobs to the Batch
        Manager".</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>Right-clicking on an Item in the Demand list enables
  you to select from the following menu options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="../supportfiles/rightclick.xml" xpointer="element(/1/5/2/7)"/>
    <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="../widgets/xtreewidget.xml" xpointer="element(xtreewidget.menu.exportcontents)"/>
  </variablelist>
</section>
