<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="enterPoitemReturn">
  <title>Enter Return Item</title>
  <para>To enter Return details, highlight a Purchase Order Item and select
  the ENTER RETURN button. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para>
<screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/enterPoitemReturn.png"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Enter Purchase Order Item Return</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
</para>
  <para>When entering Return details, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>P/O Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Purchase Order Number specified on the previous
        screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Line #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Purchase Order Line Item number selected on the
        previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Item Number of the Line Item selected on the
        previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Inventory Unit of Measure.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Vend. Item Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Vendor's Item number for the specified Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Vendor Item Description</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays Vendor's description of specified Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Vendor UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Vendor's Item UOM for the specified Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Inv./Vendor UOM Ratio</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the ratio between Inventory and Vendor Units of
        Measure.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. Ordered</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the quantity ordered of the specified Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. to Return</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the quantity of the Item you want to return.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Returnable Qty.</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the quantity available to be returned. The maximum
        returnable quantity is the original quantity ordered. The system will
        not allow you to return more than the returnable quantity.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Reject Code</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify a code to describe the return.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without entering a return for the Purchase
        Order Line Item, returning you to the application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>RETURN</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to return the specified Line Item quantity. When posting
        a Return, privileged users will be given the option to generate an A/P
        Credit Memo in the amount of the Return. This option is available when
        returning against closed Purchase Order Line Items. Closed Purchase
        Orders will be reopened automatically in this scenario to allow for
        future Receipts.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
