<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2008 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section970006">
  <title>View Database Log</title>
  <para>The Database Log viewer is designed to simplify the process of
  troubleshooting errors when and if they occur. If you experience an
  unexplained error when using the system, open the Database Log and view the
  messages written there. This information will help system administrators--or
  your support provider--to analyze and determine the root cause of the
  problem.</para>
  <note>
    <para>This tool reports only on database errors--not the full range of log
    messages which are written to the database. If no errors have occurred,
    then the log viewer will not display any information. Support personnel
    can use Database Log information to help them locate the source of errors
    should errors occur.</para>
  </note>
  <para>To view the Database Log, select the "View Database Log" option. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/errorLog.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>View Database Log Messages</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>While the information written to the Database Log may seem cryptic to
  the average user, the contents written there are invaluable to support
  technicians as they attempt to discover the root cause of a problem. The
  example shows the log information displayed after a user tried
  unsuccessfully to ship a Sales Order. Reading the Log, it becomes clear that
  an Item Site on the Order did not have its Cost Category defined
  properly.</para>
  <tip>
    <para>Include the contents of the Log file when reporting problems to your
    support provider. To copy the contents, highlight the portion you want to
    copy, then select the "Copy" option from the right-click menu. Finally,
    paste the copied text into an email or other form of communication (i.e,
    issue tracking system).</para>
  </tip>
</section>
