<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section572534">
  <title>
      <anchor id="Anchor572533" role="Index" xreflabel="financial reports:creating new"/> 
      <indexterm significance="normal">
         <primary>financial reports</primary>

         <secondary>creating new</secondary>
      </indexterm> 
      <anchor id="Anchor14666" role="Cross-Ref"
              xreflabel="14666: Heading2: Create Financial Report"/>Create Financial
  Report</title>

  <para id="Para572535">The Financial Reporting Engine (FRE) enables you to
  design custom Financial Reports, which can then be previewed, printed, or
  exported in tab-delimited format. You are free to decide how much detail to
  include in these custom reports. For example, you can create highly-detailed
  Financial Reports or executive summaries.</para>

  <para id="Para572529">To create a new Financial Report, select the "Create
  Financial Report" option. The following screen will appear:</para>

  <para id="Para589344">
      <screenshot>
         <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
               <imagedata fileref="images/GL_FR_finLayout.png" id="Graphic589342"/>
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption589345">Create New Financial Report</caption>
         </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
   </para>

  <para id="Para589346">When creating a new Financial Report, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para589347">Name</term>

         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d4da4">
            <para>Enter a name to identify the Financial Report.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para589348">Description</term>

         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d4dec">
            <para>Enter a brief description of the Financial Report.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para589666">Active</term>

         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dc824">
            <para>Select to indicate whether the Financial Report is active or
        not. Inactive Financial Reports will be hidden on the master list of
        Financial Reports by default.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para589704">Report Type</term>

         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dc86c">
            <para>Select one of the following standard statement formats to be the
        basis for your new Financial Report:</para>

            <variablelist>
               <varlistentry>
                  <term>Income Statement</term>

                  <listitem>
                     <para>Select to create an Income Statement. You might also
              consider building an Income Statement by making a copy of the
              system-defined Income Statement, using the system-defined report
              as a template. To make a copy of the system-defined Income
              Statement, simply use the COPY button on the master list of
              Financial Reports. Once copied, you can freely modify the report
              to suit your needs.</para>
                  </listitem>
               </varlistentry>

               <varlistentry>
                  <term>Balance Sheet</term>

                  <listitem>
                     <para>Select to create a Balance Sheet. You might also consider
              building an Income Statement by making a copy of the
              system-defined Balance Sheet, using the system-defined report as
              a template. To make a copy of the system-defined Balance Sheet,
              simply use the COPY button on the master list of Financial
              Reports. Once copied, you can freely modify the report to suit
              your needs.</para>
                  </listitem>
               </varlistentry>

               <varlistentry>
                  <term>Cash Flow</term>

                  <listitem>
                     <para>Select to create a Cash Flow statement. Because Cash Flow
              statements can vary so widely, there is no system-defined Cash
              Flow template.</para>
                  </listitem>
               </varlistentry>

               <varlistentry>
                  <term>Ad Hoc</term>

                  <listitem>
                     <para>Select to create an Ad Hoc report. An Ad Hoc report is
              completely free-form and user-defined. This format gives you the
              flexibility to create reports which do not fit neatly within the
              three standard report types. Any Financial Report created in the
              system prior to version 2.1.0 will be classified as an Ad Hoc
              report.</para>
                  </listitem>
               </varlistentry>
            </variablelist>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="financialLayoutIncStatement.xml"
               xpointer="element(/1)"/>

  <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="financialLayoutBalSheet.xml"
               xpointer="element(/1)"/>

  <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="financialLayoutCashFlow.xml"
               xpointer="element(/1)"/>

  <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="financialLayoutAdHoc.xml"
               xpointer="element(/1)"/>
</section>