<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section590389">
  <title><anchor id="Anchor69529" role="Cross-Ref"
  xreflabel="69529: Heading3: Ad Hoc Report" />Fianancial Report
  Special</title>

  <para id="Para576197">The Financial Reporting Engine (FRE) supports the
  addition of a limited number of Special items, which may be used to extend
  your reporting capabilities. A Special item can function as the child of a
  Top-Level or other Group. <anchor id="Anchor576196" role="Index"
  xreflabel="financial reports:adding special items to" /> <indexterm
      significance="normal" zone="Anchor576196">
      <primary>financial reports</primary>

      <secondary>adding special items to</secondary>
    </indexterm>To add a new Special item to a Financial Report, select the
  ADD SPECIAL button. The following screen will appear:</para>

  <para id="Para576437"><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/GL_FR_finLaySpec.png" id="Graphic576435" />
        </imageobject>

        <caption id="Caption576202">Add Financial Report Special
        Item</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para id="Para576229">When adding a Special item to a Financial Report, you
  are presented with the following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para577172">Name</term>

      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18ff878">
        <para>Enter a name to identify the Special item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para576170">Type</term>

      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18ff8c0">
        <para>Select one of the Special item types from the following
        options:</para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>A/R open items</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select to include the A/R open items balance for the
              specified Accounting Period(s) in the Financial Report.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>A/P open items</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select to include the A/P open items balance for the
              specified Accounting Period(s) in the Financial Report.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para576453">Show Beginning Balance</term>

      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18ff908">
        <para>Select to include the Special item's beginning balance when the
        Financial Report is generated. If selected, you also have the option
        to show the beginning balance as a percentage of the group total. Not
        selecting means the Special item's beginning balance will not be
        shown.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para576455">Show Ending Balance</term>

      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18ff950">
        <para>Select to include the Special item's ending balance when the
        Financial Report is generated. If selected, you also have the option
        to show the ending balance as a percentage of the group total. Not
        selecting means the Special item's ending balance will not be
        shown.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para576457">Show Debit/Credit</term>

      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18ff998">
        <para>Select to include the Special item's Debit/Credit balance when
        the Financial Report is generated. If selected, you also have the
        option to show Debits and Credits as a percentage of the group total.
        Not selecting means the Special item's Debit/Credit balance will not
        be shown.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para576459">Show Budget</term>

      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18ff9e0">
        <para>Select to include the Special item's Budget balance when the
        Financial Report is generated. If selected, you also have the option
        to show Budgets as a percentage of the group total. Not selecting
        means the Special item's Budget balance will not be shown.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para577098">Show Difference</term>

      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18ffa28">
        <para>Select to include the difference between Debits and Credits for
        the Special item when the Financial Report is generated. If selected,
        you also have the option to show the difference as a percentage of the
        group total. Not selecting means the Account's difference balance will
        not be shown.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para577039">Use Group for % Total calculation</term>

      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18ffa70">
        <para>Indicate which group to use if percentage of group total
        calculations are specified. By default, the system will use the parent
        group for these calculations. The parent group is understood to be the
        group within which the Special item is immediately located. If you
        prefer to determine percentage of total calculations using a different
        group than the parent group. All groups defined for the Financial
        Report will be available for selection.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para576465">Operation</term>

      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18ffab8">
        <para>Specify how the Special item should operate in relation to the
        group specified under the "Use Group" option:</para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Add to Group Total</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select if you want the Special item to be added to the
              specified group's total. If selected, a "+" will appear next to
              the group as it appears in the Financial Report.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Subtract from Group Total</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select if you want the Special item to be subtracted from
              the specified group's total. If selected, a "-" will appear next
              to the group as it appears in the Financial Report.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para577433">Show Custom Column</term>

      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18ffb00">
        <para>Select to enable Special item information to be included in a
        Custom column when the Financial Report is generated.</para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Show % of Group Total</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select to show the Custom column information as a
              percentage of the group total.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Use Beginning Balance</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select to include the beginning balance for the Special
              item in the Custom column.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Use Ending Balance</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select to include the ending balance for the Special item
              in the Custom column.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Use Debits</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select to include the Debit balance for the Special item
              in the Custom column.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Use Credits</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select to include the Credit balance for the Special item
              in the Custom column.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Use Budget</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select to include the Budget balance for the Special item
              in the Custom column.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Use Difference</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select to include the difference between Debits and
              Credits for the Special item in the Custom column.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para id="Para576551">To the far right of the screen, the following buttons
  are available:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para576552">CANCEL</term>

      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18ffb6c">
        <para>Closes the screen without adding a Special item to the Financial
        Report Group, returning you to the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para576553">SAVE</term>

      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18ffbb4">
        <para>Adds the Special item to the Financial Report Group.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <note>
    <para id="Para594023">Because Ad Hoc reports are not required to conform
    to the three standard statement formats, the "Column Layouts" tab is not
    available for Ad Hoc reports. Column layouts may only be used by Financial
    Reports which conform to these standard formats.</para>
  </note>
</section>