<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section590099">
    <title>
      <anchor id="Anchor590451" role="Index"
              xreflabel="financial reports:balance sheet type;balance sheet reports"/>
      <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>financial reports</primary>

        <secondary>balance sheet type</secondary>
      </indexterm> 
      <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>balance sheet reports</primary>
      </indexterm>Balance Sheet Report</title>

    <para id="Para590620">The system ships with a basic Balance Sheet designed
    to generate Financial Reports using your Chart of Accounts data. In this
    section, we will examine this basic Balance Sheet.</para>

    <note>
      <para id="Para590622">Because the basic Balance Sheet is a
      system-defined Financial Report, it may not be modified (except to make
      it active or inactive). However, you may copy the report and modify the
      copy. You can think of the basic Balance Sheet as a template for
      building other, similar Financial Reports.</para>
    </note>

    <para id="Para590623">To view the basic Balance Sheet, select it for
    editing from the master list of Financial Reports. A message will alert
    you that this is a system-defined report which may only be viewed, not
    edited. Select the OK button to reach the following screen:</para>

    <para id="Para588975">
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
               <imagedata fileref="images/GL_FR_basicBalSheet.png" id="Graphic588974"/>
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption588976">Basic Balance Sheet
          System-Defined</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
   </para>

    <para id="Para592084">The "Row Layout" tab displays information on all the
    Account Groups and Account Numbers which make up the basic Balance Sheet.
    If this were a custom report you were creating, you would be able to
    add/remove Account Groups and Account Numbers to meet your specific
    needs.</para>

    <tip>
      <para id="Para595256">To build row layouts for the three standard report
      types--Income Statement, Balance Sheet, and Cash Flow--use the same
      techniques as when building Ad Hoc report row layouts. The only
      difference is you won"t need to specify which balances to calculate
      (e.g., beginning, ending, etc.). The system determines which
      calculations will be done for the standard statement formats.</para>
    </tip>

    <para id="Para592085">When viewing row layouts for the basic Balance
    Sheet, you are presented with the following columns:</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dcf50">
        <para id="Para592086">Group/Account Name: Lists the Account Groups and
        Account Types used in the report. The two main groups are ASSETS and
        LIABILITIES AND OWNERS EQUITY. All Accounts having Type=Asset are
        included in the ASSETS group. And within the LIABILITIES AND OWNERS
        EQUITY group all Accounts having Type=Liability, Type=Equity, and also
        Net Income are included.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dcf74">
        <para id="Para592087">Sub./Summ.: Indicates whether group information
        will be presented as a subtotal or summary line when the report is
        run. In the basic Balance Sheet, all Account Groups are
        subtotaled--except for the Net Income group, which is
        summarized.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dcf98">
        <para id="Para595814">Oper.: Specifies whether a group will be added
        to ("+") or subtracted from ("-") the group total. In the basic Income
        Statement, LIABILITIES AND OWNERS EQUITY are subtracted from the
        ASSETS group.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <note>
      <para id="Para595816">Select the VIEW button to see the system-defined
      settings for each Account Group and Account Type used in the basic
      Income Statement. When creating your own reports, you may choose to
      either imitate or alter these default settings.</para>
    </note>

    <para id="Para592091">In addition to row layouts, you may also define
    column layouts for your Financial Reports. Column layouts are used to
    specify the time buckets financial information will be sorted into. You
    specify a column layout to use when viewing or printing Financial Reports.
    You may define any number of column layouts. Each layout will be linked to
    either a pre-defined report definition or a custom report definition you
    create yourself.</para>

    <para id="Para592092">On the basic Balance Sheet, select the "Column
    Layouts" tab to view all the time buckets available for the report. If
    this were a custom report you were creating, you would be able to
    add/remove column layouts to meet your specific needs.</para>

    <tip>
      <para id="Para596242">See the <link endterm="Anchor94732" id="XRef596244" linkend="Anchor94732"> Cash Flow Report</link>"Cash Flow
      Report" section for specific examples describing the various column
      layout options.</para>
    </tip>

    <para id="Para588995">
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
               <imagedata fileref="images/GL_FR_basicBalSheetCols.png" id="Graphic588994"/>
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption588996">Basic Balance Sheet Column
          Layouts</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
   </para>

    <para id="Para592418">When viewing column layouts for the basic Balance
    Sheet, you are presented with the following column definitions--each of
    which defines a different time bucket available for viewing Balance Sheet
    information:</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dd094">
        <para id="Para592165">Current: Displays data for the current month
        (i.e., Accounting Period). The month used as the basis for the
        reporting is specified when the report is run. Uses the
        "FinancialReportMonth" report definition.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dd0b8">
        <para id="Para592166">Current, Budget: Displays data for the current
        month, compared to Budget information for the current month. The month
        used as the basis for the reporting is specified when the report is
        run. Uses the "FinancialReportMonthBudget" report definition.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dd0dc">
        <para id="Para592205">Current, Prior Month: Displays data for the
        current month, compared to the prior month end. The month used as the
        basis for the reporting is specified when the report is run. Uses the
        "FinancialReportMonthPriorMonth" report definition.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dd100">
        <para id="Para592213">Current, Prior Quarter: Displays data for the
        current month, compared to the prior Quarter end. The month used as
        the basis for the reporting is specified when the report is run. Uses
        the "FinancialReportMonthPriorQuarter" report definition.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dd124">
        <para id="Para592221">Current, Prior Year: Displays data for the
        current month, compared to the Prior Fiscal Year end. The month used
        as the basis for the reporting is specified when the report is run.
        Uses the "FinancialReportMonthPriorYear" report definition.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dd148">
        <para id="Para592206">Current, Year Ago: Displays data for the current
        month, compared to the same month in the prior Fiscal Year. The month
        used as the basis for the reporting is specified when the report is
        run. Uses the "FinancialReportMonthPriorMonth" report
        definition.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <note>
      <para id="Para592180">Select the VIEW button to see the system-defined
      settings for each Account Group and Account Type used in the basic
      Income Statement. When creating your own reports, you may choose to
      either imitate or alter these default settings.</para>
    </note>

    <tip>
      <para id="Para595823">When creating a column layout, you can choose from
      the following standard report templates:</para>

      <para id="Para595824">FinancialReport (used by all Ad Hoc
      reports)</para>

      <para id="Para595825">FinancialReportMonth</para>

      <para id="Para595826">FinancialReportMonthBudget</para>

      <para id="Para595827">FinancialReportMonthDbCr</para>

      <para id="Para595828">FinancialReportMonthPriorMonth</para>

      <para id="Para595829">FinancialReportMonthPriorQuarter</para>

      <para id="Para595830">FinancialReportMonthPriorYear</para>

      <para id="Para595831">FinancialReportMonthQuarter</para>

      <para id="Para595832">FinancialReportMonthYear</para>

      <para id="Para595833">FinancialReportQuarter</para>

      <para id="Para595834">FinancialReportQuarterBudget</para>

      <para id="Para595835">FinancialReportQuarterPriorQuarter</para>

      <para id="Para595836">FinancialReportYear</para>

      <para id="Para595837">FinancialReportYearBudget</para>

      <para id="Para595838">FinancialReportYearPriorYear</para>

      <para id="Para595839">FinancialTrend (used by non-Ad-Hoc trend
      reports)</para>

      <para id="Para595840">If for some reason these templates don"t meet your
      needs, you can always use OpenRPT to a) modify them or b) create your
      own custom report templates.</para>
    </tip>

    <para id="Para592655">To view additional configuration options for the
    layout of the basic Balance Sheet, select the "Options" tab. The following
    screen will appear:</para>

    <para id="Para589014">
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
               <imagedata fileref="images/GL_FR_basicBalSheetOpt.png" id="Graphic589013"/>
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption589015">Basic Balance Sheet Options</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
   </para>

    <para id="Para592705">The layout for the basic Balance Sheet does not use
    any extra configuration options. However, if you were creating your own
    Balance Sheet layout, you could choose to a) include a Grand Total row and
    b) use alternate labels for Budget and Grand Total rows when viewing
    and/or printing the Financial Report.</para>
  </section>