<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section590302">
  <title id="Anchor94732"><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>financial reports</primary>
      <secondary>cash flow type</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>cash flow reports</primary>
    </indexterm> Cash Flow Report</title>
  <para>Because Cash Flow statements can vary so widely, there is no
  system-defined Cash Flow template. To create your own Cash Flow statement,
  select the "Cash Flow" report type. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/GL_FR_cashFlow.png" id="Graphic589073" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption589075">Cash Flow Financial Report</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>To create the row layouts for a Cash Flow report, you would follow the
  same basic steps as described in <xref endterm="Anchor69529"
  linkend="Anchor69529" />. The only difference is you won"t need to specify
  which balances to calculate (e.g., beginning, ending, etc.). Because the
  Cash Flow report is one of three standard statement formats, the system
  determines which calculations will be done.</para>
  <tip>
    <para>To build row layouts for the three standard report types--Income
    Statement, Balance Sheet, and Cash Flow--use the same techniques as when
    building Ad Hoc report row layouts. The only difference is you won"t need
    to specify which balances to calculate (e.g., beginning, ending, etc.).
    The system determines which calculations will be done for the standard
    statement formats.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>In addition to row layouts, you may also define column layouts for
  your Cash Flow report. Column layouts are used to specify the time buckets
  financial information will be sorted into. You specify a column layout to
  use when viewing or printing Financial Reports. You may define any number of
  column layouts. Each layout will be linked to either a pre-defined report
  definition or a custom report definition you create yourself.</para>
  <para>To create column layouts for a Cash Flow report, select the "Column
  Layouts" tab. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/GL_FR_cashFlowCols.png"
                     id="Graphic589086" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption589088">Cash Flow Report Column Layouts</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When creating column layouts for a Cash Flow report, you are presented
  with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Column Layouts</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dd3f4">
        <para>Display lists column layouts defined for the Cash Flow
        report.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dd460">
        <para>Closes the screen without creating the report, returning you to
        the application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dd4a8">
        <para>Creates the report and adds it to the master list of Financial
        Reports.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>ADD</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dd4f0">
        <para>Select to add a column layout.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>EDIT</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dd538">
        <para>Enables you to edit highlighted column layouts. The edit screen
        is the same as that for creating a new column layout--except that when
        editing, the fields will contain column layout information.
        Double-clicking on a column layout will also bring you to the editing
        screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>DELETE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dd580">
        <para>Highlight a column layout and then select this button to remove
        the column layout from the list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To create a new column layout, select the ADD button. The following
  screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/GL_FR_cashFlowColNew.png"
                     id="Graphic589478" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption589480">Add New Column Layout</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When adding a new column layout, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Name</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18f1048">
        <para>Enter a name to identify the column layout.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Description</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18f1090">
        <para>Enter a brief description of the column layout.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Report Template</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18f10d8">
        <para>Specify the report definition you want to associate with the
        column layout.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>When creating a column layout, you can choose from the following
    standard report templates:</para>
    <para>FinancialReport (used by all Ad Hoc reports)</para>
    <para>FinancialReportMonth</para>
    <para>FinancialReportMonthBudget</para>
    <para>FinancialReportMonthDbCr</para>
    <para>FinancialReportMonthPriorMonth</para>
    <para>FinancialReportMonthPriorQuarter</para>
    <para>FinancialReportMonthPriorYear</para>
    <para>FinancialReportMonthQuarter</para>
    <para>FinancialReportMonthYear</para>
    <para>FinancialReportQuarter</para>
    <para>FinancialReportQuarterBudget</para>
    <para>FinancialReportQuarterPriorQuarter</para>
    <para>FinancialReportYear</para>
    <para>FinancialReportYearBudget</para>
    <para>FinancialReportYearPriorYear</para>
    <para>FinancialTrend (used by non-Ad-Hoc trend reports)</para>
    <para>If for some reason these templates don"t meet your needs, you can
    always use OpenRPT to a) modify them or b) create your own custom report
    templates.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Selected Period</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18f1168">
        <para>Select the time period(s) you want to have included in the
        column layout:</para>
        <para>Month: Select to have the current month included as one of the
        columns in the layout. The month used as the basis for the reporting
        is specified when the report is run. If selected, you will also have
        the option to include the prior month in the layout.</para>
        <para>Quarter: Select to have the current Quarter included as one of
        the columns in the layout. The month used as the basis for the
        reporting is specified when the report is run. If selected, you will
        also have the option to include the prior Quarter in the
        layout.</para>
        <para>Year: Select to have the current Fiscal Year-to-Date included as
        one of the columns in the layout. The month used as the basis for the
        reporting is specified when the report is run. If selected, you will
        also have the option to include the prior Fiscal Year in the
        layout.</para>
        <para>Show Debits and Credits: Select to have Debits and Credits
        included as columns for each of the time periods (month, Quarter,
        Year) specified for the layout.</para>
        <para>% of Group Total: Select to have the percentage of group total
        included as a column for each of the time periods (month, Quarter,
        Year) specified for the layout. This information will only be shown
        for groups and Accounts whose row definition specifies "Show % of
        Group Total."</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>There is no relationship between the selected time periods in a
    column layout and the Trend Report options available when viewing a
    Financial Report. Trend Reporting ignores column layouts.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Prior</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18f11f8">
        <para>Select to include prior time period information in the column
        layout by selecting from the following options:</para>
        <para>Period: Will include information for the Accounting Period
        immediately prior to the Period specified when the Financial Report is
        run. You must also select at least one of the time-period check boxes
        below ("Full Month" or "Full Quarter") for prior information to be
        included.</para>
        <para>Year: Will include information for the Fiscal Year immediately
        prior to the current Year specified when the Financial Report is run.
        You must also select at least one of the time-period check boxes below
        ("Full Month," "Full Quarter," etc.) for prior information to be
        included.</para>
        <para>Full Month: If selected, a full month's worth of information
        will be included when the report is run--depending on the prior time
        period specified above. If the "Period" option is specified, then the
        month immediately prior to the selected Accounting Period will be
        included. If the "Year" option is specified, then the selected month
        in the prior Fiscal Year will be included.</para>
        <para>Full Quarter: If selected, a full Quarter's worth of information
        will be included when the report is run--depending on the prior time
        period specified above. If the "Period" option is specified, then the
        Quarter immediately prior to the selected Accounting Period's Quarter
        will be included. If the "Year" option is specified, then the selected
        Quarter in the prior Fiscal Year will be included.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>The "Full Year" and "Year To Date" check boxes are not affected by
    the "Period" or "Year" selections.</para>
  </tip>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18f1264">
      <para>Full Year: If selected, the full prior Fiscal Year's worth of
      information will be included when the report is run.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18f1288">
      <para>Year To Date: If selected, the current Fiscal Year to Date's worth
      of information will be included when the report is run.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18f12ac">
      <para>% of Group Total: If selected, the percentage of the group total
      for the prior time period will be included when the report is run. This
      information will only be shown for groups and Accounts whose row
      definition specifies "Show % of Group Total."</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18f12d0">
      <para>Difference: If selected, the amount of difference between the
      selected Accounting Period and the prior time period will be included
      when the report is run.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18f12f4">
      <para>% of Difference: If selected, the percentage difference between
      the selected Accounting Period and the prior time period will be
      included when the report is run.</para>
      <para>Budget: Select to include Budget information in the column layout.
      If selected, the following additional options will be available:</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18f1318">
      <para>% of Group Total: If selected, the Budget percentage of the group
      total will be included when the report is run. This information will
      only be shown for groups and Accounts whose row definition specifies
      "Show % of Group Total."</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18f133c">
      <para>Difference: If selected, the amount of difference between the
      selected Accounting Period and the Budget for the Period will be
      included when the report is run.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18f1360">
      <para>% of Difference: If selected, the percentage difference between
      the selected Accounting Period and the Budget for the Period will be
      included when the report is run.</para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18f13cc">
        <para>Creates the column layout and adds it to the list of column
        layouts.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18f1414">
        <para>Closes the screen without creating the column layout, returning
        you to the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To specify additional configuration options for the layout of your
  Cash Flow report, select the "Options" tab. The following screen will
  appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/GL_FR_cashFlowOpts.png"
                     id="Graphic589108" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption589110">Cash Flow Report Options</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When specifying additional configuration options for the layout of
  your Cash Flow report, you are presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Show Grand Total</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18f14ec">
        <para>Select if you want to include a grand total in the Financial
        Report.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Alternate Labels</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18f1534">
        <para>You have the option to substitute alternate text for the
        following column headers or row labels when viewing or printing your
        Financial Report:</para>
        <para>Alternate Debits: Specify an alternate label to use as the
        header text for the Debits column. If not specified, the default text
        will be used.</para>
        <para>Alternate Credits: Specify an alternate label to use as the
        header text for the Credits column. If not specified, the default text
        will be used.</para>
        <para>Alternate Budget: Specify an alternate label to use as the
        header text for the Budget column. If not specified, the default text
        will be used.</para>
        <para>Alternate Grand Total: Specify an alternate label to use as the
        text for the Grand Total row. If not specified, the default text will
        be used.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>