<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="financialLayoutGroup">
  <title>
<indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>financial reports</primary>
      <secondary>adding groups to</secondary>
    </indexterm>
<anchor id="Anchor69529" role="Cross-Ref" xreflabel="69529: Heading3: Ad Hoc Report"/>Financial Report Group</title>
  <para>To add a new Financial Report Group, select either the
  ADD TOP LEVEL GROUP or ADD GROUP buttons. The following screen will
  appear:</para>
  <para>
<screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/GL_FR_finLayGrp.png" id="Graphic571776"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption571779">Add Financial Report Group</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
</para>
  <tip>
    <para>To add a sub-group to a top level group, simply
    highlight a top level group using your mouse, then select the ADD GROUP
    button. The screen for adding a sub-group is the same as the one for
    adding a top level group.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>When creating a new Financial Report Group, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Name</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18f1b1c">
        <para>Enter a name to identify the Financial Report Group.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Description</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18f1b64">
        <para>Enter a brief description of the Financial Report Group.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Subtotal/Summarize</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18f1bac">
        <para>Specify whether you want to subtotal or summarize the Financial
        Report Group. If either is selected, specify which of the following
        display options you want to include subtotals or summaries for:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Show Subtotal</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Will show subtotals for all included Accounts when the
              Financial Report is generated.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Use Alt. Label</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if you want to replace the word "Subtotal" with an
              alternate label when the report is run. The text for the
              alternate label is entered below.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Summarized</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Will summarize the information for all included Accounts
              and roll that information up to the group's top level when the
              Financial Report is generated.</para>
              <tip>
                <para>A Financial Report can show either a
                subtotal or a summary--but not both. If neither is specified,
                the additional options will be unavailable.</para>
              </tip>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Show Beginning Balance</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Will show the subtotal or summary for all beginning
              balances included in the group when the Financial Report is
              generated. If selected, you also have the option to show the
              beginning balance as a percentage of the group total. Not
              selecting means the system will not calculate the beginning
              balance for the group.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Show Ending Balance</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Will show the subtotal or summary for all ending balances
              included in the group when the Financial Report is generated. If
              selected, you also have the option to show the ending balance as
              a percentage of the group total. Not selecting means the system
              will not calculate the ending balance for the group.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Show Debits/Credits</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Will show the subtotal or summary for all Debit/Credit
              balances included in the group when the Financial Report is
              generated. If selected, you also have the option to show Debits
              and Credits as a percentage of the group total. Not selecting
              means the system will not calculate the Debit/Credit balances
              for the group.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Show Budget</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Will show the subtotal or summary for all Budget balances
              included in the group when the Financial Report is generated. If
              selected, you also have the option to show Budgets as a
              percentage of the group total. Not selecting means the system
              will not calculate the Budget balance for the group.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Show Difference</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Will show the difference between Debits and Credits
              included in the group when the Financial Report is generated. If
              selected, you also have the option to show the difference as a
              percentage of the group total. Not selecting means the system
              will not calculate the difference between Debits and Credits for
              the group.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Show Custom Column</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Will show Custom column details included in the group when
              the Financial Report is generated. If selected, you also have
              the option to show Custom column details as a percentage of the
              group total. Not selecting means the system will not calculate
              the Custom column balance for the group.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Use Group for % Total calculation</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Indicate which group to use if percentage of group total
              calculations are specified. By default, the system will use the
              parent group for these calculations. The parent group is
              understood to be the group within which the group is immediately
              located. If you prefer to determine percentage of total
              calculations using a different group than the parent group,
              select that group from the list. All groups defined for the
              Financial Report will be available for selection.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Alt. Subtotal Label</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the label text you want to replace the word
              "Subtotal" with when the report is run.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Operation</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify how the Financial Report Group should operate in
              relation to the group specified under the "Use Group"
              option:</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Add to Group Total</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if you want the group to be added to the specified
              group's total. If selected, a "+" will appear next to the group
              as it appears in the Financial Report.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Subtract from Group Total</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if you want the group to be subtracted from the
              specified group's total. If selected, a "-" will appear next to
              the group as it appears in the Financial Report.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons
  are available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18f1da4">
        <para>Closes the screen without creating a Financial Report Group,
        returning you to the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18f1dec">
        <para>Creates the Financial Report Group and adds it to the Financial
        Report.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="financialLayoutItem.xml" xpointer="element(/1)"/>
</section>
