<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section589336">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>financial reports</primary>
      <secondary>income statement type</secondary>
    </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>income statement reports</primary>
    </indexterm>Income Statement Report</title>
  <para id="Para589688">The system ships with a basic Income Statement
  designed to generate Financial Reports using your Revenue and Expense
  Account data. In this section, we will examine this basic Income
  Statement.</para>
  <note>
    <para id="Para590507">Because the basic Income Statement is a
    system-defined Financial Report, it may not be modified (except to make it
    active or inactive). However, you may copy the report and modify the copy.
    You can think of the basic Income Statement as a template for building
    other, similar Financial Reports.</para>
  </note>
  <para id="Para589337">To view the basic Income Statement, select it for
  editing from the master list of Financial Reports. A message will alert you
  that this is a system-defined report which may only be viewed, not edited.
  Select the OK button to reach the following screen:</para>
  <para id="Para588893"><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/GL_FR_basicIncState.png" id="Graphic588891"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption588894">Basic Income Statement
        System-Defined</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para id="Para588860">The "Row Layout" tab displays information on all the
  Account Groups and Account Numbers which make up the basic Income Statement.
  If this were a custom report you were creating, you would be able to
  add/remove Account Groups and Account Numbers to meet your specific
  needs.</para>
  <tip>
    <para id="Para595284">To build row layouts for the three standard report
    types--Income Statement, Balance Sheet, and Cash Flow--use the same
    techniques as when building Ad Hoc report row layouts. The only difference
    is you won"t need to specify which balances to calculate (e.g., beginning,
    ending, etc.). The system determines which calculations will be done for
    the standard statement formats.</para>
  </tip>
  <para id="Para590724">When viewing row layouts for the basic Income
  Statement, you are presented with the following columns:</para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dc9f8">
      <para id="Para590770">Group/Account Name: Lists the Account Groups and
      Account Types used in the report. The two main groups are REVENUE and
      EXPENSES. All Accounts having Type=Revenue are included in the REVENUE
      group. And within the EXPENSES group all Accounts having Type=Expense
      are included.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dca1c">
      <para id="Para590775">Sub./Summ.: Indicates whether group information
      will be presented as a subtotal or summary line when the report is run.
      In the basic Income Statement, all Account Groups are subtotaled.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dca40">
      <para id="Para590776">Oper.: Specifies whether a group will be added to
      ("+") or subtracted from ("-") the group total. In the basic Income
      Statement, REVENUE is added to and EXPENSES are subtracted from the
      INCOME group.</para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <note>
    <para id="Para591250">Select the VIEW button to see the system-defined
    settings for each Account Group and Account Type used in the basic Income
    Statement. When creating your own reports, you may choose to either
    imitate or alter these default settings.</para>
  </note>
  <para id="Para595977">In addition to row layouts, you may also define column
  layouts for your Financial Reports. Column layouts are used to specify the
  time buckets financial information will be sorted into. You specify a column
  layout to use when viewing or printing Financial Reports. You may define any
  number of column layouts. Each layout will be linked to either a pre-defined
  report definition or a custom report definition you create yourself.</para>
  <para id="Para595978">On the basic Income Statement, select the "Column
  Layouts" tab to view all the time buckets available for the report. If this
  were a custom report you were creating, you would be able to add/remove
  column layouts to meet your specific needs.</para>
  <tip>
    <para id="Para596289">See the <xref endterm="Anchor94732" linkend="Anchor94732"/>
    FINDME
  "Cash Flow Report" section
    for specific examples describing the various column layout options.</para>
  </tip>
  <para id="Para588943"><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/GL_FR_basicIncStateCols.png" id="Graphic588941"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption588944">Basic Income Statement Column
        Layouts</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para id="Para591720">When viewing column layouts for the basic Income
  Statement, you are presented with the following column definitions--each of
  which defines a different time bucket available for viewing Income Statement
  information:</para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dcb3c">
      <para id="Para591721">Month: Displays data for the current month (i.e.,
      Accounting Period). The month used as the basis for the reporting is
      specified when the report is run. Uses the "FinancialReportMonth" report
      definition.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dcb60">
      <para id="Para591444">Month, Budget: Displays data for the current
      month, compared to Budget information for the current month. The month
      used as the basis for the reporting is specified when the report is run.
      Uses the "FinancialReportMonthBudget" report definition.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dcb84">
      <para id="Para591445">Month, Prior Month: Displays data for the current
      month, compared to the prior month. The month used as the basis for the
      reporting is specified when the report is run. Uses the
      "FinancialReportMonthPriorMonth" report definition.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dcba8">
      <para id="Para591446">Month, Prior Year Month: Displays data for the
      current month, compared to the same month in the prior Fiscal Year. The
      month used as the basis for the reporting is specified when the report
      is run. Uses the "FinancialReportMonthPriorMonth" report
      definition.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dcbcc">
      <para id="Para591447">Month, QTD: Displays data for the current month,
      compared to the current Quarter to-date. The month used as the basis for
      the reporting is specified when the report is run. Uses the
      "FinancialReportMonthQuarter" report definition.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dcbf0">
      <para id="Para591448">Month, YTD: Displays data for the current month,
      compared to the current Fiscal Year to-date. The month used as the basis
      for the reporting is specified when the report is run. Uses the
      "FinancialReportMonthYear" report definition.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dcc14">
      <para id="Para591739">QTD: Displays data for the current Quarter
      to-date. The month used as the basis for the reporting is specified when
      the report is run. Uses the "FinancialReportQuarter" report
      definition.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dcc38">
      <para id="Para591812">QTD, Budget: Displays data for the current Quarter
      to-date, compared to Budget information for the current Quarter. The
      month used as the basis for the reporting is specified when the report
      is run. Uses the "FinancialReportQuarterBudget" report
      definition.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dcc5c">
      <para id="Para591813">QTD, Prior Quarter: Displays data for the current
      Quarter to-date, compared to the prior Quarter. The month used as the
      basis for the reporting is specified when the report is run. Uses the
      "FinancialReportQuarterPriorQuarter" report definition.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dcc80">
      <para id="Para591452">QTD, Prior Year Quarter: Displays data for the
      current Quarter to-date, compared to the same Quarter in the prior
      Fiscal Year. The month used as the basis for the reporting is specified
      when the report is run. Uses the "FinancialReportQuarterPriorQuarter"
      report definition.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dcca4">
      <para id="Para591453">YTD: Displays data for the current Fiscal Year
      to-date. The month used as the basis for the reporting is specified when
      the report is run. Uses the "FinancialReportYear" report
      definition.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dccc8">
      <para id="Para591454">YTD, Budget: Displays data for the current Fiscal
      Year to-date, compared to Budget information for the current Fiscal Year
      to-date. The month used as the basis for the reporting is specified when
      the report is run. Uses the "FinancialReportYearBudget" report
      definition.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dccec">
      <para id="Para591455">YTD, Prior Full Year: Displays data for the
      current Fiscal Year to-date, compared to information for the entire
      prior Fiscal Year. The month used as the basis for the reporting is
      specified when the report is run. Uses the
      "FinancialReportYearPriorYear" report definition.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dcd10">
      <para id="Para591809">YTD, Prior Year YTD: Displays data for the current
      Fiscal Year to-date, compared to the prior Fiscal Year to-date. The
      month used as the basis for the reporting is specified when the report
      is run. Uses the "FinancialReportYearPriorYear" report
      definition.</para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <note>
    <para id="Para591408">Select the VIEW button to see the system-defined
    settings for each Account Group and Account Type used in the basic Income
    Statement. When creating your own reports, you may choose to either
    imitate or alter these default settings.</para>
  </note>
  <tip>
    <para id="Para595760">When creating a column layout, you can choose from
    the following standard report templates:</para>
    <para id="Para595761">FinancialReport (used by all Ad Hoc reports)</para>
    <para id="Para595762">FinancialReportMonth</para>
    <para id="Para595763">FinancialReportMonthBudget</para>
    <para id="Para595764">FinancialReportMonthDbCr</para>
    <para id="Para595765">FinancialReportMonthPriorMonth</para>
    <para id="Para595766">FinancialReportMonthPriorQuarter</para>
    <para id="Para595767">FinancialReportMonthPriorYear</para>
    <para id="Para595768">FinancialReportMonthQuarter</para>
    <para id="Para595769">FinancialReportMonthYear</para>
    <para id="Para595770">FinancialReportQuarter</para>
    <para id="Para595771">FinancialReportQuarterBudget</para>
    <para id="Para595772">FinancialReportQuarterPriorQuarter</para>
    <para id="Para595773">FinancialReportYear</para>
    <para id="Para595774">FinancialReportYearBudget</para>
    <para id="Para595775">FinancialReportYearPriorYear</para>
    <para id="Para595776">FinancialTrend (used by non-Ad-Hoc trend
    reports)</para>
    <para id="Para595777">If for some reason these templates don"t meet your
    needs, you can always use OpenRPT to a) modify them or b) create your own
    custom report templates.</para>
  </tip>
  <para id="Para591405">To view additional configuration options for the
  layout of the basic Income Statement, select the "Options" tab. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para id="Para592628"><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/GL_FR_basicIncStateOpt.png" id="Graphic592626"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption592629">Basic Income Statement Options</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para id="Para592630">The layout for the basic Income Statement does not use
  any extra configuration options. However, if you were creating your own
  Income Statement layout, you could choose to a) include a Grand Total row
  and b) use alternate labels for Budget and Grand Total rows when viewing
  and/or printing the Financial Report.</para>
</section>