<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section589336">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>financial reports</primary>
      <secondary>income statement type</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>income statement reports</primary>
    </indexterm>Income Statement Report</title>
  <para>The system ships with a basic Income Statement designed to generate
  Financial Reports using your Revenue and Expense Account data. In this
  section, we will examine this basic Income Statement.</para>
  <note>
    <para>Because the basic Income Statement is a system-defined Financial
    Report, it may not be modified (except to make it active or inactive).
    However, you may copy the report and modify the copy. You can think of the
    basic Income Statement as a template for building other, similar Financial
    Reports.</para>
  </note>
  <para>To view the basic Income Statement, select it for editing from the
  master list of Financial Reports. A message will alert you that this is a
  system-defined report which may only be viewed, not edited. Select the OK
  button to reach the following screen:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/GL_FR_basicIncState.png"
                     id="Graphic588891" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption588894">Basic Income Statement
        System-Defined</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>The "Row Layout" tab displays information on all the Account Groups
  and Account Numbers which make up the basic Income Statement. If this were a
  custom report you were creating, you would be able to add/remove Account
  Groups and Account Numbers to meet your specific needs.</para>
  <tip>
    <para>To build row layouts for the three standard report types--Income
    Statement, Balance Sheet, and Cash Flow--use the same techniques as when
    building Ad Hoc report row layouts. The only difference is you won"t need
    to specify which balances to calculate (e.g., beginning, ending, etc.).
    The system determines which calculations will be done for the standard
    statement formats.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>When viewing row layouts for the basic Income Statement, you are
  presented with the following columns:</para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dc9f8">
      <para>Group/Account Name: Lists the Account Groups and Account Types
      used in the report. The two main groups are REVENUE and EXPENSES. All
      Accounts having Type=Revenue are included in the REVENUE group. And
      within the EXPENSES group all Accounts having Type=Expense are
      included.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dca1c">
      <para>Sub./Summ.: Indicates whether group information will be presented
      as a subtotal or summary line when the report is run. In the basic
      Income Statement, all Account Groups are subtotaled.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dca40">
      <para>Oper.: Specifies whether a group will be added to ("+") or
      subtracted from ("-") the group total. In the basic Income Statement,
      REVENUE is added to and EXPENSES are subtracted from the INCOME
      group.</para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <note>
    <para>Select the VIEW button to see the system-defined settings for each
    Account Group and Account Type used in the basic Income Statement. When
    creating your own reports, you may choose to either imitate or alter these
    default settings.</para>
  </note>
  <para>In addition to row layouts, you may also define column layouts for
  your Financial Reports. Column layouts are used to specify the time buckets
  financial information will be sorted into. You specify a column layout to
  use when viewing or printing Financial Reports. You may define any number of
  column layouts. Each layout will be linked to either a pre-defined report
  definition or a custom report definition you create yourself.</para>
  <para>On the basic Income Statement, select the "Column Layouts" tab to view
  all the time buckets available for the report. If this were a custom report
  you were creating, you would be able to add/remove column layouts to meet
  your specific needs.</para>
  <tip>
    <para>See <xref endterm="Anchor94732" linkend="Anchor94732" /> for
    specific examples describing the various column layout options.</para>
  </tip>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/GL_FR_basicIncStateCols.png"
                     id="Graphic588941" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption588944">Basic Income Statement Column
        Layouts</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When viewing column layouts for the basic Income Statement, you are
  presented with the following column definitions--each of which defines a
  different time bucket available for viewing Income Statement
  information:</para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dcb3c">
      <para>Month: Displays data for the current month (i.e., Accounting
      Period). The month used as the basis for the reporting is specified when
      the report is run. Uses the "FinancialReportMonth" report
      definition.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dcb60">
      <para>Month, Budget: Displays data for the current month, compared to
      Budget information for the current month. The month used as the basis
      for the reporting is specified when the report is run. Uses the
      "FinancialReportMonthBudget" report definition.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dcb84">
      <para>Month, Prior Month: Displays data for the current month, compared
      to the prior month. The month used as the basis for the reporting is
      specified when the report is run. Uses the
      "FinancialReportMonthPriorMonth" report definition.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dcba8">
      <para>Month, Prior Year Month: Displays data for the current month,
      compared to the same month in the prior Fiscal Year. The month used as
      the basis for the reporting is specified when the report is run. Uses
      the "FinancialReportMonthPriorMonth" report definition.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dcbcc">
      <para>Month, QTD: Displays data for the current month, compared to the
      current Quarter to-date. The month used as the basis for the reporting
      is specified when the report is run. Uses the
      "FinancialReportMonthQuarter" report definition.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dcbf0">
      <para>Month, YTD: Displays data for the current month, compared to the
      current Fiscal Year to-date. The month used as the basis for the
      reporting is specified when the report is run. Uses the
      "FinancialReportMonthYear" report definition.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dcc14">
      <para>QTD: Displays data for the current Quarter to-date. The month used
      as the basis for the reporting is specified when the report is run. Uses
      the "FinancialReportQuarter" report definition.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dcc38">
      <para>QTD, Budget: Displays data for the current Quarter to-date,
      compared to Budget information for the current Quarter. The month used
      as the basis for the reporting is specified when the report is run. Uses
      the "FinancialReportQuarterBudget" report definition.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dcc5c">
      <para>QTD, Prior Quarter: Displays data for the current Quarter to-date,
      compared to the prior Quarter. The month used as the basis for the
      reporting is specified when the report is run. Uses the
      "FinancialReportQuarterPriorQuarter" report definition.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dcc80">
      <para>QTD, Prior Year Quarter: Displays data for the current Quarter
      to-date, compared to the same Quarter in the prior Fiscal Year. The
      month used as the basis for the reporting is specified when the report
      is run. Uses the "FinancialReportQuarterPriorQuarter" report
      definition.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dcca4">
      <para>YTD: Displays data for the current Fiscal Year to-date. The month
      used as the basis for the reporting is specified when the report is run.
      Uses the "FinancialReportYear" report definition.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dccc8">
      <para>YTD, Budget: Displays data for the current Fiscal Year to-date,
      compared to Budget information for the current Fiscal Year to-date. The
      month used as the basis for the reporting is specified when the report
      is run. Uses the "FinancialReportYearBudget" report definition.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dccec">
      <para>YTD, Prior Full Year: Displays data for the current Fiscal Year
      to-date, compared to information for the entire prior Fiscal Year. The
      month used as the basis for the reporting is specified when the report
      is run. Uses the "FinancialReportYearPriorYear" report
      definition.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dcd10">
      <para>YTD, Prior Year YTD: Displays data for the current Fiscal Year
      to-date, compared to the prior Fiscal Year to-date. The month used as
      the basis for the reporting is specified when the report is run. Uses
      the "FinancialReportYearPriorYear" report definition.</para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <note>
    <para>Select the VIEW button to see the system-defined settings for each
    Account Group and Account Type used in the basic Income Statement. When
    creating your own reports, you may choose to either imitate or alter these
    default settings.</para>
  </note>
  <tip>
    <para>When creating a column layout, you can choose from the following
    standard report templates:</para>
    <para>FinancialReport (used by all Ad Hoc reports)</para>
    <para>FinancialReportMonth</para>
    <para>FinancialReportMonthBudget</para>
    <para>FinancialReportMonthDbCr</para>
    <para>FinancialReportMonthPriorMonth</para>
    <para>FinancialReportMonthPriorQuarter</para>
    <para>FinancialReportMonthPriorYear</para>
    <para>FinancialReportMonthQuarter</para>
    <para>FinancialReportMonthYear</para>
    <para>FinancialReportQuarter</para>
    <para>FinancialReportQuarterBudget</para>
    <para>FinancialReportQuarterPriorQuarter</para>
    <para>FinancialReportYear</para>
    <para>FinancialReportYearBudget</para>
    <para>FinancialReportYearPriorYear</para>
    <para>FinancialTrend (used by non-Ad-Hoc trend reports)</para>
    <para>If for some reason these templates don"t meet your needs, you can
    always use OpenRPT to a) modify them or b) create your own custom report
    templates.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>To view additional configuration options for the layout of the basic
  Income Statement, select the "Options" tab. The following screen will
  appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/GL_FR_basicIncStateOpt.png"
                     id="Graphic592626" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption592629">Basic Income Statement Options</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>The layout for the basic Income Statement does not use any extra
  configuration options. However, if you were creating your own Income
  Statement layout, you could choose to a) include a Grand Total row and b)
  use alternate labels for Budget and Grand Total rows when viewing and/or
  printing the Financial Report.</para>
</section>