<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2008 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="importXML">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>XML</primary>
      <secondary>importing data</secondary>
    </indexterm><indexterm>
      <primary>importing data</primary>
      <secondary>XML</secondary>
    </indexterm><indexterm>
      <primary>data import</primary>
    </indexterm>Import XML</title>
  <para>Use the Import XML window to import data from XML files into a
  database for the xTuple applications. If you try to open this window without
  first configuring the system for importing XML data, you will be given the
  opportunity to go directly to the <xref endterm="configureIE.title"
  linkend="configureIE.title" /> window.</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/importXML.png" id="importXML.screenshot" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="importXML.screenshot.caption">Import XML</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When you open the Import XML window the table on the window is
  populated with a list of all XML files in the default XML directory for your
  computer (see <xref linkend="configureIE.title" />). To the far right of the
  screen, the following buttons are available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Close</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Close this window without doing any more work.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Add To List</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Add another file to the list of files to be processed.</para>
        <para>This file is not permanently added to the list; it will be
        removed when either it has been imported successfully or you close the
        window, whichever comes first.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Delete From List</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Remove a file from the list of files to be processed.</para>
        <para>This file is not permanently removed from the list; it will
        reappear after you try to import data from other files, click the
        <guibutton>Reset List</guibutton> button, or close and reopen this
        window. The only way to permanently remove a file from this list is to
        remove it from the default import directory. You can do this by
        importing the file successfully or by manually removing the
        file.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Reset List</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Rescan the default import directory and refresh the contents of
        the on-screen table.</para>
        <para>Files that have been imported successfully will be removed from
        the list, unless you selected the <xref
        endterm="configureIE.filehandling.donothing"
        linkend="configureIE.filehandling.donothing" /> option in Configure
        Import and Export. Any files you have added to the list with the
        <guibutton>Add To List</guibutton> button will be removed. Any files
        you have removed from the list with the <guibutton>Delete From
        List</guibutton> button will be put back.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Clear Status</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The Status column in the on-screen table will be set to blank on
        all rows.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Import Selected</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Import all of the files in the on-screen table that are
        currently selected. Each file is imported in its own
        transaction.</para>
        <para>Read any error messages that appear carefully. Some of them
        explicitly state that the error will be ignored and that processing
        will continue after you acknowledge the message. These warn you of
        unexpected conditions in the imported data that do not appear as
        though they will cause problems.</para>
        <para>Errors that are not marked as being ignored will cause the
        import of that one file to be rolled back but the other files will be
        processed until all selected files have been tried. This allows you to
        fix any problems with importing a particular XML file without having
        to retry all of the others as well.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Import All</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Import all of the files in the on-screen table. This behaves
        exactly the same way as the <guibutton>Import Selected</guibutton>
        button except it processes all of the listed files, not just the
        selected ones.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
