<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="invoiceItem">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>invoices</primary>
      <secondary>adding line items to</secondary>
    </indexterm>Invoice Item</title>
  <para id="Para574264">To add a new Invoice Line Item, select the NEW button.
  The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para id="Para574268"><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/AR_Inv_InvoiceItem.png"
                     id="Graphic574266" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption574269">Create Invoice Line Item</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para id="Para574270">When creating a new Invoice Line Item, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para574271">Invoice #</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1878a44">
        <para>Displays the Invoice Number specified in the "Invoice"
        screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para574272">Line #</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1878a8c">
        <para>Displays the Line Item Number for the current Line Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para574273">Item Type</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1878ad4">
        <para>Indicate the Item Type for the Invoice Line Item, by selecting
        one of the following options:</para>
        <para id="Para574274">Item: The browse button located to the right of
        the field leads to a searchable list of Inventory Items. The list will
        contain sold Items available for purchase by the specified Customer.
        The list of available Items may vary from Customer to Customer,
        depending on how Pricing Schedules are implemented at your site. Once
        an Item Number is entered, the Inventory Unit of Measure and Item
        description will automatically appear. Additionally, you may also
        specify the Item's supplying Warehouse. Items may be supplied from
        multiple Warehouses. Warehouses designated as "Sold from" Warehouses
        in the Item Site master for an Item are considered "Supplying
        Warehouses" on this screen. By default, the Item Site with the highest
        Ranking will be selected as the supplying Warehouse. If more than one
        Item Site share a Ranking of "1", the default supplying Warehouse will
        be selected in alphabetical order. Item Sites are ranked using the
        Ranking mechanism on the Item Site master.</para>
        <para id="Para574275">Miscellaneous: Enter a name and description for
        the miscellaneous, non-Inventory Item you are billing the Customer
        for. The name and description fields are free-form, meaning they
        accept unlimited alphanumeric characters. You must also select a Sales
        Category. Sales Categories are used to identify the General Ledger
        (G/L) Accounts to be used when non-Inventory Sales transactions take
        place.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para574276">Customer P/N</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1878b1c">
        <para>If applicable, enter a Customer Part Number to further identify
        the Item you are billing the Customer for.</para>
        <para id="Para574277">In the case of Inventory Items, the Customer
        Part Number will display automatically if you enter an Item Alias in
        the Item Number field. To enter an Item Alias, place the cursor in the
        Item Number field and then use the keyboard shortcut "CTRL + A". After
        you have entered a valid Item Alias, hit the TAB key. A list of Items
        that use the specified Item Alias will be displayed. Select the
        desired Item from the list. The Item Alias will display as the
        Customer Part Number. Item Aliases are defined on the Item
        master.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para574278">Qty. Ordered</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1878b64">
        <para>Enter the quantity of the Item you are billing for. The quantity
        ordered for Inventory Items is measured in the Item's Inventory
        UOM.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para id="Para574280">The Quantity Ordered for Inventory Items is based on
    the Inventory UOM. But the Price is based on the Price UOM. Whenever these
    two UOMs are not identical, the Extended Price for a Line Item will be
    based on the following formula:</para>
    <para id="Para574281">(Qty. Ordered) x (Price/Inv. Ratio) x (Net Unit
    Price)</para>
    <para id="Para574282">If for some reason the Prices don"t look correct,
    check the Item master for the Line Item in question. It may be that the
    Inventory and Price UOMs do not exist in a 1:1 relationship.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para574283">Qty. Billed</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1878bf4">
        <para>Specify the quantity of ordered Items you are billing
        for.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para574285"><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>invoices</primary>
          <secondary>line item pricing for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Net Unit Price</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1878c84">
        <para>For Inventory Items having assigned Pricing Schedules, the Net
        Unit Price will be automatically calculated. For miscellaneous Items,
        the Net Unit Price must be entered manually.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para574286">Extended Price</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1878ccc">
        <para>Displays the Extended Price.</para>
        <para id="Para574287">The Extended Price for a Line Item is based on
        the quantity ordered multiplied by the Net Unit Price.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para574288">Pricing UOM</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1878d14">
        <para>Displays the Price UOM for an Inventory Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para574289">Ratio</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1878d5c">
        <para>The ratio displayed here is the Price/Inventory UOM ratio, which
        is defined in the Item master for an Inventory Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para574290">Unit Cost</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1878da4">
        <para>Displays the Standard Cost per unit for an Inventory
        Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para574291">List Price</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1878dec">
        <para>Displays the sales List Price per unit for an Inventory
        Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para574292">Customer Price</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x187e824">
        <para>Displays the Price given to the specified Customer for an
        Inventory Item.</para>
        <para id="Para574293">Special Customer Prices can be set for
        individual Customers or Customer Groups by using a Pricing
        Schedule.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para574294">Notes</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x187e86c">
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        general Notes related to the Invoice Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>