<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2008 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section529534">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>shipping</primary>
      <secondary>issuing stock to</secondary>
    </indexterm>Issue Stock to Shipping</title>
  <para>Once Sales Order (or Transfer Order) Line Items are ready to be
  shipped, they must be issued to Shipping. Shipping is a two-step process.
  Quantity is first issued to Shipping, and then it is shipped.</para>
  <note>
    <para><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>job items</primary>
        <secondary>posting production for</secondary>
      </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>shipping</primary>
        <secondary>job items and</secondary>
      </indexterm>For Job Items linked to Sales Order Items, the act of
    issuing to Shipping serves a dual purpose. On the one hand, quantity is
    issued to Shipping. But at the same time, production for the linked Job
    Item Work Order is also posted. Issuing to Shipping is the only way to
    post production for a Job Item Work Order.</para>
  </note>
  <para>To issue Stock to Shipping, select the "Issue Stock to Shipping"
  option. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/issueToShipping.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="issueToShippingStockToShipping">Issue Stock to
        Shipping</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <note>
    <para>Before a Sales Order can be shipped successfully, Sales Account and
    A/R Account Assignments for the specified Customer must be in
    place.</para>
  </note>
  <para>When issuing Stock to Shipping, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Sales Order #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the Sales Order Number of the Sales Order whose Stock you
        want to issue to Shipping.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="standard">
      <term>Transfer Order #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the Transfer Order Number of the Transfer Order whose
        Stock you want to issue to Shipping.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="standard">
      <term>From</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Source Warehouse if a Transfer Order is
        selected.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="standard">
      <term>To</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Destination Warehouse if a Transfer Order is
        selected.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Require sufficient Inventory</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to ensure you have enough Quantity on Hand of a Line Item
        prior to issuing Stock to Shipping. If selected, this option will
        prevent you from issuing Line Item quantity to Shipping if doing so
        would force Quantity on Hand for the Item Site to fall below zero. Not
        selecting this option means issuing Stock to Shipping may drive Item
        Site Quantity on Hand negative.</para>
        <note>
          <para>If your site is configured to enable Sales Order Reservations,
          which, by definition, require sufficient Inventory before Items may
          be shipped, then the "Require sufficient Inventory" option will be
          hidden.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Line Items</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists Sales Order Line Items available for Shipping. If
        the Scheduled Date for an unshipped Line Item is in the future, the
        line will display in green text. If the Scheduled Date for an
        unshipped Line Item is not in the future, the line will display in red
        text. Once shipped, all Line Items revert to black text.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Issue Items Using Bar Code</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This is an optional field which allows you to issue stock to
        Shipping using a Bar Code scanner. Enter a UPC Code for a Sales Order
        Line Item using a Bar Code scanner&mdash;or manually enter the UPC Code.
        The UPC Code for an Item is stored on the Item master. Once the code
        is entered, specify a quantity and then select the FIND button to
        issue the Line Item quantity to shipping. You may also hit the ENTER
        key on your keyboard to select the FIND button. This field also
        supports the scanning of Work Order bar codes, if the Work Order is
        linked to a Sales Order. The Sales Order Number must already be
        entered for the Work Order scan to be successful. If the scan is not
        successful, then you know the Work Order does not belong to the Sales
        Order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>Most scanners allow you to change a setting that automatically sends
    the ENTER command after a scan. This allows keyboard-free entry.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty.</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the quantity of Line Items to be issued using a UPC
        Code. To issue the Line Item quantity to shipping, select the FIND
        button&mdash;or hit the ENTER key on your keyboard to select the FIND
        button.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CLOSE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without issuing stock to Shipping, returning
        you to the application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>If an Order is marked "Ship Complete," you will be prevented from
    shipping the Order until all Line Item quantities are issued to
    Shipping.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SHIP ORDER</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to Ship the specified Sales Order, as described in <xref
        linkend="Anchor28938" />.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>ISSUE STOCK</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a Line Item, then select this button to issue stock to
        Shipping. You may also double-click on a Line Item to reach the Issue
        Stock screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>If an Item issued to Shipping is a <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>multiple location control</primary>
        <secondary>impact on shipping</secondary>
      </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>shipping</primary>
        <secondary>MLC impact on</secondary>
      </indexterm>Multiple Location Control (MLC) Item, you will be prompted
    to specify the Location you want to issue stock from.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>ISSUE LINE BAL.</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a Line Item, then select this button to issue the
        balance of the Line to shipping.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>RETURN STOCK</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a Line Item, then select this button to remove the
        Line from Shipping, returning the stock to Inventory.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>If your site integrates UPS WorldShip with the system, you should
    process Orders in WorldShip after they have been issued to Shipping&mdash;but
    before they have been shipped. For more information, see <xref
    linkend="Anchor29552" />.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>ISSUE ALL BAL.</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to issue all Line Items to Shipping
        simultaneously.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>FIND</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Compares the UPC Code entered in the "Issue Items Using Barcode"
        field with the UPC Codes for the listed Sales Order Line Items, then
        issues to Shipping the quantity specified in the "Qty." field. The
        FIND button may be selected using your mouse&mdash;or by hitting the ENTER
        key, which corresponds to the FIND button. Because the FIND button
        corresponds to the ENTER key, you can scan in a UPC Code and then hit
        ENTER to issue a quantity of one to Shipping. If you prefer, you can
        scan in a UPC Code and then specify a different quantity before
        hitting ENTER.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <xi:include href="issueLineToShipping.xml"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
              xpointer="element(/1)" />
</section>