<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section518889">
  <title id="Anchor13555"><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>items</primary>
      <secondary>creating new</secondary>
    </indexterm>Enter New Item</title>
  <para>To enter a new Item into your system, select the "Enter New Item"
  option. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/item.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create New Item</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When creating a new Item, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a number to uniquely identify the Item. Duplicate Item
        Numbers will not be accepted.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Active</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if Item is active. Select this option if you intend to
        use the Item within the application. If you don"t select this option,
        the Item will be unavailable for use. To activate an inactive Item,
        simply open the Item master and mark the Item as active.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>An inactive Item may still be used in a Sales Order, Work Order, or
    Purchase Order if the Item was de-activated after the Order was
    created.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Description #1</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The Item master features two description lines. The first line
        is typically used for entering the name used to describe the Item. In
        printed reports or other printouts, the first line will appear on a
        separate line above the second line. However, the two lines will be
        concatenated (i.e., "joined together") when they are displayed
        on-screen within the application.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Description #2</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Use the second description line to provide additional
        information about the Item. The second line might include product,
        packaging, or any other descriptive information. In printed reports or
        other printouts, the second line will appear on a separate line below
        the first line. However, the two lines will be concatenated (i.e.,
        "joined together") when they are displayed on-screen within the
        application.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>Develop a logical, hierarchical numbering strategy before assigning
    Numbers to your Items. Using an hierarchical approach will greatly enhance
    your ability to display and search for information within the database. An
    hierarchical numbering scheme might look something like the
    following:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>MB-26-1</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>MB-26-2</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>MB-26-3</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>In this case, similar Items have been assigned sequential Item
    Numbers. By extension, similar categories of Items may be identified by
    similar numbers.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>item types</primary>
          <secondary>master list of</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>items</primary>
          <secondary>list of types</secondary>
        </indexterm>Item Type</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select one of the available Item Types:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>purchased</primary>
                <secondary>as item type</secondary>
              </indexterm>Purchased</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if the Item is an Item you purchase.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>manufactured</primary>
                <secondary>as item type</secondary>
              </indexterm>Manufactured</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if the Item is an Item you make.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>phantoms</primary>
                <secondary>as item type</secondary>
              </indexterm>Phantom</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>A transient subassembly containing component Items
              commonly used together during a manufacturing process. Phantom
              Items require a Bill of Materials, but not separate Work Orders.
              Since they are not stock Items, Material Requirements Planning
              (MRP) logic blows through phantom Items and only plans for their
              component Items. Phantom Items should be used to simplify
              complex Bills of Materials.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Breeder</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>A logical Item from which Co-Products and By-Products are
              produced. An example use for a Breeder Item is the screening of
              raw gravel to produce different sizes of gravel. The Breeder
              Item's Bill of Materials (BOM) defines the inputs--in this case
              raw gravel--and the outputs are defined on its Breeder BOM
              (i.e., Small, Medium and Large gravel). A Work Order is created
              for the Breeder Item, but this Item is never stocked or
              produced; again, it is a logical Item. Instead, raw gravel is
              consumed by the Breeder's Work Order, along with labor, and the
              resulting quantities of Co-Products and By-Products are
              recorded.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Co-Product</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Co-Products are Items that you keep and which absorb
              Costs. They are produced during a manufacturing process. See
              "Breeder" Item Type above.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>By-Product</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>By-Products are things that you throw away and incur Costs
              doing so during a manufacturing process. See "Breeder" Item Type
              above.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>reference</primary>
                <secondary>as item type</secondary>
              </indexterm>Reference</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if the Item is an Item you sell--but you neither
              manufacture nor purchase it. Services are an example of a
              reference Item. The company sells consulting services, but it
              doesn"t manufacture or purchase them.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>costing</primary>
                <secondary>as item type</secondary>
              </indexterm>Costing</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>A kind of pseudo-Item used solely to provide a costed
              value for a Costing Element. When a user-defined Costing Element
              is linked to a Costing Item, the Costing Element assumes the
              Costs associated with the Costing Item. For more information,
              see <xref linkend="Anchor68692" />.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>tooling</primary>
                <secondary>as item type</secondary>
              </indexterm>Tooling</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if the Item is an Item you make but do not sell. An
              example of a tooling Item would be an Item you must make in
              order to complete or support the building of sold Items.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Outside Process</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if the Item is an external process or service that
              is performed by someone outside your company. Outside Process
              Items are treated by the system in much the same way as
              purchased Items are. For example, Outside Process Items will be
              handled in the same was as purchased Items are when Material
              Requirements Planning (MRP) is run.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Planning</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>An Item whose Bill of Materials (BOM) groups together
              other Items so that a Production Plan may be defined for the
              Planning Item--and then exploded down to the lower level Items
              during a Master Production Scheduling (MPS) run. Planning Items
              are frequently used to group together product families or
              product lines of MPS Items. MPS Items are typically top-level
              saleable Items. By grouping together MPS Items under a Planning
              Item, the family may be forecasted through with a Production
              Plan for the Planning Item, thereby simplifying the planning
              process. The system automatically sets the Planning System as
              "MPS" by default when a Planning Item is created.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Job</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Job Items are specifically for make-to-order scenarios
              where simplified production is required. Job Items cannot be
              maintained in Inventory. And they also have no concept of
              Standard Cost or Cost variances. All Costs for Job Items are
              Actual. The Work Orders which create Job Items can only be
              created via a Sales Order. The Costs for job Work Orders are
              accumulated to WIP, and then transfered directly to Cost of
              Sales when the job is shipped. BOM and BOO Items may be assigned
              to Job items; however, they will not roll up to a Standard Cost
              for Job items.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Maximum Desired Cost</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This is an optional field to be used for entering the maximum
        Cost desired for the Item. The field is not used by the system for any
        calculations, and is provided for informational purposes only.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Class Code</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify a Class Code to associate with the Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>units of measure</primary>
          <secondary>at item level</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>pricing</primary>
          <secondary>item list price</secondary>
        </indexterm>Inventory UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the Item's primary Unit of Measure--or enter a free-form
        UOM. The Inventory (UOM) is the UOM in which Inventory is maintained.
        All Inventory transactions, sales transactions, and General Ledger
        transactions reflect movement in Inventory UOMs. The Inventory UOM is
        also the base reference for all UOM conversion ratios.</para>
        <note>
          <para>Once transactions have been posted using an Item's Inventory
          UOM, you may no longer change the Inventory UOM for the Item.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Pick List Item</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you want the Item to be included on Pick Lists when
        the Item is used. Pick Lists are printed lists showing the Work Order
        Material Requirements for a specified Work Order. You may decide not
        to include an Item on Pick Lists if the Item is insignificant or if it
        is not stored in a stock room but, for example, in a Work Center
        instead.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Fractional</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if the Item may be maintained in fractional quantities.
        If not selected, the system will assume the Item is maintained in its
        Inventory UOM, which is by definition a whole number. This means you
        may never use fractional quantities of the Item (e.g., in
        manufacturing or purchasing) unless this option is selected.</para>
        <tip>
          <para>If you will ever use the Item in fractional quantities, then
          the "Fractional" option must be selected. If it is not selected, the
          system will never let you use fractional quantities of the
          Item.</para>
        </tip>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="openmfg">
      <term>Planning System</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify which of the following planning systems you want the
        Item to be considered by:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>MRP</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if you want the Material Requirements Planning
              (MRP) system to create Planned Orders for the Item when MRP is
              run.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>MPS</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if you want the Master Production Scheduling (MPS)
              system to create Planned Orders for the Item when MPS is
              run.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>None</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if you want MRP and MPS to ignore the Item.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>The choice of planning system is exclusive. That is, MPS will not
    create Planned Orders for MRP Items when it is run. Likewise, the MRP
    system will not create Planned Orders for MPS Items when it is run.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item is Sold</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if the Item is an Item you sell. If not selected, the
        associated fields will be disabled.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Product Category</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the Product Category if the Item is sold. All sold Items
        must be assigned a Product Category.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>pricing</primary>
          <secondary>item list price</secondary>
        </indexterm>List Price</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the List Price for the Item, based on the selling UOM
        (i.e., "Per" UOM). List Prices may also be created and modified in the
        Item Pricing section of the Sales module. Changes made to the List
        Price in either location will be updated system-wide.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm>
          <primary>units of measure</primary>
          <secondary>selling specified</secondary>
        </indexterm>Per</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the selling Unit of Measure (UOM) for the Item. The List
        Price should be based on this selection. By default, the Inventory UOM
        will be used here. You will not be able to select a different UOM
        until you first manually create a selling UOM using the options found
        under the "UOM" tab on the Item master.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>UPC Code</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the Universal Product Code for the Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>Standard bar code formats supported by the system include the
    following: Code 3of9, Code 3of9 Extended, Code 128, UPC-A, UPC-E, EAN-8,
    EAN-13.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>exclusive</primary>
          <secondary>item master control</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>items</primary>
          <secondary>exclusive for customers</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>customers</primary>
          <secondary>exclusive items for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Exclusive</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if the Item is sold exclusively. If a sold Item is marked
        as Exclusive, it may only be sold to specified Customers or Customer
        Types. To link Exclusive Items to Customers, you would first include
        the Item on a Pricing Schedule--indicating relevant Prices and
        Quantity Breaks. You would then assign the Pricing Schedule to
        specified Customers or Customer Types, using the Pricing Schedule
        assignment functionality found in the Item Pricing section of the
        Sales module.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>Sold Items can be configured as Exclusive by default at the system
    level.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Product Weight</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the pre-packaging weight of the product.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Packaging Weight</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the weight of the product packaging.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Notes</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        Notes related to the Item. Any Notes entered on this screen are for
        internal purposes only.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without creating the Item, returning you to
        the application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Creates the Item and adds it to the master list of Items. Mac
        users may use COMMAND + S to save. After saving, the "Create New Item
        Sites" screen appears. If you select "YES," you will be directed to
        the screen for entering a new Item Site. If you select "No," the new
        Item will be added to Inventory, but no Item Site will be created for
        it. You may create an Item Site at a later time.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>PRINT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Runs the report associated with this screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="openmfg">
      <term>BOO</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to open the Bill of Operations (BOO) for the specified
        Item. If no BOO exists, you will have the option to create a new
        BOO.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>BOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to open the Bill of Materials (BOM) for the specified
        Item. If no BOM exists, you will have the option to create a new
        BOO.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>WORKBENCH</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to open the Item Availability Workbench for the specified
        Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>The Extended Description field is for entering descriptive Item
  information, which may be printed on Sales and/or Purchasing documents. You
  would add the Extended Description to printed documents using the report
  writer. The report writer enables you to customize Forms to include data
  stored in the database. To enter an Extended Description of an Item, select
  the "Extended Description" tab. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/item_extDescTab.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Item Extended Description</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Extended Description</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        extended descriptions of the Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>In addition to the Inventory Unit of Measure (UOM), which is defined
  on the Item master, you also have the option to define alternate UOMs for an
  Item. The following alternate UOMs may be defined:</para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>Alternate Capacity</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>Capacity</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>Material Issue</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>Selling</para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>Unless you define an alternate UOM, an Item will always be stored and
  used in its Inventory UOM. For example, you must define a selling UOM if you
  want to enable an Item to be sold in a UOM other than the Inventory UOM. To
  enter <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>units of measure</primary>
      <secondary>associating with items</secondary>
    </indexterm> Units of Measure associated with an Item, select the "UOM"
  tab. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <screenshot>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/item_tabUOM.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption><para>Item Units of Measure</para></caption>
    </mediaobject>
  </screenshot>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Conversions/Where Used</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists the UOM Conversions defined for the Item (if any)
        and where these conversions are used. Global conversion ratios are
        defined in the <xref linkend="uomConv" /> section.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Opens screen for creating a new Item UOM conversion.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>EDIT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enables you to edit highlighted Item UOM conversions. The edit
        screen is the same as that for creating a new Item UOM
        conversion--except that when editing, the fields will contain Item UOM
        conversion information. Double-clicking on an Item UOM conversion will
        also bring you to the editing screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>DELETE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight an Item UOM conversion and then select this button to
        remove the UOM conversion from the list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>units of measure</primary>
      <secondary>alternates for items</secondary>
    </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>items</primary>
      <secondary>alternate uoms for</secondary>
    </indexterm>To define an alternate Item UOM, select the NEW button. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <screenshot>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/itemUOM.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption><para>Unit of Measure Definition</para></caption>
    </mediaobject>
  </screenshot>
  <para>When defining an alternate Item UOM, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Source UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>By default the Inventory UOM will be displayed here. However,
        you may select an alternate UOM. If an alternate UOM is selected, then
        the per UOM will be the Inventory UOM.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Value</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter a value for the source UOM to be used in the
              conversion ratio for the alternate Item UOM.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <variablelist>
    <tip>
      <para>By default, the Available Types list will be empty--until you
      specify either a source or per UOM. Once a source or per UOM is
      selected, the Available Types list will be populated with the available
      options. An Item may have multiple selling UOMs but only one of each of
      the other types.</para>
    </tip>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Per UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>By default the Inventory UOM will be displayed here. However,
        you may select an alternate UOM. If an alternate UOM is selected, then
        the Source UOM will be the Inventory UOM.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Value</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter a value for the per UOM to be used in the conversion
              ratio for the alternate Item UOM.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Fractional</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify whether this alternate Item UOM may be maintained in
        fractional quantities. If not selected, transaction quantities using
        this alternate Item UOM may not be maintained in fractional
        quantities.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Available Types</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Once a source or per UOM has been specified, you may select one
        of the available UOM types. Once a UOM type has been used, you may not
        create a conversion ratio for it again--with the exception of the
        selling UOM, which may be defined multiple times for a single
        Item.</para>
        <tip>
          <para>Double-clicking on an available UOM type will move it to the
          Selected Types list.</para>
        </tip>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Alternate Capacity</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The Alt. Capacity UOM should be used to provide an
              alternate UOM for viewing Inventory details. For example, a
              Sales Manager may be satisfied looking at a group of Items
              normalized to their selling or Inventory UOM, but a Production
              Manager may need to look at the same Items normalized to a
              Production UOM--say, Cubic Feet (CuFt).</para>
              <note>
                <para>The Alternate Capacity UOM has no impact on Bills of
                Materials. It is used solely for Capacity Planning and Sales
                Analysis purposes.</para>
              </note>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Capacity</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>In Capacity Planning and Sales Analysis reports, the
              Capacity UOM enables you to make apples-to-apples comparisons of
              Items that use different Inventory UOMs. For example, let's say
              that Item A is a carton containing 24 Item B"s--and that you
              sell both Items. However, Item A and Item B use different
              Inventory UOMs. Item A is measured by the CASE (24), and Item B
              is measured by EACH. By utilizing the Capacity UOM, you have the
              ability to track total load and total sales for Item B--even
              though the Inventory UOM for Item A obscures the quantity of
              Item B's contained therein. If, when you query the database, you
              request data to be displayed in Capacity UOMs, then the system
              will normalize the quantities of Item A to EACH, allowing you to
              see the total quantity of Item Bs.</para>
              <note>
                <para>The Capacity UOM has no impact on Bills of Materials. It
                is used solely for Capacity Planning and Sales Analysis
                purposes.</para>
              </note>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Material Issue</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The Material Issue UOM defines an alternate UOM for use
              when creating Bill of Materials (BOM) Items. On the BOM Item
              screen, you have the ability to select an issue UOM. This issue
              UOM is used whenever the specified component Item is issued to a
              Work Order. If you define a Material Issue UOM on the Item
              master, then that UOM will be available for selection whenever
              the Item is used in a BOM.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term><indexterm>
                <primary>units of measure</primary>
                <secondary>selling specified</secondary>
              </indexterm><indexterm>
                <primary>items</primary>
                <secondary>selling UOM for</secondary>
              </indexterm>Selling</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>If an Item is sold, its List Price will be based on the
              Selling UOM. While the Selling UOM may often mirror the
              Inventory UOM, in some scenarios the two UOMs will be different.
              For example, cans of soda may be stocked in Inventory as
              individual units (EACH), but sold by the case (CASE24). In this
              example, Inventory transactions will be recorded using the
              Inventory UOM (EACH), but all pricing--including List Price and
              Pricing Schedules--will reflect the Selling UOM (CASE24). An
              Item may also have multiple Selling UOMs, for example SIX-PACK,
              CASE24, PALLET, etc. You specify the Selling UOM you want to use
              at Sales Order entry time.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Selected Types</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Lists the UOM types you have selected for the specified UOM
        conversion ratio. You may add multiple different UOM types for each
        conversion ratio. However, if a UOM type (except the Selling UOM) has
        already been used in another conversion ratio, you may not be able to
        select it.</para>
        <tip>
          <para>Double-clicking on a selected UOM type will remove it from the
          list, returning it to the Available Types list.</para>
        </tip>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without creating an alternate Item UOM(s),
        returning you to the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Creates the alternate Item UOM(s) and makes it available
        throughout the system.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>Item Characteristics are user-defined definitions of an Item which may
  be used to provide additional layers of description to Items. For example,
  Item Characteristics might be used to specify "Season" or "Primary Vendor".
  These constitute static descriptions which are not processed by the
  application, but are useful for informational purposes.</para>
  <tip>
    <para>You can associate Item Characteristics with Sales Order and Purchase
    Order Line Items, as well as with Work Orders.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>To enter <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>characteristics</primary>
      <secondary>creating new for item</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>characteristics</primary>
      <secondary>items having</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>items</primary>
      <secondary>characteristics for</secondary>
    </indexterm>Characteristics associated with an Item, select the
  "Characteristics" tab. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/item_characteristicsTab.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Item Characteristics</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Characteristics</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists the Characteristic name and Value of Item
        Characteristics related to the Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Opens screen for creating a new Item Characteristic.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>EDIT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enables you to edit highlighted Item Characteristics. The edit
        screen is the same as that for creating a new Item
        Characteristic--except that when editing, the fields will contain Item
        Characteristic information. Double-clicking on an Item Characteristic
        will also bring you to the editing screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>DELETE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight an Item Characteristic and then select this button to
        remove the Item Characteristic from the list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To create a new Item Characteristic, select the NEW button. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/characteristicAssignmentItem.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create New Item Characteristic</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Characteristic</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select a Characteristic from the list of Characteristics
        designated as being available for use as Item Characteristics.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Value</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a value to associate with the Item Characteristic.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Default</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if the Value entered is the default Value for the
        specified Characteristic. The default Value will be presented
        initially wherever Item Characteristics are used.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without creating the Item Characteristic,
        returning you to the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Creates the Item Characteristic and adds it to the list of Item
        Characteristics.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To view, add, or edit Item Sites associated with an Item, select the
  "Item Sites" tab. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/item_itemsites.png" remap="" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Item Sites for the Item</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Sites</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists Item Sites for the specified Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Opens screen for creating a new Item Site.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>EDIT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enables you to edit highlighted Item Sites. The edit screen is
        the same as that for creating a new Item Site--except that when
        editing, the fields will contain Item Site information.
        Double-clicking on an Item Site will also bring you to the editing
        screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>VIEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight an Item Site and then select this button to reach a
        read-only view of the "Edit" screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>DELETE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight an Item Site and then select this button to remove the
        Item Site from the list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>The Tax policy for an Item is determined by how its Tax Type settings
  are configured. To associate Tax Types with an Item, select the "Tax Types"
  tab. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/item_taxtypes.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Item Tax Types</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <tip>
    <para>To mark an Item as non-taxable, simply do not associate any Tax
    Types with the Item.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Tax Types</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists Tax Types for the specified Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Opens screen for creating a new Tax Type definition.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>EDIT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enables you to edit highlighted Tax Type definitions. The edit
        screen is the same as that for creating a new Tax Type
        definition--except that when editing, the fields will contain Tax Type
        definition information. Double-clicking on a Tax Type definition will
        also bring you to the editing screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>DELETE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a Tax Type definition and then select this button to
        remove the Tax Type definition from the list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To create a new Tax Type definition, select the NEW button. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/itemtax.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create New Tax Type</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When creating a new Tax Type definition, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>tax authorities</primary>
          <secondary>for sales orders</secondary>
        </indexterm>Tax Authority</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the Tax Authority you want to associate with the
        specified Tax Type. Tax Authorities are any entity legally-authorized
        to collect Taxes--for example, city, county, state, or federal
        government agencies. Creating a relationship between a Tax Authority
        and a Tax Type enables you to determine how Tax will be applied when
        processing transactions using the Item. The next step is to ensure
        this relationship is configured on the Tax Selection matrix, where Tax
        Authorities and Tax Types are linked to specific Tax Codes. This
        combination of three elements (Tax Authority + Tax Type + Tax Code)
        determines the Tax rate to be charged when processing transactions for
        an Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>Consider creating separate Tax Types for any groups or classes of
    Items which are taxed at different rates. This will enable you to link
    distinct Tax Codes to each Tax Type definition on the Tax Selection
    matrix.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Tax Types</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the Tax Type you want to associate with the specified
        Tax Authority. Tax Types provide a system for classifying goods and
        services into taxable categories. Creating a relationship between a
        Tax Authority and a Tax Type enables you to determine how Tax will be
        applied when processing transactions using the Item. The next step is
        to ensure this relationship is configured on the Tax Selection matrix,
        where Tax Authorities and Tax Types are linked to specific Tax Codes.
        This combination of three elements (Tax Authority + Tax Type + Tax
        Code) determines the Tax rate to be charged when processing
        transactions for an Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without creating the Tax Type definition,
        returning you to the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Creates the Tax Type definition and adds it to the list of Tax
        Type definitions.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To view system-generated Comments associated with an Item--or to add
  new Comments of your own--select the "Comments" tab. The following screen
  will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/item_commentsTab.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Item Comments</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Comments</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists the date Comment entered, Comment Type, user who
        entered Comment, and a content preview.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Opens screen for creating a new Comment.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>VIEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a Comment and then select this button to reach a
        read-only view of the Comment.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To create a new Comment, select the NEW button. The following screen
  will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/CommentNew.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create New Comment</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Comment Type</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify one of the following Comment Types from the drop-down
        list: ChangeLog or General. Comment Types are used to categorize
        Comments. Once you have specified a Comment Type, you may type your
        Comment in the main text area. The text area features word-wrapping
        and scroll-bar support for longer Comments.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without creating the Comment, returning you to
        the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Creates the Comment and adds it to the list of Comments.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>item aliases</primary>
      <secondary>for cross-referencing</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>items</primary>
      <secondary>aliases for</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>aliases</primary>
      <see>item aliases</see>
    </indexterm>Item Aliases are assigned to Items as a means for
  cross-referencing internal and external Item information. For example, a
  Customer may refer to an Item by a different Item Number than you do. To
  avoid confusion--and to simplify Item lookups--you can create an Item Alias
  linking the Customer's external Part Number to your own internal Item
  Number. The Item Alias acts as an alternate identifier. In this way, Items
  may be located using either internal or external Item information. To
  associate an Item Alias with an Item, select the "Alias" tab. The following
  screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/item_aliasesTab.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Item Alias</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Alias</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists Item Alias numbers and related Comments.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Opens screen for creating a new Item Alias.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>Multiple Item Aliases can be assigned to a single Item, allowing you
    to cross-reference an Item using many different Item Numbers.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>EDIT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enables you to edit highlighted Item Alias definitions. The edit
        screen is the same as that for creating a new Item Alias
        definition--except that when editing, the fields will contain Item
        Alias information. Double-clicking on an Item Alias definition will
        also bring you to the editing screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>DELETE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight an Item Alias definition and then select this button
        to remove the Item Alias from the list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To create an Item Alias, select the NEW button. The following screen
  will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/itemAlias.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create New Item Alias</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When creating a new Item Alias, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Item Number entered into previous screen will be
        displayed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Inventory Unit of Measure.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This is the Alias number for the Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>item aliases</primary>
          <secondary>related to billing</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>item aliases</primary>
          <secondary>related to shipping</secondary>
        </indexterm>Use an Alias Description on Billing and Shipping
      Paperwork</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Billing and Shipping Paperwork: Select to include an Item Alias
        description on Billing and Shipping paperwork.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Description</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a description of the Item Alias for inclusion on Billing
        and Shipping paperwork.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Comments</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        Comments related to the Item Alias. This field may be useful for
        explaining why an Item Alias was created (e.g., "Customer XYZ, Inc.
        refers to this Item Alias whenever they place an Order.").</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without creating an Item Alias, returning you
        to the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Creates the Item Alias and adds it to the list of Item
        Aliases.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>items</primary>
      <secondary>substitutes for</secondary>
    </indexterm>Item Substitutes can be established for Items that are
  interchangeable with other Items. To associate an Item Substitute with an
  Item, select the "Substitute" tab. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/item_substitutesTab.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Item Substitute</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <note>
    <para>There is a difference between Item Substitutes and Substitutions
    defined in a Bill of Materials (BOM). The difference is that BOM-defined
    Substitutions may be implemented on the fly during Work Order
    processing--Item Substitutes cannot be.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Substitute</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists the rank of the Item Substitute, Substitute Item
        Number, Substitute Item description, and Substitute/Parent UOM
        ratio.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Opens screen for creating a new Item Substitute.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>Multiple Item Substitutes can be assigned to a single Item, allowing
    you to cross-reference an Item using many different Item Numbers.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>EDIT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enables you to edit highlighted Item Substitute definitions. The
        edit screen is the same as that for creating a new Item Substitute
        definition--except that when editing, the fields will contain Item
        Substitute information. Double-clicking on an Item Substitute
        definition will also bring you to the editing screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>DELETE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight an Item Substitute definition and then select this
        button to remove the Item Substitute from the list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>item substitutes</primary>
      <secondary>creating new</secondary>
    </indexterm>create an Item Substitute, select the NEW button. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/itemSubstitute.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create New Item Substitute</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When creating a new Item Substitute, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Number (Root Item)</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Item Number entered into previous screen will be
        displayed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Inventory Unit of Measure.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Number (Substitution)</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the Item Number of the Substitute Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Inventory Unit of Measure.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Substitute/Parent UOM Ratio</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specifies the ratio between the Root Item's Inventory UOM and
        the Substitute Item's Inventory UOM.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>item substitutes</primary>
          <secondary>ranking of</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>ranking</primary>
          <secondary>of item substitutes</secondary>
        </indexterm>Ranking</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select a number using the arrow buttons, or manually enter a
        value up to a maximum of 9. Enter the specified ranking order of the
        Item Substitute. You may assign the same ranking to multiple Items, if
        this is appropriate.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CLOSE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without creating an Item Substitute, returning
        you to the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Creates the Item Substitute and adds it to the list of Item
        Substitutes.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para role="standard">To identify Items which may be chosen as target Items
  during transformation transactions, select the "Transformations" tab. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/item_transformationsTab.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Item Transformations</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <note>
    <para>You may only transform an Item if the source Item is located in the
    same Warehouse as the target Item.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Transformations</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists Items which may be chosen as target Items during
        Transformation transactions.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Opens a searchable Item list showing Items which may be chosen
        as target Items during Transformation transactions.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>DELETE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a target Item and then select this button to remove
        the target Item from the list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>item images</primary>
      <secondary>associate with items</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>images</primary>
      <secondary>items associated with</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>items</primary>
      <secondary>images associated with</secondary>
    </indexterm>associate an Image with an Item, select the "Images" tab. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/item_imagesTab.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Item Images</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Images</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists information about stored Item Images.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Opens master list of stored Item Images.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>EDIT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enables you to edit highlighted Item Image definitions. The edit
        screen is the same as that for creating a new Item Image
        definition--except that when editing, the fields will contain Item
        Image information. Double-clicking on an Item Image definition will
        also bring you to the editing screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>VIEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight an Item Image and then select this button to reach a
        read-only view of the "Edit" screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>PRINT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Runs the report associated with this screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>DELETE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight an Item Image definition and then select this button
        to remove the Item Image from the list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>item images</primary>
      <secondary>master list of</secondary>
    </indexterm>To specify an Image to associate with an Item, select the NEW
  button. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/itemImage.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Item Images Master List</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When specifying an Image to associate with an Item, you are presented
  with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Purpose</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select one of the available purposes an Image might
        serve:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Inventory Description</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if the Item Image describes Inventory.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Product Description</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if the Item Image describes a Product.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Engineering Reference</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if the Item Image serves as an engineering
              reference.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Miscellaneous</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if the Item Image is a miscellaneous Image.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>An Item may have multiple Images associated with it, but only one
    Image per purpose.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Images</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists stored Images available for association with the
        specified Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CLOSE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen, returning you to the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight an Image, then select the SAVE button to associate the
        Image with the specified Item and purpose.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Opens screen for adding a new Image to the master list of stored
        Images.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>images</primary>
      <secondary>adding new</secondary>
    </indexterm>To add a new Image to the master list of stored Images, select
  the NEW button. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/image.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create New Image</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When adding a new Image to the master list of stored Images, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>File Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the physical directory location of the Image. The browse
        button enables you to search your system for the physical directory
        location of the Image file. Once you locate the file, simply select it
        to have it entered into the "File Name" field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a unique name for the Image.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Description</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a description to further identify the Image.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without adding a new Image to the master list
        of stored Images.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Creates the Image and adds it to the master list of stored
        Images.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To enter Files associated with an Item, select the "Files" tab. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/item_files.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Item Files</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Files</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists the title and URL for any Files related to the
        Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Opens screen for creating a new Item File.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>EDIT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enables you to edit highlighted Item File definitions. The edit
        screen is the same as that for creating a new Item File
        definition--except that when editing, the fields will contain Item
        File definition information. Double-clicking on an Item File
        definition will also bring you to the editing screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>VIEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight an Item File definition and then select this button to
        reach a read-only view of the "Edit" screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>DELETE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight an Item File definition and then select this button to
        remove the Item File definition from the list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>OPEN</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight an Item File definition and then select this button to
        open the URL in a web browser.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To create a new Item File, select the NEW button. The following screen
  will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/itemFile.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create New Item File</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When creating a new Item File, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Title</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a title to identify the Item File.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>URL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the URL indicating where the Item File is located. Users
        will be able to access the file within a web browser when they select
        the OPEN button.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without creating an Item File, returning you
        to the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Creates the Item File and adds it to the list of Item
        Files.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
