<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
  <section id="Section518694">
    <title><anchor id="Anchor41372" role="Cross-Ref"
    xreflabel="41372: Heading2: Enter Item Site" /> <anchor id="Anchor552128"
    role="Index" xreflabel="item sites:creating new" /> <indexterm
        significance="normal" zone="Anchor552128">
        <primary>item sites</primary>

        <secondary>creating new</secondary>
      </indexterm>Enter Item Site</title>

    <para id="Para518695">An Item Site identifies and defines the methods and
    controls used when maintaining a given Item within a given Warehouse. To
    enter a new Item Site into your system, select the "Enter Item Site"
    option. The following screen will appear:</para>

    <para id="Para631959"><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/IM_IS_enterItemSite.png"
                       id="Graphic631957" />
          </imageobject>

          <caption id="Caption631960">Create New Item Site</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>

    <para id="Para631961">When creating a new Item Site, you are presented
    with the following options:</para>

    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para518707">Item Number</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18569b0">
          <para>Enter the Item Number of the Item you want to create an Item
          Site for.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para671933">UOM</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18569f8">
          <para>Inventory Unit of Measure.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para518711">Active</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1856a40">
          <para>Select to indicate the Item Site is active.</para>

          <para id="Para518712">Not selecting means the Item Site will be
          considered inactive. If inactive, the Item Site will not appear on
          lists of active Item Sites. To re-activate an Item Site, simply
          select this option.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para591231">Warehouse</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1856a88">
          <para>Specify Warehouse where Item Site is located.</para>

          <para id="Para670298">Use this selection in conjunction with the
          additional Warehouse settings found on the Item Site screen.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para653486"><anchor id="Anchor653485" role="Index"
        xreflabel="order parameters:enforcement of;item sites:enforcing order parameters in" />
        <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor653485">
            <primary>order parameters</primary>

            <secondary>enforcement of</secondary>
          </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor653485">
            <primary>item sites</primary>

            <secondary>enforcing order parameters in</secondary>
          </indexterm>Enforce Order Parameters</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1856b60">
          <para>Order Parameters: Select to enforce Order Parameters.</para>

          <para id="Para653487">If this option is selected, then Material
          Requirements Planning (MRP) will follow the Order Parameters defined
          below when generating Planned Replenishment Orders. Parameters you
          define will be saved if this option is turned ON/OFF. If you want to
          enforce Order Parameters on manual Orders as well, select the "on
          Manual Orders" option. For more information on how Order Parameters
          interact with MRP, see the <link endterm="Anchor14508"
          id="XRef653489" linkend="Anchor14508"> Order Parameters and
          MRP</link>" section.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>

    <note>
      <para id="Para591572">Running Material Requirements Planning (MRP) on
      your system consists entirely of running the Create Planned
      Replenishment Orders screens--either by Item or by Planner Code. As MRP
      runs, the Planned Replenishment Orders are generated
      automatically.</para>
    </note>

    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para518722">Reorder Level</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1856bf0">
          <para>The Reorder Level specifies when a Planned Replenishment Order
          should be created for an Item Site. If Planned Availability minus
          Safety Stock falls below the Reorder Level, then a Replenishment
          Order will be created when Material Requirements Planning (MRP) is
          run. The Replenishment Order quantity will be equal to the quantity
          required to return Planned Availability to either the Reorder Level
          or the Order Up To quantity--whichever is greater. For more
          information, see the <link endterm="Anchor14508" id="XRef638200"
          linkend="Anchor14508"> Order Parameters and MRP</link>
          section.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>

    <note>
      <para id="Para617601">Planned Availability differs from Quantity on Hand
      (QOH). The difference is that Planned Availability considers both QOH
      and also the time-phased demands placed on Inventory by Sales Orders and
      Work Orders. MRP uses Planned Availability when calculating which Item
      Sites require Planned Replenishment Orders.</para>
    </note>

    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para614529">Order Up To</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1856c80">
          <para>The Order Up To (OUT) Level indicates the level of Planned
          Availability an Item Site should be replenished up to when Material
          Requirements Planning (MRP) is run. In cases where the Reorder Level
          for an Item Site exceeds the Order Up To Level, MRP will replenish
          the Item Site up to the Reorder Level. For more information, see the
          <link endterm="Anchor14508" id="XRef638208" linkend="Anchor14508">
          Order Parameters and MRP</link> section.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>

    <tip>
      <para id="Para617380">Setting the Order Up To Level to "0" removes any
      restrictions on maximum Order quantities. Removing quantity restrictions
      can be an effective strategy to help ensure that all Order demands are
      satisfied when MRP is run. Order demands may not be met if Order Up To
      Levels are set below the demand threshold.</para>
    </tip>

    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para518732">Minimum Order</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1856d10">
          <para>Value entered indicates the minimum quantity that may be
          entered for a Planned Replenishment Order when MRP is run. If the
          "on Manual Orders" option is selected above, manually-created Work
          Orders will recognize the Minimum Order value.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para627359">Maximum Order</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1856d58">
          <para>This is a special setting which regulates the maximum quantity
          for Planned Replenishment Orders when MRP is run. The setting does
          not apply to manual Orders, but to Planned Orders only. When a
          maximum Order quantity is specified, MRP will ignore Order multiples
          and minimum Order specifications--focusing instead solely on the
          maximum Order setting. For example, if the maximum Order quantity is
          set to 10 and there is demand for 17, then Planned Orders of 10 and
          7 would be generated when MRP is run.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>

    <tip>
      <para id="Para631638">Setting the maximum order quantity too low has
      been shown to slow performance when MRP is run. Unless you have special
      needs (i.e., crate packaging limits) which require you to set a low
      maximum order quantity, you should consider setting the maximum order
      value to "0".</para>
    </tip>

    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para518737">Order Multiple</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1856de8">
          <para>Value entered indicates the quantity multiple that should be
          used for Planned Replenishment Orders when MRP is run. If the "on
          Manual Orders" option is selected above, manually-created Work
          Orders will recognize the Order Multiple value.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para626942">Enforce on Manual Orders</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1856e30">
          <para>Select to enforce Order Parameters on manually-created Work
          Orders.</para>

          <para id="Para626943">If this option is selected, Order Parameters
          will also be enforced whenever Work Orders are manually created.
          This option applies only to the following two parameters: Minimum
          Order and Order Multiple. The other Order Parameters listed below do
          not apply to manually-created Work Orders. For manual Purchase
          Orders, the Minimum Order and Order Multiple parameters are
          determined on a Vendor-by-Vendor basis, using Item Source
          masters.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry role="openmfg">
        <term id="Para624563">Group MPS/MRP Orders Every</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1856e54">
          <para>Specify the length of a periodmeasured in days--within which
          MPS or MRP Planned Orders will be grouped together (i.e,
          consolidated) to meet scheduled demand for the period.</para>

          <para id="Para670332">This functionality serves to limit the total
          number of Planned Orders, thereby simplifying order processing. For
          example, to consolidate demand for an Item Site into 30-day buckets,
          set the value to "30." When MRP is run, the system will
          automatically consolidate all demand falling within the 30-day
          horizon into a single Planned Purchase Order or Planned Work Order.
          The grouping of Planned Orders moves forward in time, meaning the
          system will create as many buckets as will fit within the cutoff
          date specified when MRP is run.</para>

          <para id="Para628073">The initial grouping of Planned Orders is
          handled differently than subsequent buckets. The following formula
          specifies how the date range for the initial period is
          determined:</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>

    <para id="Para628074">Start Date = Today's Date</para>

    <para id="Para628075">End Date = Today's Date + Lead Time</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1856e9c">
        <para id="Para624897">All subsequent periods are determined using the
        following calculations:</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <para id="Para624912">Start Date = End Date of Previous Period + 1</para>

    <para id="Para624913">End Date = Start Date of Current Period + Group
    Value</para>

    <tip>
      <para id="Para624876">To enforce <anchor id="Anchor624879" role="Index"
      xreflabel="just-in-time:delivery of planned orders;planned orders:just-in-time delivery and;material requirements planning:just-in-time delivery and" />
      <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor624879">
          <primary>just-in-time</primary>

          <secondary>delivery of planned orders</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor624879">
          <primary>planned orders</primary>

          <secondary>just-in-time delivery and</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor624879">
          <primary>material requirements planning</primary>

          <secondary>just-in-time delivery and</secondary>
        </indexterm>Just-In-Time (JIT) delivery methods, set the MRP group
      value to "0." This will ensure that Planned Order due dates are the same
      as the demand due dates to which they correspond. If the MRP Order
      grouping value is set to "0", the initial period will be determined in
      the same way as for all Planned Order groups:</para>

      <para id="Para624957">Start Date = Today's Date</para>

      <para id="Para624961">End Date = Today's Date + Lead Time</para>

      <para id="Para624943">However, the date range for all subsequent JIT
      Planned Orders will be based on the following calculations:</para>

      <para id="Para624964">Start Date = Demand Due Date - Lead Time</para>

      <para id="Para670380">End Date = Demand Due Date</para>
    </tip>

    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry role="openmfg">
        <term id="Para670385">MPS Time Fence</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1856fe0">
          <para>Specify the length of the Demand Time Fence by using the arrow
          buttons or manually entering a value up to a maximum of 999.</para>

          <para id="Para670386">The Demand Time Fence (also known as the
          demand fence) is used by the Master Production Scheduling (MPS)
          system to evaluate when forecasted demand (i.e., from Production
          Plans) should be used in place of actual demand (i.e., from Sales
          Orders)--and vice versa. Measured in days, the Demand Time Fence is
          the period of time extending from the current day to the number of
          days into the future as specified in this field. The Demand Time
          Fence option applies only to those Items which currently appear on a
          released Production Plan. If demand for these Items falls within the
          Demand Time Fence period, then the Forecast will be ignored. If
          demand falls outside the Demand Time Fence, then the larger of
          actual or forecasted demand will be used. MPS responds to the demand
          it locates by creating firm Planned Orders for the required
          quantities.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para593801">Safety Stock</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1857028">
          <para>Specify the quantity of Stock for the Item you want to keep in
          Inventory to protect against unplanned, unforeseeable trends in your
          Order forecasts.</para>

          <para id="Para670350">When Material Requirements Planning (MRP) is
          run, the system considers the Safety Stock value when determining
          whether to create Planned Replenishment Orders. If Planned
          Availability minus Safety Stock is below the Reorder Level, then
          Planned Orders will be created. If not below the Reorder Level, then
          no Planned Orders will be created. The system's calculation
          effectively creates a buffer Inventory (if needed) to handle
          unexpected fluctuations in demand. If you do not want to use the
          Safety Stock functionality, set the Safety Stock value to
          "0".</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para518744">ABC Class</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1857070">
          <para>Specify the ABC classification for the specified Item.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para612236">Allow Automatic Updates</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18570b8">
          <para>Select to allow the ABC Class setting for the Item Site to be
          updated whenever the ABC Class update utility is run.</para>

          <para id="Para612247">Not selecting indicates the ABC Class for the
          Item Site should not be updated whenever the ABC Class update
          utility is run.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para518746">Cycl. Cnt. Freq.</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1857100">
          <para>Cnt. Freq.: Select a number using the arrow buttons, or
          manually enter a value up to a maximum of 999.</para>

          <para id="Para593785">A Cycle Count is a periodic issue of a Count
          Tag to count Inventory quantity within an Item Site. The Cycle Count
          frequency defines the length of that period, measured in
          days.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>

    <tip>
      <para id="Para595910">To monitor the frequency of Item Site Cycle
      Counts, view the "Last Counted" column in any of the Item Site Reports:
      by Item, by Class Code, etc. The Last Counted date represents the date a
      Count Tag was last posted (not simply issued) for the Item Site.</para>
    </tip>

    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para518748">Lead Time</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1857190">
          <para>Select a number using the arrow buttons, or manually enter a
          value up to a maximum of 999.</para>

          <para id="Para623768">Specifies the Lead Time for the specified
          Item, measured in days. If the Item is a manufactured Item, then the
          Lead Time refers to the production Lead Time. If the Item is a
          purchased Item, then the Lead Time refers to the planning Lead Time.
          The procurement Lead Time for purchased Items is determined on a
          Vendor-by-Vendor basis, using Item Source masters. Material
          Requirements Planning (MRP) will consider Lead Times when
          calculating Planned Order start dates when MRP is run.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para518750"><anchor id="Anchor557799" role="Index"
        xreflabel="event fences:in item sites;item sites:event fences in" />
        <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor557799">
            <primary>event fences</primary>

            <secondary>in item sites</secondary>
          </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor557799">
            <primary>item sites</primary>

            <secondary>event fences in</secondary>
          </indexterm>Event Fence</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1857268">
          <para>Select a number using the arrow buttons, or manually enter a
          value up to a maximum of 99.</para>

          <para id="Para518751">Specify the period of time, measured in days,
          within which relevant Event notifications should be issued. If an
          Event affecting the Item Site occurs within the Event Fence, then
          the system will issue a notification. Consider the case of a
          manufactured Item whose Event Fence is set to five (5) days. Assume
          that a Work Order exists for this Item and that the scheduled start
          date for that Work Order is three (3) days from the current date. If
          someone were to change the quantity of that Work Order, the Event
          "WoQtyChanged" would be triggered. And because the Work Order start
          date falls within the Event Fence for the Item Site, an Event
          notification would be issued.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para518752">Planner Code</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18572b0">
          <para>Specify the Planner Code you want to assign the Item Site
          to.</para>

          <para id="Para670404">Assigning a Planner Code to an Item Site makes
          it possible to group Item Sites by Planner Code for the purposes of
          Planning.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para561209">Supplied at this Warehouse</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18572f8">
          <para>Select if Item is supplied at specified Warehouse.</para>

          <para id="Para518755">If selected, "Supplied at" means that Purchase
          Orders may be issued for this Item in this Warehouse if the Item is
          a purchased Item, and Work Orders may be issued for this Item in
          this Warehouse if the Item is a manufactured Item. These rules apply
          also to Planned Orders generated when Material Requirements Planning
          (MRP) is run. Planned Orders may only be released to "Supplied at"
          Item Sites.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para614739">Create P/Rs to Meet Demands</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1857340">
          <para>Select to create Purchase Requests whenever Sales Orders or
          Work Orders demand quantities from the Item Site.</para>

          <para id="Para614740">This option pertains to purchased and
          outside-process Items. If you select this option, you are indicating
          that you want Purchase Requests to be generated for the Item in
          question whenever quantities are demanded by either Sales Orders or
          Work Orders. For Sales Orders, the "Create Purchase Request" flag on
          the Sales Order Item screen will automatically be selected. For Work
          Orders using a purchased or outside process Item, Purchase Requests
          will be generated automatically.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>

    <note>
      <para id="Para617348">Purchase Requests created, as specified above, to
      meet Sales Order and Work Order demands will be created regardless of an
      Item's Availability--and also regardless of whether Material
      Requirements Planning (MRP) is being run in parallel.</para>
    </note>

    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para634824">Create W/Os to Meet Demand</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18573d0">
          <para>Select to create Work Orders whenever Sales Orders demand
          quantities from the Item Site.</para>

          <para id="Para634825">This option pertains to manufactured Items. If
          you select this option, you are indicating that you want Work Orders
          to be generated for the Item in question whenever quantities are
          demanded by a Sales Order. Selecting this option will cause the
          "Create Work Order" flag to be checked whenever you enter Sales
          Order Line Items for the Item Site.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>

    <note>
      <para id="Para634827">Work Orders created, as specified above, to meet
      Sales Order demand will be created regardless of an Item's
      Availability--and also regardless of whether Material Requirements
      Planning (MRP) is being run in parallel.</para>
    </note>

    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para634812">Sold from this Warehouse</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1857460">
          <para>Select if Item is sold from specified Warehouse.</para>

          <para id="Para518759">If selected, "Sold from" means that Sales
          Orders Line Items may request to Ship from the Warehouse. When
          adding Sales Order Line Items to a Sales Order, a "Sold from"
          Warehouse appears as the "Supplying Warehouse."</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para518760"><anchor id="Anchor560251" role="Index"
        xreflabel="ranking:of item sites;sold ranking:for item sites;item sites:sold ranking of" />
        <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor560251">
            <primary>ranking</primary>

            <secondary>of item sites</secondary>
          </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor560251">
            <primary>sold ranking</primary>

            <secondary>for item sites</secondary>
          </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor560251">
            <primary>item sites</primary>

            <secondary>sold ranking of</secondary>
          </indexterm>Ranking</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1857580">
          <para>Select a number using the arrow buttons, or manually enter a
          value up to a maximum of 10.</para>

          <para id="Para518761">Value entered specifies the order in which
          Item Sites will be chosen during Sales Order and Sales Quote
          creation. If an Item is located in more than one "Sold from"
          Warehouse, the Item Site with the highest ranking will be chosen
          first. If two Item Sites happen to share the same ranking, selection
          will be based on alphabetical order. The highest ranking an Item
          Site can have is one (1).</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para617275">Stocked</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18575c8">
          <para>Select if Item is stocked at specified Warehouse.</para>

          <para id="Para617276">This option pertains to manufactured Items. If
          you select this option, you are indicating that the Item is a
          make-to-stock Item. If not selected, the Item will be identified as
          a make-to-order Item.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para617278"><anchor id="Anchor617277" role="Index"
        xreflabel="control methods:at item site level;item sites:control methods in" />
        <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor617277">
            <primary>control methods</primary>

            <secondary>at item site level</secondary>
          </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor617277">
            <primary>item sites</primary>

            <secondary>control methods in</secondary>
          </indexterm>Control Method</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1867e90">
          <para>Specify the Item Site control method by selecting one of the
          available options:</para>

          <para id="Para518765">None: Select if you don"t care to see
          Inventory history transactions for the Item Site.</para>

          <para id="Para518766">Regular: Select to monitor Inventory history
          transactions for the Item Site using a Regular method. Regular means
          without Lot Number or Serial Number control.</para>

          <para id="Para518767" role="openmfg">Lot #: Select to impose Lot
          Number control methods on the Item Site. Item Sites using Lot Number
          control are subject to unique processing requirements whenever
          Inventory is received or distributed. For additional information on
          some of the unique methods required to handle Lot-controlled Items,
          see the <link endterm="Anchor58321" id="XRef591397"
          linkend="Anchor58321"> Receiving Lot/Serial Items into
          Inventory</link>"Topic: Receiving Lot/Serial Items into
          Inventory"section.</para>

          <para id="Para518768" role="openmfg">Serial #: Select to impose
          Serial Number control methods on the Item Site. Item Sites using
          Serial Number control are subject to unique processing requirements
          whenever Inventory is received or distributed. For additional
          information on some of the unique methods required to handle
          Serial-controlled Items, see the <link endterm="Anchor58321"
          id="XRef638219" linkend="Anchor58321"> Receiving Lot/Serial Items
          into Inventory</link> section.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry role="openmfg">
        <term id="Para518769">Perishable</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1867eb4">
          <para>Select if the Item is perishable.</para>

          <para id="Para593600">For Item Sites whose control method is either
          Lot Number or Serial Number, you have the option of also designating
          the Item Site as Perishable. Materials received into a Perishable
          Item Site are required to specify an expiration date, thereby
          increasing your ability to monitor the status of the goods.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para593602"><anchor id="Anchor593601" role="Index"
        xreflabel="multiple location control:establishing in item sites" />
        <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor593601">
            <primary>multiple location control</primary>

            <secondary>establishing in item sites</secondary>
          </indexterm>Multiple Location Control</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1867f44">
          <para>Select if the specified Item is to be stored in multiple
          Locations within a single Warehouse.</para>

          <para id="Para567406">Items designated as Multiple Location Control
          (MLC) Items require special processing whenever Item quantities are
          distributed. For more information on distributing MLC Item
          quantities, see the <link endterm="Anchor81167" id="XRef593620"
          linkend="Anchor81167"> Distributing Multiple Location Control (MLC)
          Items</link>"Inter-Warehouse Transfer" section.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>

    <tip>
      <para id="Para627349">Exercise caution when adjusting the Multiple
      Location Control (MLC) setting for an Item Site. If you turn off MLC for
      an Item Site which was previously MLC, you will lose detailed Inventory
      records for that Item Site. All quantity will be merged into one
      Quantity on Hand value for the Item Site.</para>
    </tip>

    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para518771"><anchor id="Anchor557801" role="Index"
        xreflabel="default locations;locations:default;item sites:setting default locations in" />
        <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor557801">
            <primary>default locations</primary>
          </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor557801">
            <primary>locations</primary>

            <secondary>default</secondary>
          </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor557801">
            <primary>item sites</primary>

            <secondary>setting default locations in</secondary>
          </indexterm>Use Default Location</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1868088">
          <para>Default Location: Select to designate one Location within a
          Warehouse as the default Location for the specified Item.</para>

          <para id="Para593625">This option may be used for single Location
          and Multiple Location Control (MLC) Items alike. You may find that
          Inventory distributions for MLC Items are greatly simplified if you
          designate a default Location.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para518772">Location</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18680d0">
          <para>Specify the Warehouse Location to be used as the default
          Location.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para518777">User-Defined</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1868118">
          <para>This is a free-form field for describing storage areas with a
          Warehouse not specifically designated as Warehouse Locations.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para518781">Location Comment</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1868160">
          <para>Enter any free-form Comment related to the Warehouse Location.
          This is additional information which may be placed on a Pick List or
          a Pack List.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry role="openmfg">
        <term id="Para627400">Disallow Blank WIP Locations</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1868184">
          <para>Select to require the use of work-in-process (WIP) Locations
          when posting Work Order Operations for Multiple Location Control
          (MLC) finished goods.</para>

          <para id="Para627690">WIP Locations are an optional feature which
          may be defined on the Bill of Operations (BOO) for manufactured MLC
          Items. The feature enables you to track finished goods Inventory as
          it moves through the manufacturing process. If your site does not
          combine Multiple Location Control with Operations posting, then this
          option should be left unchecked.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para543842"><anchor id="Anchor557808" role="Index"
        xreflabel="item sites:cost categories in" /> <indexterm
            significance="normal" zone="Anchor557808">
            <primary>item sites</primary>

            <secondary>cost categories in</secondary>
          </indexterm>Cost Category</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1868214">
          <para>Specify the Cost Category you want to associate with the Item
          Site.</para>

          <para id="Para518782">Item Sites must be assigned a Cost Category.
          This requirement helps ensure that all Inventory transactions
          involving an Item Site will be properly tracked and recorded in the
          General Ledger.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para518786">Notes</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x186825c">
          <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
          free-form Notes related to the Item Site. Notes differ from Comments
          in that Comments are time/date and user stamped.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>

    <para id="Para518788">To the far right of the screen, the following
    buttons are available:</para>

    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para518789">CANCEL</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18682c8">
          <para>Closes the screen without creating an Item Site, returning you
          to the application desktop.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para627111">SAVE</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1868310">
          <para>Creates the Item Site and adds it to the master list of Item
          Sites.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>

    <para id="Para627113">To associate Comments with an Item Site, select the
    "Comments" tab. The following screen will appear:</para>

    <para id="Para593860"><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/IM_IS_itemSiteComm.png"
                       id="Graphic593858" />
          </imageobject>

          <caption id="Caption593861">Add Item Site Comments</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>

    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para594046">Comments</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18683e8">
          <para>Display lists the date Comment entered, Comment Type, user who
          entered Comment, and a content preview.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>

    <para id="Para594048">To the far right of the screen, the following
    buttons are available:</para>

    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para594049">NEW</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1868454">
          <para>Opens screen for creating a new Comment.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para594050">VIEW</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x186849c">
          <para>Highlight a Comment and then select this button to reach a
          read-only view of the Comment.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>

    <para id="Para612992">To create a new Comment, select the NEW button. The
    following screen will appear:</para>

    <para id="Para612996"><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/CommentNew.png" id="Graphic612994" />
          </imageobject>

          <caption id="Caption612997">Create New Comment</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>

    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para612998">Comment Type</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1868574">
          <para>Specify one of the following Comment Types from the drop-down
          list: ChangeLog or General.</para>

          <para id="Para612999">Comment Types are used to categorize Comments.
          Once you have specified a Comment Type, you may type your Comment in
          the main text area. The text area features word-wrapping and
          scroll-bar support for longer Comments.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>

    <para id="Para613000">To the far right of the screen, the following
    buttons are available:</para>

    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para613001">CANCEL</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18685e0">
          <para>Closes the screen without creating the Comment, returning you
          to the previous screen.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para613002">SAVE</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1868628">
          <para>Creates the Comment and adds it to the list of
          Comments.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>

    <para id="Para627441"><anchor id="Anchor627653" role="Index"
    xreflabel="warehouse locations:restricted;item sites:restricted locations and" />
    <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor627653">
        <primary>warehouse locations</primary>

        <secondary>restricted</secondary>
      </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor627653">
        <primary>item sites</primary>

        <secondary>restricted locations and</secondary>
      </indexterm>Warehouse Locations may be restricted to allow for storage
    of certain Items. To view restricted Locations within an Item Site's
    Warehouse, select the "Restricted Locations" tab. The following screen
    will appear:</para>

    <para id="Para627512"><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/IM_IS_itemSiteRestr.png"
                       id="Graphic627510" />
          </imageobject>

          <caption id="Caption627513">Restricted Locations for Item Site
          Warehouse</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>

    <para id="Para627445">The Restricted Locations list will show restricted
    Locations associated with the Warehouse the Item Site is located
    in.</para>

    <para id="Para627571">To the far right of the screen, the following
    buttons are available:</para>

    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para627572">TOGGLE</term>

        <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1868790">
          <para>Highlight a Warehouse Location and then select this button to
          change the allowed status for the Item.</para>

          <para id="Para627662">Any changes made on the Item Site master
          related to an Item's allowed status will also be saved to the
          Warehouse Location master record.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
  </section>