<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section572294">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>budgets</primary>
      <secondary>creating new</secondary>
    </indexterm>New Budget</title>
  <para>The Budget utility is designed to store budgetary information, by
  Account Number, in a table format. Once stored, this information may then be
  accessed and viewed using the Financial Report engine. The Financial
  Reporting Engine specifically includes options for generating reports
  showing Budget information. To access the Budget utility, select the "New
  Budget" option. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/maintainBudget.png" id="Graphic573208" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption573211">Maintain Budget</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <note>
    <para>While all Budget amounts entered in the generated table are stored
    in the database, the particular groupings of Accounts and Accounting
    Periods are used only during the current session. If you want to
    re-generate a particular Budget table, the Accounts and Accounting Periods
    must be manually entered again.</para>
  </note>
  <para>When creating or maintaining Budget information, you are presented
  with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Table Parameters</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1908bd0">
        <para>Select from the following options to determine which Accounts
        and Accounting Periods you want to enter budgetary information
        for:</para>
        <para>Accounts: Select one or multiple Accounts to include when
        generating a Budget table.</para>
        <para>ADD: Select to add Accounts from your Chart of Account.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>You may select multiple Accounts to add to your Budget by
    highlighting the Accounts using your mouse--or a combination of your mouse
    and either the SHIFT or CTRL keys.</para>
  </tip>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1908c3c">
      <para>MOVE UP: Highlight an Account and then select this button to move
      the Account up in the list.</para>
      <para>MOVE DOWN: Highlight an Account and then select this button to
      move the Account down in the list.</para>
      <para>REMOVE: Highlight an Account and then select this button to remove
      the Account from the list.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1908c60">
      <para>Accounting Periods: Using your mouse in conjunction with the SHIFT
      and/or CRTL keys, select one or multiple Accounting Periods to include
      when generating the Budget table.</para>
      <para>SELECT ALL: Select to include all Accounting Periods in the
      table.</para>
      <para>INVERT: Selecting this option will cause the inverse of any
      selected Accounting Periods to be selected.</para>
      <para>UNSELECT ALL: Select to de-select all Accounting Periods.</para>
      <para>GENERATE TABLE: Select to generate the Budget table using the
      specified parameters.</para>
      <para>Table: Enter Budget amounts in the fields provided.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1908c84">
      <para>The table will consist of a grid, showing the specified Account
      Numbers listed down the left side--and the indicated Accounting Periods
      across the top. Simply click in a field to begin entering or editing
      Budget information. The TAB key may be used to move from field to field.
      Any Budget information you save in the table will be stored in the
      database for future reference. You may view Budget information by
      Account and Accounting Period using the Financial Reporting Engine. You
      may also edit Budget information by regenerating a Budget table.</para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CLOSE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1908cf0">
        <para>Closes the screen, returning you to the application
        desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1908d38">
        <para>Saves the budgetary information entered in the Budget
        table.</para>
        <para>Any information saved in the table will be available for future
        revision using the Budget utility. You may view Budget information
        using the Financial Reporting Engine.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>PRINT</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1908d80">
        <para>Runs the report associated with this screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>