<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section972251">
  <title>
<indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>vouchers</primary>

      <secondary>list of unposted</secondary>
    </indexterm>Unposted Vouchers</title>

  <para>To display unposted Vouchers, select the "List Unposted Vouchers"
  option. The following screen will appear:</para>

  <para>
<screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata id="Graphic972254" fileref="images/openVouchers.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption id="Caption972257">List Unposted Vouchers</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
</para>

  <note>
    <para>Actual Costs for purchased Items will be automatically updated when
    Vouchers are posted if there are differences between current Actual Costs
    and the vouchered Costs for the Items in question. Please keep in mind
    that Actual Costs only will be updated at posting. For new Costs to be
    recognized as Standard Costs, Actual Costs must be posted to
    Standard.</para>
  </note>

  <para>The "Vouchers" screen displays information on all unposted Vouchers,
  including Voucher Number, Purchase Order Number, Vendor Number/Vendor name,
  Vendor Invoice Number, and distribution date. Users with the appropriate
  privilege will also see the G/L distribution date column.</para>

  <tip>
    <para>You may select multiple Vouchers for posting by highlighting them
    using your mouse--or a combination of your mouse and either the SHIFT or
    CTRL keys.</para>
  </tip>

  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CLOSE</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen, returning you to the application
        desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>PRINT</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Runs the report associated with this screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Opens screen for creating a new Voucher.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW MISC.</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Opens screen for creating a new Miscellaneous Voucher.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>EDIT</term>

      <listitem id="openVouchersEDIT">
        <para>Enables you to edit highlighted Vouchers. The edit screen is the
        same as that for creating a new Voucher--except that when editing, the
        fields will contain Voucher information. Double-clicking on a Voucher
        will also bring you to the editing screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>VIEW</term>

      <listitem id="openVouchersVIEW">
        <para>Highlight a Voucher and then select this button to reach a
        read-only view of the "Edit" screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <tip>
    <para>If you have a Purchase Order Voucher that was corrupted by, for
    example, a sudden power outage, you can clear the record by running the
    Post Vouchers screen. In most cases, this action will remove the corrupted
    record and allow you to voucher the Purchase Order with a fresh
    Voucher.</para>
  </tip>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>POST</term>

      <listitem id="openVouchersPOST">
        <para>Highlight one--or multiple--Vouchers, then select this button to
        post the selected Voucher(s). By default, Vouchers post to the General
        Ledger (G/L) on their distribution date. However, users with the
        appropriate privilege may change the G/L distribution date to an
        alternate date during the Voucher posting process. If used, Vouchers
        will post on the alternate date. The ability privileged users have to
        change the distribution date applies to the posting of both individual
        and also batches of Vouchers from this screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>DELETE</term>

      <listitem id="openVouchersDELETE">
        <para>Highlight a Voucher and then select this button to remove the
        Voucher from the list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Print Journal after Post</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you want to print a copy of the Payables Journal after
        the selected Vouchers are posted.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>Right-clicking on an unposted Voucher in the list of unposted Vouchers
  enables you to select from the following menu options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Edit Voucher</term>

      <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xpointer="element(openVouchersEDIT)"/>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>View Voucher</term>

      <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xpointer="element(openVouchersVIEW)"/>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Delete Voucher</term>

      <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xpointer="element(openVouchersDELETE)"/>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Post Voucher</term>

      <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xpointer="element(openVouchersPOST)"/>
    </varlistentry>

    <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="../widgets/xtreewidget.xml" xpointer="element(xtreewidget.menu.exportcontents)"/>
  </variablelist>
</section>
