<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section537763" role="openmfg">
    <title>New Production Plan</title>

    <para id="Para539762">Production Plans are used for loading sales
    Forecasts into the system. These Forecasts are then accounted for when the
    Master Production Scheduling (MPS) system is run. Firm Planned Orders may
    be created for Items listed on Production Plans as the result of an MPS
    run. To create a new Production Plan, select the NEW button. The following
    screen will appear:</para>

    <para id="Para539316">
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
               <imagedata fileref="images/MS_Plan_prodPlanNew.png" id="Graphic539314"/>
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption539317">Create New Production Plan</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
   </para>

    <para id="Para539318">When creating a new Production Plan you are
    presented with the following options:</para>

    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para539319">Schedule #</term>

        <listitem>
            <para>Enter a name to identify the Production Plan.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para539320">Description</term>

        <listitem>
            <para>Enter a brief description of the Production Plan.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para539321">Warehouse</term>

        <listitem>
            <para>Specify the Warehouse where the forecasted quantity would be
          located.</para>

            <para id="Para540241">By specifying a Warehouse you indicate the
          specific Item Site which the MPS planning system should create
          Planned Orders for, if required.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para546060">Schedule Type</term>

        <listitem>
            <para>Select one of the available Production Plan schedule
          types:</para>

            <para id="Para546061">
               <anchor id="Anchor546148" role="Index"
                       xreflabel="mps:forecast reporting and;forecast:reporting for mps"/>
               <indexterm significance="normal">
                  <primary>mps</primary>

                  <secondary>forecast reporting and</secondary>
               </indexterm> 
               <indexterm significance="normal">
                  <primary>forecast</primary>

                  <secondary>reporting for mps</secondary>
               </indexterm>Forecast Reporting: Planning Items having this
          schedule type are not taken into account by MPS. Instead, use this
          schedule type for reporting purposes only, such as the reporting
          found on the MPS Detail screen. Forecast reporting can be useful as
          a reference of progress against Cumulative MPS Schedules, usually in
          scenarios where demand is discontinuous or "lumpy," but production
          schedules are continuous.</para>

            <para id="Para546125">Forecast Netted to MPS: Used for forecast
          reporting and netted as demand to existing supply by the MPS
          processor for Items scheduled inside the Demand Time Fence. Use
          where you desire supply to automatically be created to fulfill, but
          not exceed, the greater of forecasted and actual demand. Inside the
          Demand Time Fence, MPS ignores the forecast and plans an amount
          based on actual demand net of projected Availability. Outside of the
          Demand Time Fence, MPS uses the larger of actual demand or the
          forecast and nets this against projected Availability.</para>

            <para id="Para546110">
               <anchor id="Anchor546147" role="Index"
                       xreflabel="mps:cumulative schedules and; cumulative schedules:explained"/>
               <indexterm significance="normal">
                  <primary>mps</primary>

                  <secondary>cumulative schedules and</secondary>
               </indexterm> 
               <indexterm significance="normal">
                  <primary>cumulative schedules</primary>

                  <secondary>explained</secondary>
               </indexterm>Cumulative MPS: Cumulative Schedules allow the forced
          accumulation of inventory in a discontinuous or "lumpy" demand
          situation where load leveling or continuous production is desired.
          With this setting, MPS may release more, but never less, than the
          quantity dictated in a Cumulative MPS Schedule. Inside the Demand
          Time Fence, Cumulative Schedules are ignored--and only actual demand
          is considered. Outside the Demand Time Fence, Planned Orders for
          Cumulative Schedules are created per the greater of schedule
          quantity or net actual demand. The system interprets "net actual
          demand" to mean that it will use, for a given period, the larger of
          A) Cumulative Schedule quantity or B) quantity required to
          accommodate time-phased Availability (i.e., QOH + Qty. On Order -
          Allocations).</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para546111">Status</term>

        <listitem>
            <para>Displays the current status of the Production Plan.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>

    <note>
      <para id="Para539898">Production Plans may exist in either of the
      following two statuses:</para>

      <para id="Para539913">U = Un-released</para>

      <para id="Para539918">R = Released</para>

      <para id="Para539919">The Master Production Scheduling (MPS) system will
      only consider Production Plans which have been released. Any un-released
      Production Plans will be ignored by MPS when it is run.</para>
    </note>

    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para539323">Start Date</term>

        <listitem>
            <para>Enter the first date when MPS Items may be added to the
          Production Plan.</para>

            <para id="Para540052">Items having a planned date earlier than the
          date entered here may not be added to the Production Plan.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para539324">End Date</term>

        <listitem>
            <para>Enter the last date when MPS Items may be added to the
          Production Plan.</para>

            <para id="Para540062">Items having a planned date later than the
          date entered here may not be added to the Production Plan.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para539325">Planned Items</term>

        <listitem>
            <para>Displays the current list of Planned Items associated with the
          Production Plan.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>

    <para id="Para539326">To the far right of the screen, the following
    buttons are available:</para>

    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para539327">CANCEL</term>

        <listitem>
            <para>Closes the screen, returning you to the application
          desktop.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para539328">SAVE</term>

        <listitem>
            <para>Creates the Production Plan and adds it to the list of
          Production Plans.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para539329">NEW</term>

        <listitem>
            <para>Opens screen for creating a new Production Plan Item.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para539330">EDIT</term>

        <listitem>
            <para>Enables you to edit highlighted Production Plan Items. The
          edit screen is the same as that for creating a new Production Plan
          Item--except that when editing, the fields will contain Production
          Plan Item information. Double-clicking on a Production Plan Item
          will also bring you to the editing screen.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para539331">COPY</term>

        <listitem>
            <para>Highlight a Production Plan Item and then select this button
          to reach a screen for copying the Production Plan Item.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para539332">DELETE</term>

        <listitem>
            <para>Highlight a Production Plan Item and then select this button
          to remove it from the list.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>

    <para id="Para539334">
      <anchor id="Anchor539333" role="Index" xreflabel="production plans:creating new"/> 
      <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>production plans</primary>

        <secondary>creating new</secondary>
      </indexterm>To create a new Production Plan Item, select the NEW button.
    The following screen will appear:</para>

    <para id="Para539338">
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
               <imagedata fileref="images/MS_Plan_prodPlanItem.png" id="Graphic539336"/>
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption540082">New Production Plan Item</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
   </para>

    <tip>
      <para id="Para540176">You can reduce clutter (and simplify) your
      Production Plans by taking advantage of the Planning Item Type. A
      Planning Item is an Item whose Bill of Materials (BOM) groups together
      other Items so that a Production Plan may be defined for the Planning
      Item--and then exploded down to the lower level Items during a Master
      Production Scheduling (MPS) run. Planning Items are frequently used to
      group together product families or product lines of MPS Items.</para>
    </tip>

    <para id="Para539340">When creating a new Production Plan Item, you are
    presented with the following options:</para>

    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para540086">Item Number</term>

        <listitem>
            <para>Enter the Item Number of the Item you want to add to the
          Production Plan.</para>

            <para id="Para540087">You may only add Items which are specifically
          associated with the MPS Planning system. Items may be associated
          with a planning system (i.e., MRP, MPS, or None) on the Item master.
          Use the browse button located to the right of the field to reach a
          searchable MPS Items list.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para553562">UOM</term>

        <listitem>
            <para>Inventory Unit of Measure.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para539351">Planned Date</term>

        <listitem>
            <para>Enter the date when the specified Item quantity will be
          required.</para>

            <para id="Para540189">When MPS is run, the system will look at the
          planned date for Production Plan Items. If a planned date falls
          within the cutoff date for the MPS run, the system will plan for the
          demand accordingly. If the planned date falls beyond the cutoff
          date, the demand will be ignored.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para540191">Qty.</term>

        <listitem>
            <para>Specify the demand quantity for the Production Plan
          Item.</para>

            <para id="Para540214">In the case of a Planning Item, the quantity
          entered here will have a ripple effect on any component Items listed
          on the Planning Item's Bill of Materials.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>

    <para id="Para539354">To the far right of the screen, the following
    buttons are available:</para>

    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para539355">CANCEL</term>

        <listitem>
            <para>Closes the screen, returning you to the application
          desktop.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para539356">SAVE</term>

        <listitem>
            <para>Creates the Production Plan Item and adds it to the list of
          Production Plan Items.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
  </section>