<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section647767">
  <title>
<indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>standard costs</primary>
      <secondary>updating by item</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>items</primary>
      <secondary>updating standard costs for</secondary>
    </indexterm>Update Standard Costs by Item</title>
  <para>Standard Costs are the Costs which are recorded in the General Ledger
  (G/L) whenever transactions are posted. As such, they are the Costs of
  record. Typically, a company will update its Standard Costs on a periodic
  basis--for example, annually or quarterly.</para>
  <para>If you introduce new products into production between Standard Cost
  updates, you may want to roll up existing Standard Costs into the cost of
  your new manufactured Items. To update Standard Costs individually by Item,
  select the "Update Standard Costs by Item" option. The following screen will
  appear:</para>
  <para>
<screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata id="Graphic647509" fileref="images/postStandCostsByItem.png"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption647512">Update Standard Costs by Item</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
</para>
  <note>
    <para>Updating Standard Costs has absolutely no impact on an Item's Actual
    Costs. The only Costs affected will be Standard Costs.</para>
  </note>
  <para>When updating Standard Costs by Item, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the Item Number of the Item whose Standard Costs you want
        to update.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Inventory Unit of Measure.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>For manufactured Items, rolling up Standard Costs ensures that lower
    level Costs are reflected in the Cost for the parent Item.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>
<indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>standard costs</primary>
          <secondary>rolling up of</secondary>
        </indexterm>Roll Up Standard Costs</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to roll up Standard Costs. When this option is specified,
        all selected Costs will be added together to establish a revised total
        Standard Cost for the Item. This revised total goes into effect after
        the UPDATE button is selected. If all Costs are selected, all Costs
        will be rolled up. If a subset of all Costs is selected, only the
        subset will be rolled up. If the Roll Up Standard Costs option is not
        specified, the selected Cost updates will not be valid above their
        current level.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>
<indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>material costs</primary>
          <secondary>updating of</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>costing</primary>
          <secondary>updating of material costs</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>standard costs</primary>
          <secondary>updating material costs</secondary>
        </indexterm>Update Lower Level Material Costs</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to update lower level material Costs. Not selecting means
        lower level material Costs will not be included in the Cost
        update.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="openmfg">
      <term>Update Direct Labor Cost</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to update direct labor Cost. Not selecting means the
        direct labor Cost will not be included in the Cost update.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="openmfg">
      <term>Update Lower Level Direct Labor Cost</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to update lower level direct labor Cost. Not selecting
        means the lower level direct labor Cost will not be included in the
        Cost update.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>You have the flexibility of updating all or only a subset of the
    listed Costs. Updating a subset might be desirable if only Material or
    User Costs have changed, for example.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry role="openmfg">
      <term>Update Overhead Cost</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to update overhead Cost. Not selecting means the overhead
        Cost will not be included in the Cost update.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="openmfg">
      <term>Update Lower Level Overhead Cost</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to update lower level overhead Cost. Not selecting means
        the lower level overhead Cost will not be included in the Cost
        update.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="openmfg">
      <term>Update Machine Overhead</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to update machine overhead Cost. This option is selected
        by default.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="openmfg">
      <term>Update Lower Machine Overhead</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to update lower level machine overhead Cost. This option
        is selected by default.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>
<indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>user costs</primary>
          <secondary>updating of</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>costing</primary>
          <secondary>updating of user costs</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>standard costs</primary>
          <secondary>updating user costs</secondary>
        </indexterm>Update User Costs</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to update user Costs. Not selecting means user Costs will
        not be included in the Cost update.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Update Lower Level User Costs</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to update lower level user Costs. Not selecting means
        lower level user Costs will not be included in the Cost update.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without updating selected Costs, returning you
        to the application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>UPDATE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Updates all selected Costs for the specified Item. If the option
        "Roll Up Standard Costs" has been selected, the total Standard Cost
        for the specified Item will be updated.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="openmfg">
      <term>SUBMIT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to submit requested action to the Batch Manager for
        processing. For additional information, see <xref linkend="Anchor61009"/>.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SELECT ALL COSTS</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Selects all Costs for updating. Use this option to save time
        when selecting all Costs for updating. The option "Roll Up Standard
        Costs" must be selected separately if you want to include a rolled up
        total for the parent Item in the Cost update.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
