<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section519141">
  <title>
<indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>production</primary>
      <secondary>posting miscellaneous</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>miscellaneous production</primary>
      <secondary>posting of</secondary>
    </indexterm>Post Miscellaneous Production</title>
  <para>In repetitive manufacturing environments where production is
  continuous, the option to post miscellaneous production can be a useful
  feature. It can also be a useful feature for shops where disassembling
  manufactured Items is required. To post miscellaneous production, select the
  "Post Miscellaneous Production" option. The following screen will
  appear:</para>
  <para>
<screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/postMiscProduction.png"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Post Miscellaneous Work Order
        Production</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
</para>
  <tip>
    <para>If you want to disassemble a manufactured Item and return the
    component Items to Inventory, simply enter a negative quantity for the
    manufactured Item. Posting negative miscellaneous Production effectively
    reverses the Production process.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>When posting miscellaneous production, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the Item Number of the Item you want to post miscellaneous
        production for.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Inventory Unit of Measure.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Warehouse</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify Warehouse Location for selected Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. to Post</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>to Post: Enter the quantity of production you want to post. This
        field will accept negative numbers for disassembly purposes.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Document #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Creates a user-defined reference for the miscellaneous
        production. The document number will be posted with the General Ledger
        (G/L) transaction record when the miscellaneous production is
        generated. This field may be used for internal tracking and auditing
        purposes.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Backflush</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to indicate that the material requirements indicated by
        the associated Work Order Material Requirement record should be issued
        to the selected Work Order regardless of the issue method associated
        with these requirements.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Issue Items not on Pick List</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to indicate that non-Pick List Items should be
        backflushed as well.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Comments</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        Comments related to the miscellaneous production posting.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Immediate Transfer to Warehouse</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to transfer miscellaneous production to specified
        Warehouse. Specify the Warehouse you want to transfer production
        to.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>Miscellaneous Production may not be posted for Breeder Items.</para>
  </note>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without posting the miscellaneous production,
        returning you to the application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>POST</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Posts the production for the selected Item in the specified
        quantity.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
