<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="purchaseOrderItem">
  <title>
<indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>purchase orders</primary>
      <secondary>creating items for</secondary>
    </indexterm>Purchase Order Item</title>
  <para>To create a new Purchase Order Line Item, select the
  NEW button. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para>
<screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/PO_PO_POLineItemNew.png" id="Graphic972377"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption972380">Create New Purchase Order Line
        Item</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
</para>
  <para>When creating a new Purchase Order Line Item, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>P/O Number</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x185d3ac">
        <para>Displays the Purchase Order Number specified in the "New
        Purchase Order" screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Line #</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x185d3f4">
        <para>The application automatically assigns line numbers to Purchase
        Order Line Items. Numbering begins at one ("1") and increases
        automatically in increments of one.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Inventory Item</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x185d43c">
        <para>If the Item being purchased is an Inventory Item, select this
        option and specify the following:</para>
        <para>Item Number: Enter the Item Number of the Item
        you want to add to the Purchase Order.</para>
        <para>Supplying Whse.: Specify the Warehouse the Item
        will be supplied from. The supplying Warehouse is the Warehouse that
        supplies the Item in question to the shipping Warehouse for shipment
        to Customers. Warehouses may be designated as supplying Warehouses in
        the Item Site definition.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>The supplying Warehouse may differ from the
    receiving Warehouse(s) for some Purchase Order Line Items. To update your
    Inventory records to indicate that Items have been moved from the
    receiving to the supplied from Warehouse, perform an Inter-Warehouse
    Transfer.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Non-Inventory Item</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x185d4cc">
        <para>If the Item being purchased is a non-Inventory Item, select this
        option and specify the following:</para>
        <para>Expense Category: Select an Expense Category to
        assign the non-Inventory Item to.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Source Information</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x185d514">
        <para>If Item Source information exists for an Inventory Item, that
        information will display automatically here. For non-Inventory Items,
        you should specify an Item Number and Item description.</para>
        <para>Vend. Item Number: Enter the Item number the
        Vendor assigns to the specified Item.</para>
        <para>Vendor Item Description: Enter the description
        the Vendor uses to describe to the specified Item.</para>
        <para>Min. Order Qty.: For Inventory Items only,
        displays the minimum order quantity for the specified Item and the
        specified Vendor. Minimum order quantities are established in the Item
        Source master.</para>
        <para>Order Qty. Mult.: For Inventory Items only,
        displays the order multiple for the specified Item and the specified
        Vendor. Order multiples are established in the Item Source
        master.</para>
        <para>Vendor UOM: For Inventory Items only, displays
        the Unit of Measure used by the Vendor for the specified Item.</para>
        <para>Inv./Vendor UOM Ratio: For Inventory Items only,
        displays the ratio between Inventory and Vendor Units of
        Measure.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>The Inv./Vendor UOM Ratio specifies the ratio
    between Inventory and Vendor Units of Measure (UOM). For example, if you
    store an Item in single units, but a Vendor sells you the Item in cases of
    12, then the ratio would be 12--or 12:1. When an Inv./Vend. ratio is
    specified, the system allows you to purchase Items using the Vendor's UOM;
    however, when the Items are received, the system will automatically
    convert the Inventory to your Inventory UOM.</para>
  </note>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x185d580">
      <para>Earliest Due Date: For Inventory Items only,
      displays the earliest due date for the specified Item.</para>
      <para>Qty. Ordered: Enter the quantity of the specified
      Item to be ordered.</para>
      <para>Unit Price: Enter the Unit Price for the specified
      Item.</para>
      <para>Due Date: Specify date when Order is expected to
      be received.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x185d5a4">
      <para>If your system is configured to use Item Source
      Earliest Available dates as the default due date for manual Purchase
      Orders, then this field will be automatically calculated. Earliest
      Available dates are determined by adding Item Source Lead Times to the
      current date.</para>
      <para>Line Item Freight: Enter the amount of freight
      charges for the entire Line Item quantity. The system automatically
      calculates the per unit freight charge by dividing the Line Item freight
      amount by the Line Item quantity. This per unit freight charge is needed
      when receiving or vouchering quantities less than the original quantity
      ordered. Line Item freight is distinguished from miscellaneous freight,
      which applies to the Purchase Order as a whole.</para>
      <para>Qty. Received: Displays quantity received from
      quantity ordered.</para>
      <para>Extended Price: Displays the Extended Price. The
      Extended Price for a Line Item is based on the quantity ordered
      multiplied by the Unit Price.</para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <note>
    <para>The option to associate a Project with a Purchase
    Order Line Item will only be visible if your site is configured to use
    Projects.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Project #</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1865c24">
        <para>Select a Project Number to associate with the Purchase Order
        Line Item.</para>
        <para>If the Purchase Order Line Item is being created
        from a Purchase Request driven by Sales Order demand--and the parent
        Sales Order had a Project Number associated with it--then the Project
        Number from the parent Sales Order will automatically be entered here.
        In this way, Sales Orders and Purchase Order Line Items may be linked
        to the same Project.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Notes</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1865c6c">
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        Notes related to the Purchase Order Line Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons
  are available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1865cd8">
        <para>Closes the screen without creating a new Purchase Order Line
        Item, returning you to the application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1865d20">
        <para>Creates the new Purchase Order Line Item and adds it to the list
        of Purchase Order Line Items.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>If an Item has Characteristics associated with it, you
  have the option of linking those Characteristics to a Purchase Order Item.
  In the case where Sales Order demand generates a Purchase Request, Item
  Characteristics and Values inherited from the Sales Order will already be
  linked to the Purchase Order. Ultimately, Characteristics associated with a
  Purchase Order Item may be printed on the Purchase Order report.</para>
  <tip>
    <para>You can link Characteristics and Values to an Item
    by using the Item master. Once entered, these Characteristics and Values
    will be available to users entering Purchase Order Items.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>To specify or edit Characteristics for a Purchase
  Order Item, select the "Characteristics" tab at the bottom of the screen.
  The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para>
<screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/PO_PO_POItemChar.png" id="Graphic972421"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption972424">Purchase Order Line Item
        Characteristics</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
</para>
  <para>When selecting or editing Characteristics for a
  Purchase Order Line Item, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Name</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1865e1c">
        <para>Displays the name of any Item Characteristics associated with
        the Item.</para>
        <para>Characteristics defined as Item Characteristics
        may be associated with Items on the Item master.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Value</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1865e64">
        <para>Displays the default Value associated with an Item
        Characteristic, but permits you to specify an alternate Value.</para>
        <para>When associating Characteristic Values with a
        Purchase Order Item, you have four options: 1) Select the default
        Value; 2) select an alternate pre-defined Value; 3) manually enter a
        new Value in place of the pre-defined Value; or 4) make no selection.
        Making no selection means the Characteristics will not be associated
        with the Purchase Order Item--except in the case of Characteristics
        inherited from Sales Orders, by way of Purchase Requests.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To add Comments to a Purchase Order Line Item--or to
  view system-generated Comments--select the "Comments" tab at the bottom of
  the screen. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para>
<screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/PO_PO_POItemComm.png" id="Graphic972432"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption972435">Add Comments to Purchase Order Line
        Item</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
</para>
  <para>When adding Comments to a Purchase Order Line Item,
  you are presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Comments</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1865f3c">
        <para>Display lists Comments for the specified Line Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons
  are available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1865fa8">
        <para>Opens screen for creating a new Comment.</para>
        <para>Purchase Order Line Item Comments may only be
        added after the Line Item has been saved to the Purchase Order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>VIEW</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1865ff0">
        <para>Highlight a Comment and then select this button to reach a
        read-only view of the Comment.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To create a Purchase Order Line Item Comment, select
  the NEW button. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para>
<screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/CommentNew.png" id="Graphic972444"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption972447">Create New Comment</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Comment Type</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18660c8">
        <para>Specify one of the following Comment Types from the drop-down
        list: ChangeLog or General.</para>
        <para>Comment Types are used to categorize Comments.
        Once you have specified a Comment Type, you may type your Comment in
        the main text area. The text area features word-wrapping and
        scroll-bar support for longer Comments.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons
  are available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1866134">
        <para>Closes the screen without creating a new Comment, returning you
        to the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x186617c">
        <para>Creates the Comment and adds it to the list of Line Item
        Comments.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
