<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="purchaseOrderItem">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>purchase orders</primary>
      <secondary>creating items for</secondary>
    </indexterm>Purchase Order Item</title>
  <para>To create a new Purchase Order Line Item, select the NEW button. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/purchaseOrderItem.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create New Purchase Order Line Item</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When creating a new Purchase Order Line Item, you are presented with
  the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>P/O Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Purchase Order Number specified in the "New
        Purchase Order" screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Line #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The application automatically assigns line numbers to Purchase
        Order Line Items. Numbering begins at one ("1") and increases
        automatically in increments of one.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Inventory Item</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>If the Item being purchased is an Inventory Item, select this
        option and specify the following:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Item Number</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the Item Number of the Item you want to add to the
              Purchase Order.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Supplying Whse.</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the Warehouse the Item will be supplied from. The
              supplying Warehouse is the Warehouse that supplies the Item in
              question to the shipping Warehouse for shipment to Customers.
              Warehouses may be designated as supplying Warehouses in the Item
              Site definition.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>The supplying Warehouse may differ from the receiving Warehouse(s)
    for some Purchase Order Line Items. To update your Inventory records to
    indicate that Items have been moved from the receiving to the supplied
    from Warehouse, perform an Inter-Warehouse Transfer.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Non-Inventory Item</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>If the Item being purchased is a non-Inventory Item, select this
        option and specify the following:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Expense Category</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select an Expense Category to assign the non-Inventory
              Item to.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. Ordered</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the quantity of the specified Item to be ordered.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. Received</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays quantity received from quantity ordered.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Unit Price</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the Unit Price for the specified Item. </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Extended Price</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Extended Price. The Extended Price for a Line Item
        is based on the quantity ordered multiplied by the Unit Price.</para>
        <note>
          <para>The option to associate a Project with a Purchase Order Line
          Item will only be visible if your site is configured to use
          Projects.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Line Item Freight</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the amount of freight charges for the entire Line Item
        quantity. The system automatically calculates the per unit freight
        charge by dividing the Line Item freight amount by the Line Item
        quantity. This per unit freight charge is needed when receiving or
        vouchering quantities less than the original quantity ordered. Line
        Item freight is distinguished from miscellaneous freight, which
        applies to the Purchase Order as a whole</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Due Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para> Specify date when Order is expected to be received.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Project #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select a Project Number to associate with the Purchase Order
        Line Item. If the Purchase Order Line Item is being created from a
        Purchase Request driven by Sales Order demand--and the parent Sales
        Order had a Project Number associated with it--then the Project Number
        from the parent Sales Order will automatically be entered here. In
        this way, Sales Orders and Purchase Order Line Items may be linked to
        the same Project.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Vendor Source Information</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>If Item Source information exists for an Inventory Item, that
        information will display automatically here. For non-Inventory Items,
        you should specify an Item Number and Item description.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Vend. Item Number</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the Item number the Vendor assigns to the specified
              Item.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Vendor Item Description</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the description the Vendor uses to describe to the
              specified Item.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Min. Order Qty</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>For Inventory Items only, displays the minimum order
              quantity for the specified Item and the specified Vendor.
              Minimum order quantities are established in the Item Source
              master.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Order Qty. Mult.</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>For Inventory Items only, displays the order multiple for
              the specified Item and the specified Vendor. Order multiples are
              established in the Item Source master.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Vendor UOM:</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>For Inventory Items only, displays the Unit of Measure
              used by the Vendor for the specified Item.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Inv./Vendor UOM Ratio:</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>For Inventory Items only, displays the ratio between
              Inventory and Vendor Units of Measure.</para>
              <note>
                <para>The Inv./Vendor UOM Ratio specifies the ratio between
                Inventory and Vendor Units of Measure (UOM). For example, if
                you store an Item in single units, but a Vendor sells you the
                Item in cases of 12, then the ratio would be 12--or 12:1. When
                an Inv./Vend. ratio is specified, the system allows you to
                purchase Items using the Vendor's UOM; however, when the Items
                are received, the system will automatically convert the
                Inventory to your Inventory UOM.</para>
              </note>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Earliest Avail. Due Date</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>For Inventory Items only, displays the earliest due date
              for the specified Item.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without creating a new Purchase Order Line
        Item, returning you to the application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Creates the new Purchase Order Line Item and adds it to the list
        of Purchase Order Line Items.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To add miscellaneous Notes to the Purchase Order Item, select the
  "Notes" tab. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/purchaseOrderItem_notesTab.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Purchase Order Notes</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>When entering miscellaneous Notes to a Purchase Order Item,
  you are presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Notes</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        Notes related to the Purchase Order Line Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>If an Item has Characteristics associated with it, you have the option
  of linking those Characteristics to a Purchase Order Item. In the case where
  Sales Order demand generates a Purchase Request, Item Characteristics and
  Values inherited from the Sales Order will already be linked to the Purchase
  Order. Ultimately, Characteristics associated with a Purchase Order Item may
  be printed on the Purchase Order report.</para>
  <tip>
    <para>You can link Characteristics and Values to an Item by using the Item
    master. Once entered, these Characteristics and Values will be available
    to users entering Purchase Order Items.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>To specify or edit Characteristics for a Purchase Order Item, select
  the "Characteristics" tab at the bottom of the screen. The following screen
  will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/purchaseOrderItem_itemchar.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Purchase Order Line Item Characteristics</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When selecting or editing Characteristics for a Purchase Order Line
  Item, you are presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the name of any Item Characteristics associated with
        the Item. Characteristics defined as Item Characteristics may be
        associated with Items on the Item master.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Value</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the default Value associated with an Item
        Characteristic, but permits you to specify an alternate Value. When
        associating Characteristic Values with a Purchase Order Item, you have
        four options: 1) Select the default Value; 2) select an alternate
        pre-defined Value; 3) manually enter a new Value in place of the
        pre-defined Value; or 4) make no selection. Making no selection means
        the Characteristics will not be associated with the Purchase Order
        Item--except in the case of Characteristics inherited from Sales
        Orders, by way of Purchase Requests.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To add Comments to a Purchase Order Line Item--or to view
  system-generated Comments--select the "Comments" tab at the bottom of the
  screen. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/purchaseOrderItem_commentsTab.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Add Comments to Purchase Order Line Item</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When adding Comments to a Purchase Order Line Item, you are presented
  with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Comments</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists Comments for the specified Line Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Opens screen for creating a new Comment. Purchase Order Line
        Item Comments may only be added after the Line Item has been saved to
        the Purchase Order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>VIEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a Comment and then select this button to reach a
        read-only view of the Comment.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To create a Purchase Order Line Item Comment, select the NEW button.
  The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/CommentNew.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create New Comment</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Comment Type</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify one of the following Comment Types from the drop-down
        list: ChangeLog or General. Comment Types are used to categorize
        Comments. Once you have specified a Comment Type, you may type your
        Comment in the main text area. The text area features word-wrapping
        and scroll-bar support for longer Comments.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without creating a new Comment, returning you
        to the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Creates the Comment and adds it to the list of Line Item
        Comments.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para role="standard">When ordering purchased Items, you have the option to specify which
  Revision of the Item's Bill of Materials and Bill of Operations you want to
  buy. By default, the active Revision will be used. To specify Revision
  information for a Purchase Order Item, select the "Revision" tab. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <screenshot role="standard">
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/purchaseOrderItem_revision.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption>Line Item Revisions</caption>
    </mediaobject>
  </screenshot>
  <note>
    <para role="standard">You may create Purchase Order Items for pending Revisions. For
    Purchase Order purposes, a pending Revision is considered to be the same
    as an inactive Revision. The Revision status of a pending Revision will
    not be changed if a Purchase Order Item is created for it.</para>
  </note>
  <para role="standard">When specifying Revision information for a Purchase
  Order Item, you are presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist role="standard">
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Bill of Materials</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the BOM Revision you want to use for the Purchase Order
        Item. By default, the active Revision will be used.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Revision</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select from the list of existing available Revisions. The
              status of the Revision will also be displayed.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="openmfg">
      <term>Bill of Operations</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the BOO Revision you want to use for the Purchase Order
        Item. By default, the active Revision will be used.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Revision</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select from the list of existing available Revisions. The
              status of the Revision will also be displayed.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
