<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section528866">
  <title>
      <anchor id="Anchor548960" role="Index"
              xreflabel="quotes:creating new;sales quotes. See quotes"/> 
      <indexterm significance="normal">
         <primary>quotes</primary>

         <secondary>creating line items for</secondary>
      </indexterm> 
      <anchor id="Anchor51214" role="Cross-Ref" xreflabel="51214: Heading2: New Quote"/>Quote Item</title>

  <para id="Para532489">To create a new Quote Line Item, select the NEW
  button. The following screen will appear:</para>

  <para id="Para532493">
      <screenshot>
         <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
               <imagedata fileref="images/SO_Ord_quoteItem.png" id="Graphic532491"/>
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption532494">Create New Quote Line Item</caption>
         </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
   </para>

  <para id="Para532495">When creating a Quote Line Item, you are presented
  with the following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para612051">Order #</term>

         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e79d4">
            <para>Displays the Quote Number specified in the "New Quote"
        screen.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para612052">Line #</term>

         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e7a1c">
            <para>Displays the Line Item Number for the current Line Item.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para612053">Item Number</term>

         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e7a64">
            <para>Enter the Item Number of the Item you want to sell.</para>

            <para id="Para612054">The Item list will contain sold Items available
        for purchase by the specified Customer. The list of available Items
        may vary from Customer to Customer, depending on how Pricing Schedules
        are implemented at your site. Once an Item Number is entered, the
        Inventory Unit of Measure and Item description will automatically
        appear.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para612055">Customer P/N</term>

         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e7aac">
            <para>Displays the Customer Part Number (i.e., Item Alias) that
        corresponds to the Item Number entered in the Item Number
        field.</para>

            <para id="Para612056">The Customer Part Number will display only if
        you enter an Item Alias in the Item Number field. To enter an Item
        Alias, place the cursor in the Item Number field and then use the
        keyboard shortcut "CTRL + A". After you have entered a valid Item
        Alias, hit the TAB key. A list of Items that use the specified Item
        Alias will be displayed. Select the desired Item from the list. The
        Item Alias will display as the Customer Part Number. Item Aliases are
        defined on the Item master.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para626787">
            <anchor id="Anchor626785" role="Index"
                    xreflabel="warehouses:sold from for sales orders"/> 
            <indexterm significance="normal">
               <primary>warehouses</primary>

               <secondary>sold from for sales orders</secondary>
            </indexterm> 
            <anchor id="Anchor626786" role="Index" xreflabel="sales orders:selling warehouses for"/> 
            <indexterm significance="normal">
               <primary>sales orders</primary>

               <secondary>selling warehouses for</secondary>
            </indexterm>Sold from Whs.</term>

         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e7b84">
            <para>Specify the Warehouse the Sales Order Item is sold from.</para>

            <para id="Para628619">Items may be supplied to Sales Orders from
        multiple Item Sites. After an Item Number is entered above, the system
        checks for available Item Sites for the Item. Any Item Sites having
        the "Sold from" flag set on them will be selectable from this
        Warehouse list. By default, the Item Site having the highest Ranking
        will be selected as the first available Warehouse. If more than one
        Item Site share a Ranking of "1," the Warehouses will be sorted in
        alphabetical order. Item Site Rankings are set on the Item Site
        master.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <tip>
      <para id="Para628621">If a preferred Selling Warehouse is specified for
    the Customer, then that Warehouse will be selected here by default. If the
    preferred Selling Warehouse is not selected--and you think it should
    be--verify that the Item Site master for the Line Item in question is
    marked as a "Sold from" Warehouse.</para>
  </tip>

  <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para612070">Qty. Ordered</term>

         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e7c14">
            <para>Enter the quantity of the specified Item to be ordered. The
        quantity ordered for sold Items is measured in the Item's Inventory
        UOM.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <note>
      <para id="Para612073">The Quantity Ordered for sold Items is based on the
    Inventory UOM. But the Price is based on the Price UOM. Whenever these two
    UOMs are not identical, the Extended Price for a Line Item will be based
    on the following formula:</para>

      <para id="Para612074">(Qty. Ordered) x (Price/Inv. Ratio) x (Net Unit
    Price)</para>

      <para id="Para612075">If for some reason the Prices don"t look correct,
    check the Item master for the Line Item in question. It may be that the
    Inventory and Price UOMs do not exist in a 1:1 relationship.</para>
  </note>

  <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para630865">
            <anchor id="Anchor630861" role="Index" xreflabel="sales orders:line item pricing for"/> 
            <indexterm significance="normal">
               <primary>sales orders</primary>

               <secondary>line item pricing for</secondary>
            </indexterm>Net Unit Price</term>

         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e7cec">
            <para>By default, the system will choose the lower of the following
        two Prices: A) The most-specific Pricing Schedule Assignment or B) any
        Sale in effect at the time of Order entry. The specificity of Pricing
        Schedule Assignments is determined in the following descending order:
        By Customer Ship-To Address (most specific), by Customer, by Customer
        Type, by Customer Type pattern, by all Customers. The browse button
        located to the right of the field leads to a Price List screen.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <tip>
      <para id="Para630868">The system can be configured to prevent users from
    editing the Net Unit Price. If your system is configured that way, the Net
    Unit Price field will not be editable.</para>
  </tip>

  <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para630869">Extended Price</term>

         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e7d7c">
            <para>Displays the Extended Price.</para>

            <para id="Para630870">The Extended Price for a Line Item is based on
        the quantity ordered multiplied by the Net Unit Price.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para612087">Scheduled Date</term>

         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e7dc4">
            <para>The scheduled date is the date when the Line Item should be
        Shipped. The user who enters the Line Item is responsible for
        determining the scheduled date. After entering the scheduled date, hit
        the TAB key on your keyboard to display values in the remaining
        display only fields.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <note>
      <para id="Para612090">The Quote Item having the earliest scheduled date
    will determine the ship date for the Quote.</para>
  </note>

  <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para637903">Tax Type</term>

         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e7e54">
            <para>Specify the Tax Type for the Quote Item.</para>

            <para id="Para637904">By default, the Item's Tax Type corresponding to
        the Quote's Tax Authority will be presented here. The link between Tax
        Types and Tax Authorities is made on the Item master. If the Item
        master does not have a Tax Type for the Quote's Tax Authority, then no
        Tax will be charged.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para637905">Tax Code</term>

         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e7e9c">
            <para>Specify the Tax Code to be applied to the Quote Item.</para>

            <para id="Para637906">By default, the Tax Code specified in the Tax
        Selection matrix will be displayed here. For a Tax Code to be used,
        the matrix must have an entry which matches both the Item's Tax Type
        definition and the Tax Authority specified on the Quote header. If no
        Tax Selection match exists, then no Tax Code will be used--meaning no
        Tax will be charged.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <tip>
      <para id="Para637908">The relationship between Tax Authorities, Tax Types,
    and Tax Codes is established in the Tax Selection matrix.</para>
  </tip>

  <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para637909">Tax</term>

         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e7f2c">
            <para>Displays the amount of Tax to be charged for the Quote Line Item
        quantity.</para>

            <para id="Para612092">Sales Tax is calculated at the Quote Line Item
        level. To get a detailed view of the Tax calculation, click on the Tax
        link using your mouse.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para637931">
            <anchor id="Anchor612091" role="Index"
                    xreflabel="sales orders:availability of items for"/> 
            <indexterm significance="normal">
               <primary>sales orders</primary>

               <secondary>availability of items for</secondary>
            </indexterm>Show Availability</term>

         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e7fbc">
            <para>Select to display Item Availability in the following
        categories:</para>

            <para id="Para628642">On Hand: Displays the current Quantity on Hand
        value.</para>

            <para id="Para628643">Allocated: Displays the quantity allocated to
        current Sales Orders and/or Work Orders in the system. An Item is
        considered allocated to a Sales Order if a Sales Order Line Item
        exists for the Item--and that Line Item has not yet been issued to
        Shipping. An Item is considered allocated to a Work Order if the Item
        is a material requirement--and the material has not yet been issued to
        the Work Order. Once the current Sales Order Line Item is saved, the
        "Allocated" value will increase by the quantity ordered.</para>

            <para id="Para628644">Unallocated: Displays the Quantity on Hand
        remaining after allocations have been accounted for, as in: QOH -
        Allocated Qty. = Unallocated Qty.</para>

            <para id="Para628645">On Order: If the Sales Order Item is a
        manufactured Item, the quantity ordered by current Work Orders will be
        displayed. If the Sales Order Item is a purchased Item, the quantity
        ordered by current Purchase Orders will be displayed.</para>

            <para id="Para628646">Available: Displays the available quantity.
        Available quantity is determined using the following formula:
        Unallocated Qty. + On Order Qty. = Available Qty.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <note>
      <para id="Para612099">The "Show Availability" feature can be turned on or
    off by default at the system level. If the feature is turned on, the
    Availability totals will display only after a Scheduled Date has been
    entered for the Line Item.</para>
  </note>

  <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para612100">Pricing UOM</term>

         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e804c">
            <para>Displays the Price UOM for the Item.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para612102">Ratio</term>

         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e8094">
            <para>The ratio displayed here is the Price/Inventory UOM ratio, which
        is defined in the Item master for an Item.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para612103">Unit Cost</term>

         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e80dc">
            <para>Displays the Standard Cost per unit.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para612104">List Price</term>

         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e8124">
            <para>Displays the sales List Price per unit.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para612106">Customer Price</term>

         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e816c">
            <para>Displays the Price given to the specified Customer.</para>

            <para id="Para612107">Special Customer Prices can be set for
        individual Customers or Customer Groups by using a Pricing
        Schedule.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para612109">
            <anchor id="Anchor612108" role="Index"
                    xreflabel="sales orders:discount percentages for"/> 
            <indexterm significance="normal">
               <primary>sales orders</primary>

               <secondary>discount percentages for</secondary>
            </indexterm>Discount % from List</term>

         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e81fc">
            <para>Displays the percentage discount off the List Price.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para612113">Discount % from Customer</term>

         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e8244">
            <para>Specify here and apply any discount for specified Customer for
        this Quote.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para630385">Qty. Shipped to Date</term>

         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e828c">
            <para>Shipped to Date: Indicates the total quantity shipped against
        the specified Line Item to date.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para612116">
            <anchor id="Anchor612115" role="Index"
                    xreflabel="sales orders:work orders generated by;work orders:generated by sales orders;purchase requests:generated by sales orders;sales orders:purchase requests generated by"/>
            <indexterm significance="normal">
               <primary>sales orders</primary>

               <secondary>work orders generated by</secondary>
            </indexterm> 
            <indexterm significance="normal">
               <primary>work orders</primary>

               <secondary>generated by sales orders</secondary>
            </indexterm> 
            <indexterm significance="normal">
               <primary>purchase requests</primary>

               <secondary>generated by sales orders</secondary>
            </indexterm> 
            <indexterm significance="normal">
               <primary>sales orders</primary>

               <secondary>purchase requests generated by</secondary>
            </indexterm>Create Work Order</term>

         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e83f4">
            <para>If the Line Item is a manufactured Item, select this option to
        automatically create a Work Order for the specified quantity once the
        Quote is converted to a Sales Order.</para>

            <para id="Para612289">For make-to-order manufactured Items, this
        option will be selected automatically. A Work Order will be created to
        meet the demand when and if the Quote is converted to a Sales Order.
        An Item is designated as make-to-order if the "Stocked at" flag on the
        Item Site master is not selected. A Work Order created automatically
        from a Sales Order Line Item will assume the same Order Number as the
        Sales Order the Line Item is associated with--even if that Order
        Number has already been used by a previous Work Order.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <note>
      <para id="Para630371">For purchased Items, the option "Create Purchase
    Request" will appear instead. The displayed fields will resemble the
    fields shown when "Create Work Order" is visible. One difference is you
    will be given the option to override the purchase Price for the Line Item.
    If used, this one-time override will replace any Item Source Price(s) when
    the Purchase Request is converted to a Purchase Order Line Item.</para>
  </note>

  <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para613089">
            <anchor id="Anchor613088" role="Index"
                    xreflabel="warehouses:for make-to-order items;quotes:supplying warehouses and"/>
            <indexterm significance="normal">
               <primary>warehouses</primary>

               <secondary>for make-to-order items</secondary>
            </indexterm> 
            <indexterm significance="normal">
               <primary>quotes</primary>

               <secondary>supplying warehouses and</secondary>
            </indexterm>Supplying Whs.</term>

         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e8514">
            <para>Specify the Warehouse a corresponding Work Order would be
        supplied from.</para>

            <para id="Para637993">Work Orders may only be created for manufactured
        Items having a supplying Warehouse. Warehouses designated as "Supplied
        at" Warehouses in the Item Site master for an Item are considered
        supplying Warehouses. If no supplying Warehouse exists for an Item, a
        Work Order may not be created for the Item.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para id="Para637994">If an Item has Characteristics associated with it, you
  have the option of linking those Characteristics to a Quote Line Item. And,
  in the case where Sales Order demand automatically generates either a
  Purchase Request or a Work Order, the Characteristics defined here will be
  inherited by those subsequent Orders.</para>

  <tip>
      <para id="Para637955">You can link Characteristics and Values to an Item
    by using the Item master. Once entered, these Characteristics and Values
    will be available to users entering Quote Line Items.</para>
  </tip>

  <para id="Para637956">When selecting or editing Characteristics for a Quote
  Line Item, you are presented with the following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para637957">Name</term>

         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e85a4">
            <para>Displays the name of any Item Characteristics associated with
        the Item.</para>

            <para id="Para637958">Characteristics defined as Item Characteristics
        may be associated with Items on the Item master.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para637959">Value</term>

         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e85ec">
            <para>Displays the default Value associated with an Item
        Characteristic, but permits you to specify an alternate Value.</para>

            <para id="Para637960">When associating Characteristic Values with a
        Quote Line Item, you have four options: 1) Select the default Value;
        2) select an alternate pre-defined Value; 3) manually enter a new
        Value in place of the pre-defined Value; or 4) make no selection.
        Making no selection means the Characteristics will not be associated
        with the Quote Line Item.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para id="Para637961">To the far right of the screen, the following buttons
  are available:</para>

  <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para637962">CLOSE</term>

         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18f3448">
            <para>Closes the screen without creating a new Quote Line Item,
        returning you to the Sales Order header.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para637963">SAVE</term>

         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18f3490">
            <para>Creates the new Quote Line Item and adds it to the list of Sales
        Order Line Items. If "Create Work Order" is specified, the associated
        Work Order will also be created.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para637964">PREVIOUS</term>

         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18f34d8">
            <para>Select to view previous Line Items associated with the
        Quote.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para637965">NEW</term>

         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18f3520">
            <para>Select to create a new Quote Line Item.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para637966">CANCEL ITEM</term>

         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18f3568">
            <para>Select to cancel the current Quote Line Item.</para>

            <para id="Para540294">Records of canceled Line Items will be retained
        for informational purposes. To view canceled Line Items associated
        with a Quote, select the "Show Canceled Line Items" option on the
        Quote header's "Line Items tab.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para id="Para606071">To enter Notes related to a Quote Line Item, select
  the "Notes" tab at the bottom of the screen, as shown below:</para>

  <para id="Para606075">
      <screenshot>
         <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
               <imagedata fileref="images/SO_Ord_quoteItemNote.png" id="Graphic606073"/>
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption606076">Quote Line Item Notes</caption>
         </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
   </para>

  <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para606080">Notes</term>

         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18f38ec">
            <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        general Notes related to the Quote Line Item.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para id="Para605810">To add Comments related to a Quote Line Item, select
  the "Comments" tab. The following screen will appear:</para>

  <para id="Para605814">
      <screenshot>
         <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
               <imagedata fileref="images/SO_Ord_quoteItemComm.png" id="Graphic605812"/>
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption605815">Quote Line Item Comments</caption>
         </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
   </para>

  <note>
      <para id="Para605817">Whenever Quote Line Items are created or their
    quantities are changed, the system will automatically generate a Comment,
    which will appear in the list of Line Item Comments.</para>
  </note>

  <para id="Para605818">When adding Comments related to a Quote Line Item, you
  are presented with the following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para605819">Comments</term>

         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18f39e8">
            <para>Display lists Comments for the specified Line Item.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para id="Para605821">To the far right of the screen, the following buttons
  are available:</para>

  <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para605822">NEW</term>

         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18f3a54">
            <para>Opens screen for creating a new Comment.</para>

            <para id="Para612198">Quote Line Item Comments may only be added after
        the Line Item has been saved to the Quote.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para605823">VIEW</term>

         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18f3a9c">
            <para>Highlight a Comment and then select this button to reach a
        read-only view of the Comment.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para id="Para605824">To create a Quote Line Item Comment, select the NEW
  button. The following screen will appear:</para>

  <para id="Para605828">
      <screenshot>
         <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
               <imagedata fileref="images/CommentNew.png" id="Graphic605826"/>
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption605829">Create New Comment</caption>
         </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
   </para>

  <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para605830">Comment Type</term>

         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18f3b74">
            <para>Specify one of the following Comment Types from the drop-down
        list: ChangeLog or General.</para>

            <para id="Para605831">Comment Types are used to categorize Comments.
        Once you have specified a Comment Type, you may type your Comment in
        the main text area. The text area features word-wrapping and
        scroll-bar support for longer Comments.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para id="Para605832">To the far right of the screen, the following buttons
  are available:</para>

  <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para605833">CANCEL</term>

         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18f3be0">
            <para>Closes the screen without creating a new Comment, returning you
        to the previous screen.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para605834">SAVE</term>

         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18f3c28">
            <para>Creates the Comment and adds it to the list of Order
        Comments.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para id="Para605835">If the Quote Line Item is a manufactured Item, you
  have the ability to view Pending Availability for any of its component
  Items. To view the Pending Availability for Quote Line Item component Items,
  select the "Pending Availability" tab, as shown below:</para>

  <para id="Para605839">
      <screenshot>
         <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
               <imagedata fileref="images/SO_Ord_quotePendAvail.png" id="Graphic605837"/>
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption605840">Pending Availability for Component
        Items</caption>
         </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
   </para>

  <note>
      <para id="Para612222">The "Pending Availability" tab features details
    related to component Items and so only applies if a Quote Line Item is a
    manufactured Item. If a Line Item is not manufactured, Pending
    Availability does not apply.</para>
  </note>

  <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
         <term id="Para605843">Pending Availability</term>

         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18f3d24">
            <para>Displays Pending Availability for component Items associated
        with sold manufactured Items.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <tip>
      <para id="Para605846">Keep in mind that Pending Availability in this case
    is not the same as Available to Promise. This view to Pending Availability
    reflects current Inventory Levels--it is not a time-phased view of
    Availability.</para>
  </tip>

  <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="priceListQuote.xml"
               xpointer="element(/1)"/>
</section>