<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section528866">
  <title>
<indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>quotes</primary>
      <secondary>creating new</secondary>
    </indexterm>
<indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>sales quotes</primary>
      <see>quotes</see>
    </indexterm> <anchor id="Anchor51214" role="Cross-Ref" xreflabel="51214: Heading2: New Quote"/>New Quote</title>
  <para>A Quote is a statement issued to a Customer or
  Prospect indicating pricing and sales Terms for specified quantities of sold
  Items. Quotes are often precursors to Sales Orders. To create a Quote,
  select the "New Quote" option. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para>
<screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/SO_Ord_newSalesQuote.png" id="Graphic532372"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption532375">Create New Quote</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
</para>
  <tip>
    <para>Be sure to close all Sales Order windows before
    exiting the system. This will prevent the creation of orphan Sales Order
    records.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Order #</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d6204">
        <para>Next available Quote Number will automatically display, unless
        your system requires you to enter Quote Numbers manually.</para>
        <para>Default values and input parameters for Quote
        Numbers are configurable at the system level.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>By default, the Quote Number will be assumed by the
    Sales Order when a Quote is converted to a Sales Order.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Warehouse</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d6294">
        <para>Specify the shipping Warehouse associated with the Quote.</para>
        <para>This Warehouse selection is for informational
        purposes only. A Warehouse may be designated as a shipping Warehouse
        on the Warehouse master.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Order Date</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d62dc">
        <para>Displays current day's date.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Scheduled Date</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d6324">
        <para>Displays the Quote's earliest scheduled date.</para>
        <para>The scheduled date corresponds to the earliest
        scheduled date for an included Quote Item. Because Quotes may contain
        multiple Quote Items, the scheduled date indicates the most recent
        scheduled date. No scheduled date will display in the "Scheduled Date"
        field until a Quote Line Item has been created and a scheduled date
        assigned to it.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>
<indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>pack dates</primary>
          <secondary>for quotes</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>quotes</primary>
          <secondary>pack dates for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Pack Date</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d63fc">
        <para>The pack date is the same date as the ship date. Because the
        field can be edited, you have the ability to change the pack date and
        make it different from the ship date.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Originated By</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d6444">
        <para>Specify the origin of the Order using the available
        options:</para>
        <para>Customer: Indicates the Order was originated by
        the Customer.</para>
        <para>Internet: Indicates the Order was originated by
        an Internet lead.</para>
        <para>Sales Rep.: Indicates the Order was originated
        by the Sales Representative.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>Quotes may not be entered for Customers whose credit
    status is either "On Credit Warning" or "On Credit Hold." Only users with
    special privileges may override these credit settings.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Customer #</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d64d4">
        <para>Enter the Customer Number of the Customer (or Prospect) you want
        to create a Quote for.</para>
        <para>The browse button located to the right of the
        field leads to a searchable Customers list. You may also access this
        list using the keyboard shortcut "CTRL + L". Once a Customer Number is
        entered, the Customer name and billing address will display. Select
        the "?" or "$" symbol next to the browse button to view Customer
        information for the specified Customer. If a Customer's credit is "In
        Good Standing," the button will feature a black question mark ("?")
        icon. If the icon turns to an orange dollar sign ("$"), the Customer's
        credit Status is "On Credit Warning." A red dollar sign ("$")
        indicates the Customer's credit Status is "On Credit Hold."</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>A valid Customer Number or Prospect Number must be
    entered in the "Customer #" field before Line Items can be added to a
    Quote. If no valid Number is entered, you will not be able to add Line
    Items to the Quote. Additionally, Quotes may only be entered for active
    Customers and Prospects.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Cust. Type</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d6564">
        <para>Displays the Customer Type for the specified Customer.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>
<indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>quotes</primary>
          <secondary>billing information for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Bill-To Name</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d65f4">
        <para>Displays the Customer's Bill-To name.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Bill-To Phone</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d663c">
        <para>Displays the Customer's Bill-To phone number.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Address</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d6684">
        <para>Displays the Customer's Bill-To Address. You may manually
        override the displayed Address information in the fields below--or use
        the browse button to select another Address.</para>
        <para>Street Address: The Customer's Bill-To street
        Address.</para>
        <para>City: The Customer's Bill-To city.</para>
        <para>State: The Customer's Bill-To state.</para>
        <para>Postal Code: The Customer's Bill-To Postal
        Code.</para>
        <para>Country: The Customer's Bill-To country.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Copy to Ship-to</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d66cc">
        <para>Select to copy contents of billing address into Ship-To address
        field.</para>
        <para>This option is enabled if the Customer master
        for the specified Customer indicates that free-form Ship-To's are
        allowed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Ship-To #</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d6714">
        <para>Enter the number of the preferred Ship-To Address.</para>
        <para>Customers may maintain multiple Ship-To
        Addresses. If the Customer master for the specified Customer indicates
        that free-form Ship-To's are allowed, then any address may be entered.
        If free-form Ship-To's are not allowed, then the Ship-To Address must
        be entered using the browse button located to the right of the field.
        The browse button leads to a searchable Ship-To Addresses list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>
<indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>quotes</primary>
          <secondary>ship-to details for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Ship-To Name</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d67a4">
        <para>Displays the name for the specified Ship-To.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Ship-To Phone</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d67ec">
        <para>Displays the phone number for the specified Ship-To.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Address</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18df424">
        <para>Displays the specified Ship-To Address. You may manually
        override the displayed Address information in the fields below--or use
        the browse button to select another Address.</para>
        <para>Street Address: The specified Ship-To street
        Address.</para>
        <para>City: The specified Ship-To city.</para>
        <para>State: The specified Ship-To state.</para>
        <para>Postal Code: The specified Ship-To Postal
        Code.</para>
        <para>Country: The specified Ship-To country.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>
<indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales representatives</primary>
          <secondary>commissions for</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>quotes</primary>
          <secondary>commissions on</secondary>
        </indexterm>Sales Rep.</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18df4fc">
        <para>Specify the Sales Representative associated with the
        Order.</para>
        <para>Sales Representatives are linked to a Customer
        on the Customer master--either by a default setting or through the
        assignment of Ship-To Addresses. Each Ship-To Address may have a
        different Sales Representative associated with it. Consequently, the
        name of the Sales Representative appearing on the Sales Order header
        will be the same as specified for the Ship-To Address being
        used.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Commission</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18df544">
        <para>By default, the commission percentage recorded on the Customer
        master will be automatically entered in this field. If for some reason
        you select a non-default Sales Representative at Order entry, the
        commission rate will not change. To adjust the commission rate, you
        must make the change manually.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>
<indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>tax authorities</primary>
          <secondary>for quotes</secondary>
        </indexterm>Tax Authority</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18df5d4">
        <para>Specify the Tax Authority associated with the Quote.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term/>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18df61c">
        <para>The Tax Authority for the specified Ship-To Address will be
        entered here by default. Otherwise, the primary Tax Authority for the
        Customer will be entered. Ultimately, Tax is applied at the Line Item
        level--so the Tax Authority associated with an Item's Tax Type will be
        used.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>
<indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>quotes</primary>
          <secondary>setting terms for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Terms</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18df6ac">
        <para>Specify the billing Terms associated with the Order.</para>
        <para>By default, the Customer's standard billing
        Terms will appear in the field. Customer billing.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>The option to associate a Project with a Quote will
    only be visible if your site is configured to use Projects.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Project #</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18df73c">
        <para>Select a Project Number to associate with the Quote.</para>
        <para>If a Sales Order is created from a converted
        Quote--and the Quote had a Project Number associated with it--then the
        Project Number from the originating Quote will automatically be
        entered here. Once a Project Number is associated with a Sales Order,
        any Work Orders or Purchase Orders created by the Sales Order demand
        will automatically be linked to the same Project Number as the Sales
        Order. In this way, Sales Orders, Work Orders, and Purchase Orders may
        be linked to the same Project.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>If your site is configured to create Projects
    automatically whenever new Sales Orders or Quotes are entered, the
    Projects generated in this way will assume the number of the Sales Order
    or Quote which caused their creation.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Cust. PO #</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18df7cc">
        <para>PO #: Enter a Customer Purchase Order Number, as needed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>You will be required to enter a Customer Purchase
    Order Number for Customers who require them. If required, duplicate
    numbers will only be allowed if the Customer uses blanket Purchase Orders.
    All Customer requirements are specified on the Customer master.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>F.O.B.</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18df85c">
        <para>Enter free on board (FOB) Terms for the Order. By default,
        F.O.B. Terms entered on the Shipping Warehouse master will appear in
        this field. The default Terms may be changed during Order entry--and
        also at later stages during the billing cycle.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Ship Via</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18df8a4">
        <para>The preferred Ship Via method for the Customer will appear in
        the field.</para>
        <para>You may change the default Ship Via using the
        list. You may also enter a free-form Ship Via simply by typing the
        name of the Ship Via into the field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>The system supports up-to-date shipment tracking
    with links to the websites of many leading shipping companies ((i.e.,
    "Ship Vias").</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>
<indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>hold types</primary>
          <secondary>for quotes</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>quotes</primary>
          <secondary>hold types for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Hold Type</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18df9c4">
        <para>Specify a hold type (if any) from the available options:</para>
        <para>None: Indicates no hold is applied, meaning the
        Order may be processed and shipped.</para>
        <para>Shipping: Indicates a Shipping hold has been
        placed on the Order. Users who attempt to ship an Order on Shipping
        hold will be prevented from doing so.</para>
        <para>Packing: Indicates a Packing hold has been
        placed on the Order. Users who attempt to issue stock to Shipping for
        an Order on Packing hold will be prevented from doing so.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>Shipping defaults specified on the Customer master
    will transfer to the Quote header when a new Quote is entered for a
    Customer.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>
<indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>quotes</primary>
          <secondary>shipping charges on</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>shipping</primary>
          <secondary>charges on quotes</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>quotes</primary>
          <secondary>shipping forms on</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>shipping forms</primary>
          <secondary>selecting on quotes</secondary>
        </indexterm>Shipping Chgs.</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dfb74">
        <para>Specify the shipping charges associated with the Order.</para>
        <para>The preferred Shipping Charges Type for the
        Customer will appear in the field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Shipping Form</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dfbbc">
        <para>Specify the shipping Form associated with the Order.</para>
        <para>The preferred Shipping Form for the Customer
        will appear in the field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons
  are available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dfc28">
        <para>Creates the new Quote and saves the Quote information.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dfc70">
        <para>Closes the screen without creating a new Quote, returning you to
        the application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>
<indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>quotes</primary>
      <secondary>creating line items for</secondary>
    </indexterm>To create or modify Quote Line Items, select the "Line Items"
  tab at the top of the "New Quote" screen. The following screen will
  appear:</para>
  <para>
<screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/SO_Ord_quoteLineItem.png" id="Graphic626471"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption626474">Quote Line Items</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
</para>
  <tip>
    <para>The system will allow you to enter Quotes for Items
    which do not have Item Sites. However, Item Sites must be defined before a
    Quote can be converted to a Sales Order.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>When creating or modifying Quote Line Items, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Line Items</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dfdb4">
        <para>Display lists Line Items for this Quote.</para>
        <para>A valid Customer Number must be entered in the
        "Customer #" field before Line Items can be added to the Order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>$ Margin</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dfdfc">
        <para>Displays the total profit margin for the Quote.</para>
        <para>The profit margin is based on the following
        formula:</para>
        <para>Quote Subtotal - Total Standard Costs for all
        Line Items</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Subtotal</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dfe44">
        <para>Displays the subtotal for the Quote Line Items.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Tax</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dfe8c">
        <para>Displays the amount of Tax that will be added to the Sales
        Order, as defined by the specified Tax Code.</para>
        <para>To get a detailed view of the Tax calculation,
        click on the Tax link using your mouse.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Misc. Charge Amount</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dfed4">
        <para>Enter the amount of any miscellaneous charge. Examples of
        miscellaneous charges include palletization costs, co-op refund, etc.
        Before entering a miscellaneous charge amount, you must first assign
        the charge to a Sales Account and also enter a description of the
        charge.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>If you do not use Miscellaneous Charges at your
    site, you can hide these fields so they are not visible when entering
    Sales Orders. To do so, simply select the "Hide Misc. Charges" option in
    the system-level configuration.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Misc. Charge Description</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dff64">
        <para>Enter a description to identify the miscellaneous charge.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Misc. Charge Sales Account</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dffac">
        <para>Enter a Sales Account to assign the miscellaneous charge
        to.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Freight Weight</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18dfff4">
        <para>Displays the combined weight of all Quote Line Items.</para>
        <para>Freight weight represents the sum of an Item's
        product weight and packaging weight, both of which are defined on the
        Item master. The per unit freight weight multiplied by the quantity
        per gives you the Line Item freight weight. The sum of all Line Item
        freight weights is the combined weight for the Quote.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>
<indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>freight</primary>
          <secondary>on sales orders</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales orders</primary>
          <secondary>freight charges on</secondary>
        </indexterm>Freight</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e00cc">
        <para>Enter the amount of freight charge to be added to the specified
        Order. Freight charges may be entered during the creation or
        modification of a Quote--or at the time of shipment.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Total</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e0114">
        <para>Displays the total amount of the Quote.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>Any Quote Line Item may be shipped--even if the Item
    or Item Site in question becomes inactive after the Quote has been
    created.</para>
  </note>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons
  are available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e01a4">
        <para>Saves the Quote Line Item information.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e01ec">
        <para>Closes the screen without creating a new Quote, returning you to
        the application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e7824">
        <para>Opens screen for creating a new Quote Line Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>EDIT</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e786c">
        <para>Enables you to edit highlighted Quote Line Items. The edit
        screen is the same as that for creating a new Quote Line Item--except
        that when editing, the fields will contain Quote Line Item
        information. Double-clicking on a Quote Line Item will also bring you
        to the editing screen.</para>
        <para>Mac users may use COMMAND + E to edit an
        existing Line Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>DELETE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18e78b4">
        <para>Highlight a Quote Line Item and then select this button to
        remove the Quote Line Item from the list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>Order Notes added to a Quote are used for internal
  purposes only. To add Order Notes to a Quote, select the "Order Notes" tab
  at the top of the "New Quote" screen. The following screen will
  appear:</para>
  <para>
<screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/SO_Ord_quoteNote.png" id="Graphic586247"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption532574">Order Notes</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
</para>
  <para>When adding Order Notes to a Quote, you are presented
  with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Order Notes</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18f3e20">
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        general Notes related to the Quote. These Notes are for internal use
        only.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons
  are available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18f3e8c">
        <para>Saves the Order Note.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18f3ed4">
        <para>Closes the screen without creating an Order Note, returning you
        to the application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To add Comments related to a Quote, select the
  "Comments" tab. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para>
<screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/SO_Ord_quoteComment.png" id="Graphic622879"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption622882">Quote Comments</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
</para>
  <para>When adding Comments related to a Quote, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Comments</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18f3fac">
        <para>Display lists Comments for the specified Quote.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons
  are available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18f4018">
        <para>Opens screen for creating a new Comment.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>VIEW</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18f4060">
        <para>Highlight a Comment and then select this button to reach a
        read-only view of the Comment.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To create a Quote Comment, select the NEW button. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para>
<screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/CommentNew.png" id="Graphic597098"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption597101">Create New Comment</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Comment Type</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18f4138">
        <para>Specify one of the following Comment Types from the drop-down
        list: ChangeLog or General.</para>
        <para>Comment Types are used to categorize Comments.
        Once you have specified a Comment Type, you may type your Comment in
        the main text area. The text area features word-wrapping and
        scroll-bar support for longer Comments.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons
  are available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18f41a4">
        <para>Closes the screen without creating a new Comment, returning you
        to the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18f41ec">
        <para>Creates the Comment and adds it to the list of Quote
        Comments.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>Shipping Notes are drawn from the Customer
  master--specifically from the "Shipping Notes" tab on the Ship-To Address
  master. The Notes may vary depending on the Ship-To Address specified for
  the Quote. These Notes provide a mechanism for transferring shipping
  information from the Customer master to the Quote. To add Shipping Notes to
  a Quote, select the "Shipping Notes" tab at the top of the "New Quote"
  screen. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para>
<screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/SO_Ord_quoteShipNote.png" id="Graphic622799"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption622802">Quote Shipping Notes</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
</para>
  <para>When adding shipping Notes to a Quote, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Shipping Notes</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18fb6b4">
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        shipping Notes related to the Quote. These Notes are for internal use
        only.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons
  are available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18fb720">
        <para>Saves the Shipping Notes.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18fb768">
        <para>Closes the screen without creating Shipping Notes, returning you
        to the application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="quoteItem.xml" xpointer="element(/1)"/>
</section>
