<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section519497">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>credit memos</primary>
      <secondary>re-printing of</secondary>
    </indexterm>Re-Print Credit Memos</title>
  <para>To print a Credit Memo that was previously printed, select the
  "Re-Print Credit Memos" option. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/SO_Bill_re-PrintCredMems.png"
                     id="Graphic570249" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption570252">Re-Print Credit Memos</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When re-printing a Credit Memo, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Invoices</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x193ad6c">
        <para>Display lists previously printed Credit Memos. To select a
        sequence of Credit Memos, highlight the first in the sequence using
        your mouse button. Then, holding down the SHIFT key on your keyboard,
        highlight the last Credit Memo in the sequence. The entire sequence is
        now selected. To select Credit Memos that are out of sequence,
        highlight the first Credit Memo in the group. Then, holding down the
        CTRL key on your keyboard, highlight the next Credit Memo you want to
        select. Continue highlighting Credit Memos with the CTRL key depressed
        until all desired Credit Memos are selected. The entire group is now
        ready for re-printing.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Invoice Copies</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x193adb4">
        <para>Specify details for the Credit Memo copies you want to print.
        </para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term># of Copies</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Indicate the number of copies you want to re-print using
              the arrow buttons. Information about the specified copies will
              display below. To add a Watermark, double-click on a copy line,
              as shown in <xref endterm="Anchor57653" linkend="Anchor57653" />
              FINDME Figure 10.111.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CLOSE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x193ae20">
        <para>Closes the screen without re-printing Credit Memos, returning
        you to the application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>PRINT</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x193ae68">
        <para>Prints the highlighted Credit Memos, using the specified
        parameters.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>