<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section role="openmfg">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>return authorizations</primary>
      <secondary>creating new</secondary>
    </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>customers</primary>
      <secondary>return authorizations for</secondary>
    </indexterm>Return Authorization</title>
  <para>Many users of OpenMFG have a company policy to accept returned goods.
  To adequately handle this situation they need a mechanism to keep a record
  of what goods have been authorized for a return, credit, or other
  disposition. A Return Authorization is an internal approval system to
  resolve a problem resulting from dissatisfaction with products or services
  shipped. Depending on the business model, users may handle the return in a
  number of ways. The OpenMFG return system is flexible enough to handle the
  needs of most business scenarios.</para>
  <para>To access the Return Authorization window, Return Authorizations must
  be enabled in Sales Configuration. A Return Authorization appears as
  follows:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/returnAuthorization.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create New Return Authorization</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When creating a new Return Authorization, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Auth #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Next available Return Authorization Number will automatically
        display, unless your system requires you to enter Return Authorization
        Numbers manually. Default values and input parameters for Return
        Authorization Numbers are configurable at the system level.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Auth. Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays current day's date.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Expire Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the date when the Return Authorization will expire. This
        is an optional setting used to determine the amount of time that
        should pass before the transactions on the Return Authorization are
        considered past due</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales representatives</primary>
          <secondary>commissions for</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>return authorizations</primary>
          <secondary>commissions on</secondary>
        </indexterm>Sales Rep.</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the Sales Representative associated with the Return
        Authorization. Sales Representatives are linked to a Customer on the
        Customer master--either by a default setting or through the assignment
        of Ship-To Addresses. Each Ship-To Address may have a different Sales
        Representative associated with it. Consequently, the name of the Sales
        Representative appearing on the Return Authorization header will be
        the same as specified for the Ship-To Address being used.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Commission</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>By default, the commission percentage recorded on the Customer
        master will be automatically entered in this field. If for some reason
        you select a non-default Sales Representative, the commission rate
        will not change. To adjust the commission rate, you must make the
        change manually.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>tax authorities</primary>
          <secondary>for return authorizations</secondary>
        </indexterm>Tax Authority</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the Tax Authority associated with the Return
        Authorization. The Tax Authority for the specified Ship-To Address
        will be entered here by default. Otherwise, the primary Tax Authority
        for the Customer will be entered. Ultimately, Tax is applied at the
        Line Item level--so the Tax Authority associated with an Item's Tax
        Type will be used.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Reason Code</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the reason for the Return Authorization. Reason Codes
        are used to explain why a Customer return is being authorized.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Disposition</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the method to be used for handling the Return
        Authorization. If your system is configured to use a default
        disposition, then that value will be shown.</para>
        <note>
          <para>The disposition of individual Line Items will be determined
          conditionally based on the settings made at the Return Authorization
          header level.</para>
        </note>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Credit</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to authorize the issuing of credit to the specified
              Customer. No return is required or expected; as a result, the
              Credit/Ship timetable option will be disabled for this
              disposition method. Return Authorization Line Items will close
              when an associated Credit Memo is posted.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Return</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to authorize returns from the specified Customer.
              Return Authorization Items will close when an associated Credit
              Memo is posted, or when all Items on a line have been returned,
              whichever comes last.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Replace</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to authorize the replacement of Items returned by
              the specified Customer. Authorized quantities will be added as
              additional order quantity to a new associated Sales Order.
              Return Authorization Items will close when all Items on the line
              have been returned or all authorized Items on the line have been
              shipped, whichever comes last. Any money to be credited to the
              customer is set on the Return Authorization line; any money to
              be billed to the customer is set at the new sales order
              line.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Service</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to authorize the repair or service of Items
              returned by the specified Customer. To isolate costing
              implications, only Items of type Job may be selected. Service or
              repair items will first be received by the Return Authorization.
              A new Sales Order with linked Work Order(s) will be created to
              track work and shipping on the repair or service. Money to be
              billed for service or repair should be set at the New Sales
              Order.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Substitute</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to authorize the substitution of Items returned by
              the specified Customer. Under this option, when an original
              Sales Order is imported into the Return Authorization, the
              Return Authorization Line Items will default to the Return
              disposition. Any new Line Items added beyond the original ones
              will have a default disposition of Ship.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Credit/Ship</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the timing for the Return Authorization:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Immediately</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to issue credit or send returns to the specified
              Customer immediately.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Upon Receipt</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to issue credit or ship new associated Sales Order
              items only after you have received the returned goods.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Credit by</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the method to be used for crediting the Customer:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>None</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if you will not be issuing credit to the Customer.
              If you select this option, you will be unable to add pricing
              information at the Return Authorization Line Item level.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Credit Memo</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to credit the return with a Credit Memo to the
              Customer's account. If selected, a sales Credit Memo will be
              automatically queued up for processing on the Return
              Authorizations Workbench.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Check</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to credit the return by sending the Customer a
              Check. If selected, a Customer Check will be queued up for
              processing on the Return Authorizations Workbench. When the
              Check is processed, a sales Credit Memo will be created
              automatically--and the Check will be applied to it.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Credit Card</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to credit the return with a refund to the
              Customer's Credit Card. If selected, the payment will be queued
              up for processing on the Return Authorizations Workbench. A
              Credit Memo will be posted when the refund is processed--and the
              refund charges will be applied to it. If the timing of the
              credit is immediately, then you may issue the refund directly
              from the Line Items tab of the Return Authorization.</para>
              <note>
                <para>The Credit Card functionality must be enabled at your
                site for the Credit Card method to function properly.</para>
              </note>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Print on Save</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to print a copy of the Return Authorization when you
        select the SAVE button. You must have a Form "keyed on" Return
        Authorizations for this option to work. The keyed on process is
        described here: <xref linkend="formCreateNew" />.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Original Order #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>You have the option to select an original Sales Order for all
        disposition types. When an original Sales Order is selected, all Line
        Items from the original Order will be imported into the Return
        Authorization automatically. For dispositions Credit and Return this
        feature imports the original pricing and billing information. When a
        Sales Order number is selected, the Customer Number and address
        information will be populated and disabled. If the Customer is
        selected first, only Sales Orders for that customer will appear on the
        search list.</para>
        <note>
          <para>A Sales Order may be linked to only one open Return
          Authorization at a time.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>New Order #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>For Return Authorizations having either Replace, Service, or
        Substitute dispositions, the system will automatically generate a new
        Sales Order for shipping purposes once any Line Item quantity has been
        authorized. Authorized Line Item quantities are added automatically to
        the new Sales Order, enabling you to ship the quantity at the
        appropriate time.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Project #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>You have the option to select a Project Number to associate with
        the Return Authorization. This enables you to link the Return
        Authorization with other Orders linked to the same project. The browse
        button located to the right of the field enables you to select from a
        list of available Projects.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Customer #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the Customer Number of the Customer whose return you are
        authorizing. The browse button located to the right of the field leads
        to a searchable Customers list. You may also access this list using
        the keyboard shortcut "CTRL + L".</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>A valid Customer Number must be entered in the "Customer #" field
    before Line Items can be added to a Return Authorization for all
    disposition types except Return. If no valid Customer Number is entered,
    you will not be able to add Line Items to the Return Authorization.
    Additionally, Return Authorizations may only be entered for active
    Customers.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Cust. Type</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Customer Type for the specified Customer.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>return authorizations</primary>
          <secondary>billing information for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Bill-To Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Customer's Bill-To name.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Bill-To Phone</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Customer's Bill-To phone number.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Address</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Customer's Bill-To Address. You may manually
        override the displayed Address information in the fields below--or use
        the browse button to select another Address.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Street Address</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The Customer's Bill-To street Address.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>City</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The Customer's Bill-To city.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>State</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The Customer's Bill-To state.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Postal Code</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The Customer's Bill-To Postal Code.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Country</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The Customer's Bill-To country.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Copy to Ship-to -\&gt;</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to copy contents of billing address into Ship-To address
        field. This option is enabled if the Customer master for the specified
        Customer indicates that free-form Ship-To's are allowed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Ship-To #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the number of the preferred Ship-To Address. Customers may
        maintain multiple Ship-To Addresses. If the Customer master for the
        specified Customer indicates that free-form Ship-To's are allowed,
        then any address may be entered. If free-form Ship-To's are not
        allowed, then the Ship-To Address must be entered using the browse
        button located to the right of the field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>return authorizations</primary>
          <secondary>ship-to details for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Ship-To Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the name for the specified Ship-To.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Ship-To Phone</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the phone number for the specified Ship-To.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Address</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the specified Ship-To Address. You may manually
        override the displayed Address information in the fields below--or use
        the browse button to select another Address.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Street Address:</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The specified Ship-To street Address.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>City</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The specified Ship-To city.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>State</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The specified Ship-To state.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Postal Code</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The specified Ship-To Postal Code.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Country</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The specified Ship-To country.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Cust. PO #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a Customer Purchase Order Number, as needed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Incident</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>You have the option to associate an Incident Number with the
        Return Authorization. The browse button located to the right of the
        field enables you to select from a list of available Projects.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>At the top of the screen, the following buttons are available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Creates the Return Authorization and saves the Return
        Authorization information. The SAVE button must be selected in order
        to save the Return Authorization record. It is not enough to save
        Return Authorization Line Item information. The Return Authorization
        header must also be saved.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without creating a new Return Authorization,
        returning you to the application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>return authorizations</primary>
      <secondary>adding line items to</secondary>
    </indexterm>To create or modify Return Authorization Line Items, select
  the "Line Items" tab at the top of the "Return Authorization" screen. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/returnAuthorization_lineItemsPage.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Return Authorization Line Items</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When creating or modifying Return Authorization Line Items, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Line Items</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists Line Items for this Return Authorization. A valid
        Customer Number must be entered in the "Customer #" field before Line
        Items can be added to the Return Authorization for all Dispositions
        except Return.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Subtotal</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the subtotal for the Return Authorization Line
        Items.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Misc. Charge Amount</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the amount of any miscellaneous charge. Before entering a
        miscellaneous charge amount, you must first assign the charge to a
        Sales Account and also enter a description of the charge.</para>
        <tip>
          <para>You may only enter miscellaneous charges on a Return
          Authorization only when a valid credit method is selected and a
          credit amount has been specified for one or more line items. Once a
          credit memo has been created against the Return Authorization, the
          header amounts may not be subsequently modified.</para>
        </tip>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Misc. Charge Description</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a description to identify the miscellaneous charge.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Misc. Charge Credit Account</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a Credit Account to assign the miscellaneous charge
        to.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>freight</primary>
          <secondary>on return authorizations</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>return authorizations</primary>
          <secondary>freight charges on</secondary>
        </indexterm>Freight</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the amount of freight charge to be credited on the
        specified Return Authorization.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Tax</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the total amount of Tax to be charged on the Return
        Authorization. The Tax amount displayed here represents the total for
        all Line Item Tax amounts. To get a detailed view of the Tax
        calculation, click on the Tax link using your mouse.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Total</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the total amount of the Return Authorization.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CVV Code</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the Card Verification Value (CVV) Code found on the back
        of the specified Credit Card. This may be an optional feature at your
        site. Contact your Systems Administrator for details.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>At the top of and to the far right of the screen, the following
  buttons are available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Saves the Return Authorization information.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL/CLOSE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Cancel closes the screen without creating a new Return
        Authorization, returning you to the application desktop. When editing
        a pre-existing Return Authorization, the same button will display
        "Close." Closing will close the window without saving changes to the
        header.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Opens screen for creating a new Return Authorization Line
        Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>EDIT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para id="returnAuthorizationEDIT">Enables you to edit highlighted
        Return Authorization Line Items. The edit screen is the same as that
        for creating a new Return Authorization Line Item--except that when
        editing, the fields will contain Return Authorization Line Item
        information. Double-clicking on a Return Authorization Line Item will
        also bring you to the editing screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>VIEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a Return Authorization Line Item and then select this
        button to reach a read-only view of the "Edit" screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CLOSE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para id="returnAuthorizationCLOSE">Highlight a Return Authorization
        Line Item and then select this button to close the Return
        Authorization Line Item. If the highlighted Line Item is already
        closed, this button will revert to an OPEN button, which may be used
        to open the closed Line Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>DELETE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para id="returnAuthorizationDELETE">Highlight a Return Authorization
        Line Item and then select this button to remove the Return
        Authorization Line Item from the list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>AUTHORIZE LINE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a Return Authorization Line Item and then select this
        button to authorize the Line Item quantity. This option is available
        only when an imported original Sales Order is being used--and then,
        the original Line Item quantity must be shipped before it may be
        authorized.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CLEAR AUTHORIZATION</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a Return Authorization Line Item and then select this
        button to change the authorization quantity to zero for the Line
        Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>AUTHORIZE ALL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to authorize the full quantity for all unathorized Line
        Items. This option is available only when an imported original Sales
        Order is being used--and then, the original Line Item quantity must be
        shipped before it may be authorized.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>ENTER RECEIPT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight an authorized Return Authorization Line Item and then
        select this button to receive the authorized quantity. The received
        quantity will be saved for subsequent posting.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>RECEIVE ALL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to automatically receive all authorized Line Item
        quantity. The received quantities will be saved for subsequent
        posting.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>POST RECEIPTS</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to post all pending receipts for the Return
        Authorization.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>REFUND</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to issue the specified Customer a refund on their Credit
        Card. This option is only available for credits issued by Credit Card.
        Your system must also be configured to use Credit Cards for this
        option to work.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>Right-clicking on an Item in the Line Items list enables you to select
  from the following menu options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Edit Line</term>
      <listitem>
        <xi:include href="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                    xpointer="element(returnAuthorizationEDIT)" />
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Close Line</term>
      <listitem>
        <xi:include href="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                    xpointer="element(returnAuthorizationCLOSE)" />
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Delete Line</term>
      <listitem>
        <xi:include href="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                    xpointer="element(returnAuthorizationDELETE)" />
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <xi:include href="../widgets/xtreewidget.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(xtreewidget.menu.exportcontents)" />
  </variablelist>
  <para>If a new Sales Order has been created for the Return Authorization,
  the following additional options will be available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <xi:include href="../supportfiles/rightclick.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(rightclickEditNewOrder)" />
    <xi:include href="../supportfiles/rightclick.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(rightclickViewNewOrder)" />
    <xi:include href="../supportfiles/rightclick.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(rightclickEditNewOrderLine)" />
    <xi:include href="../supportfiles/rightclick.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(rightclickViewNewOrderLine)" />
    <xi:include href="../supportfiles/rightclick.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(rightclickNewOrderShipStatus)" />
    <xi:include href="../supportfiles/rightclick.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(rightclickNewOrderShipments)" />
  </variablelist>
  <para>If the Line Items were imported from an original Sales Order, the
  following additional option will be available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <xi:include href="../supportfiles/rightclick.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(rightclickViewOriginalOrder)" />
  </variablelist>
  <para>Order Notes added to a Return Authorization are used for internal
  purposes only. To add Notes to a Return Authorization, select the "Order
  Notes" tab at the top of the "Return Authorization" screen. The following
  screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/returnAuthorization_authCommentsPage.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Return Authorization Notes</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When adding Notes to a Return Authorization, you are presented with
  the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Order Notes</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        general Notes related to the Return Authorization. These Notes are for
        internal use only.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To add Comments related to a Return Authorization, select the
  "Comments" tab. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/returnAuthorization_commentsPage.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Return Authorization Comments</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When adding Comments related to a Return Authorization, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Comments</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists Comments for the specified Order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Opens screen for creating a new Comment.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>VIEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a Comment and then select this button to reach a
        read-only view of the Comment.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To create a Return Authorization Comment, select the NEW button. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/CommentNew.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create New Comment</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Comment Type</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify one of the following Comment Types from the drop-down
        list: ChangeLog or General. Comment Types are used to categorize
        Comments. Once you have specified a Comment Type, you may type your
        Comment in the main text area. The text area features word-wrapping
        and scroll-bar support for longer Comments.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without creating a new Comment, returning you
        to the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Creates the Comment and adds it to the list of Order
        Comments.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <xi:include href="returnAuthorizationItem.xml"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
              xpointer="element(/1)" />
</section>