<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section role="openmfg">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>return authorizations</primary>
      <secondary>adding line items to</secondary>
    </indexterm>Return Authorization Item</title>
  <para>To add a new Return Authorization Line Item, select the NEW button.
  The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/returnAuthorizationItem.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create New Return Authorization Line Item</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When creating a new Return Authorization Line Item, you are presented
  with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Anth #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Return Authorization Number specified on the Return
        Authorization header.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Line #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Line Item Number for the current Line Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Original Order #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the original Sales Order Number if the Line Item has
        been imported into the Return Authorization. Importing Return
        Authorization Line Items from an original Sales Order is optional
        only. When Line Items are imported, the original quantities and
        pricing information are imported also.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Line #</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the original Sales Order Line Item Number.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>New Order #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Order Number for the new Sales Order created in
        support of the Return Authorization, if applicable. New Sales Orders
        will be automatically created for Return Authorizations having the
        following dispositions: Replace, Service, Ship.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Line #</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the Line Item Number for the new Sales
              Order.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Disposition</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Line Item dispositions are determined conditionally, based on
        the Return Authorization's header-level disposition setting. If Line
        Items have been imported from an original Sales Order, then the line
        level disposition may not be changed. However, you may manually set
        the line level disposition when creating new Return Authorization Line
        Items. The following options are available:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Credit</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to authorize the issuing of credit for the
              specified Item quantity at the specified Price. No return is
              required or expected.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Return</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to authorize the return of the specified Item
              quantity at the specified Price.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Replace</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to authorize the replacement of the specified Item
              quantity. The Price controls will be disabled for this
              disposition.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Service</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to authorize the servicing of Service (i.e., Job)
              Item for the specified quantity. This disposition is valid only
              for Items having the Job Item Type. The Price controls will be
              disabled for this disposition. A new corresponding Sales Order
              and line will be created if one does not already exist.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Ship</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to authorize the shipment of the specified
              quantity. The Price controls will be disabled for this
              disposition. A new corresponding Sales Order and line will be
              created if one does not already exist.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Reason Code</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the reason for the Return Authorization. Reason codes
        are used to explain why a Customer return is being authorized. The
        Line Item inherits the Reason Code from the header, but may be
        overridden at the line level.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the Item Number of the Item you want to authorize. The
        Items you may select will vary depending on the Line Item disposition.
        For example, only Job Items may be selected for Line Items having the
        Service disposition. Once an Item Number is entered, the Inventory
        Unit of Measure and Item description will automatically appear.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>warehouses</primary>
          <secondary>for receiving returns</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>return authorizations</primary>
          <secondary>receiving warehouses for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Recv. Whs.</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the Warehouse where you want the returned Item quantity
        to be received. </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>warehouses</primary>
          <secondary>for shipping returns</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>return authorizations</primary>
          <secondary>shipping warehouses for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Ship Whs.</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the Warehouse where you want authorized Return
        Authorization quantity to be shipped from. This option is only
        available for Line Items having a disposition which requires creation
        of a new Sales Order (i.e., Replace, Service, Ship).</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. Auth.</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the quantity of the specified Item you want to
        authorize.</para>
        <note>
          <para>The quantity authorized is based on the quantity Unit of
          Measure.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the Unit of Measure to be used when authorizing the Line
        Item. Sold Items may be assigned multiple Selling UOMs. These
        alternate UOMs may be defined on the Item master. If a Line Item has
        no Selling UOM defined, then the Inventory UOM will be used here by
        default.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. Received</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the quantity received against the Return Authorization
        Line Item (if any) to date.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. Shipped</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Return Authorization Line Item quantity shipped (if
        any) to date. This value applies to Line Items having a corresponding
        line on a new Sales Order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Restock Charge Discount %</term>
      <listitem>
        <para><remark>findme</remark></para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales orders</primary>
          <secondary>line item pricing for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Net Unit Price</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Net Unit Price for the Sales Order Item. This
        information will be imported automatically for Return Authorizations
        linked to an original Sales Order. The browse button located to the
        right of the field leads to a Price List screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>The Price controls will be automatically disabled for Line Items
    having the following dispositions: Replace, Service, Ship.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Price UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The Price Unit of Measure is the same as the Selling UOM. If an
        Item has Selling UOMs defined, then the Item may be sold and priced in
        these alternate UOMs. If no Selling UOMs are defined, then the
        Inventory UOM will be used here by default.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Extended Price</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Extended Price. The Extended Price for a Line Item
        is based on the quantity ordered multiplied by the Net Unit
        Price.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Scheduled Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The scheduled date is the date when the Line Item quantity
        should be shipped. The user who enters the Line Item is responsible
        for determining the scheduled date. After entering the scheduled date,
        hit the TAB key on your keyboard to display values in the remaining
        display only fields.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Warranty</term>
      <listitem>
        <para><remark>findme</remark></para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>When entering Sales Orders you have the ability to view current
  availability for Line Items. You may also create replenishment Orders if
  they are needed.</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales orders</primary>
          <secondary>availability of items for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Availability</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to display Availability information for the Sales Order
        Item in the following categories:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>On Hand</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the current Quantity on Hand value.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Allocated</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the quantity allocated to current Sales Orders
              and/or Work Orders in the system. An Item is considered
              allocated to a Sales Order if a Sales Order Line Item exists for
              the Item--and that Line Item has not yet been issued to
              Shipping. An Item is considered allocated to a Work Order if the
              Item is a material requirement--and the material has not yet
              been issued to the Work Order. Once the current Sales Order Line
              Item is saved, the "Allocated" value will increase by the
              quantity ordered.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Unallocated</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the Quantity on Hand remaining after allocations
              have been accounted for, as in: QOH - Allocated Qty. =
              Unallocated Qty.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>On Order</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>If the Sales Order Item is a manufactured Item, the
              quantity ordered by current Work Orders will be displayed. If
              the Sales Order Item is a purchased Item, the quantity ordered
              by current Purchase Orders will be displayed.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Available</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the available quantity. Available quantity is
              determined using the following formula: Unallocated Qty. + On
              Order Qty. = Available Qty.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Lead Time</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the Item Site Lead Time for the specified Line
              Item.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
        <tip>
          <para>The "Show Availability" feature can be turned on or off by
          default at the system level. If the feature is turned on, the
          Availability totals will display only after a Scheduled Date has
          been entered for the Line Item.</para>
        </tip>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales orders</primary>
          <secondary>work orders generated by</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>work orders</primary>
          <secondary>generated by sales orders</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>purchase requests</primary>
          <secondary>generated by sales orders</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales orders</primary>
          <secondary>purchase requests generated by</secondary>
        </indexterm>Create Work Order</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>If the Line Item is a manufactured Item, select this option to
        automatically create a Work Order for the specified quantity. For
        make-to-order manufactured Items, this option will be selected
        automatically. A Work Order will be created to meet the Sales Order
        demand once you save the Line Item to the Order. An Item is designated
        as make-to-order if the "Stocked at" flag on the Item Site master is
        not selected. A Work Order created automatically from a Sales Order
        Line Item will assume the same Order Number as the Sales Order the
        Line Item is associated with--even if that Order Number has already
        been used by a previous Work Order.</para>
        <note>
          <para>For purchased Items, the option "Create Purchase Request" will
          appear instead. The displayed fields will resemble the fields shown
          when "Create Work Order" is visible. One difference is you will be
          given the option to override the purchase Price for the Line Item.
          If used, this one-time override will replace any Item Source
          Price(s) when the Purchase Request is converted to a Purchase Order
          Line Item.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>W/O Qty.</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The quantity ordered by the Sales Order Line Item will display
        here. If the Line Item is a purchased Item, the option "P/R Qty" will
        appear instead.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>W/O Due Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The scheduled date of the Sales Order Line Item will display
        here. If the Line Item is a purchased Item, the option "P/R Due Date"
        will appear instead.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>warehouses</primary>
          <secondary>for make-to-order</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales orders</primary>
          <secondary>supplying warehouses and</secondary>
        </indexterm>Supplying Whs.</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the Warehouse a corresponding Work Order would be
        supplied from. Work Orders may only be created for manufactured Items
        having a supplying Warehouse. Warehouses designated as "Supplied at"
        Warehouses in the Item Site master for an Item are considered
        supplying Warehouses. If no supplying Warehouse exists for an Item, a
        Work Order may not be created for the Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CLOSE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without creating a new Sales Order Line Item,
        returning you to the Sales Order header.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Creates the new Sales Order Line Item and adds it to the list of
        Sales Order Line Items. If "Create Work Order" is specified, the
        associated Work Order will also be created.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>PREVIOUS</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to view previous Line Items associated with the Sales
        Order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to create a new Sales Order Line Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL ITEM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to cancel the current Sales Order Line Item. Records of
        canceled Line Items will be retained for informational purposes. To
        view canceled Line Items associated with a Sales Order, select the
        "Show Canceled Line Items" option on the Sales Order header's "Line
        Items tab.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To view Costs or adjust Tax information for a Sales Order Line Item,
  select the "Detail" tab at the bottom of the screen, as shown below:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/returnAuthorizationItem_detail.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Return Authorization Line Item Detail</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When viewing Costs or adjusting Tax information for a Sales Order Line
  Item, you are presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Unit Cost (Inv. UOM)</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Standard Cost per unit based on the Inventory Unit
        of Measure.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>List Price</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the sales List Price per unit.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Customer Price</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Price given to the specified Customer. Special
        Customer Prices can be set for individual Customers or Customer Groups
        by using a Pricing Schedule.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales orders</primary>
          <secondary>discount percentages for</secondary>
        </indexterm>List Discount %</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the percentage discount off the List Price. Indicates
        the difference between the List Price for an Item and the Net Unit
        Price as a percentage. This is the margin between the Net Unit Price
        and the List Price.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Tax</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The following Tax options are available, should you need to
        override the Tax Selection settings for the Line Item:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Tax Type</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the Tax Type for the Sales Order Item. By default,
              the Item's Tax Type corresponding to the Sales Order's Tax
              Authority will be presented here. The link between Tax Types and
              Tax Authorities is made on the Item master. If the Item master
              does not have a Tax Type for the Sales Order's Tax Authority,
              then no Tax will be charged.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Tax Code</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the Tax Code to be applied to the Sales Order
              Item. By default, the Tax Code specified in the Tax Selection
              matrix will be displayed here. For a Tax Code to be used, the
              matrix must have an entry which matches both the Item's Tax Type
              definition and the Tax Authority specified on the Sales Order
              header. If no Tax Selection match exists, then no Tax Code will
              be used--meaning no Tax will be charged.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
        <tip>
          <para>The relationship between Tax Authorities, Tax Types, and Tax
          Codes is established in the Tax Selection matrix.</para>
        </tip>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Tax</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the amount of Tax to be charged for the Sales
              Order Line Item quantity. Sales Tax is calculated at the Sales
              Order Line Item level. To get a detailed view of the Tax
              calculation, click on the Tax link using your mouse.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To enter Notes related to a Sales Order Line Item, select the "Notes"
  tab at the bottom of the screen, as shown below:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/returnAuthorizationItem_comments.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Return Authorization Line Item Notes</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When adding Notes related to a Sales Order Line Item, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Notes</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        general Notes related to the Sales Order Line Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>If a Sales Order Item is marked to create a Work Order, the
    Production Notes for the created Work Order will contain the Sales Order
    Number, the Customer Name, and any additional Sales Order Line Item
    Notes.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>To define an alternate Cost of Sales Account for a Sales Order Line
  Item, select the "Accounting" tab at the bottom of the screen, as shown
  below:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/returnAuthorizationItem_accounts.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Return Authorization Line Item Accounting</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When defining an alternate Cost of Sales Account for a Sales Order
  Line Item, you are presented with the following options:</para>
  <para><remark>findme</remark></para>
  <para></para>
</section>