<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section537794" role="openmfg">
    <title>Run MPS by Planner Code</title>

    <para id="Para540542">When you run MPS by Planner Code, you are running
    the Master Production Scheduling (MPS) system. This utility creates firm
    Planned Orders to meet forecasted demand (i.e., from Production Plans) and
    also actual demand (i.e., from Sales Orders) for MPS Items. An Item is
    defined as an MPS Item on its Item master.</para>

    <para id="Para540655">By default, Planned Orders created by the MPS
    planning system will be firm when they are generated. This establishes
    them as a legitimate source of demand within the wider planning system.
    The firm-by-default nature of MPS Orders distinguishes them from MRP
    Orders, which must be manually firmed.</para>

    <para id="Para540596">The quantities for MPS Planned Orders will vary
    depending on the source of demand. The following considerations are used
    to identify the appropriate demand:</para>

    <orderedlist continuation="restarts" inheritnum="ignore">
      <listitem>
        <para id="Para540648">Actual demand quantity (i.e., from Sales Orders)
        will be used if the planned date for a Production Plan Item falls
        within the Demand Time Fence for that Item; forecasted demand is
        ignored within the Time Fence</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para id="Para540736">Outside the Demand Time Fence, the system will
        create Planned Orders for whichever demand source is greater--that is,
        actual demand or forecasted demand</para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>

    <tip>
      <para id="Para540522">You might consider running the MRP system after
      you run MPS. Running MRP after MPS will ensure you plan for the
      materials required to satisfy your MPS-driven demand.</para>
    </tip>

    <para id="Para540463">To run MPS by Planner Code, select the "Run MPS by
    Planner Code" option. The following screen will appear:</para>

    <para id="Para540378">
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
               <imagedata fileref="images/MS_Sched_runMPSPCode.png" id="Graphic540376"/>
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption540379">Run MPS by Planner Code</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
   </para>

    <note>
      <para id="Para541916">Only Items designated as MPS Items will have
      Planned Orders created for them when MPS is run. By default, MPS
      generates firm Planned Orders.</para>
    </note>

    <para id="Para541907">When running MPS by Planner Code, you are presented
    with the following options:</para>

    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para540750">All Planner Codes</term>

        <listitem>
            <para>Select to create firm Planned Orders for all Planner
          Codes.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para540751">Selected</term>

        <listitem>
            <para>Specify Planner Code you want to create firm Planned Orders
          for.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para554561">Pattern</term>

        <listitem>
            <para>Enter a Planner Code pattern to select a range of Planner
          Codes.</para>

            <para id="Para554695">Refine your search using Regular Expressions,
          as described in <xref endterm="Anchor77806" linkend="Anchor77806"/>
    FINDME
  "Topic: Pattern Matching with Regular
          Expressions".</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para554566">All Warehouses</term>

        <listitem>
            <para>Select to create firm Planned Orders by Planner Code for all
          Warehouses.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para540394">Selected</term>

        <listitem>
            <para>Specify Warehouse firm Planned Order by Planner Code should be
          created for.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para540395">Cutoff Date</term>

        <listitem>
            <para>Specify how far into the future the MPS run should look for
          demand.</para>

            <para id="Para540862">The forecast will be ignored if the planned
          date for a Production Plan Item falls within the Demand Time Fence
          for that Item. Outside the Demand Time Fence, the greater of actual
          or forecasted demand will be used.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>

    <tip>
      <para id="Para546234">If you schedule an MRP or MPS job submitted to the
      Batch Manager to run on a periodic basis--daily, weekly, monthly--the
      cutoff date used for the run will automatically be updated by the number
      of days in the specified reschedule interval (Day = +1, Week = +7, and
      Month = +30).</para>
    </tip>

    <para id="Para540399">To the far right of the screen, the following
    buttons are available:</para>

    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para540400">CANCEL</term>

        <listitem>
            <para>Closes the screen without creating firm Planned Orders by
          Planner Code, returning you to the application desktop.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term id="Para540401">CREATE</term>

        <listitem>
            <para>Creates firm Planned Orders by Planner Code, using the
          specified parameters.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry role="openmfg">
        <term id="Para540402">SUBMIT</term>

        <listitem>
            <para>Select to submit the MPS run to the Batch Manager. For
          additional information, see the <xref endterm="Anchor61009" linkend="Anchor61009"/>
    FINDME
  "Topic: Submitting Reports and Jobs to
          the Batch Manager".</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
  </section>