<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section519027">
  <title><anchor id="Anchor23923" role="Cross-Ref"
  xreflabel="23923: Heading2: New Sales Order" /> <indexterm
      significance="normal">
      <primary>sales orders</primary>
      <secondary>creating new</secondary>
    </indexterm>New Sales Order</title>
  <para>Creating a new Sales Order requires a detailed mix of Customer, Sales
  Representative, and Shipping information. To access the Sales Order area,
  select the "New Sales Order" option. The following screen will
  appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/SO_Ord_newSalesOrder.png"
                     id="Graphic523154" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption519033">Create New Sales Order</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <tip>
    <para>Be sure to close all Sales Order windows before exiting the system.
    This will prevent the creation of orphan Sales Order records.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>When creating a new Sales Order, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Order #</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x188e628">
        <para>Next available Sales Order Number will automatically display,
        unless your system requires you to enter Sales Order Numbers
        manually.</para>
        <para>Default values and input parameters for Sales Order Numbers are
        configurable at the system level.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Warehouse</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x188e670">
        <para>Specify the shipping Warehouse associated with the Sales
        Order.</para>
        <para>The Warehouse selected here acts as the default free on board
        (FOB) location. A Warehouse may be designated as a shipping Warehouse
        on the Warehouse master.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Order Date</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x188e6b8">
        <para>Displays current day's date.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Scheduled Date</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x188e700">
        <para>Displays the Order's earliest scheduled date.</para>
        <para>The scheduled date corresponds to the earliest scheduled date
        for an included Sales Order Item. Because Sales Orders may contain
        multiple Sales Order Items, the scheduled date indicates the most
        recent scheduled date. No scheduled date will display in the
        "Scheduled Date" field until a Sales Order Line Item has been created
        and a scheduled date assigned to it.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>pack dates</primary>
          <secondary>for sales orders</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales orders</primary>
          <secondary>pack dates for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Pack Date</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x188e7d8">
        <para>The pack date is the same date as the ship date. Because the
        field can be edited, you have the ability to change the pack date and
        make it different from the ship date.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Originated By</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x188e820">
        <para>Specify the origin of the Sales Order using the available
        options:</para>
        <para>Customer: Indicates the Order was originated by the
        Customer.</para>
        <para>Internet: Indicates the Order was originated by an Internet
        lead.</para>
        <para>Sales Rep.: Indicates the Order was originated by the Sales
        Representative.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>Sales Orders may not be entered for Customers whose credit status is
    either "On Credit Warning" or "On Credit Hold." Only users with special
    privileges may override these credit settings.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>From Quote</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x188e8b0">
        <para>If a Sales Order was converted from a Quote, the originating
        Quote Number will display here.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Customer #</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x188e8f8">
        <para>Enter the Customer Number of the Customer to be billed for the
        sale.</para>
        <para>The browse button located to the right of the field leads to a
        searchable Customers list. You may also access this list using the
        keyboard shortcut "CTRL + L". Once a Customer Number is entered, the
        Customer name and billing address will display. Select the "?" or "$"
        symbol next to the browse button to view Customer information for the
        specified Customer. If a Customer's credit is "In Good Standing," the
        button will feature a black question mark ("?") icon. If the icon
        turns to an orange dollar sign ("$"), the Customer's credit Status is
        "On Credit Warning." A red dollar sign ("$") indicates the Customer's
        credit Status is "On Credit Hold."</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>A valid Customer Number must be entered in the "Customer #" field
    before Line Items can be added to a Sales Order. If no valid Customer
    Number is entered, you will not be able to add Line Items to the Sales
    Order. Additionally, Sales Orders may only be entered for active
    Customers.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Cust. Type</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x188e988">
        <para>Displays the Customer Type for the specified Customer.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales orders</primary>
          <secondary>billing information for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Bill-To Name</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x188ea18">
        <para>Displays the Customer's Bill-To name.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Bill-To Phone</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x188ea60">
        <para>Displays the Customer's Bill-To phone number.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Address</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x188eaa8">
        <para>Displays the Customer's Bill-To Address. You may manually
        override the displayed Address information in the fields below--or use
        the browse button to select another Address.</para>
        <para>Street Address: The Customer's Bill-To street Address.</para>
        <para>City: The Customer's Bill-To city.</para>
        <para>State: The Customer's Bill-To state.</para>
        <para>Postal Code: The Customer's Bill-To Postal Code.</para>
        <para>Country: The Customer's Bill-To country.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Copy to Ship-to -\&gt;</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x188eaf0">
        <para>Select to copy contents of billing address into Ship-To address
        field.</para>
        <para>This option is enabled if the Customer master for the specified
        Customer indicates that free-form Ship-To's are allowed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Ship-To #</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x188eb38">
        <para>Enter the number of the preferred Ship-To Address.</para>
        <para>Customers may maintain multiple Ship-To Addresses. If the
        Customer master for the specified Customer indicates that free-form
        Ship-To's are allowed, then any address may be entered. If free-form
        Ship-To's are not allowed, then the Ship-To Address must be entered
        using the browse button located to the right of the field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales orders</primary>
          <secondary>ship-to details for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Ship-To Name</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x188ebc8">
        <para>Displays the name for the specified Ship-To.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Ship-To Phone</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1896200">
        <para>Displays the phone number for the specified Ship-To.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Address</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1896248">
        <para>Displays the specified Ship-To Address. You may manually
        override the displayed Address information in the fields below--or use
        the browse button to select another Address.</para>
        <para>Street Address: The specified Ship-To street Address.</para>
        <para>City: The specified Ship-To city.</para>
        <para>State: The specified Ship-To state.</para>
        <para>Postal Code: The specified Ship-To Postal Code.</para>
        <para>Country: The specified Ship-To country.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales representatives</primary>
          <secondary>commissions for</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales orders</primary>
          <secondary>commissions on</secondary>
        </indexterm>Sales Rep.</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1896320">
        <para>Specify the Sales Representative associated with the
        Order.</para>
        <para>Sales Representatives are linked to a Customer on the Customer
        master--either by a default setting or through the assignment of
        Ship-To Addresses. Each Ship-To Address may have a different Sales
        Representative associated with it. Consequently, the name of the Sales
        Representative appearing on the Sales Order header will be the same as
        specified for the Ship-To Address being used.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Commission</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1896368">
        <para>By default, the commission percentage recorded on the Customer
        master will be automatically entered in this field.</para>
        <para>If for some reason you select a non-default Sales Representative
        at Order entry, the commission rate will not change. To adjust the
        commission rate, you must make the change manually.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>tax authorities</primary>
          <secondary>for sales orders</secondary>
        </indexterm>Tax Authority</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18963f8">
        <para>Specify the Tax Authority associated with the Sales
        Order.</para>
        <para>The Tax Authority for the specified Ship-To Address will be
        entered here by default. Otherwise, the primary Tax Authority for the
        Customer will be entered. Ultimately, Tax is applied at the Line Item
        level--so the Tax Authority associated with an Item's Tax Type will be
        used.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales orders</primary>
          <secondary>setting terms for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Terms</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1896488">
        <para>Specify the billing Terms associated with the Order.</para>
        <para>By default, the Customer's standard billing Terms will appear in
        the field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>The option to associate a Project with a Sales Order will only be
    visible if your site is configured to use Projects.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Project #</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1896518">
        <para>Select a Project Number to associate with the Sales
        Order.</para>
        <para>If a Sales Order is created from a converted Quote--and the
        Quote had a Project Number associated with it--then the Project Number
        from the originating Quote will automatically be entered here. Once a
        Project Number is associated with a Sales Order, any Work Orders or
        Purchase Orders created by the Sales Order demand will automatically
        be linked to the same Project Number as the Sales Order. In this way,
        Sales Orders, Work Orders, and Purchase Orders may be linked to the
        same Project.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>If your site is configured to create Projects automatically whenever
    new Sales Orders or Quotes are entered, the Projects generated in this way
    will assume the number of the Sales Order or Quote which caused their
    creation.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Cust. PO #</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18965a8">
        <para>PO #: Enter a Customer Purchase Order Number, as needed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>You will be required to enter a Customer Purchase Order Number for
    Customers who require them. If required, duplicate numbers will only be
    allowed if the Customer uses blanket Purchase Orders. All Customer
    requirements are specified on the Customer master.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>F.O.B.</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1896638">
        <para>Enter free on board (FOB) Terms for the Order. By default, FOB.
        Terms entered on the Shipping Warehouse master will appear in this
        field. The default Terms may be changed during Order entry--and also
        at later stages during the billing cycle.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Ship Complete</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1896680">
        <para>Select to require that all Sales Order Line Item quantities be
        issued to Shipping before the Order is shipped.</para>
        <para>This feature is designed to prevent partial shipments. If
        selected, users will be prevented from shipping the Order unless all
        Line Item quantities have been issued to Shipping. If not selected,
        partial shipments for the Order will be allowed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Ship Via</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18966c8">
        <para>The preferred Ship Via method for the Customer will appear in
        the field.</para>
        <para>You may change the default Ship Via using the list. You may also
        enter a free-form Ship Via simply by typing the name of the Ship Via
        into the field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>The system supports up-to-date shipment tracking with links to the
    websites of many leading shipping companies (i.e., "Ship Vias").</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>hold types</primary>
          <secondary>for sales orders</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales orders</primary>
          <secondary>hold types for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Hold Type</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18967e8">
        <para>Specify a hold type (if any) from the available options:</para>
        <para>None: Indicates no hold is applied, meaning the Order may be
        processed and shipped.</para>
        <para>Shipping: Indicates a Shipping hold has been placed on the
        Order. Users who attempt to ship an Order on Shipping hold will be
        prevented from doing so.</para>
        <para>Packing: Indicates a Packing hold has been placed on the Order.
        Users who attempt to issue stock to Shipping for an Order on Packing
        hold will be prevented from doing so.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>Shipping defaults specified on the Customer master will transfer to
    the Sales Order header when a new Sales Order is entered for a
    Customer.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales orders</primary>
          <secondary>shipping charges on</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>shipping</primary>
          <secondary>charges on sales orders</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales orders</primary>
          <secondary>shipping forms on</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>shipping forms</primary>
          <secondary>selecting on sales orders</secondary>
        </indexterm>Shipping Chgs.</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1896998">
        <para>Specify the Shipping charges associated with the Order.</para>
        <para>The preferred Shipping Charges Type for the Customer will appear
        in the field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Shipping Form</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18969e0">
        <para>Specify the Shipping Form associated with the Order.</para>
        <para>The preferred Shipping Form for the Customer will appear in the
        field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>At the top of the screen, the following buttons are available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CLEAR</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1896a4c">
        <para>Select to clear the current Sales Order screen without closing
        the screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE AND ADD TO PACKING LIST BATCH</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1896a94">
        <para>Creates the Sales Order, saves it, and adds it to the list of
        Orders available for printing on the Packing List Batch.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1896adc">
        <para>Creates the Sales Order and saves the Sales Order
        information.</para>
        <para>The SAVE button must be selected in order to save the Sales
        Order record. It is not enough to save Sales Order Line Item
        information. The Sales Order header must also be saved. If your system
        is configured to prompt for printing on SAVE, then you will be
        presented with additional processing options after this button is
        selected.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1896b24">
        <para>Closes the screen without creating a new Sales Order, returning
        you to the application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>sales orders</primary>
      <secondary>adding line items to</secondary>
    </indexterm>To create or modify Sales Order Line Items, select the "Line
  Items" tab at the top of the "Sales Order" screen. The following screen will
  appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/SO_Ord_newOrdLineItem.png"
                     id="Graphic533771" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption525533">Sales Order Line Items</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When creating or modifying Sales Order Line Items, you are presented
  with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Line Items</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1896c44">
        <para>Display lists Line Items for this Sales Order.</para>
        <para>A valid Customer Number must be entered in the "Customer #"
        field before Line Items can be added to the Order. The
        Shipping-related columns will not be visible if the system is
        configured to hide Shipping options at Sales Order entry. However, if
        the Shipping options are enabled, the Line Items may display in
        different colors, depending on their scheduling. If the Scheduled Date
        for an unshipped Line Item is in the future, the line will display in
        green text. If the Scheduled Date for an unshipped Line Item is not in
        the future, the line will display in red text. Once shipped, all Line
        Items revert to black text.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>Sales Order Line Items may exist in any of the following
    statuses:</para>
    <para>"O" = Open</para>
    <para>"C" = Closed</para>
    <para>"X" = Cancelled</para>
    <para>"R" = Ready for Shipment (i.e., quantity available)</para>
    <para>"I" = Invoiced</para>
    <para>"P" = Partially-invoiced</para>
    <para>"H" = On credit hold</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Require sufficient Inventory</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1896cd4">
        <para>Select to ensure you have enough Quantity on Hand of a Line Item
        prior to issuing Stock to Shipping.</para>
        <para>If selected, this option will prevent you from issuing Line Item
        quantity to Shipping if doing so would force Quantity on Hand for the
        Item Site to fall below zero. Not selecting this option means issuing
        Stock to Shipping may drive Item Site Quantity on Hand negative. This
        option will not be visible if the system is configured to hide
        Shipping options at Sales Order entry.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Show Canceled Line Items</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1896d1c">
        <para>Select to include in the Line Items display Sales Order Line
        Items which have been specifically canceled.</para>
        <para>Displaying canceled Line Items can provide useful Customer and
        Order history information.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>$ At Shipping</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1896d64">
        <para>Displays the monetary value of Sales Order Line Items at
        Shipping.</para>
        <para>The shipment value represents the total of the extended prices
        for all Items included in the Shipment. The amount does not include
        freight or Tax. This displayed information will not be visible if the
        system is configured to hide Shipping options at Sales Order
        entry.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>$ Margin</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1896dac">
        <para>Displays the total profit margin for the Order.</para>
        <para>The profit margin is based on the following formula:</para>
        <para>Order Subtotal - Total Standard Costs for all Line Items</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Subtotal</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1896df4">
        <para>Displays the subtotal for the Sales Order Line Items.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Tax</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1896e3c">
        <para>Displays the total amount of Tax to be charged on the Sales
        Order.</para>
        <para>Sales Tax is calculated at the Sales Order Line Item level. The
        Tax amount displayed here represents the total for all Line Item Tax
        amounts. To get a detailed view of the Tax calculation, click on the
        Tax link using your mouse.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Misc. Charge Amount</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1896e84">
        <para>Enter the amount of any miscellaneous charge. Examples of
        miscellaneous charges include palletization costs, co-op refund, etc.
        Before entering a miscellaneous charge amount, you must first assign
        the charge to a Sales Account and also enter a description of the
        charge.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>If you do not use Miscellaneous Charges at your site, you can hide
    these fields so they are not visible when entering Sales Orders. To do so,
    simply select the "Hide Misc. Charges" option in the system-level
    configuration.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Misc. Charge Description</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1896f14">
        <para>Enter a description to identify the miscellaneous charge.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Misc. Charge Sales Account</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1896f5c">
        <para>Enter a Sales Account to assign the miscellaneous charge
        to.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Allocated C/Ms</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1896fa4">
        <para>Displays the monetary value of any open Credit Memos and/or
        Credit Card charges which have been specifically allocated to the
        Sales Order.</para>
        <para>If your system is configured to automatically allocate open
        Credit Memo balances to new Sales Orders, then the monetary value of
        these allocated Credit Memos--plus any Credit Card charges applied to
        the Order--will display here. If your system is not configured to
        automatically allocate Credit Memos, then this field will display only
        the monetary value of any Credit Card charges applied to the Order--if
        any. The automatic allocation of Credit Memos helps reduce Customer
        credit balances by ensuring that Customer credits are consumed when
        new Sales Orders are entered. Any available, open Credit Memos are
        eligible for allocation. The allocation of available Credit Memos
        occurs only once--when a Sales Order is saved for the first time.
        Subsequent saves will not result in additional allocations. Credit
        Memos which have been allocated to a Sales Order are applied at the
        point when the Invoice resulting from the Sales Order is posted. Once
        the full balance of a Credit Memo has been applied, the Credit Memo is
        then closed. The printed Invoice the Customer receives will indicate
        whether Credit Memos have been applied. In addition, the total due
        from the Customer will be automatically adjusted to reflect any
        applied credits.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>The allocation of available Credit Memos occurs only once--when a
    Sales Order is saved for the first time. Subsequent saves will not result
    in additional allocations.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Outstanding C/Ms</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18a3224">
        <para>Displays the total monetary value of all unallocated Credit
        Memos for the Customer.</para>
        <para>If no Credit Memos are allocated to the Sales Order, then the
        amount displayed here will be equal to the Customer's total open
        Credit Memo balance. If Credit Memos are allocated to the Order, then
        the remaining Credit Memo balance will be displayed. The open Credit
        Memo balance is considered when calculating the outstanding balance
        due for the Order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Authorized CC Payments</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18a326c">
        <para>Displays the monetary value of any credit card
        pre-authorizations for the Order.</para>
        <para>Credit Card charges may be pre-authorized using the options
        found under the "Payment" tab. When a Credit Card charge is
        pre-authorized, the authorization is stored and may later be posted as
        a completed charge using the A/R Workbench.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Freight Weight</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18a32b4">
        <para>Displays the combined weight of all Sales Order Line
        Items.</para>
        <para>Freight weight represents the sum of an Item's product weight
        and packaging weight, both of which are defined on the Item master.
        The per unit freight weight multiplied by the quantity per gives you
        the Line Item freight weight. The sum of all Line Item freight weights
        is the combined weight for the Order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>freight</primary>
          <secondary>on sales orders</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales orders</primary>
          <secondary>freight charges on</secondary>
        </indexterm>Freight</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18a338c">
        <para>Enter the amount of freight charge to be added to the specified
        Order. Freight charges may be entered during the creation or
        modification of a Sales Order--or at the time of shipment.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Total</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18a33d4">
        <para>Displays the total amount of the Sales Order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>Any Sales Order Line Item may be shipped--even if the Item or Item
    Site in question becomes inactive after the Sales Order has been
    created.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Outstanding Balance</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18a3464">
        <para>Displays the projected total due for the Sales Order.</para>
        <para>The outstanding balance represents the amount the Customer would
        owe if all allocated and outstanding Credit Memos and Credit Card
        pre-authorizations were applied to the Order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>At the top of and to the far right of the screen, the following
  buttons are available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CLEAR</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18a34d0">
        <para>Select to clear the contents of the current Sales Order and open
        a fresh, new Sales Order for Order entry.</para>
        <para>The Order Number of the Order being cleared will display next to
        the CLEAR button.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>Selecting the CLEAR button on the Sales Order header does not delete
    any information which has been saved previously.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18a3560">
        <para>Saves the Sales Order information.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18a35a8">
        <para>Closes the screen without creating a new Sales Order, returning
        you to the application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18a35f0">
        <para>Opens screen for creating a new Sales Order Line Item. Mac users
        may use COMMAND + N to enter a new Line Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>EDIT</term>
      <listitem id="salesOrderEDIT">
        <para>Enables you to edit highlighted Sales Order Line Items. The edit
        screen is the same as that for creating a new Sales Order Line
        Item--except that when editing, the fields will contain Sales Order
        Line Item information. Double-clicking on a Sales Order Line Item will
        also bring you to the editing screen. Mac users may use COMMAND + E to
        edit an existing Line Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CLOSE</term>
      <listitem id="salesOrderCLOSE">
        <para>Highlight a Sales Order Line Item and then select this button to
        close the Sales Order Line Item. If the highlighted Line Item is
        already closed, this button will revert to an OPEN button, which may
        be used to open the closed Line Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>DELETE</term>
      <listitem id="salesOrderDELETE">
        <para>Highlight a Sales Order Line Item and then select this button to
        remove the Sales Order Line Item from the list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>shipping</primary>
          <secondary>issuing stock to</secondary>
        </indexterm>ISSUE STOCK</term>
      <listitem id="salesOrderISSUESTOCK">
        <para>Highlight a Sales Order Line Item and then select this button to
        issue quantity to Shipping. This button will not be visible if the
        system is configured to hide Shipping options at Sales Order
        entry.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>You may select multiple Line Items for issuing to Shipping by
    highlighting them using your mouse--or a combination of your mouse and
    either the SHIFT or CTRL keys.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>ISSUE LINE BAL.</term>
      <listitem id="salesOrderISSUELINEBAL">
        <para>Highlight a Sales Order Line Item and then select this button to
        issue the balance of the Line Item quantity to Shipping. This button
        will not be visible if the system is configured to hide Shipping
        options at Sales Order entry.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>Right-clicking on an Item in the Line Items list enables you to select
  from the following menu options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Edit Line</term>
      <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                  xpointer="element(salesOrderEDIT)" />
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Close Line</term>
      <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                  xpointer="element(salesOrderCLOSE)" />
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Delete Line</term>
      <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                  xpointer="element(salesOrderDELETE)" />
    </varlistentry>
    <xi:include href="../supportfiles/rightclick.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(rightclickReturnStock)" />
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="salesOrderISSUESTOCK">Issue Stock</term>
      <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                  xpointer="element(salesOrderISSUESTOCK)" />
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Issue Line Balance</term>
      <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                  xpointer="element(salesOrderISSUELINEBAL)" />
    </varlistentry>
    <xi:include href="../widgets/xtreewidget.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(xtreewidget.menu.exportcontents)" />
  </variablelist>
  <para>The Shipping-related options will not be visible if the system is
  configured to hide Shipping options at Sales Order entry. Also, if a
  highlighted Line Item is Closed, the following additional option will be
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <xi:include href="../supportfiles/rightclick.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(rightclickOpenLine)" />
  </variablelist>
  <para>Order Notes added to a Sales Order are used for internal purposes
  only. To add Notes to a Sales Order, select the "Order Notes" tab at the top
  of the "Sales Order" screen. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/SO_Ord_newNote.png" id="Graphic525485" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption525417">Sales Order Notes</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When adding Notes to a Sales Order, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Order Notes</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b6958">
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        general Notes related to the Sales Order. These Notes are for internal
        use only.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b69c4">
        <para>Saves the Order Note.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b6a0c">
        <para>Closes the screen without creating an Order Note, returning you
        to the application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To add Comments related to a Sales Order, select the "Comments" tab.
  The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/SO_Ord_newComment.png" id="Graphic585532" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption585535">Sales Order Comments</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When adding Comments related to a Sales Order, you are presented with
  the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Comments</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b6ae4">
        <para>Display lists Comments for the specified Order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b6b50">
        <para>Opens screen for creating a new Comment.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>VIEW</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b6b98">
        <para>Highlight a Comment and then select this button to reach a
        read-only view of the Comment.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To create a Sales Order Comment, select the NEW button. The following
  screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/CommentNew.png" id="Graphic597083" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption597086">Create New Comment</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Comment Type</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b6c70">
        <para>Specify one of the following Comment Types from the drop-down
        list: ChangeLog or General.</para>
        <para>Comment Types are used to categorize Comments. Once you have
        specified a Comment Type, you may type your Comment in the main text
        area. The text area features word-wrapping and scroll-bar support for
        longer Comments.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b6cdc">
        <para>Closes the screen without creating a new Comment, returning you
        to the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b6d24">
        <para>Creates the Comment and adds it to the list of Order
        Comments.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>Shipping Notes are drawn from the Customer master--specifically from
  the "Shipping Notes" tab on the Ship-To Address master. The Notes may vary
  depending on the Ship-To Address specified for the Order. These Notes
  provide a mechanism for transferring shipping information from the Customer
  master to the Sales Order. To view Sales Order Shipping Notes, select the
  "Shipping Notes" tab at the top of the "Sales Order" screen. The following
  screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/SO_Ord_newShipNote.png"
                     id="Graphic623121" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption623124">Sales Order Shipping Notes</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When viewing or editing Shipping Notes for a Sales Order, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Shipping Notes</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b6dfc">
        <para>While Shipping Notes content may originate from the Customer
        master, you can edit the Notes to fit the requirements of an Order.
        This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b6e68">
        <para>Saves the Shipping Note.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b6eb0">
        <para>Closes the screen without creating a Shipping Note, returning
        you to the application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>If your system is configured to use Credit Cards, the "Payment" tab
    will be visible. This tab will not be visible if your system is not
    configured to use Credit Cards.</para>
  </note>
  <para><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>credit cards</primary>
      <secondary>sales orders and</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>sales orders</primary>
      <secondary>credit cards and</secondary>
    </indexterm>To authorize or charge Customer Credit Cards, select the
  "Payment" tab at the top of the "Sales Order" screen. The following screen
  will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/SO_Ord_newPayment.png" id="Graphic624029" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption624032">Customer Credit Card Payment</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When authorizing or charging Customer Credit Cards, you are presented
  with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Payment</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b703c">
        <para>Display lists Credit Card information for the specified
        Customer.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b70a8">
        <para>Opens screen for entering new Credit Card information for the
        Customer.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>EDIT</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b70f0">
        <para>Enables you to edit highlighted Credit Cards. The edit screen is
        the same as that for entering new Credit Card information--except that
        when editing, the fields will contain Credit Card information.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>VIEW</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b7138">
        <para>Highlight a Credit Card and then select this button to reach a
        read-only view of the "Edit" screen. Double-clicking on a Credit Card
        will also bring you to the view screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>MOVE UP</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b7180">
        <para>Highlight a Credit Card and then select this button to move the
        Credit Card up in the sequence of Credit Cards.</para>
        <para>Sequence numbers are automatically adjusted to reflect the
        change in position.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>MOVE DOWN</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b71c8">
        <para>Highlight a Credit Card and then select this button to move the
        Credit Card down the sequence of Credit Cards.</para>
        <para>Sequence numbers are automatically adjusted to reflect the
        change in position.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>AUTHORIZE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18be000">
        <para>After entering an amount below, highlight an active Credit Card
        and then select this button to pre-authorize the Credit Card charge
        for the amount specified.</para>
        <para>Pre-authorized Credit Card charges will be displayed in the
        "Authorized CC Payments" field on the "Line Items" tab. After a Credit
        Card charge has been pre-authorized, the charge may then be
        post-authorized using the A/R Workbench--thereby completing the Credit
        Card transaction.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CHARGE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18be048">
        <para>After entering an amount below, highlight an active Credit Card
        and then select this button to charge the Credit Card for the amount
        specified.</para>
        <para>When a Credit Card is charged, both a Credit Memo and a Cash
        Receipt are posted for the charge amount. The total due from the
        Customer will be automatically adjusted on the Invoice to reflect the
        amount of any Credit Card charges. If, by chance, you charge a
        Customer's Credit Card but fail to save the Sales Order, the link
        between the Order and the charge will be broken; however, the
        transactions resulting from the charge will remain in the
        system.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Amount</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18be090">
        <para>Enter the amount of the Credit Card pre-authorization or charge.
        By default, the outstanding balance due will be displayed here.
        However, you may edit the default amount.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CVV Code</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18be0d8">
        <para>Enter the Card Verification Value (CVV) Code found on the back
        of the specified Credit Card. This may be an optional feature at your
        site. Contact your Systems Administrator for details.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <xi:include href="salesOrderItem.xml"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
              xpointer="element(/1)" />
</section>