<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="salesOrderItem">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>sales orders</primary>
      <secondary>adding line items to</secondary>
    </indexterm>Sales Order Item</title>
  <para>To add a new Sales Order Line Item, select the NEW button. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/SO_Ord_newSOItem.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create New Sales Order Line Item</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When creating a new Sales Order Line Item, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Order #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Sales Order Number specified in the "Sales Order"
        screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Line #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Line Item Number for the current Line Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the Item Number of the Item you want to sell. The Item
        list will contain sold Items available for purchase by the specified
        Customer. The list of available Items may vary from Customer to
        Customer, depending on how Pricing Schedules are implemented at your
        site. Once an Item Number is entered, the Inventory Unit of Measure
        and Item description will automatically appear.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Customer P/N</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Customer Part Number (i.e., Item Alias) that
        corresponds to the Item Number entered in the Item Number field. The
        Customer Part Number will display only if you enter an Item Alias in
        the Item Number field. To enter an Item Alias, place the cursor in the
        Item Number field and then use the keyboard shortcut "CTRL + A". After
        you have entered a valid Item Alias, hit the TAB key. A list of Items
        that use the specified Item Alias will be displayed. Select the
        desired Item from the list. The Item Alias will display as the
        Customer Part Number. Item Aliases are defined on the Item
        master.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Substitute for</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Optional selection used solely for gathering information related
        to Sales Order Line Item substitutions. This feature can be used, for
        example, to gather information about Inventory shortages or Customer
        first preferences. There is no impact on the system of using this
        feature. Its function is simply to store information in the database,
        where it may be accessed for reporting purposes.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>warehouses</primary>
          <secondary>sold from for sales orders</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales orders</primary>
          <secondary>selling warehouses for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Sold from Whs.</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the Warehouse the Sales Order Item is sold from. Items
        may be supplied to Sales Orders from multiple Item Sites. After an
        Item Number is entered above, the system checks for available Item
        Sites for the Item. Any Item Sites having the "Sold from" flag set on
        them will be selectable from this Warehouse list. By default, the Item
        Site having the highest Ranking will be selected as the first
        available Warehouse. If more than one Item Site share a Ranking of
        "1," the Warehouses will be sorted in alphabetical order. Item Site
        Rankings are set on the Item Site master.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>If a preferred Selling Warehouse is specified for the Customer, then
    that Warehouse will be selected here by default. If the preferred Selling
    Warehouse is not selected--and you think it should be--verify that the
    Item Site master for the Line Item in question is marked as a "Sold from"
    Warehouse.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. Ordered</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the quantity of the specified Item to be ordered. The
        quantity ordered for sold Items is measured in the Item's Inventory
        UOM.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>The Quantity Ordered for sold Items is based on the Inventory UOM.
    But the Price is based on the Price UOM. Whenever these two UOMs are not
    identical, the Extended Price for a Line Item will be based on the
    following formula:</para>
    <para>(Qty. Ordered) x (Price/Inv. Ratio) x (Net Unit Price)</para>
    <para>If for some reason the Prices don"t look correct, check the Item
    master for the Line Item in question. It may be that the Inventory and
    Price UOMs do not exist in a 1:1 relationship.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales orders</primary>
          <secondary>line item pricing for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Net Unit Price</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Unit Price for the Sales Order Item. By default,
        the system will choose the lower of the following two Prices: A) The
        most-specific Pricing Schedule Assignment or B) any Sale in effect at
        the time of Order entry. The specificity of Pricing Schedule
        Assignments is determined in the following descending order: By
        Customer Ship-To Address (most specific), by Customer, by Customer
        Type, by Customer Type pattern, by all Customers. The browse button
        located to the right of the field leads to a Price List screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>The system can be configured to prevent users from editing the Net
    Unit Price. If your system is configured that way, the Net Unit Price
    field will not be editable.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Extended Price</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Extended Price. The Extended Price for a Line Item
        is based on the quantity ordered multiplied by the Net Unit
        Price.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Scheduled Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The scheduled date is the date when the Line Item should be
        Shipped. The user who enters the Line Item is responsible for
        determining the scheduled date. After entering the scheduled date, hit
        the TAB key on your keyboard to display values in the remaining
        display only fields.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>The Sales Order Item having the earliest scheduled date will
    determine the ship date for the Sales Order.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Tax Type</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the Tax Type for the Sales Order Item. By default, the
        Item's Tax Type corresponding to the Sales Order's Tax Authority will
        be presented here. The link between Tax Types and Tax Authorities is
        made on the Item master. If the Item master does not have a Tax Type
        for the Sales Order's Tax Authority, then no Tax will be
        charged.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Tax Code</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the Tax Code to be applied to the Sales Order Item. By
        default, the Tax Code specified in the Tax Selection matrix will be
        displayed here. For a Tax Code to be used, the matrix must have an
        entry which matches both the Item's Tax Type definition and the Tax
        Authority specified on the Sales Order header. If no Tax Selection
        match exists, then no Tax Code will be used--meaning no Tax will be
        charged.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>The relationship between Tax Authorities, Tax Types, and Tax Codes
    is established in the Tax Selection matrix.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Tax</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the amount of Tax to be charged for the Sales Order
        Line Item quantity. Sales Tax is calculated at the Sales Order Line
        Item level. To get a detailed view of the Tax calculation, click on
        the Tax link using your mouse.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales orders</primary>
          <secondary>availability of items for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Show Availability</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to display Availability information for the Sales Order
        Item in the following categories:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>On Hand</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the current Quantity on Hand value.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Allocated</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the quantity allocated to current Sales Orders
              and/or Work Orders in the system. An Item is considered
              allocated to a Sales Order if a Sales Order Line Item exists for
              the Item--and that Line Item has not yet been issued to
              Shipping. An Item is considered allocated to a Work Order if the
              Item is a material requirement--and the material has not yet
              been issued to the Work Order. Once the current Sales Order Line
              Item is saved, the "Allocated" value will increase by the
              quantity ordered.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Unallocated</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the Quantity on Hand remaining after allocations
              have been accounted for, as in: QOH - Allocated Qty. =
              Unallocated Qty.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>On Order</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>If the Sales Order Item is a manufactured Item, the
              quantity ordered by current Work Orders will be displayed. If
              the Sales Order Item is a purchased Item, the quantity ordered
              by current Purchase Orders will be displayed.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Available</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the available quantity. Available quantity is
              determined using the following formula: Unallocated Qty. + On
              Order Qty. = Available Qty.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>The "Show Availability" feature can be turned on or off by default
    at the system level. If the feature is turned on, the Availability totals
    will display only after a Scheduled Date has been entered for the Line
    Item.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Pricing UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Price UOM for the Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Ratio</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The ratio displayed here is the Price/Inventory UOM ratio, which
        is defined in the Item master for an Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Unit Cost</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Standard Cost per unit.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>List Price</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the sales List Price per unit.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Customer Price</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Price given to the specified Customer. Special
        Customer Prices can be set for individual Customers or Customer Groups
        by using a Pricing Schedule.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales orders</primary>
          <secondary>discount percentages for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Discount % from List</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the percentage discount off the List Price. Indicates
        the difference between the List Price for an Item and the Net Unit
        Price as a percentage. This is the margin between the Net Unit Price
        and the List Price.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Discount % from Cust</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify here and apply any discount for specified Customer for
        this Sales Order. This is a discount off the regular Customer Price,
        obtained either from the Customer master or a Pricing Schedule.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. Shipped to Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Shipped to Date: Displays the total quantity shipped of the
        specified Line Item to date.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales orders</primary>
          <secondary>work orders generated by</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>work orders</primary>
          <secondary>generated by sales orders</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>purchase requests</primary>
          <secondary>generated by sales orders</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales orders</primary>
          <secondary>purchase requests generated by</secondary>
        </indexterm>Create Work Order</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>If the Line Item is a manufactured Item, select this option to
        automatically create a Work Order for the specified quantity. For
        make-to-order manufactured Items, this option will be selected
        automatically. A Work Order will be created to meet the Sales Order
        demand once you save the Line Item to the Order. An Item is designated
        as make-to-order if the "Stocked at" flag on the Item Site master is
        not selected. A Work Order created automatically from a Sales Order
        Line Item will assume the same Order Number as the Sales Order the
        Line Item is associated with--even if that Order Number has already
        been used by a previous Work Order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>For purchased Items, the option "Create Purchase Request" will
    appear instead. The displayed fields will resemble the fields shown when
    "Create Work Order" is visible. One difference is you will be given the
    option to override the purchase Price for the Line Item. If used, this
    one-time override will replace any Item Source Price(s) when the Purchase
    Request is converted to a Purchase Order Line Item.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>W/O Qty.</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The quantity ordered by the Sales Order Line Item will display
        here. If the Line Item is a purchased Item, the option "P/R Qty" will
        appear instead.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>W/O Due Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The scheduled date of the Sales Order Line Item will display
        here. If the Line Item is a purchased Item, the option "P/R Due Date"
        will appear instead.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>warehouses</primary>
          <secondary>for make-to-order</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales orders</primary>
          <secondary>supplying warehouses and</secondary>
        </indexterm>Supplying Whs.</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the Warehouse a corresponding Work Order would be
        supplied from. Work Orders may only be created for manufactured Items
        having a supplying Warehouse. Warehouses designated as "Supplied at"
        Warehouses in the Item Site master for an Item are considered
        supplying Warehouses. If no supplying Warehouse exists for an Item, a
        Work Order may not be created for the Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>If an Item has Characteristics associated with it, you have the option
  of linking those Characteristics to a Sales Order Line Item. And, in the
  case where Sales Order demand automatically generates either a Purchase
  Request or a Work Order, the Characteristics defined here will be inherited
  by those subsequent Orders.</para>
  <tip>
    <para>You can link Characteristics and Values to an Item by using the Item
    master. Once entered, these Characteristics and Values will be available
    to users entering Sales Order Line Items.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>When selecting or editing Characteristics for a Sales Order Line Item,
  you are presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the name of any Item Characteristics associated with
        the Item. Characteristics defined as Item Characteristics may be
        associated with Items on the Item master.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Value</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the default Value associated with an Item
        Characteristic, but permits you to specify an alternate Value. When
        associating Characteristic Values with a Sales Order Line Item, you
        have four options: 1) Select the default Value; 2) select an alternate
        pre-defined Value; 3) manually enter a new Value in place of the
        pre-defined Value; or 4) make no selection. Making no selection means
        the Characteristics will not be associated with the Sales Order Line
        Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CLOSE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without creating a new Sales Order Line Item,
        returning you to the Sales Order header.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Creates the new Sales Order Line Item and adds it to the list of
        Sales Order Line Items. If "Create Work Order" is specified, the
        associated Work Order will also be created.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>PREVIOUS</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to view previous Line Items associated with the Sales
        Order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to create a new Sales Order Line Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL ITEM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to cancel the current Sales Order Line Item. Records of
        canceled Line Items will be retained for informational purposes. To
        view canceled Line Items associated with a Sales Order, select the
        "Show Canceled Line Items" option on the Sales Order header's "Line
        Items tab.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To enter Notes related to a Sales Order Line Item, select the "Notes"
  tab at the bottom of the screen, as shown below:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/SO_Ord_soItemNotes.png"
                     />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Sales Order Line Item Notes</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When adding Notes related to a Sales Order Line Item, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Notes</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        general Notes related to the Sales Order Line Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>If a Sales Order Item is marked to create a Work Order, the
    Production Notes for the created Work Order will contain the Sales Order
    Number, the Customer Name, and any additional Sales Order Line Item
    Notes.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>To add Comments related to a Sales Order Line Item, select the
  "Comments" tab. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/SO_Ord_soItemComm.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Sales Order Line Item Comments</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <note>
    <para>Whenever Sales Order Line Items are created or their quantities are
    changed, the system will automatically generate a Comment, which will
    appear in the list of Line Item Comments.</para>
  </note>
  <para>When adding Comments related to a Sales Order Line Item, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Comments</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists Comments for the specified Line Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Opens screen for creating a new Comment. Sales Order Line Item
        Comments may only be added after the Line Item has been saved to the
        Sales Order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>VIEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a Comment and then select this button to reach a
        read-only view of the Comment.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To create a Sales Order Line Item Comment, select the NEW button. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/CommentNew.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create New Comment</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Comment Type</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify one of the following Comment Types from the drop-down
        list: ChangeLog or General. Comment Types are used to categorize
        Comments. Once you have specified a Comment Type, you may type your
        Comment in the main text area. The text area features word-wrapping
        and scroll-bar support for longer Comments.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without creating a new Comment, returning you
        to the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Creates the Comment and adds it to the list of Order
        Comments.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>If the Sales Order Line Item is a manufactured Item, you have the
  ability to view Pending Availability for any of its component Items. To view
  the Pending Availability for Sales Order Line Item component Items, select
  the "Pending Availability" tab, as shown below:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/SO_Ord_soItemPendAvail.png"
                     />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Pending Availability for Component
        Items</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When displaying Pending Availability for component Items, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <note>
    <para>The "Pending Availability" tab features details related to component
    Items and so only applies if a Sales Order Line Item is a manufactured
    Item. If a Line Item is not manufactured, Pending Availability does not
    apply.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Show Pending Availability as Indented BOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to display Pending Availability as an indented Bill of
        Materials.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Pending Availability</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays Pending Availability for component Items associated
        with sold manufactured Items. If you choose the "Show Pending
        Availability as Indented BOM" option, the information will be
        displayed in a nested list--with a plus ("+") sign located to the far
        left of the screen next to each line that may be expanded to lower
        levels. By clicking your mouse on a plus sign, you reveal lower levels
        of information related to the Line Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>Keep in mind that Pending Availability in this case is not the same
    as Available to Promise. This view to Pending Availability reflects
    current Inventory Levels--it is not a time-phased view of
    Availability.</para>
  </tip>
  <xi:include href="priceList.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
              xpointer="element(/1)" />
</section>
