<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2008 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section955847" role="standard">
  <title>Schedule Server Maintenance</title>
  <para>The server maintenance utility is designed to perform automated
  maintenance on your server. Server maintenance should be performed on a
  regular basis to ensure the smooth operation of your server. </para>
  <note>
    <para>When server maintenance is performed, a VACUUM FULL ANALYZE
    operation is run on your server, followed by a REINDEX. The user who
    schedules server maintenance must be a superuser (i.e., have the ability
    to create system users). For more information on the VACUUM, ANALYZE, and
    REINDEX operations, visit the PostgreSQL website at <ulink
    id="Hypertext956137"
    url="http://www.postgresql.com">http://www.postgresql.com</ulink>.</para>
  </note>
  <para>To run the server maintenance utility, select the "Schedule Server
  Maintenance" option. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/schedServerMaint.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Schedule Server Maintenance</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When scheduling server maintenance, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Action</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the name of the action to be performed by the Batch
        Manager.</para>
        <para>In this case, the name of the action is
        serverMaintenance.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Response Email</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>By default, the email address of the logged-in user will be
        entered here. This address may be edited or changed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Scheduled</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select one of the following Schedule options:</para>
        <para>ASAP: Select to have the job run as soon as possible.</para>
        <para>Scheduled: Schedule a date and time to run the job. Specify a
        date in the first field using a standard date format. Use the arrow
        buttons in the second field to specify a time of day.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>When a job is submitted to the Batch Manager with a scheduled time
    of ASAP, the Batch Manager sets the scheduled time to the current time.
    However, a job will not necessarily be run immediately if it is scheduled
    for the current time. Any pre-existing jobs with scheduled times prior to
    the current time must be completed first. In other words, ASAP jobs will
    not necessarily be run immediately. Previously scheduled jobs will be run
    first.</para>
  </note>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without performing server maintenance,
        returning you to the application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SUBMIT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to submit requested action to the Batch Manager for
        processing. For additional information, see <xref
        linkend="Anchor61009" />.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
