<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section955847" role="openmfg">
  <title>Schedule Server Maintenance</title>

  <para>The server maintenance utility is designed to perform
  automated maintenance on your server. You should perform server maintenance
  on a regular basis to ensure the smooth operation of your server.</para>

  <note>
      <para>When server maintenance is performed, a VACUUM FULL
    ANALYZE operation is run on your server. For more information on the
    VACUUM and ANALYZE operations, visit the PostgreSQL website at <ulink id="Hypertext956137" url="http://www.postgresql.com">http://www.postgresql.com</ulink>www.postgresql.com.</para>
  </note>

  <para>To run the server maintenance utility, select the "Schedule Server
  Maintenance" option. The following screen will appear:</para>

  <para>
      <screenshot>
         <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
               <imagedata fileref="images/Sys_serveMaint.png" id="Graphic955964"/>
            </imageobject>

            <caption id="Caption955967">Schedule Server Maintenance</caption>
         </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
   </para>

  <para>When scheduling server maintenance, you are presented
  with the following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
         <term>Action</term>

         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18ec15c">
            <para>Displays the name of the action to be performed by the Batch
        Manager.</para>

            <para>In this case, the name of the action is
        serverMaintenance.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
         <term>Response Email</term>

         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18ec1a4">
            <para>By default, the email address of the logged-in user will be
        entered here. This address may be edited or changed.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
         <term>Scheduled</term>

         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18ec1ec">
            <para>Select one of the following Schedule options:</para>

            <para>ASAP: Select to have the job run as soon as
        possible.</para>

            <para>Scheduled: Schedule a date and time to run the
        job. Specify a date in the first field using a standard date format.
        Use the arrow buttons in the second field to specify a time of
        day.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <note>
      <para>When a job is submitted to the Batch Manager with a
    scheduled time of ASAP, the Batch Manager sets the scheduled time to the
    current time. However, a job will not necessarily be run immediately if it
    is scheduled for the current time. Any pre-existing jobs with scheduled
    times prior to the current time must be completed first. In other words,
    ASAP jobs will not necessarily be run immediately. Previously scheduled
    jobs will be run first.</para>
  </note>

  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons
  are available:</para>

  <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
         <term>CANCEL</term>

         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18f626c">
            <para>Closes the screen without performing server maintenance,
        returning you to the application desktop.</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
         <term>SUBMIT</term>

         <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18f62b4">
            <para>Select to submit requested action to the Batch Manager for
        processing. For additional information, see the <xref endterm="Anchor61009" linkend="Anchor61009"/>
    FINDME
  "Topic:
        Submitting Reports and Jobs to the Batch Manager".</para>
         </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
