<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section519242">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>billing</primary>
      <secondary>select order for</secondary>
    </indexterm>Select Order for Billing</title>
  <para>This utility enables you to manually enter billing details for
  individual Sales Order Line Items. Both shipped Orders and unshipped Line
  Items may be selected for billing in this manner. This individualized
  approach differs from the approach taken by the Select All Shipped Orders
  for Billing utility, which by default selects for billing the full Line Item
  quantities for all shipped Orders. To select an individual shipped Order for
  billing, select the "Select Order for Billing" option. The following screen
  will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/selectOrderForBilling.png"
                     id="Graphic523420" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption519248">Select Order for Billing</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <note>
    <para>When you select an Order for billing, you are indicating that you
    wish to create an Invoice for the Order. Invoice Numbers are assigned when
    an Invoice is printed.</para>
  </note>
  <para>When selecting an Order for billing, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Sales Order #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the Sales Order Number of the Sales Order you want to
        select for billing.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Order Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the original Sales Order date.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Ship Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>By default, the most-recent ship date will appear in the field.
        You may override the default value by entering ship date information
        manually.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Invoice Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>By default, the current (today"s) date will appear in the field.
        You may override the default value by entering Invoice date
        information manually.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Cust. Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Name: Displays Customer's name.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Cust. Phone</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Phone: Displays Customer's phone number.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>P/O Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays purchase for the specified Sales Order. Indicates the
        Customer Purchase Order Number assigned to the specified Sales
        Order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Ship-To Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays Ship-To name.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Show Closed Line Items</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to show closed Line Items in the "Line Items"
        display.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>billing</primary>
          <secondary>at line item level</secondary>
        </indexterm>Line Items</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Sales Order Line Items selected for billing.
        Double-clicking on a Line Item--or highlighting it and selecting the
        EDIT SELECTION button--enables you to select a billing quantity for
        that Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>In the Line Items display, the Uninvoiced column refers to quantity
    that has been shipped but not yet invoiced. Quantity must have been
    shipped to appear in the Uninvoiced column. If no quantity has been
    shipped, then no quantity will appear as uninvoiced.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Ship Via</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>By default, the preferred Ship Via method for specified Customer
        will appear in the field. You may enter a free-form Ship Via simply by
        typing the name of the Ship Via into the field. Default Ship Vias may
        be defined at the system level.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>The system supports up-to-date shipment tracking with links to the
    websites of many leading shipping companies (i.e., "Ship Vias").</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Close all Open Items</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to close all open Sales Order Line Items.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Subtotal</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the subtotal for the Sales Order Line Items.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Sales Tax</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the amount of Tax that will be added to the Sales
        Order, as defined by the specified Tax Code. To get a detailed view of
        the Tax calculation, click on the Tax link using your mouse.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>billing</primary>
          <secondary>related charges for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Misc. Charge Amount</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the amount of the miscellaneous charge. Before entering a
        miscellaneous charge amount, you must first assign the charge to a
        Sales Account and also enter a description of the charge.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Misc. Charge Description</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a description to identify the miscellaneous charge.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Misc. Charge Sales Account</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a Sales Account to assign the miscellaneous charge
        to.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Freight</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the amount of freight charge to be added to the specified
        Order. The freight charge may be entered during the creation or
        modification of a Sales Order--or at the time of shipment.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>The Payment Received field is an optional field which may be used to
    provide visibility into prepaid amounts. Because the field exists for
    visual purposes only, entering an amount in this field will not affect the
    amount due. The only way an Invoice may be offset is through the
    application of a Cash Receipt or a Credit Memo.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Total</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the total amount of all uninvoiced Sales Orders.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Payment Received</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the amount of payment received against the specified Sales
        Order, if any. This amount will appear on any resulting Invoice, but
        will not be posted as a credit against the Invoice.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Notes</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        Notes related to the Sales Order selected for billing. Notes entered
        on this screen will follow the Order through the billing process. For
        example, you may view notes associated with a posted Invoice within
        the Invoice Information report.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CLOSE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without selecting the Order for billing,
        returning you to the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Saves the information you specified in the screen and selects
        the Order for billing, creating an Invoice in the process.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>EDIT ORDER</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Brings you to the Sales Order screen, where you may edit the
        specified Sales Order. The Sales Order screen is described at length
        in <xref endterm="Anchor23923" linkend="Anchor23923" />.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>EDIT SELECTION</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enables you to specify or edit the billing quantity for the
        highlighted Line Item. Double-clicking on a Line Item will also bring
        you to the billing quantity edit screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL SELECTION</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Removes previously entered billing quantity from a selected Line
        Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SELECT BALANCE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a Line Item, then select this button to transfer the
        full balance to Billing.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <xi:include href="selectBillingQty.xml"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
              xpointer="element(/1)" />
</section>
