<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section518859">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>ship vias</primary>
      <secondary>master list of</secondary>
    </indexterm>List Ship Vias</title>
  <para>Ship Vias describe the transportation method used to ship Sales Order
  Items. Shipping companies, for example, are considered to be Ship Vias. For
  certain shipping companies, the system will launch a browser and link
  directly to shipper websites--where up-to-date shipment tracking information
  can be obtained.</para>
  <note>
    <para>To obtain up-to-date shipment tracking information by linking to
    shipping company websites, use the "Query Shipment Status" option found in
    the "Shipments by Sales Order" report.</para>
  </note>
  <para>For the shipment tracking feature to perform correctly, specific Ship
  Via naming conventions must be followed. The following shipping companies
  and naming conventions are currently supported:</para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x186faac">
      <para>United Parcel Service: The first three letters of the Ship Via
      name must be "UPS" to enable connection to the UPS website. A link will
      be made using the specific tracking number for the shipment in
      question.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x186fad0">
      <para>SAIA, Inc.: The first four letters of the Ship Via name must be
      "SAIA" to enable connection to the SAIA website. A link will be made
      using the specific tracking number for the shipment in question.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x186faf4">
      <para>Federal Express: The first five letters of the Ship Via name must
      be "FEDEX" to enable connection to the FedEx website. A link will be
      made using the specific tracking number for the shipment in
      question.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x186fb18">
      <para>Roadway Express: The first seven letters of the Ship Via name must
      be "ROADWAY" to enable connection to the Roadway website. A link will be
      made using the specific tracking number for the shipment in
      question.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x186fb3c">
      <para>USF Logistics, Inc.: The first three letters of the Ship Via name
      must be "USF" to enable connection to the USF website. A link will be
      made using the specific tracking number for the shipment in
      question.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x186fb60">
      <para>A &amp; B Freight Line, Inc.: The first three letters of the Ship
      Via name must be "A&amp;B" to enable connection to the A&amp;B website.
      The tracking number must be entered manually.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x186fb84">
      <para>Averitt Express, Inc.: The first seven letters of the Ship Via
      name must be "AVERITT" to enable connection to the Averitt website. The
      tracking number must be entered manually.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x186fba8">
      <para>DHL International GmbH: The first three letters of the Ship Via
      name must be "DHL" to enable connection to the DHL website. The tracking
      number must be entered manually.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x186fbcc">
      <para>R &amp; L Carriers: The first three letters of the Ship Via name
      must be "R&amp;L" to enable connection to the R&amp;L website. The
      tracking number must be entered manually.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x186fbf0">
      <para>Watkins Motor Lines, Inc.: The first seven letters of the Ship Via
      name must be "WATKINS" to enable connection to the Watkins website. The
      tracking number must be entered manually.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x186fc14">
      <para>Yellow Transportation, Inc.: The first seven letters of the Ship
      Via name must be "YELLOW" to enable connection to the Yellow website.
      The tracking number must be entered manually.</para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <note>
    <para>If you are running an xTuple client on a Linux machine, you should
    set the BROWSER environment variable so it points to the executable for
    your default browser. This will prevent error messages when connecting to
    shipping company websites.</para>
  </note>
  <para>To access the master list of Ship Vias, select the "Ship Vias" option.
  The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/SO_MI_shipViaList.png" id="Graphic523030" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption518865">Ship Vias Master List</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <tip>
    <para>If your site integrates UPS WorldShip with OpenMFG, there are
    separate steps to be followed. For more information, see <xref
    linkend="Anchor29552" />.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>The Ship Vias master list displays the code and description for all
  existing Ship Vias.</para>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CLOSE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x186fd34">
        <para>Closes the screen, returning you to the application
        desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x186fd7c">
        <para>Opens screen for creating a new Ship Via.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>EDIT</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x186fdc4">
        <para>Enables you to edit the highlighted Ship Via. The edit screen is
        the same as that for creating a new Ship Via--except that when
        editing, the fields will contain Ship Via information. Double-clicking
        on a Ship Via will also bring you to the editing screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>DELETE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x186fe0c">
        <para>Highlight a Ship Via and then select this button to remove the
        Ship Via from the master list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>