<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section658633" role="openmfg">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>transfer orders</primary>
      <secondary>creating new</secondary>
    </indexterm>New Transfer Order</title>
  <para>Transfer Orders are used to move Inventory between Warehouses. They
  are distinct from Inter-Warehouse Transfers in three primary ways: 1) you
  can add multiple Items to a single Transfer Order and transfer all the Items
  at once; 2) all Transfer Order transfers involve a Transit Warehouse, for
  tracking Inventory while it is "in transit"; and 3) there are reports (i.e.,
  paperwork) associated with Transfer Orders. To enter a new Transfer Order,
  select the "New Transfer Order" option. The following screen will
  appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/IM_IT_transferOrdNew.png"
                     id="Graphic659333" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption659336">Create New Transfer Order</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When creating a new Transfer Order, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Order #</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b4800">
        <para>Next available Transfer Order Number will automatically display,
        unless your system requires you to enter Transfer Order Numbers
        manually. Default values and input parameters for Transfer Order
        Numbers are configurable at the system level.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Order Status</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b4848">
        <para>Displays the current status of the Transfer Order. Transfer
        Orders may be either Open = "O" or Closed = "C" depending on the
        status of the associated Line Items.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Order Date</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b4890">
        <para>Displays current day's date.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Scheduled Date</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b48d8">
        <para>Displays the Order's earliest scheduled date. The scheduled date
        corresponds to the earliest scheduled date for an included Transfer
        Order Item. Because Transfer Orders may contain multiple Transfer
        Order Items, the scheduled date indicates the most recent scheduled
        date. No scheduled date will display in the "Scheduled Date" field
        until a Transfer Order Line Item has been created and a scheduled date
        assigned to it.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>pack dates</primary>
          <secondary>for transfer orders</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>transfer orders</primary>
          <secondary>pack dates for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Pack Date</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b49b0">
        <para>The pack date is the same date as the ship date. Because the
        field can be edited, you have the ability to change the pack date and
        make it different from the ship date.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Agent</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b49f8">
        <para>Specify the Agent associated with the Transfer Order. By
        default, the name of the logged-in user will be entered as Purchasing
        Agent-assuming that user is designated as a Purchasing Agent. If the
        user is not a Purchasing Agent, the first alphabetical name in the
        list of Purchasing Agents will be entered.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Project #</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b4a40">
        <para>Select a Project Number to associate with the Transfer Order.
        Projects may be used to link Transfer Orders with Work Orders, Sales
        Orders, Purchase Orders, etc.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>tax authorities</primary>
          <secondary>for transfer orders</secondary>
        </indexterm>Tax Authority</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b4ad0">
        <para>Specify the Tax Authority associated with the Transfer Order.
        The Tax Authority associated with the Destination Warehouse will be
        entered here by default.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>From Warehouse</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b4b18">
        <para>Select a Source Warehouse from the available options. If the
        following Contact and Address information is defined on the Warehouse
        master, then it will be entered automatically; otherwise you may enter
        that information manually:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Name</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The name of the primary Contact at the Source
              Warehouse.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Job Title</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The primary Contact's Job Title.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Voice</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The primary Contact's phone number.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Fax</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The primary Contact's fax number.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>E-Mail</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The primary Contact's email address.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Street Address</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The street Address for the Source Warehouse.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>City</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The city the Source Warehouse is located in.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>State</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The state the Source Warehouse is located in.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Postal Code</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The Postal Code for the Source Warehouse</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Country</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The country the Source Warehouse is located in.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>To Warehouse</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b4b60">
        <para>Select a Destination Warehouse from the available options. If
        the following Contact and Address information is defined on the
        Warehouse master, then it will be entered automatically; otherwise you
        may enter that information manually:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Name</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The name of the primary Contact at the Destination
              Warehouse.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Job Title</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The primary Contact's Job Title.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Voice</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The primary Contact's phone number.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Fax</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The primary Contact's fax number.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>E-mail</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The primary Contact's email address.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Street Address</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The street Address for the Destination Warehouse.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>City</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The city the Destination Warehouse is located in.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>State</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The state the Destination Warehouse is located in.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Postal Code</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The Postal Code for the Destination Warehouse.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Country</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The country the Destination Warehouse is located
              in.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Ship Complete</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b4ba8">
        <para>Select to require that all Transfer Order Line Item quantities
        be issued to Shipping before the Order is shipped. This feature is
        designed to prevent partial shipments. If selected, users will be
        prevented from shipping the Order unless all Line Item quantities have
        been issued to Shipping. If not selected, partial shipments for the
        Order will be allowed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Ship Via</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b4bf0">
        <para>Specify the Ship Via associated with the Transfer Order. You may
        enter a free-form Ship Via simply by typing the name of the Ship Via
        into the field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Shipping Form</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b4c38">
        <para>Specify the Shipping Form associated with the Transfer
        Order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>At the top of the screen, the following buttons are available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE AND ADD TO PACKING LIST BATCH</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b4ca4">
        <para>Creates the Transfer Order, saves it, and adds it to the list of
        Orders available for printing on the Packing List Batch.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b4cec">
        <para>Creates the Transfer Order and saves the Transfer Order
        information. The SAVE button must be selected in order to save the
        Transfer Order record. It is not enough to save Transfer Order Line
        Item information. The Transfer Order header must also be saved.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b4d34">
        <para>Closes the screen without creating a new Transfer Order,
        returning you to the application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>transfer orders</primary>
      <secondary>adding line items to</secondary>
    </indexterm>To create or modify Transfer Order Line Items, select the
  "Line Items" tab at the top of the "Transfer Order" screen. The following
  screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/IM_IT_transferOrdLines.png"
                     id="Graphic659968" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption660626">Transfer Order Line Items</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When creating or modifying Transfer Order Line Items, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Line Items</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b4e54">
        <para>Display lists Line Items for this Transfer Order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>Transfer Order Line Items may exist in any of the following
    statuses:</para>
    <para>"O" = Open</para>
    <para>"C" = Closed</para>
    <para>"X" = Cancelled</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Show Canceled Line Items</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b4ee4">
        <para>Select to include in the Line Items display Transfer Order Line
        Items which have been specifically canceled. Displaying canceled Line
        Items can provide useful Order history information.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Require sufficient Inventory</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b4f2c">
        <para>Select to ensure you have enough Quantity on Hand of a Line Item
        prior to issuing Stock to Shipping. If selected, this option will
        prevent you from issuing Line Item quantity to Shipping if doing so
        would force Quantity on Hand for the Item Site to fall below zero. Not
        selecting this option means issuing Stock to Shipping may drive Item
        Site Quantity on Hand negative.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Freight Weight</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b4f74">
        <para>Displays the combined weight of all Transfer Order Line Items.
        Freight weight represents the sum of an Item's product weight and
        packaging weight, both of which are defined on the Item master. The
        per unit freight weight multiplied by the quantity per gives you the
        Line Item freight weight. The sum of all Line Item freight weights is
        the combined weight for the Order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>freight</primary>
          <secondary>on transfer orders</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>transfer orders</primary>
          <secondary>freight charges on</secondary>
        </indexterm>Line Item Freight Subtotal</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b504c">
        <para>Displays the subtotal for all Line Item Freight. Freight charges
        may be added when entering or editing a Transfer Order Line
        Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Tax</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b5094">
        <para>Displays the total amount of Tax to be charged on the Transfer
        Order. Sales Tax is calculated at the Transfer Order Line Item level.
        The Tax amount displayed here represents the total for all Line Item
        Tax amounts. To get a detailed view of the Tax calculation, click on
        the Tax link using your mouse.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Total</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b50dc">
        <para>Displays the total amount of the Transfer Order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>Any Transfer Order Line Item may be shipped--even if the Item or
    Item Site in question becomes inactive after the Sales Order has been
    created.</para>
  </note>
  <para>At the top of and to the far right of the screen, the following
  buttons are available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CLEAR</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b516c">
        <para>Select to clear the contents of the current Transfer Order and
        open a fresh, new Transfer Order for Order entry. The Order Number of
        the Order being cleared will display next to the CLEAR button.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>Selecting the CLEAR button on the Transfer Order header does not
    delete any information which has been saved previously.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b51fc">
        <para>Saves the Transfer Order information.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b5244">
        <para>Closes the screen without creating a new Transfer Order,
        returning you to the application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b528c">
        <para>Opens screen for creating a new Transfer Order Line Item. Mac
        users may use COMMAND + N to enter a new Line Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>EDIT</term>
      <listitem id="transferOrderEDIT">
        <para>Enables you to edit highlighted Transfer Order Line Items. The
        edit screen is the same as that for creating a new Transfer Order Line
        Item--except that when editing, the fields will contain Transfer Order
        Line Item information. Double-clicking on a Transfer Order Line Item
        will also bring you to the editing screen. Mac users may use COMMAND +
        E to edit an existing Line Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CLOSE</term>
      <listitem id="transferOrderCLOSE">
        <para>Highlight a Transfer Order Line Item and then select this to
        close the Transfer Order Line Item. If the highlighted Line Item is
        already closed, the label will revert to an OPEN, which may be used to
        open the closed Line Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>DELETE</term>
      <listitem id="transferOrderDELETE">
        <para>Highlight a Transfer Order Line Item and then select this to
        remove the Transfer Order Line Item from the list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>shipping</primary>
          <secondary>issuing stock to</secondary>
        </indexterm>ISSUE STOCK</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b53f4">
        <para>Highlight a Transfer Order Line Item and then select this button
        to issue quantity to Shipping.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>You may select multiple Line Items for issuing to Shipping by
    highlighting them using your mouse--or a combination of your mouse and
    either the SHIFT or CTRL keys.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>ISSUE LINE BAL.</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18b5484">
        <para>Highlight a Transfer Order Line Item and then select this button
        to issue the balance of the Line Item quantity to Shipping.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>Right-clicking on an Item in the Line Items list enables you to select
  from the following menu options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Edit Line</term>
      <xi:include href="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                  xpointer="element(transferOrderEDIT)" />
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Close Line</term>
      <xi:include href="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                  xpointer="element(transferOrderCLOSE)" />
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Delete Line</term>
      <xi:include href="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                  xpointer="element(transferOrderDELETE)" />
    </varlistentry>
    <xi:include href="../supportfiles/rightclick.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(rightclickReturnStock)" />
    <xi:include href="../supportfiles/rightclick.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(rightclickIssueStock)" />
    <xi:include href="../supportfiles/rightclick.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(rightclickIssueLineBalance)" />
    <xi:include href="../widgets/xtreewidget.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(xtreewidget.menu.exportcontents)" />
  </variablelist>
  <para>Order Notes added to a Transfer Order are used for internal purposes
  only. To add Notes to a Transfer Order, select the "Order Notes" tab at the
  top of the "Transfer Order" screen. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/IM_IT_transferOrdNotes.png"
                     id="Graphic659574" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption659397">Transfer Order Notes</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When adding Notes to a Transfer Order, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Order Notes</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c9490">
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        general Notes related to the Transfer Order. These Notes are for
        internal use only.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c94fc">
        <para>Saves the Order Note.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c9544">
        <para>Closes the screen without creating an Order Note, returning you
        to the application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To add Comments related to a Transfer Order, select the "Comments"
  tab. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/IM_IT_transferOrdComm.png"
                     id="Graphic659414" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption659417">Transfer Order Comments</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When adding Comments related to a Transfer Order, you are presented
  with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Comments</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c961c">
        <para>Display lists Comments for the specified Order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c9688">
        <para>Opens screen for creating a new Comment.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>VIEW</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c96d0">
        <para>Highlight a Comment and then select this button to reach a
        read-only view of the Comment.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To create a Transfer Order Comment, select the NEW button. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/CommentNew.png" id="Graphic661520" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption661523">Create New Comment</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Comment Type</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c97a8">
        <para>Specify one of the following Comment Types from the drop-down
        list: ChangeLog or General. Comment Types are used to categorize
        Comments. Once you have specified a Comment Type, you may type your
        Comment in the main text area. The text area features word-wrapping
        and scroll-bar support for longer Comments.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c9814">
        <para>Closes the screen without creating a new Comment, returning you
        to the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c985c">
        <para>Creates the Comment and adds it to the list of Order
        Comments.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>Shipping Notes are drawn from the Shipping Comments (if any)
  associated with Transit Warehouses. The Notes may vary depending on the
  Transit Warehouse being used. These Notes provide a mechanism for
  transferring information about Transit Warehouses to the Transfer Order. To
  view Transfer Order Shipping Notes, select the "Shipping Notes" tab at the
  top of the "Transfer Order" screen. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/IM_IT_transferOrdShNtes.png"
                     id="Graphic659441" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption659443">Transfer Order Shipping Notes</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When viewing or editing Shipping Notes for a Transfer Order, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Shipping Notes</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c9934">
        <para>While the content for Shipping Notes may originate from the
        Transit Warehouse master, you can edit the Notes to fit the
        requirements of an Order. This is a scrolling text field with
        word-wrapping.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c99a0">
        <para>Saves the Shipping Note.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c99e8">
        <para>Closes the screen without creating a Shipping Note, returning
        you to the application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>If you want to speed up your data entry of Transfer Order Line Items,
  you can use the Quick Entry interface. This screen allows you to enter
  multiple Line Items in one session. It also simplifies the process by
  presenting only the minimum required fields. To enter Line Items using the
  Quick Entry interface, select the "Quick Entry" tab at the top of the
  "Transfer Order" screen. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/IM_IT_transferOrdQEntry.png"
                     id="Graphic659461" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption659463">Transfer Order Quick Entry</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <tip>
    <para>To get started entering Line Items, place your cursor in the "Item"
    field. You can then move from field-to-field using the TAB button on your
    keyboard.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>When entering Transfer Order Line Items using the Quick Entry
  interface, you are presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c9ae4">
        <para>Enter an Inventory Item Number. This field is used for entering
        Items stored in Inventory.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty.</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c9b2c">
        <para>Enter the quantity you want to transfer.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Standard Cost</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c9b74">
        <para>Displays the Standard Cost per unit.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Freight</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c9bbc">
        <para>Enter the Freight amount, if any.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Due Date</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c9c04">
        <para>Enter the due date.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE QUICK ENTRIES</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c9c70">
        <para>Select to save all the Line Items entered using the Quick Entry
        interface.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>DELETE QUICK ENTRY</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18c9cb8">
        <para>Highlight a Line Item and then select this button to remove the
        Item from the list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <xi:include href="transferOrderItem.xml"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
              xpointer="element(/1)" />
</section>