<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section>
  <title>Global Conversion Ratio</title>
  <para>Global conversion ratios enable you to create basic conversions such
  as inches to feet, pounds to ounces, etc. Once defined here, these
  conversions may be used throughout the system. The master list of global
  conversion ratios should include conversions both from and to the specified
  Unit of Measure. That is to say, if the conversion from ounces to pounds is
  defined in the maintenance for pounds, the calculated conversion from pounds
  to ounces should also appear in the ounces maintenance. Users can add, edit
  and delete from the list of conversions. However, users should be
  discouraged from editing or changing a conversion ratio that is being or has
  been used in a transaction.</para>
  <para>To create a new global conversion ratio, select the NEW button. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/PD_MI_uomNewConv.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Captiond1e1">Global Conversion Ratio</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <note>
    <para>As their name implies, global conversion ratios may be used
    throughout the system once they are defined in the UOM Master
    Information.</para>
  </note>
  <para>When creating a new global conversion ratio, you are presented with
  the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Source UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select a source Unit of Measure from the list of defined Units
        of Measure.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Value</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter a value for the source Unit of Meaure to be used in
              the conversion ratio.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Per UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select a per Unit of Measure from the list of defined Units of
        Measure.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Value</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter a value for the per Unit of Meaure to be used in the
              conversion ratio.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Fractional</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify whether Inventory processed using this alternate Unit of
        Measure may be maintained in fractional quantities. If not selected,
        Inventory using this global conversion ratio may not be maintained in
        fractional quantities.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x181a430">
        <para>Closes the screen without creating a global conversion ratio,
        returning you to the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x181a478">
        <para>Creates the global conversion ratio and adds it to the master
        list of global conversion ratios.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>