<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section548558">
  <title>
<indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>reorder levels</primary>
      <secondary>updating by planner code</secondary>
    </indexterm>
<indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>planner codes</primary>
      <secondary>updating reorder levels using</secondary>
    </indexterm>Update Reorder Levels by Planner Code</title>
  <para>To update Reorder Levels by Planner Code, select the
  "Reorder Levels by Planner Code" option. The following screen will
  appear:</para>
  <para>
<screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/IM_Utilities_upReordbyPCode.png" id="Graphic549142"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption549145">Update Reorder Levels by Planner
        Code</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
</para>
  <para>When updating Reorder Levels by Planner Code, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry role="openmfg">
      <term>All Warehouses</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19a915c">
        <para>Select to update Reorder Levels by Planner Code for all
        Warehouses.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="openmfg">
      <term>Selected</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19a9180">
        <para>Specify Warehouse where Reorder Levels by Planner Code are to be
        updated.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>All Planner Codes</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19a91c8">
        <para>Select to update Reorder Levels for all Planner Codes.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Selected</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19b0e00">
        <para>Specify Planner Code whose Reorder Levels you want to
        update.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Pattern</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19b0e48">
        <para>Enter a Planner Code pattern to select a range of Planner
        Codes.</para>
        <para>Refine your search using Regular Expressions, as
        described in <xref endterm="Anchor77806" linkend="Anchor77806"/>
    FINDME
  "Topic: Pattern Matching with Regular
        Expressions".</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Days of Stock at Reorder Level</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19b0e90">
        <para>Specify number of days using one of the following
        options:</para>
        <para>Item Site Lead Time +: Select a number using the
        arrow buttons, or manually enter a value up to a maximum of 99.
        Average daily usage calculated using selected Calendar periods will be
        multiplied by this value to determine Reorder Level.</para>
        <para>Fixed Days: Select a number using the arrow
        buttons, or manually enter a value up to a maximum of 999. Average
        daily usage calculated using selected Calendar periods will be
        multiplied by this value to determine Reorder Level.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Periods to Include in Analysis</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19b0ed8">
        <para>Specify the periods to include in the analysis using the
        following Calendar options:</para>
        <para>Calendar: Select the Calendar you want to use
        for the analysis.</para>
        <para>Name/Selected Periods: Select as many periods as
        you want to include in the analysis. Selected periods correspond to
        Calendar specified in the "Calendar" field. Select individual periods
        or groups of periods together. To select an individual period,
        highlight the period using your mouse button. The period is now
        selected. To select a sequence of periods, highlight the first in the
        sequence using your mouse button. Then, holding down the SHIFT key on
        your keyboard, highlight the last period in the sequence. The entire
        sequence is now selected. To select periods that are out of sequence
        (e.g., January, April, July, October), highlight the first period in
        the group. Then, holding down the CTRL key on your keyboard, highlight
        the next period you want to select. Continue highlighting periods with
        the CTRL key depressed until all desired periods are selected. The
        entire group is now selected.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons
  are available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19b0f44">
        <para>Closes the screen without updating Reorder Levels by Planner
        Code, returning you to the application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>UPDATE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19b0f8c">
        <para>Updates Reorder Levels by Planner Code, using the specified
        parameters.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="openmfg">
      <term>SUBMIT</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x19b0fb0">
        <para>Select to submit requested action to the Batch Manager for
        processing. For additional information, see the <xref endterm="Anchor61009" linkend="Anchor61009"/>
    FINDME
  "Topic:
        Submitting Reports and Jobs to the Batch Manager".</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
