<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="userEventNotification">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>events</primary>
      <secondary>user notification of</secondary>
    </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>users</primary>
      <secondary>event notification for</secondary>
    </indexterm>User Event Notification</title>
  <para id="Para976931">To define or modify a user's Event notification
  preferences, select the EVENTS button. The following screen will
  appear:</para>
  <note>
    <para id="Para947292">The complete list of user-defined Events has been
    reproduced in this manual. See <link endterm="Anchor80421" id="XRef947304"
    linkend="Anchor80421"> Appendix A</link>Appendix A to view the
    list.</para>
  </note>
  <para id="Para947296"><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/Sys_userPrefEvents.png"
                     id="Graphic947294" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption947297">User Event Notification</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para id="Para519389">When defining or modifying a user's Event notification
  preferences, you are presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para919679">Username</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d8998">
        <para>Displays the username of the current or selected user.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para919686">Proper Name</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d89e0">
        <para>Displays the proper name of the current or selected user.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para519390">Event</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d8a28">
        <para>Displays the complete list of system-defined Events.</para>
        <para id="Para979467">Highlight an Event and then double-click a
        Warehouse in the adjacent Warehouse column to set the user's Event
        notification preference for that Warehouse. Selecting "Yes" means the
        user will be notified if the specified event occurs in the specified
        Warehouse. Selecting "No" means the user will not be notified about
        the Event if it occurs in that Warehouse. To globally affect the
        settings for all Warehouses, double-click on an Event. Double-clicking
        on an Event causes the Warehouse settings to toggle back-and-forth
        between "Yes" and "No."</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para id="Para947267">When an Event occurs, the Event notification button
    will appear in the lower left-hand corner of the application desktop. This
    alerts the user that one of the Events they subscribe to has occurred.
    Open the Event Manager to view and respond to the Event.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para947268">Warehouses</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d8ab8">
        <para>Displays the complete list of Warehouses.</para>
        <para id="Para979475">Highlight an Event in the adjacent Event column
        and then double-click a Warehouse to set the user's Event notification
        preference for that Warehouse. Selecting "Yes" means the user will be
        notified if the specified event occurs in the specified Warehouse.
        Selecting "No" means the user will not be notified about the Event if
        it occurs in that Warehouse. To globally affect the settings for all
        Warehouses, double-click on an Event. Double-clicking on an Event
        causes the Warehouse settings to toggle back-and-forth between "Yes"
        and "No."</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para id="Para926673">To the far right of the screen, the following buttons
  are available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para926674">CLOSE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18d8b24">
        <para>Closes the screen without making any changes to the user's
        preferences, returning you to the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>