<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="userEventNotification">
  <title>
<indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>events</primary>
      <secondary>user notification of</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>users</primary>
      <secondary>event notification for</secondary>
    </indexterm>User Event Notification</title>
  <para>To define or modify a user's Event notification preferences, select
  the EVENTS button. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <note>
    <para>The complete list of user-defined Events has been reproduced in this
    manual. See <xref linkend="Anchor80421"/>.</para>
  </note>
  <para>
<screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata id="Graphic947294" fileref="images/userEventNotification.png"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption947297">User Event Notification</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
</para>
  <para>When defining or modifying a user's Event notification preferences,
  you are presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Username</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the username of the current or selected user.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Proper Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the proper name of the current or selected user.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Event</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the complete list of system-defined Events.</para>
        <para>Highlight an Event and then double-click a Warehouse in the
        adjacent Warehouse column to set the user's Event notification
        preference for that Warehouse. Selecting "Yes" means the user will be
        notified if the specified event occurs in the specified Warehouse.
        Selecting "No" means the user will not be notified about the Event if
        it occurs in that Warehouse. To globally affect the settings for all
        Warehouses, double-click on an Event. Double-clicking on an Event
        causes the Warehouse settings to toggle back-and-forth between "Yes"
        and "No."</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>When an Event occurs, the Event notification button will appear in
    the lower left-hand corner of the application desktop. This alerts the
    user that one of the Events they subscribe to has occurred. Open the Event
    Manager to view and respond to the Event.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Warehouses</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the complete list of Warehouses.</para>
        <para>Highlight an Event in the adjacent Event column and then
        double-click a Warehouse to set the user's Event notification
        preference for that Warehouse. Selecting "Yes" means the user will be
        notified if the specified event occurs in the specified Warehouse.
        Selecting "No" means the user will not be notified about the Event if
        it occurs in that Warehouse. To globally affect the settings for all
        Warehouses, double-click on an Event. Double-clicking on an Event
        causes the Warehouse settings to toggle back-and-forth between "Yes"
        and "No."</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CLOSE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without making any changes to the user's
        preferences, returning you to the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
