<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2008 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="user">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>users</primary>
      <secondary>creating new</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>xtuple administrators</primary>
      <secondary>new users created by</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>administrators</primary>
      <see>xtuple administrators</see>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>system administrators</primary>
      <see>xtuple administrators</see>
    </indexterm>User</title>
  <para>To create a new user, select the NEW button. The following screen will
  appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/user.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>User Information</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When creating a new user, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>usernames</primary>
          <secondary>creating for users</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>users</primary>
          <secondary>creating usernames for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Username</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a unique username to clearly distinguish the new user from
        existing users. The username is case-sensitive. This is a required
        field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Active</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to mark the user as Active.</para>
        <para>Not selecting marks the user as Inactive. Users cannot be
        deleted from the system, but marking them Inactive prevents them from
        logging into the application.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Proper Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the user's first name and last name (e.g., John
        Smith).</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Initials</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the user's initials.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>users</primary>
          <secondary>passwords for</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>xtuple administrators</primary>
          <secondary>passwords created by</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>passwords</primary>
          <secondary>created by administrators</secondary>
        </indexterm>Password</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>User passwords are established to ensure application and system
        security. Passwords are case-sensitive. As you can see in the example,
        this field does not display the values entered on the screen. Instead,
        individual keystrokes are replaced by asterisks (*) to protect the
        password from being viewed. Once the user's password is entered, it
        can only be reset by an system administrator who must overwrite the
        existing password.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Verify</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Verify the accuracy of the user's password by retyping it in
        this field. Again, individual keystrokes will be replaced by asterisks
        (*) to protect the password from being viewed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="openmfg">
      <term>Dept.</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select a Department to associate with the specified user.</para>
        <para>This is an optional setting.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Shift</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select a Shift to associate with the specified user.</para>
        <para>This is an optional setting.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>locales</primary>
          <secondary>user specific</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>xtuple administrators</primary>
          <secondary>user locales established by</secondary>
        </indexterm>Locale</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select one of the available Locales.</para>
        <para>Locale settings affect how information is formatted and
        displayed on a user's screen. The default Locale is "USEnglish", but
        multinational companies may have multiple Locales defined. Only users
        who have been granted the "MaintainLocales" privilege can define and
        maintain Locale settings. For more information on Locales and Locale
        settings, see <xref linkend="Anchor54109" />.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>users</primary>
          <secondary>privileges for</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>xtuple administrators</primary>
          <secondary>user privileges defined by</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>privileges</primary>
          <secondary>for users</secondary>
        </indexterm>Purchasing Agent</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if the users is authorized to make purchases.</para>
        <para>Not selecting means the user is not authorized to make
        purchases.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Can Create System Users</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if the user is authorized to create new users.</para>
        <para>Not selecting means the user is not authorized to create new
        users.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>System administrators are able to assign and/or revoke privileges on
    a module-by-module basis. The application provides granular security
    settings for each module, down to the submenu level.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Disable Export Display Contents</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to prevent user from exporting display contents.</para>
        <para>The "Export Contents" option can be found on right-click menus
        throughout the application. If selected, the user will be blocked from
        using the "Export Contents" option.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Use Enhanced Authentication</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to require users to use enhanced authentication when they
        log in to the application.</para>
        <para>Enhanced authentication adds a layer to the authentication
        process used to log in to the system. When this feature is turned on,
        user passwords are stored in the database in a modified form. The end
        result is that users may only log in to the database using the xTuple
        Client. If users try to access the database using a tool other than an
        xTuple application, they will not be able to connect. User passwords
        entered when logging in via the xTuple Client will not be recognized
        if the xTuple Client is not used. If enhanced authentication is
        specified for a user, that user must also select the "Use Enhanced
        Authentication" flag in their log in options. If enhanced
        authentication is not specified, users will be permitted to log in to
        the database using database tools other than the xTuple Client.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>The enhanced authentication option will only affect users whose
    passwords are created or updated after the option is enabled/disabled.
    Legacy users will not be affected if the option is not used. Legacy users
    may continue logging in as before this feature was implemented.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>May only use Shop Floor Workbench</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you want the user to have access only to the Shop
        Floor Workbench&mdash;and to no other screens.</para>
        <para>If selected, the Shop Floor Workbench will be the only screen
        the user will have access to when they log in to the database. The log
        in screen for this user will be the same as for all users. However,
        once logged in, the user will only be able to see and use the Shop
        Floor Workbench. This option will override any other privileges which
        may have been assigned previously to the user.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Module</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select an individual module to assign privileges for that
        module.</para>
        <para>Assign privileges to the user on a module-by-module basis.
        Select one module, assign the appropriate privileges, and then repeat
        for each subsequent module the user will need access to. All
        application modules are included in the list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>privileges</primary>
          <secondary>list of available</secondary>
        </indexterm>Available Privileges</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select appropriate privileges from list of available
        privileges.</para>
        <para>The privileges listed in this column represent the full range of
        privileges available for the specified module. The list of available
        privileges will change as different modules are specified. To grant
        privileges to a user, highlight an available privilege and then click
        the ADD button. The highlighted privilege will be added to the user's
        list of granted privileges. Double-clicking on a privilege will also
        move it to the granted privileges column. You can grant all privileges
        for a specified module by clicking on the ADD ALL button.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>privileges</primary>
          <secondary>list of granted</secondary>
        </indexterm>Granted Privileges</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays granted privileges for the specified user.</para>
        <para>To remove a user's granted privileges for a specified module,
        highlight a granted privilege and then click the REVOKE button. The
        highlighted privilege will be removed from the user's list of granted
        privileges. Double-clicking on a privilege will also remove it from
        the granted privileges column. You can remove all granted privileges
        for a specified module by clicking on the REVOKE ALL button.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>The following buttons are located between the Available Privileges and
  Granted Privileges columns:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>ADD-\&gt;</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a specific privilege in the available privileges
        column, then select this button to transfer the privilege to the
        granted privileges column.</para>
        <para>Double-clicking on an available privilege will also transfer it
        to the granted privileges column.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>ADD ALL-\&gt;\&gt;</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select this button to automatically transfer all available
        privileges to the granted privileges column.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>&lt;-REVOKE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a specific privilege in the granted privileges column,
        then select this button to remove the privilege from the granted
        privileges column.</para>
        <para>Double-clicking on a granted privilege will also remove it from
        the granted privileges column.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>&lt;&lt;-REVOKE ALL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select this button to automatically remove all granted
        privileges from the granted privileges column.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Saves the specified user's information and adds it to the list
        of registered users.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CLOSE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without saving any changes, returning you to
        the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>Remember to select the ADD button when you have finished entering a
    user's information.</para>
  </tip>
</section>