<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="voucherItemDistrib">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>vouchers</primary>
      <secondary>costing elements associated with</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>vouchers</primary>
      <secondary>automatic updating of actual costs</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>actual costs</primary>
      <secondary>automatic updating of at vouchering</secondary>
    </indexterm>Voucher Item Distribution</title>
  <para>To distribute purchasing Costs to specific Costing Elements for the
  Item quantity being vouchered, select the NEW button. The following screen
  will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/PO_Vouch_voucherItemDistr.png"
                     id="Graphic972171" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption972174">Distributing Costs to Costing
        Element</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <note>
    <para>An Item's per unit Actual Cost will be automatically updated after a
    Voucher is posted if the vouchered Cost differs from the Item's current
    Actual Cost. The vouchered Cost for an Item is determined by dividing the
    amount to distribute by the quantity to voucher.</para>
  </note>
  <para>When distributing purchasing Costs to a specific Costing Element, you
  are presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Costing Element</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1889558">
        <para>Specify the Costing Element you want to distribute purchasing
        Costs to. The "Material" Costing Element will be selected by default
        once Line Item quantity has been tagged. You may distribute Costs to
        more than one Costing Element per Voucher Item. The list of available
        Costing Elements includes the system-defined "Material" Costing
        Element, as well as any user-defined Costing Elements designated as
        available to accept Purchase Order distributions.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>Be sure to specify the amount to distribute based on the pricing
    found on the Purchase Order. The system will automatically handle any
    calculations required to accommodate Inventory/Vendor Unit of Measure
    (UOM) ratios which are not 1:1.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Amount to Distribute</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18895e8">
        <para>Specify the purchasing amount to distribute to the specified
        Costing Element. By default, the extended Price for the Purchase Order
        Line Item will be entered here once Line Item quantity has been
        tagged. Any difference between the distribution amount and the current
        Actual Cost amount for the Costing Element will result in the posting
        of automatic updates to the current Actual Cost when the Voucher is
        posted.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1889654">
        <para>Closes the screen, returning you to the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x188969c">
        <para>Saves the distribution information and adds it to the
        distribution list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>