<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="voucherItem">
  <title>
<indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>vouchers</primary>
      <secondary>distributing quantities to</secondary>
    </indexterm>Voucher Item</title>
  <para>To distribute quantities from Purchase Order Line Items to the
  Voucher, highlight a Line Item and then select the DISTRIBUTIONS button. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para>
<screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata id="Graphic972130" fileref="images/voucherItem.png"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption972133">Voucher Item Distribution</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
</para>
  <note>
    <para>An Item's per unit Actual Cost will be automatically updated after a
    Voucher is posted if the vouchered Cost differs from the Item's current
    Actual Cost. The vouchered Cost for an Item is determined by dividing the
    amount to distribute by the quantity to voucher.</para>
  </note>
  <para>When distributing quantities from a Purchase Order Line Item to the
  Voucher, you are presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>P/O Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays Purchase Order Number specified on previous
        screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Line #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays Line Item selected for distribution on previous
        screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays Item Number associated with specified Line Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Inventory Unit of Measure.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>P/O Item Price Info</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Unit Price, Extended Price, and Line Item Freight
        for the Line Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Vend. Item Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays Item number the Vendor assigns to the specified
        Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Unit of Measure used by the Vendor for specified
        Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Vend. Item Descrip.</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays description the Vendor uses to describe the specified
        Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Due Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the date Line Item was expected to be received.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Total Quantity Ordered</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the quantity ordered in the specified Purchase Order
        Line Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Total Quantity Received</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the quantity received to date of the specified Line
        Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Total Quantity Rejected</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the quantity rejected to date of the specified Line
        Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Uninvoiced Qty. Received</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the uninvoiced quantity received to date of the
        specified Line Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Uninvoiced Qty. Rejected</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the uninvoiced quantity rejected to date of the
        specified Line Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>
<indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>vouchers</primary>
          <secondary>distributing quantities to</secondary>
        </indexterm>Qty. to Voucher</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This is a read-only field displaying the Purchase Order Line
        Item quantity tagged to be vouchered for the given Voucher Item. The
        quantity displayed equals the tagged received qty. minus any returned
        qty. which may also have been tagged. The quantity to voucher is a
        divisor applied to the distribution amount. The resulting amount--that
        is, the Voucher Item distribution amount divided by the quantity
        vouchered--determines the per unit Actual Cost for an Item. The system
        will automatically handle any differences between the Inventory and
        Vendor UOMs--if any differences exist.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>If you want to partially pay for a Receipt--but find you cannot edit
    the value in the "Qty. to Voucher" field--you should first correct the
    quantity on the original Receipt to be the amount you want to pay for,
    then enter a second Receipt for the balance. To correct Receipt
    quantities, use the right-click menu on the "Uninvoiced Receipts and
    Returns" screen.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>PO Line Freight to Voucher</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the amount of any Purchase Order Line Item freight
        charges. The freight amount entered in this field will be added to the
        total amount for the Voucher Item. If you are vouchering for less than
        the original quantity ordered--and if Line Item freight was entered
        when the Purchase Order was created--then you should consider
        adjusting the Line Item freight amount accordingly. To make this
        adjustment, multiply the quantity you are vouchering by the per unit
        freight charge. The per unit freight charge is determined by dividing
        the original Line Item freight amount by the original Line Item
        quantity.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Close P/O Item</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to close specified Line Item. This flag will be selected
        automatically if the received quantity tagged for vouchering is equal
        to or greater than the Order quantity.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Uninvoiced Receipts and Returns</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists uninvoiced Receipts and Returns for the specified
        Line Item. To change the tagged status for a Line Item, double-click
        on the quantity in the Uninvoiced Receipts and Returns display. If a
        received (or returned) quantity has been tagged "Yes," this means the
        quantity will be marked as invoiced when the Voucher is posted.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Distribution List</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists Costing Elements used for distributing Voucher
        Costs. At the bottom of the display the total amount distributed will
        display. This total includes Costing Element distributions and any
        Purchase Order Line Item freight charges.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen, returning you to the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Saves the Line Item information and adds it to the
        Voucher.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Opens screen for adding a new Costing Element to the
        distribution list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>EDIT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enables you to edit highlighted Costing Element. The edit screen
        is the same as that for adding a new Costing Element--except that when
        editing, the fields will contain Costing Element information.
        Double-clicking on a Costing Element will also bring you to the
        editing screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>DELETE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a Costing Element and then select this button to
        remove the Costing Element from the list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="voucherItemDistrib.xml" xpointer="element(/1)"/>
</section>
