<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="warehouse">
  <title>
<indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>warehouses</primary>
      <secondary>creating new</secondary>
    </indexterm>Warehouse</title>
  <para>To create a new Warehouse, select the NEW button. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para>
<screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/IM_MI_warehouseNew.png" id="Graphic525430"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption518546">Create New Inventory Warehouse</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
</para>
  <tip>
    <para>Warehouse Codes are abbreviations used to quickly
    and easily identify Warehouses. Keep these Codes short and meaningful so
    employees will have an easy time identifying them.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>When creating a new Warehouse, you are presented with
  the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Code</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x181a478">
        <para>The Warehouse code is used to identify a given Warehouse.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Active</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x181a4c0">
        <para>Select to specify the Warehouse is active. Not selecting means
        the Warehouse will be considered inactive. To re-activate a Warehouse,
        simply select this option.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Description</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x181a508">
        <para>Enter a brief description of the Warehouse.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>If a new Address is manually entered here, that
    Address will be added automatically to the master list of
    Addresses.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Address</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x181a598">
        <para>Manually enter Address information in the fields below--or use
        the browse button to select pre-existing Address information. The
        Warehouse Address is used on shipping and receiving paperwork.</para>
        <para>Street Address: Enter the street Address for the
        Warehouse.</para>
        <para>City: Enter the city where the Warehouse is
        located.</para>
        <para>State: Enter the state where the Warehouse is
        located.</para>
        <para>Postal Code: Enter the Postal Code for the
        Warehouse.</para>
        <para>Country: Enter the country where the Warehouse
        is located.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>If a new Contact is manually entered here, that
    Contact will be added automatically to the master list of Contacts.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Contact</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x181a628">
        <para>Manually enter Contact information in the fields below--or use
        the browse button to select pre-existing Contact information.</para>
        <para>Title: Select a Title from the list of available
        Titles.</para>
        <para>First: Enter the Contact's first name.</para>
        <para>Last: Enter the Contact's last name.</para>
        <para>Job Title: Enter the Contact's job title.</para>
        <para>Voice: Enter the Contact's phone number.</para>
        <para>Fax: Enter the Contact's fax number.</para>
        <para>E-Mail: Enter the Contact's e-mail
        address.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Post Unassigned Transactions to</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x181a670">
        <para>Specify a General Ledger Account to post unassigned transactions
        to.</para>
        <para>This account is used as a general bucket for
        General Ledger transactions which the system, for one reason or
        another, may not know how to handle. A transaction is considered
        unassigned if the affected Item Site does not have a Cost Category
        assigned to it for the transaction type in question. By specifying an
        Account to post unassigned transactions to, you can remove most of the
        ambiguous error messages that may result from inadequately assigned
        Item Site Cost Categories. For example, if an Inventory Asset Account
        is not defined, Inventory transactions may proceed--but the Asset
        portion of the transactions will be posted to the unassigned
        transaction Account.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Inventory Warehouse</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x181a6b8">
        <para>Select if the Warehouse is to be used for Inventory storage. The
        following options are available for Inventory Warehouses:</para>
        <para>Next <indexterm significance="normal">
            <primary>bills of lading</primary>
            <secondary>numbering of</secondary>
          </indexterm>Bill of Lading #: There are two parts to this field.
        These two parts include a "prefix" that will appear at the beginning
        of all system-generated bill of lading numbers for this Warehouse and
        a starting number sequence (e.g., 10000, 20000, etc.). Use the first
        field window to prefix the bill of lading number with user-defined
        information (e.g., Warehouse code). Prefixing bill of lading numbers
        may be helpful in tracking Items that were shipped to customers from a
        specific Warehouse Location. Use the second part of this two-part
        field window to enter an unlimited number of whole numbers.</para>
        <para>Next <indexterm significance="normal">
            <primary>count tags</primary>
            <secondary>numbering of</secondary>
          </indexterm>Count Tag#: There are two parts to this field. These two
        parts include a "prefix" that will appear at the beginning of all
        system-generated Count Tag Numbers for this Warehouse and a starting
        number sequence (e.g., 10000, 20000, etc.). Use the first field window
        to prefix the Count Tag Number with user-defined information (e.g.,
        Warehouse code). Use the second part of this two-part field window to
        enter an unlimited number of whole numbers.</para>
        <para>
<indexterm significance="normal">
            <primary>shipping warehouses</primary>
            <secondary>designation of</secondary>
          </indexterm>Shipping Warehouse: Select if the Warehouse is used for
        Shipping. Not selecting means materials are not shipped from the
        Warehouse.</para>
        <para>Force the use of Count Slips: Select to enforce
        the use of Count Slips. Not selecting means Count Slips will not be
        required when counting Inventory in this Warehouse.</para>
        <para>
<indexterm significance="normal">
            <primary>zones</primary>
            <secondary>enforcing in warehouses</secondary>
          </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
            <primary>warehouses</primary>
            <secondary>enforcing zones in</secondary>
          </indexterm>Enforce the use of Zones: Select to enforce the use of
        Zones within the Warehouse. A Warehouse Zone is a defined section or
        area within a Warehouse. For example, separate Warehouse Zones might
        be designated to define areas where Orders are selected, Picked, and
        Packed. If selected, Zones may be specified when defining Warehouse
        Locations. If not selected, Warehouse Locations may not include
        Zones.</para>
        <para>Shipping Commission: Enter a commission
        percentage to be charged whenever Inventory is shipped from the
        Warehouse. This is an optional feature to be used specifically for
        contract Warehouses, which charge a commission based on shipping
        volume. If the Warehouse does not charge a commission, then this field
        may be ignored, leaving the default value of "0.00".</para>
        <para>
<indexterm significance="normal">
            <primary>tax authorities</primary>
            <secondary>for warehouses</secondary>
          </indexterm>Tax Authority: Specify the Tax Authority associated with
        the Warehouse.</para>
        <para>
<indexterm significance="normal">
            <primary>default FOB</primary>
            <secondary>in warehouse master</secondary>
          </indexterm>Default F.O.B.: Enter default free on board (FOB) Terms
        for the Warehouse. The default F.O.B. Terms will be entered on the
        Sales Order header for any Orders where the Warehouse is specified as
        the Shipping Warehouse.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para role="openmfg">Transit Warehouses are special
  Warehouses used by Transfer Orders. When Transfer Order Inventory is shipped
  from the Source Warehouse, it is moved to a Transit Warehouse. Inventory
  stays in the Transit Warehouse until it is received at the Destination
  Warehouse. If the Warehouse is to be used as a Transit Warehouse, select the
  "Transit Warehouse" option. The following changes to the main screen will
  appear:</para>
  <para>
<screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/IM_MI_warehouseTransNew.png" id="Graphic663280"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption663283">Create New Transit Warehouse</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
</para>
  <tip>
    <para>Be sure to define a default Transit Warehouse on
    your Inventory Configuration screen. This will make it easier to generate
    Transfer Orders, as Transit Warehouses are required for Transfer
    Orders.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>When defining a Warehouse as a Transit Warehouse, you
  are presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Default Ship Via</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x181a9ac">
        <para>Specify a default Ship Via to be used by the Transit
        Warehouse.</para>
        <para>The selected Ship Via will be used by default on
        the Transfer Order header whenever the specified Transit Warehouse is
        used.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Default Shipping Form</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x181a9f4">
        <para>Specify a default Shipping Form to be used by the Transit
        Warehouse.</para>
        <para>The selected Shipping Form will be used by
        default on the Transfer Order header whenever the specified Transit
        Warehouse is used.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>The Shipping Form will be used when printing Packing
    Lists for the Transfer Order.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Default Cost Category</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x181aa84">
        <para>Specify a default Cost Category to be used by the Transit
        Warehouse.</para>
        <para>Associating a Cost Category with a Transit
        Warehouse makes it possible for the system to create Item Sites for
        Transit Warehouses automatically when Transfer Order Inventory is
        shipped. This greatly simplifies the use of Transit Warehouses, as
        Item Sites do not need to be created manually beforehand. The
        accounting for in-transit goods is handled by the default Cost
        Category associated with the Transit Warehouse.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>Consider creating a separate Cost Category for
    Transit Warehouses. In this way you can use unique Accounts to reflect the
    movement of Inventory which is in-transit.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Shipping Comments</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x181ab14">
        <para>Enter shipping Comments you want to associate with the Transit
        Warehouse.</para>
        <para>Shipping Comments entered here will be used on
        any Transfer Order which uses specified Transit Warehouse. This is a
        scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering shipping
        Comments.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons
  are available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x181ab80">
        <para>Closes the screen without creating a Warehouse, returning you to
        the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x181abc8">
        <para>Creates the Warehouse and adds it to the master list of
        Warehouses.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To define ARBL (Aisle, Rack, Bin, Location) naming
  conventions for your Warehouse Locations, select the "Warehouse Locations"
  tab. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para>
<screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/IM_MI_wareMasterLocs.png" id="Graphic662518"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption662520">Warehouse Locations Master List</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
</para>
  <para>When defining ARBL naming conventions for your
  Warehouse Locations, you are presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>
<indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>ARBL</primary>
          <secondary>enforcing in warehouses</secondary>
        </indexterm>Enforce ARBL Naming Convention</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1830ed8">
        <para>Select to enforce the aisle, rack, bin, Location (ARBL) naming
        convention when defining Warehouse Locations. Specify values for the
        following ARBL parameters:</para>
        <para>Aisle Size: Specify the maximum number of
        characters allowed in an aisle name by using the arrow buttons or
        manually entering a value up to a maximum of 99. Also specify whether
        alpha characters are allowed in aisle names.</para>
        <para>Rack Size: Specify the maximum number of
        characters allowed in a rack name by using the arrow buttons or
        manually entering a value up to a maximum of 99. Also specify whether
        alpha characters are allowed in rack names.</para>
        <para>Bin Size: Specify the maximum number of
        characters allowed in a bin name by using the arrow buttons or
        manually entering a value up to a maximum of 99. Also specify whether
        alpha characters are allowed in bin names.</para>
        <para>Location Size: Specify the maximum number of
        characters allowed in a Location name by using the arrow buttons or
        manually entering a value up to a maximum of 99. Also specify whether
        alpha characters are allowed in Location names.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>Warehouse Zones are defined sections or areas within a
  Warehouse. For example, separate Warehouse Zones might be designated to
  define areas where Orders are selected, Picked, and Packed. To define or
  maintain Warehouse Zones, select the "Warehouse Zones" tab. The following
  screen will appear:</para>
  <para>
<screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/IM_MI_wareMasterZones.png" id="Graphic662535"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption662537">Warehouse Zones Master List</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
</para>
  <para>When defining or maintaining Warehouse Zones, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>
<indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>zones</primary>
          <secondary>for warehouses</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>warehouses</primary>
          <secondary>zones for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Warehouse Zones</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1831040">
        <para>Display includes Warehouse Zones for the specified
        Warehouse.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons
  are available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18310ac">
        <para>Opens screen for creating a new Warehouse Zone.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>EDIT</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18310f4">
        <para>Enables you to edit highlighted Warehouse Zones. The edit screen
        is the same as that for creating a new Warehouse Zone--except that
        when editing, the fields will contain Warehouse Zone information.
        Double-clicking on a Warehouse Zone also bring you to the editing
        screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>DELETE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x183113c">
        <para>Highlight a Warehouse Zone and then select this button to remove
        the Zone from the list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>warehouses</primary>
      <secondary>creating zones in</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>zones</primary>
      <secondary>creating new in warehouse</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>warehouse zones</primary>
      <secondary>creating new</secondary>
    </indexterm>create a new Warehouse Zone, select the NEW button. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para>
<screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/IM_MI_wareZoneNew.png" id="Graphic662761"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption662764">Create New Warehouse Zone</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
</para>
  <para>When creating a new Warehouse Zone, you are presented
  with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Name</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18312ec">
        <para>Enter a unique name for the Warehouse Zone.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Description</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1831334">
        <para>Enter a brief description of the Warehouse Zone.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons
  are available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18313a0">
        <para>Closes the screen without adding a new Warehouse Zone to the
        list of Warehouse Zones.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18313e8">
        <para>Creates the Warehouse Zone and adds it to the list of Warehouse
        Zones.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To associate Comments with a Warehouse, select the
  "Comments" tab. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para>
<screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/IM_MI_warehouseComm.png" id="Graphic594394"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption594325">Add Warehouse Comments</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Comments</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18314c0">
        <para>Display lists the date Comment entered, Comment Type, user who
        entered Comment, and a content preview.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons
  are available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x183152c">
        <para>Opens screen for creating a new Comment.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>VIEW</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1831574">
        <para>Highlight a Comment and then select this button to reach a
        read-only view of the Comment.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To create a new Comment, select the NEW button. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para>
<screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/CommentNew.png" id="Graphic594333"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption594336">Create New Comment</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Comment Type</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x183164c">
        <para>Specify one of the following Comment Types from the drop-down
        list: ChangeLog or General.</para>
        <para>Comment Types are used to categorize Comments.
        Once you have specified a Comment Type, you may type your Comment in
        the main text area. The text area features word-wrapping and
        scroll-bar support for longer Comments.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons
  are available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18316b8">
        <para>Closes the screen without creating the Comment, returning you to
        the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1831700">
        <para>Creates the Comment and adds it to the list of Comments.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
