<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.3//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.3/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section518522">
  <title><anchor id="Anchor552120" role="Index"
  xreflabel="warehouses:master list of" /> <indexterm significance="normal"
      zone="Anchor552120">
      <primary>warehouses</primary>
      <secondary>master list of</secondary>
    </indexterm>Warehouses</title>
  <para id="Para518523">Warehouses typically describe physical production and
  storage facilities. Work Centers, Item Sites, and Warehouse Locations belong
  to Warehouses. To access the master list of Warehouses, select the
  "Warehouses" option. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para id="Para518527"><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/IM_MI_warehouse.png" id="Graphic525415" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption518528">Warehouses Master List</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para id="Para518529">The "Warehouses" screen displays information on all
  existing Warehouses, including Warehouse code, Warehouse description, and
  Warehouse address. To include inactive Warehouses in the display, select the
  "Show Inactive Warehouses" option.</para>
  <para id="Para518530">To the far right of the screen, the following buttons
  are available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para518531">CLOSE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x181a0d0">
        <para id="Para">Closes the screen, returning you to the application
        desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para518532">PRINT</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x181a118">
        <para id="Para">Runs the report associated with this screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para518533">NEW</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x181a160">
        <para id="Para">Opens screen for creating a new Warehouse.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para518534">EDIT</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x181a1a8">
        <para id="ParaWarehousesEdit">Enables you to edit highlighted
        Warehouses. The edit screen is the same as that for creating a new
        Warehouse--except that when editing, the fields will contain Warehouse
        information. Double-clicking on a Warehouse will also bring you to the
        editing screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para518535">VIEW</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x181a1f0">
        <para id="Para">Highlight a Warehouse and then select this button to
        reach a read-only view of the "Edit" screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para id="Para524217">Right-clicking on a Warehouse in the Warehouses list
  enables you to select from the following menu options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para518537">Edit</term>
      <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                  xpointer="element(listitemN0x180ac00N0x181a1a8)" />
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para518538">View</term>
      <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                  xpointer="element(listitemN0x180ac00N0x181a1f0)" />
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para518539">List Item Sites</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x181a2ec"></listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <xi:include href="../widgets/xtreewidget.xml"
                xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
                xpointer="element(xtreewidget.menu.exportcontents)" />
  </variablelist>
  <para id="Para518541">To <anchor id="Anchor559094" role="Index"
  xreflabel="warehouses:creating new" /> <indexterm significance="normal"
      zone="Anchor559094">
      <primary>warehouses</primary>
      <secondary>creating new</secondary>
    </indexterm>create a new Warehouse, select the NEW button. The following
  screen will appear:</para>
  <para id="Para518545"><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/IM_MI_warehouseNew.png"
                     id="Graphic525430" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption518546">Create New Inventory Warehouse</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <tip>
    <para id="Para529971">Warehouse Codes are abbreviations used to quickly
    and easily identify Warehouses. Keep these Codes short and meaningful so
    employees will have an easy time identifying them.</para>
  </tip>
  <para id="Para518548">When creating a new Warehouse, you are presented with
  the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para518552">Code</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x181a478">
        <para id="Para">The Warehouse code is used to identify a given
        Warehouse.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para555667">Active</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x181a4c0">
        <para id="Para">Select to specify the Warehouse is active.</para>
        <para id="Para628603">Not selecting means the Warehouse will be
        considered inactive. To re-activate a Warehouse, simply select this
        option.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para628607">Description</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x181a508">
        <para id="Para">Enter a brief description of the Warehouse.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para id="Para633951">If a new Address is manually entered here, that
    Address will be added automatically to the master list of
    Addresses.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para633907">Address</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x181a598">
        <para id="Para">Manually enter Address information in the fields
        below--or use the browse button to select pre-existing Address
        information. The Warehouse Address is used on shipping and receiving
        paperwork.</para>
        <para id="Para633897">Street Address: Enter the street Address for the
        Warehouse.</para>
        <para id="Para633898">City: Enter the city where the Warehouse is
        located.</para>
        <para id="Para633899">State: Enter the state where the Warehouse is
        located.</para>
        <para id="Para633900">Postal Code: Enter the Postal Code for the
        Warehouse.</para>
        <para id="Para633901">Country: Enter the country where the Warehouse
        is located.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para id="Para633956">If a new Contact is manually entered here, that
    Contact will be added automatically to the master list of Contacts.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para633880">Contact</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x181a628">
        <para id="Para">Manually enter Contact information in the fields
        below--or use the browse button to select pre-existing Contact
        information.</para>
        <para id="Para633881">Title: Select a Title from the list of available
        Titles.</para>
        <para id="Para633882">First: Enter the Contact's first name.</para>
        <para id="Para633883">Last: Enter the Contact's last name.</para>
        <para id="Para634869">Job Title: Enter the Contact's job title.</para>
        <para id="Para633884">Voice: Enter the Contact's phone number.</para>
        <para id="Para633885">Fax: Enter the Contact's fax number.</para>
        <para id="Para633886">E-Mail: Enter the Contact's e-mail
        address.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para662823">Post Unassigned Transactions to</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x181a670">
        <para id="Para">Specify a General Ledger Account to post unassigned
        transactions to.</para>
        <para id="Para662824">This account is used as a general bucket for
        General Ledger transactions which the system, for one reason or
        another, may not know how to handle. A transaction is considered
        unassigned if the affected Item Site does not have a Cost Category
        assigned to it for the transaction type in question. By specifying an
        Account to post unassigned transactions to, you can remove most of the
        ambiguous error messages that may result from inadequately assigned
        Item Site Cost Categories. For example, if an Inventory Asset Account
        is not defined, Inventory transactions may proceed--but the Asset
        portion of the transactions will be posted to the unassigned
        transaction Account.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para662841">Inventory Warehouse</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x181a6b8">
        <para id="Para">Select if the Warehouse is to be used for Inventory
        storage. The following options are available for Inventory
        Warehouses:</para>
        <para id="Para662855">Next <anchor id="Anchor662617" role="Index"
        xreflabel="bills of lading:numbering of" /> <indexterm
            significance="normal" zone="Anchor662617">
            <primary>bills of lading</primary>
            <secondary>numbering of</secondary>
          </indexterm>Bill of Lading #: There are two parts to this field.
        These two parts include a "prefix" that will appear at the beginning
        of all system-generated bill of lading numbers for this Warehouse and
        a starting number sequence (e.g., 10000, 20000, etc.). Use the first
        field window to prefix the bill of lading number with user-defined
        information (e.g., Warehouse code). Prefixing bill of lading numbers
        may be helpful in tracking Items that were shipped to customers from a
        specific Warehouse Location. Use the second part of this two-part
        field window to enter an unlimited number of whole numbers.</para>
        <para id="Para662858">Next <anchor id="Anchor662619" role="Index"
        xreflabel="count tags:numbering of" /> <indexterm
            significance="normal" zone="Anchor662619">
            <primary>count tags</primary>
            <secondary>numbering of</secondary>
          </indexterm>Count Tag#: There are two parts to this field. These two
        parts include a "prefix" that will appear at the beginning of all
        system-generated Count Tag Numbers for this Warehouse and a starting
        number sequence (e.g., 10000, 20000, etc.). Use the first field window
        to prefix the Count Tag Number with user-defined information (e.g.,
        Warehouse code). Use the second part of this two-part field window to
        enter an unlimited number of whole numbers.</para>
        <para id="Para662861"><anchor id="Anchor662621" role="Index"
        xreflabel="shipping warehouses:designation of" /> <indexterm
            significance="normal" zone="Anchor662621">
            <primary>shipping warehouses</primary>
            <secondary>designation of</secondary>
          </indexterm>Shipping Warehouse: Select if the Warehouse is used for
        Shipping. Not selecting means materials are not shipped from the
        Warehouse.</para>
        <para id="Para662866">Force the use of Count Slips: Select to enforce
        the use of Count Slips. Not selecting means Count Slips will not be
        required when counting Inventory in this Warehouse.</para>
        <para id="Para662871"><anchor id="Anchor662626" role="Index"
        xreflabel="zones:enforcing in warehouses;warehouses:enforcing zones in" />
        <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor662626">
            <primary>zones</primary>
            <secondary>enforcing in warehouses</secondary>
          </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor662626">
            <primary>warehouses</primary>
            <secondary>enforcing zones in</secondary>
          </indexterm>Enforce the use of Zones: Select to enforce the use of
        Zones within the Warehouse. A Warehouse Zone is a defined section or
        area within a Warehouse. For example, separate Warehouse Zones might
        be designated to define areas where Orders are selected, Picked, and
        Packed. If selected, Zones may be specified when defining Warehouse
        Locations. If not selected, Warehouse Locations may not include
        Zones.</para>
        <para id="Para662876">Shipping Commission: Enter a commission
        percentage to be charged whenever Inventory is shipped from the
        Warehouse. This is an optional feature to be used specifically for
        contract Warehouses, which charge a commission based on shipping
        volume. If the Warehouse does not charge a commission, then this field
        may be ignored, leaving the default value of "0.00".</para>
        <para id="Para662929"><anchor id="Anchor662928" role="Index"
        xreflabel="tax authorities:for warehouses" /> <indexterm
            significance="normal" zone="Anchor662928">
            <primary>tax authorities</primary>
            <secondary>for warehouses</secondary>
          </indexterm>Tax Authority: Specify the Tax Authority associated with
        the Warehouse.</para>
        <para id="Para662895"><anchor id="Anchor662894" role="Index"
        xreflabel="default FOB:in warehouse master" /> <indexterm
            significance="normal" zone="Anchor662894">
            <primary>default FOB</primary>
            <secondary>in warehouse master</secondary>
          </indexterm>Default F.O.B.: Enter default free on board (FOB) Terms
        for the Warehouse. The default F.O.B. Terms will be entered on the
        Sales Order header for any Orders where the Warehouse is specified as
        the Shipping Warehouse.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para id="Para663278" role="openmfg">Transit Warehouses are special
  Warehouses used by Transfer Orders. When Transfer Order Inventory is shipped
  from the Source Warehouse, it is moved to a Transit Warehouse. Inventory
  stays in the Transit Warehouse until it is received at the Destination
  Warehouse. If the Warehouse is to be used as a Transit Warehouse, select the
  "Transit Warehouse" option. The following changes to the main screen will
  appear:</para>
  <para id="Para663282"><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/IM_MI_warehouseTransNew.png"
                     id="Graphic663280" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption663283">Create New Transit Warehouse</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <tip>
    <para id="Para664202">Be sure to define a default Transit Warehouse on
    your Inventory Configuration screen. This will make it easier to generate
    Transfer Orders, as Transit Warehouses are required for Transfer
    Orders.</para>
  </tip>
  <para id="Para662483">When defining a Warehouse as a Transit Warehouse, you
  are presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para663039">Default Ship Via</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x181a9ac">
        <para id="Para">Specify a default Ship Via to be used by the Transit
        Warehouse.</para>
        <para id="Para663040">The selected Ship Via will be used by default on
        the Transfer Order header whenever the specified Transit Warehouse is
        used.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para663041">Default Shipping Form</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x181a9f4">
        <para id="Para">Specify a default Shipping Form to be used by the
        Transit Warehouse.</para>
        <para id="Para663042">The selected Shipping Form will be used by
        default on the Transfer Order header whenever the specified Transit
        Warehouse is used.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para id="Para664084">The Shipping Form will be used when printing Packing
    Lists for the Transfer Order.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para663107">Default Cost Category</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x181aa84">
        <para id="Para">Specify a default Cost Category to be used by the
        Transit Warehouse.</para>
        <para id="Para663108">Associating a Cost Category with a Transit
        Warehouse makes it possible for the system to create Item Sites for
        Transit Warehouses automatically when Transfer Order Inventory is
        shipped. This greatly simplifies the use of Transit Warehouses, as
        Item Sites do not need to be created manually beforehand. The
        accounting for in-transit goods is handled by the default Cost
        Category associated with the Transit Warehouse.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para id="Para663129">Consider creating a separate Cost Category for
    Transit Warehouses. In this way you can use unique Accounts to reflect the
    movement of Inventory which is in-transit.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para663125">Shipping Comments</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x181ab14">
        <para id="Para">Enter shipping Comments you want to associate with the
        Transit Warehouse.</para>
        <para id="Para663150">Shipping Comments entered here will be used on
        any Transfer Order which uses specified Transit Warehouse. This is a
        scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering shipping
        Comments.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para id="Para662834">To the far right of the screen, the following buttons
  are available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para662835">CANCEL</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x181ab80">
        <para id="Para">Closes the screen without creating a Warehouse,
        returning you to the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para662836">SAVE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x181abc8">
        <para id="Para">Creates the Warehouse and adds it to the master list
        of Warehouses.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para id="Para663173">To define ARBL (Aisle, Rack, Bin, Location) naming
  conventions for your Warehouse Locations, select the "Warehouse Locations"
  tab. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para id="Para662519"><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/IM_MI_wareMasterLocs.png"
                     id="Graphic662518" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption662520">Warehouse Locations Master List</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para id="Para662515">When defining ARBL naming conventions for your
  Warehouse Locations, you are presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para662682"><anchor id="Anchor662681" role="Index"
      xreflabel="ARBL:enforcing in warehouses" /> <indexterm
          significance="normal" zone="Anchor662681">
          <primary>ARBL</primary>
          <secondary>enforcing in warehouses</secondary>
        </indexterm>Enforce ARBL Naming Convention</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1830ed8">
        <para id="Para">Select to enforce the aisle, rack, bin, Location
        (ARBL) naming convention when defining Warehouse Locations. Specify
        values for the following ARBL parameters:</para>
        <para id="Para662683">Aisle Size: Specify the maximum number of
        characters allowed in an aisle name by using the arrow buttons or
        manually entering a value up to a maximum of 99. Also specify whether
        alpha characters are allowed in aisle names.</para>
        <para id="Para662684">Rack Size: Specify the maximum number of
        characters allowed in a rack name by using the arrow buttons or
        manually entering a value up to a maximum of 99. Also specify whether
        alpha characters are allowed in rack names.</para>
        <para id="Para662685">Bin Size: Specify the maximum number of
        characters allowed in a bin name by using the arrow buttons or
        manually entering a value up to a maximum of 99. Also specify whether
        alpha characters are allowed in bin names.</para>
        <para id="Para662686">Location Size: Specify the maximum number of
        characters allowed in a Location name by using the arrow buttons or
        manually entering a value up to a maximum of 99. Also specify whether
        alpha characters are allowed in Location names.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para id="Para662530">Warehouse Zones are defined sections or areas within a
  Warehouse. For example, separate Warehouse Zones might be designated to
  define areas where Orders are selected, Picked, and Packed. To define or
  maintain Warehouse Zones, select the "Warehouse Zones" tab. The following
  screen will appear:</para>
  <para id="Para662536"><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/IM_MI_wareMasterZones.png"
                     id="Graphic662535" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption662537">Warehouse Zones Master List</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para id="Para662532">When defining or maintaining Warehouse Zones, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para662750"><anchor id="Anchor662749" role="Index"
      xreflabel="zones:for warehouses;warehouses:zones for" /> <indexterm
          significance="normal" zone="Anchor662749">
          <primary>zones</primary>
          <secondary>for warehouses</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor662749">
          <primary>warehouses</primary>
          <secondary>zones for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Warehouse Zones</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1831040">
        <para id="Para">Display includes Warehouse Zones for the specified
        Warehouse.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para id="Para662752">To the far right of the screen, the following buttons
  are available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para662755">NEW</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18310ac">
        <para id="Para">Opens screen for creating a new Warehouse Zone.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para662756">EDIT</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18310f4">
        <para id="Para">Enables you to edit highlighted Warehouse Zones. The
        edit screen is the same as that for creating a new Warehouse
        Zone--except that when editing, the fields will contain Warehouse Zone
        information. Double-clicking on a Warehouse Zone also bring you to the
        editing screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para662757">DELETE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x183113c">
        <para id="Para">Highlight a Warehouse Zone and then select this button
        to remove the Zone from the list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para id="Para662759">To <anchor id="Anchor662758" role="Index"
  xreflabel="warehouses:creating zones in;zones:creating new in warehouse;warehouse zones:creating new" />
  <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor662758">
      <primary>warehouses</primary>
      <secondary>creating zones in</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor662758">
      <primary>zones</primary>
      <secondary>creating new in warehouse</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal" zone="Anchor662758">
      <primary>warehouse zones</primary>
      <secondary>creating new</secondary>
    </indexterm>create a new Warehouse Zone, select the NEW button. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para id="Para662763"><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/IM_MI_wareZoneNew.png" id="Graphic662761" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption662764">Create New Warehouse Zone</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para id="Para662765">When creating a new Warehouse Zone, you are presented
  with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para662766">Name</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18312ec">
        <para id="Para">Enter a unique name for the Warehouse Zone.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para662767">Description</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1831334">
        <para id="Para">Enter a brief description of the Warehouse
        Zone.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para id="Para662768">To the far right of the screen, the following buttons
  are available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para662769">CANCEL</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18313a0">
        <para id="Para">Closes the screen without adding a new Warehouse Zone
        to the list of Warehouse Zones.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para662770">SAVE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18313e8">
        <para id="Para">Creates the Warehouse Zone and adds it to the list of
        Warehouse Zones.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para id="Para662497">To associate Comments with a Warehouse, select the
  "Comments" tab. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para id="Para594324"><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/IM_MI_warehouseComm.png"
                     id="Graphic594394" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption594325">Add Warehouse Comments</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para594326">Comments</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18314c0">
        <para id="Para">Display lists the date Comment entered, Comment Type,
        user who entered Comment, and a content preview.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para id="Para594328">To the far right of the screen, the following buttons
  are available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para594329">NEW</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x183152c">
        <para id="Para">Opens screen for creating a new Comment.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para594330">VIEW</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1831574">
        <para id="Para">Highlight a Comment and then select this button to
        reach a read-only view of the Comment.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para id="Para594331">To create a new Comment, select the NEW button. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para id="Para594335"><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/CommentNew.png" id="Graphic594333" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="Caption594336">Create New Comment</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para594340">Comment Type</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x183164c">
        <para id="Para">Specify one of the following Comment Types from the
        drop-down list: ChangeLog or General.</para>
        <para id="Para594341">Comment Types are used to categorize Comments.
        Once you have specified a Comment Type, you may type your Comment in
        the main text area. The text area features word-wrapping and
        scroll-bar support for longer Comments.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para id="Para594342">To the far right of the screen, the following buttons
  are available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para594343">CANCEL</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x18316b8">
        <para id="Para">Closes the screen without creating the Comment,
        returning you to the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para653109">SAVE</term>
      <listitem id="listitemN0x180ac00N0x1831700">
        <para id="Para">Creates the Comment and adds it to the list of
        Comments.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>