<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section518517">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>work orders</primary>
      <secondary>creating new</secondary>
    </indexterm>Create New Work Order</title>
  <para>Work Orders define requirements for the production of manufactured
  Items. These Items may have a Bill of Materials (BOM)--or not. The system
  supports both BOM-based and non-BOM-based Work Orders.</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>BOM-based</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Material Requirements are drawn from the Bill of Materials when
        the Work Order is exploded, using the specified Revision. Users may
        add or subtract Material Requirements as needed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Non-BOM-based</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Ideal for labor-only Work Orders having a Bill of Operations
        (BOO) but no BOM--for example, service Work Orders which require labor
        Operations only. Also good for Items or Jobs where the Material
        Requirements are not-known--but must be added on an ad-hoc
        basis.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To create a new Work Order, select the "Create New Work Order" option.
  The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/workOrder.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create New Work Order</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <tip>
    <para>To edit a Work Order after it has been created, use the right-click
    menu in any of the "Work Order Schedule by..." displays. There you will
    find an "Edit W/O" option.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>When creating a new Work Order, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Work Order #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Next available Work Order Number will automatically display,
        unless your system requires you to enter Work Order Numbers manually.
        Default values and input parameters for Work Order Numbers are
        configurable at the system level.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the Item Number of the manufactured Item you want to
        create a Work Order for.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Inventory Unit of Measure.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Warehouse</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify supplying Warehouse for selected Item. Only Warehouses
        that contain supplying Item Sites for the selected Item may be
        chosen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>Order Parameters may have an impact on Work Order quantity if the
    "on Manual Orders" option is selected in the Item Site master for a
    manufactured Item. If Order Parameters are in effect, the Work Order must
    conform to those restrictions. Both Minimum Order size and Order Multiple
    may be governed by Order Parameter settings.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. Ordered</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Value entered specifies the number of Item units to be processed
        by the Work Order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. Received</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the quantity of finished product posted as received
        into Inventory to date, if any.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>work orders</primary>
          <secondary>adjusting lead times for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Lead Time (Days)</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select a number using the arrow buttons, or manually enter a
        value up to a maximum of 999. Value entered specifies the
        manufacturing Lead Time required between the date the Work Order
        starts and the date it is due. Lead Times for Items are specified in
        the Item Site master, but may be modified on this screen.</para>
        <tip>
          <para>The Lead Time option is only available when creating a new
          Work Order. Once the Order is created, this option will not be
          visible.</para>
        </tip>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Due Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the date the Work Order must be completed by.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Start Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the date the Work Order must be started by. By default,
        this date will be the due date less the Lead Time. The start date may
        be changed by altering the Lead Time field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Priority</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select a number using the arrow buttons, or manually enter a
        value up to a maximum of 99. Value entered assigns a priority to the
        selected Work Order. By assigning a priority to a Work Order, you can
        indicate the relative importance of a Work Order in comparison to
        other Work Orders.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Project #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select a Project Number to associate with the Work Order. If the
        Work Order was created from Sales Order demand--and the parent Sales
        Order had a Project Number associated with it--then the Project Number
        from the parent Sales Order will automatically be entered here. In
        this way, Sales Orders and Work Orders may be linked to the same
        Project.</para>
        <note>
          <para>The option to associate a Project with a Work Order will only
          be visible if your site is configured to use Projects.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Production Notes</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        production Notes related to the Work Order. Production Notes are
        printed on Pick Lists and Packing Lists for reference by production
        personnel.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>If a Work Order was created from a Sales Order, the Production Notes
    field will contain the Sales Order Number, the Customer Name, and any
    additional Sales Order Line Item Notes.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Print Traveler</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to print a Work Order Traveler when the Work Order is
        created. This option will no longer be available once the Work Order
        is created.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Creates the Work Order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without creating the Work Order, returning you
        to the application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>If an Item has Characteristics associated with it, you have the option
  of linking those Characteristics to a Work Order Item. And, in the case
  where a Work Order is generated from a linked Sales Order, the Work Order
  will inherit Characteristics defined at the Sales Order level.</para>
  <tip>
    <para>You can link Characteristics and Values to an Item by using the Item
    master. Once entered, these Characteristics and Values will be available
    to users entering Sales Order Line Items.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>To associate Characteristics with a Work Order Item, select the
  "Characteristics" tab at the bottom of the screen, as shown below:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/workOrder_itemchar.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Work Order Characteristics</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>When specifying Characteristics for a Work Order Item, you
  are presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the name of any Item Characteristics associated with
        the Item. Characteristics defined as Item Characteristics may be
        associated with Items on the Item master.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Value</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the default Value associated with an Item
        Characteristic, but permits you to specify an alternate Value. When
        associating Characteristic Values with a Work Order Item, you have
        four options: 1) Select the default Value; 2) select an alternate
        pre-defined Value; 3) manually enter a new Value in place of the
        pre-defined Value; or 4) make no selection. Making no selection means
        the Characteristics will not be associated with the Work Order
        Item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To create or view Comments related to a Work Order, select the
  "Comments" tab. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/workOrder_TabPage.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Add Work Order Comments</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <note>
    <para>Work Order Comments may not be added at the time of Work Order
    creation. Instead, use the Production Notes tab for entering Notes related
    to a Work Order.</para>
  </note>
  <para>When creating or viewing Comments related to a Work Order, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Comments</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists Comments for the specified Order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>Once a Work Order is in process--that is, either materials have been
  issued or Production or Operations have been posted--you can begin to view
  Costing information for the Work Order. To view Costing information for the
  Work Order, select the "Costing" tab. The following screen will
  appear:</para>
  <para><tip>
      <para>The Costing tab will not be visible until after a Work Order has
      been created. You will not see Costing information when creating a Work
      Order.</para>
    </tip><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/workOrder_costing.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Work Order Costing</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>When viewing Work Order Costing information, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Accumulated Costs</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Information about the following categories of currently
        accumulated Work Order Costs will be shown:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Posted</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displayes the current posted value of the Work Order. The
              posted value is equal to the received value of finished goods
              minus WIP.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Received</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the current value of finished goods received into
              Inventory from the Work Order.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>WIP</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the current value of Work in Process (WIP) for
              the Work Order.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para role="openmfg">When creating a Work Order, you have the option to
  specify which Revision of the Work Order Item's Bill of Materials and Bill
  of Operations you want to use. By default, the active Revision will be used.
  Once the Work Order has been created, these options will become read-only.
  To specify Revision information for a Work Order Item, select the "Revision"
  tab. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para role=""><screenshot role="openmfg">
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/workOrder_revision.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Revision Information</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <note>
    <para>You may create Work Orders for pending Revisions. For Work Order
    purposes, a pending Revision is considered to be the same as an inactive
    Revision. The Revision status of a pending Revision will not be changed if
    a Work Order is created for it.</para>
  </note>
  <para role="openmfg">When specifying Revision information for a Work Order
  Item, you are presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist role="openmfg">
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Bill of Materials</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the BOM Revision you want to use for the Work Order. By
        default, the active Revision will be used.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Revision</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select from the list of existing available Revisions. The
              status of the Revision will also be displayed.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Bill of Operations</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the BOO Revision you want to use for the Work Order. By
        default, the active Revision will be used.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Revision</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select from the list of existing available Revisions. The
              status of the Revision will also be displayed.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>