<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2008 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section559720">
  <title>Shop Floor Workbench</title>
  <para>The Shop Floor Workbench offers enhanced labor tracking and
  streamlined Work Order processing for either Operations or Production
  posting environments. Its built-in Time Clock functionality ensures precise
  run-time reporting. Workbench users are required to clock-in to and
  clock-out of Work Orders.</para>
  <tip>
    <para>The clock-in requirement applies only to Shop Floor Workbench users.
    If you don"t use the Workbench, no clock-in is required.</para>
  </tip>
  <note role="openmfg">
    <para>This section description includes references to both Operations and
    Production posting. Operations posting is only allowed in the OpenMFG edition
    of xTuple ERP.
    </para>
  </note>
  <para>To access the Shop Floor Workbench, select the "Shop Floor Workbench"
  option. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para>
<screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/woTimeClock.png"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Shop Floor Workbench</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
</para>
  <note>
    <para>The Shop Floor Workbench must be configured for either Operations
    posting or Production posting. You may not use the Workbench for both
    methods simultaneously. To configure the method used by the Shop Floor
    Workbench, use the Configure W/O screen in the System module.</para>
  </note>
  <para>When accessing the Shop Floor Workbench, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Username</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the name of the user wanting to clock-in or clock-out of a
        Work Order. Once a username is entered, the display at the bottom of
        the screen will show all the Work Orders the user is currently
        clocked-in to.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>At the system level, you can restrict a user's privileges so the
    Shop Floor Workbench is the only interface they see when they log in to
    the application.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Work Order #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the Work Order Number of the Work Order the user wants to
        clock-in to or clock-out of. Only released "R" and in-process "I" Work
        Orders may be processed using the Shop Floor Workbench.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>A Work Order must be released "R" before users may clock-in or clock
    out. The release of a Work Order occurs after the Work Order has been
    exploded.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Whs.</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays Warehouse code automatically when Work Order Number is
        entered into "Work Order #" field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays Item Number automatically when Work Order Number is
        entered into "Work Order #" field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Inventory Unit of Measure.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Status</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays Work Order Status automatically when Work Order Number
        is entered into "Work Order #" field. Only released "R" and in-process
        "I" Work Orders may be processed using the Shop Floor
        Workbench.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="openmfg">
      <term>Operation</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>If the Workbench is configured for Operations-posting, select an
        Operation from the list of Operations. Users are required to clock-in
        and clock-out of individual Operations. This allows run-time
        calculations to be performed on an Operation-by-Operation basis. A
        user may be clocked-in to multiple Operations simultaneously. Also,
        multiple users may be clocked-in to the same Operation. Whatever the
        case, the run-time clock starts when a user(s) clocks in to an
        Operation, and it stops when the user(s) clocks out.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CLOSE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without clocking-in or clocking-out, returning
        you to the application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CLOCK IN</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to clock-in to the specified Work Order. When a user
        clocks-in to a Work Order, the run-time clock starts running from that
        point. The clock stops when a user clocks-out of the Work Order. The
        elapsed time--or "effort"--is used for labor reporting purposes. Users
        may only clock-in to Work Orders they are not already clocked-in to.
        However, users may clock-in to and clock-out of the same Work Order as
        many times as necessary. Each clock-in starts the run-time Time Clock;
        each clock-out stops it.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CLOCK OUT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to clock-out of the specified Work Order. When selected,
        the run-time clock stops for the specified Work Order. The time
        elapsed since the user last clocked-in is added to the run time total
        for the Work Order. This run-time calculation is automatic and cannot
        be overridden--except by users who have override privileges. Users may
        only clock-out of Work Orders they are already clocked-in to. If the
        Workbench is configured for Operations-posting, the "Post Operations"
        screen will be presented immediately after the CLOCK OUT button is
        selected. By default, the "Scrap Work Order Material from W/O" screen
        will immediately follow the "Post Operations" screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>Shop Floor Workbench users should only scrap top-level Items after
    they have posted production sufficient to cover the scrap quantity. For
    example, if a user assembles 10 top-level Items successfully but
    significantly damages the 11th, the user should post a quantity of 11
    produced and then scrap one (i.e., 11 - 1 = 10).</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>POST PRODUCTION</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>If the Workbench is configured for Production-posting, the Post
        Production screen will be presented immediately after this button is
        selected. The button will be hidden if the Workbench is configured for
        Operations-posting.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
