<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2008 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<chapter id="Chapter464102">
  <title><anchor id="Anchor23250" role="Cross-Ref"
  xreflabel="23250: ChapterTitleNoNumber: Introduction" />Introduction</title>
  <para>Welcome to the Reference Guide (formerly User Guide) for xTuple
  Enterprise Resource Planning! This Reference Guide is designed as a
  screen-by-screen reference for anyone using any of the following xTuple ERP
  applications:</para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>xTuple ERP: PostBooks Free Edition <inlinemediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="css/pbicon.jpg" />
          </imageobject>
        </inlinemediaobject></para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>xTuple ERP: Standard Edition <inlinemediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="css/stdicon.jpg" />
          </imageobject>
        </inlinemediaobject></para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>xTuple ERP: OpenMFG Edition <inlinemediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="css/omfgicon.jpg" />
          </imageobject>
        </inlinemediaobject></para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <note>
    <para>If you are looking for more detailed user or developer
    documentation, you can find that and more in the <ulink
    url="http://wiki.xtuple.org/">xTuple wiki</ulink> featured on xTuple's
    <ulink url="http://www.xtuple.org">community website</ulink>.</para>
  </note>
  <para>Since all three applications share a common code base, it makes sense
  that they also share a Reference Guide. OpenMFG contains features Standard
  Edition does not, and Standard Edition contains features that PostBooks does
  not. To highlight these differences, we have placed indicators in the
  Reference Guide. Whenever you see one of these markers, you'll know the
  functionality you're reading about exists in OpenMFG or Standard Edition but
  not in PostBooks.</para>
  <para>For more information on the differences between the xTuple ERP,
  including licensing options, please visit <ulink
  url="http://www.xtuple.com/comparison">www.xtuple.com/comparison</ulink>.</para>
  <section id="Section468080">
    <title>Getting Started</title>
    <para>The goal of this chapter is to orient you to some of the basic
    features of xTuple ERP. As you will see, these fundamentals appear
    throughout the application. We wanted to introduce them to you early so
    you would be familiar with them as you work your way through the xTuple
    Application modules.</para>
    <note>
      <para>The screenshots and examples used throughout this Reference Guide
      are taken from the OpenMFG Client for Windows, running on Windows XP.
      There is no functional difference between the Windows, Mac, or Linux
      Clients. You will find only minor graphical user interface differences.
      The same holds true for the xTuple ERP products.</para>
    </note>
    <para>The next sections describe the steps required to log in to and exit
    xTuple ERP. In some cases, you may need to ask your system administrator
    for information concerning site-specific settings.</para>
    <section id="Section466744">
      <title>Log In Options</title>
      <para>To log in using a Windows client, you should double-click on the
      xTuple ERP icon wherever it appears on your computer desktop. Likewise,
      Macintosh users may click on the xTuple ERP icon from their desktop.
      <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>linux</primary>
          <secondary>client log in procedure</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>windows</primary>
          <secondary>client log in procedure</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>log in</primary>
          <secondary>linux</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>log in</primary>
          <secondary>windows</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>mac</primary>
          <secondary>client log in procedure</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>log in</primary>
          <secondary>mac</secondary>
        </indexterm>Linux users should run the appropriate xTuple ERP .sh file
      to launch the application. The following screen will appear:</para>
      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/INTRO_loginScreen.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>Log In Screen</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <tip>
        <para>You should always be sure to use a version of xTuple ERP which
        matches the version of your xTuple Database. Using mis-matched
        versions can lead to errors and loss of data integrity. The system
        will issue a warning message whenever you attempt to log in to a
        database whose version does not match the client version.</para>
      </tip>
      <para>When logging into xTuple ERP, you are presented with the following
      options:</para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Log in to registered xTuple demo account</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select this option if you are logging in to a demo database
            hosted on an xTuple server. If selected, the OPTIONS button will
            be disabled.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Log in to server I specify</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select this option if you are logging in to any database
            other than an xTuple demo database. If selected, you can specify
            your connection details using the OPTIONS button.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term><indexterm significance="normal">
              <primary>usernames</primary>
              <secondary>required at log in</secondary>
            </indexterm>Username</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Enter your assigned username. Usernames are established by
            your system administrator. The username is case-sensitive.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term><indexterm significance="normal">
              <primary>passwords</primary>
              <secondary>at log in</secondary>
            </indexterm>Password</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Enter your assigned password. Passwords are established by
            your system administrator. The password you type into this field
            will not display on your screen, but will be represented by
            asterisks (*) for security purposes.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Server</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Displays the name of the server you will be connecting
            to.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Database</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Displays the name of the database you will be connecting
            to.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
      <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
      available:</para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>CANCEL</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Closes the screen, returning you to your computer
            desktop.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>LOGIN</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Click to log in to the application.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>OPTIONS</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select to verify or change your connection settings. This
            button will be disabled if logging in to an xTuple demo
            database.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
      <note>
        <para>Most users will not need to change their Login options. If you
        have questions about your option settings, contact your system
        administrator.</para>
      </note>
      <para>To verify or change your connection settings, select the OPTIONS
      button. The following screen will appear:</para>
      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/INTRO_loginOptions.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>Login Options</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <para>When viewing or changing your connection settings, you are
      presented with the following options:</para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term><indexterm significance="normal">
              <primary>servers</primary>
              <secondary>identifying at log in</secondary>
            </indexterm>Server</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Enter the address of the server where your xTuple Database
            is running. The address will consist of either a TCP/IP Address or
            a Network Alias Name. If the network address for the xTuple Server
            changes, you may need to change the address in this field.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term><indexterm significance="normal">
              <primary>databases</primary>
              <secondary>identify at log in</secondary>
            </indexterm>Database</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Enter the name of the xTuple Database you want to connect
            to. The application can be used to connect to multiple xTuple
            databases. Be sure to enter the correct name of the database you
            want to access.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term><indexterm significance="normal">
              <primary>ports</primary>
              <secondary>for database access</secondary>
            </indexterm>Port</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Displays the default port. The default port for the xTuple
            Database is 5432.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term><indexterm significance="normal">
              <primary>authentication</primary>
              <secondary>enhanced</secondary>
            </indexterm>Use Enhanced Authentication</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select if your site requires you to use enhanced
            authentication. Enhanced authentication adds a layer to the
            authentication process used to log in to xTuple ERP. When this
            feature is turned on, user passwords are stored in the xTuple
            Database in a modified form. The end result is that you may only
            log in to an xTuple Database using xTuple ERP.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
      <tip>
        <para>Do not select the enhanced authentication option if your site
        does not use this method. You will find you cannot connect to the
        database.</para>
      </tip>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term><indexterm significance="normal">
              <primary>authentication</primary>
              <secondary>requiring SSL for</secondary>
            </indexterm>Require SSL Connection</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select if your site requires you to use a Secure Sockets
            Layer (SSL) connection. Selecting this option guarantees you will
            connect to your xTuple Database with an SSL connection. If your
            xTuple Database is not configured to support SSL, you will not be
            able to connect if this option is selected. Using SSL for
            client-server connections adds a layer of encryption to the
            authentication process.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
      <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
      available:</para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>CANCEL</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Closes the screen, returning you to the previous
            screen.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>SAVE</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Saves your connection settings. Any settings you save will
            become your default connection settings. To change your default
            settings, update your Login options and then save them.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
      <para>Once your username and password have been successfully <indexterm
          significance="normal">
          <primary>authentication</primary>
          <secondary>at log-in</secondary>
        </indexterm>authenticated, the main application desktop will appear,
      as shown below:</para>
      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/INTRO_appDesktop.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>Main xTuple ERP Desktop</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <note>
        <para>The main application desktop may vary from user to user,
        depending on the user's granted privileges, preference settings, and
        the xTuple ERP version used.</para>
      </note>
      <para>In general, each of the main menu options corresponds to a
      different module. There are three exceptions to that rule:</para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Window</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>The following options appear under the "Window" menu:</para>
            <variablelist>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Cascade</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Select to arrange open screens in a cascading
                  pattern.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Tile</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Select to arrange open screens in a tiled
                  pattern.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Close Active Window</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Select to close the currently active screen.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Close All Windows</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Select to close all open screens.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
            </variablelist>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Community</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>If you have an open Internet connection, the following
            "Community" menu options will open in your default web
            browser:</para>
            <variablelist>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>xTuple.org Home</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Select to launch the xTuple.org home page.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry role="postbooks">
                <term>Register</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>PostBooks users are given the opportunity to register
                  with xTuple using this menu option. Registration gives users
                  access to additional resources not available to unregistered
                  users&mdash;for example, extra documentation, videos,
                  etc.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>New Account</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Select to create a new xTuple.org account.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Edit Account</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Select to edit your xTuple.org account.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Discussion Forums</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Select to browse the discussion forums on the
                  xTuple.org site.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Blogs</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Select to browse the blogs on the xTuple.org
                  site.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Bugs and Feature Requests</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Select to access the Issue Tracking system on the
                  xTuple.org site.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Downloads</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Select to access the downloads page on the xTuple.org
                  site.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
            </variablelist>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Help</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>The following options appear under the "Help" menu:</para>
            <variablelist>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>About</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Select to view version information.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Table of Contents</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Select to access xTuple ERP Help files. For this to
                  work, the Help files must be installed on your
                  system.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
            </variablelist>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
    </section>
    <section id="Section474320">
      <title><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>exiting</primary>
          <secondary>how to</secondary>
        </indexterm>Exit the Application</title>
      <para>There are two ways to successfully exit xTuple ERP. Either use the
      "X" symbol associated with the desktop window. Or use the System menu's
      "Exit" option. Both work the same way and are equally valid methods for
      exiting the application.</para>
      <para>To exit the application using the System menu, select the "Exit"
      option from the System module, as shown below:</para>
      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/Sys_Exit.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>Exit xTuple Application</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <para>After selecting this option, the application will close, returning
      you to your computer desktop</para>
      <tip>
        <para>Be sure to close all open screens before exiting xTuple ERP to
        help prevent data loss.</para>
      </tip>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section id="Section482543">
    <title><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>application fundamentals</primary>
      </indexterm>Application Fundamentals</title>
    <para>xTuple ERPs contain a number of fundamental features designed to
    simplify your use of the software. In this section, we describe those
    fundamentals in an effort to familiarize you with their use.</para>
    <para>Let's look first at a sample Bill of Materials screen, as shown
    below. We will use this Bill of Materials screen to illustrate several of
    the application fundamentals to be found throughout the
    application&mdash;across multiple screens and modules.</para>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/INTRO_bomScreen.png" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Sample Bill of Materials</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <section id="Section456193">
      <title><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>browse button</primary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>lookup</primary>
          <see>browse button</see>
        </indexterm>Browse Button</title>
      <para>Next to the "Item Number" field in the sample Bill of Materials
      screen is a square box with an ellipsis in the center of it. That square
      box is called a "browse button," and it looks like this:</para>
      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/INTRO_browseButton.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>Browse Button</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <para>Whenever you see a browse button in the application, you have the
      ability to locate information in an efficient manner. Using this feature
      saves time because rather than having to remember detailed strings of
      numbers or codes, you can look them up&mdash;browse for them&mdash;using
      the browse button tool.</para>
      <para><anchor id="Anchor12329" role="Cross-Ref"
      xreflabel="12329: Figure: Figure 2.7:  Browse Button Detail" /><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/INTRO_browseCallout.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>Browse Button Detail</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <para>In the case of our Bill of Materials example, the browse button is
      located next to the "Item Number" field. Obviously, you need to link an
      Item to a Bill of Materials. If that Item happens to be a "Boys 27 Speed
      Mountain Bike," you might not know the Item Number off the top of your
      head. Simply select the browse button, and you will automatically be
      brought to a searchable master list of Items. The master list shows not
      only Item Numbers but also Item descriptions. The list is displayed in
      ascending order by Item Number. If your master list of Items is
      extensive, you can scroll through the list using the scroll bar to the
      right of the screen. Or, simply begin typing the first letters or
      numbers of the Item Number in the "Search" field. The list will
      automatically begin scrolling toward your Item in sequential
      order.</para>
      <para>As noted above, the application contains numerous screens where
      browse buttons are available. Browse buttons can be used to look up Item
      Numbers&mdash;as in the Bill of Materials example&mdash;or use them to
      look up a wide range of other references. The following list indicates a
      small sampling of references you can access using the browse
      button:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Item Numbers</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Item Aliases</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Component Parts</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Sites</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Sales Orders</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Customers</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Purchase Orders</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Vendors</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>And more....</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>
    <section id="Section456208">
      <title><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>right-click</primary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>mouse options</primary>
        </indexterm>Right-Click Options</title>
      <para>Going back to our Bill of Materials example, let's look at another
      fundamental feature involving the right-click button on your computer
      mouse.</para>
      <note>
        <para>For Macintosh users who don"t have a dual button mouse, use the
        CTRL key on your keyboard when clicking on a record to reveal the
        right-click options.</para>
      </note>
      <para>xTuple ERPs are full of displays similar to our sample Bill of
      Materials example. Display screens feature parameter settings at the top
      of the screen&mdash;and a main display area located toward the bottom of
      the screen. Whenever you encounter a display like this, you can
      right-click on a line in the display to reveal a host of additional
      options, as shown in the following screen:</para>
      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/INTRO_bomRightClick.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>Bill of Materials with Right-Click Detail</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <para>As you can see, right-clicking on a component Item in the Bill of
      Materials screen gives you access to the following options:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>View: Gives you a read-only view of the Item</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Edit: Enables you to edit the Item</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Delete: Delete the Item</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Replace: Replace one Item with another Item</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Move Up: Move the Item up the Bill of Materials
          sequence</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Move Down: Move the Item down the Bill of Materials
          sequence.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Export Contents: Export the data displayed on the screen into
          a plain-text, TAB-delimited file. This file may subsequently be
          imported into a spreadsheet or other office tool.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>Right-click options will vary from screen to screen. In our sample
      Bill of Materials example, the right-click options basically mirror the
      functionality of buttons already available within the screen. This will
      not always be the case, though. Often, the right-click feature reveals
      important and useful functionality not to be found on the main display
      screen.</para>
    </section>
    <section id="Section486620">
      <title><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>columns</primary>
          <secondary>size remembered for</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>memory</primary>
          <secondary>for columns</secondary>
        </indexterm>Column Memory</title>
      <para>The system gives you the ability to customize the column layout of
      screens&mdash;and once customized, the columns will remember your
      preferences the next time you visit. To customize the column layout of a
      screen which supports this feature, simply right-click on any column
      header, as shown below:</para>
      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/INTRO_colMemory.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>Typical Report Screen With Column Memory
            Options</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <note>
        <para>The column configuration options will vary depending on the
        current status of the screen. And of course, individual column names
        will differ from screen to screen.</para>
      </note>
      <para>When right-clicking on a column header to configure the column
      settings, you are presented with the following options:</para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Reset this Width</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select this option to reset the selected column to its
            default, system-defined width. You will only see this option if
            the width of column has been changed (i.e., made wider or
            narrower).</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Reset all Widths</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select this option to reset all columns on the screen to the
            default settings.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Do Not Remember Widths</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select this option if you do not want the screen to remember
            column width changes made during active sessions.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Remember Widths</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select this option if you want the screen to remember column
            width changes made during active sessions.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
      <para>Beneath the column width options, you will see a list of all the
      column names in the screen. As a further customization, you may choose
      to show or hide as many columns as you want. For example, if you do not
      need the Username in the G/L Transactions screen, simply uncheck the
      Username row in the list. The screen will only display columns which
      have a check mark next to them in the column configuration list.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>check boxes</primary>
          <secondary>setting for remembered</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>memory</primary>
          <secondary>for check boxes</secondary>
        </indexterm>Check Box Memory</title>
      <para>On many screens where there are check box options (i.e.,
      parameters used for filtering data displayed on a screen), the system
      will remember your preferred settings. An example of this functionality
      is shown in the following screen:</para>
      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/INTRO_checkBoxMemory.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>Check Box Memory</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <para>A shaded bullet symbol indicates whether a check box supports the
      memory feature. In our example, the "Show All Unvouchered P/Os" check
      box has a shaded bullet next to it. When you see a shaded bullet next to
      a check box it means your preferences will be remembered by the system.
      If you select the check box, then it will remain selected the next time
      you open the screen. Conversely, if you don't select the check box, it
      won't be selected when the screen is next used.</para>
      <tip>
        <para>The Check Box memory feature can be de-activated by de-selecting
        the "Remember Check Box Settings" option on the user Preferences
        screen. Turning this setting off will hide the shaded bullet symbols
        from view.</para>
      </tip>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>screens</primary>
          <secondary>size remembered for</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>memory</primary>
          <secondary>for screen sizes</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>memory</primary>
          <secondary>for screen position</secondary>
        </indexterm>Screen Position/Size Memory</title>
      <para>The system gives you the ability to specify a default screen size
      and position on a screen-by-screen basis. This feature applies to all
      Window screens, but not to Dialog screens. A Dialog screen is a screen
      which holds the focus when it is open and prevents you from working on
      other screens at the same time. The controls for the screen position and
      size memory are located under the Windows menu, as shown in the
      following screen:</para>
      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/INTRO_screenMemory.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>Setting Screen Position/Size Memory</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <note>
        <para>Unless you specify otherwise, the system will always remember
        the size of all Window screens--and also the position where the screen
        was located&mdash;when you last used it.</para>
      </note>
      <para>When opening the Windows menu to set your screen position or size,
      you are presented with the following options:</para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Remember Position</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select to have the system remember the position of the
            specified screen. If selected, the system will remember the
            position of the screen where it was last located. Un-selecting
            this option means the screen position will not be
            remembered&mdash;and the default position will be used
            instead.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Remember Size</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select to have the system remember the size of the specified
            screen. If selected, the system will remember the size of the
            screen where it was last located. Un-selecting this option means
            the screen size will not be remembered&mdash;and the default size
            will be used instead.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
    </section>
    <section id="Section483123">
      <title><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>keyboard shortcuts</primary>
          <secondary>drag-and-drop</secondary>
        </indexterm>Drag-and-Drop</title>
      <para>The application supports drag-and-drop functionality for screens
      which use the Item Number widget. Using this functionality, you have the
      ability to drag an Item Number from one screen to another screen.</para>
      <para>For example, let's say you have two xTuple ERP screens open on
      your desktop at the same time: The Bill of Materials (BOM) for Item XYZ
      and also the Quantity on Hand (QOH) by Item display. In this example,
      the QOH display does not have an Item Number entered in it yet.</para>
      <para>To drag Item Number XYZ from the BOM screen to the QOH display,
      simply click your mouse on the Item Number in the BOM&mdash;and then
      drag the Item Number over to the Item Number field on the QOH display.
      You may now QUERY the display to get QOH information on Item XYZ.</para>
    </section>
    <section id="Section456222">
      <title><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>keyboard shortcuts</primary>
          <secondary>using instead of mouse</secondary>
        </indexterm>Keyboard Shortcuts</title>
      <para>Many people prefer to use keyboard shortcuts&mdash;instead of a
      mouse&mdash;when navigating within a software application. xTuple ERP
      features a number of keyboard shortcuts designed just for this
      purpose.</para>
      <section id="Section456225">
        <title><indexterm significance="normal">
            <primary>TAB key</primary>
          </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
            <primary>keyboard shortcuts</primary>
            <secondary>TAB key</secondary>
          </indexterm>TAB Key</title>
        <para>The TAB key on your keyboard may be used to move the cursor from
        one field to the next within any given data-entry screen. Simply place
        the cursor in the first field you want to enter data into&mdash;and
        when you"re done entering data, hit the TAB key to move the cursor to
        the next field.</para>
        <para>Also use the TAB key as a shortcut for converting date field
        entries to the proper format for your system. For example, in a "Start
        Date" field you might enter the numbers "022503". Then, with the
        cursor still blinking in the field, hit the TAB key. The date will be
        converted to "02/25/03"--or whatever the proper date format is for
        your system. For more information on keyboard shortcuts related to
        dates, see the <xref linkend="Anchor73705" />.</para>
        <note>
          <para>Date formats are controlled by Locale settings.</para>
        </note>
      </section>
      <section id="Section456228">
        <title><indexterm significance="normal">
            <primary>CTRL key</primary>
          </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
            <primary>keyboard shortcuts</primary>
            <secondary>CTRL key</secondary>
          </indexterm>CTRL Key</title>
        <para>Three keyboard shortcuts are available at several points
        throughout the application when you place the cursor in an "Item
        Number" field. You saw the "Item Number" field in the Bill of
        Materials example above. The "Item Number" field appears frequently
        throughout the application. Use the CTRL key&mdash;usually located on
        the bottom left-hand corner of your keyboard&mdash;in combination with
        either "L", "A", or "S" to reach the three screens shown in the
        following examples:</para>
        <tip>
          <para>Macintosh users should substitute the APPLE key for the CTRL
          key to achieve the results described in this section.</para>
        </tip>
        <para><screenshot>
            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="images/INTRO_CTRL-L.png" />
              </imageobject>
              <caption>Item Lookup (CTRL + L)</caption>
            </mediaobject>
          </screenshot></para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>List (CTRL + L)</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>This is the same Item lookup you would reach if you
              clicked your mouse on the browse button located next to the
              "Item Number" field.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
        <para><screenshot>
            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="images/INTRO_CTRL-A.png" />
              </imageobject>
              <caption>Item Alias Lookup (CTRL + A)</caption>
            </mediaobject>
          </screenshot></para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>item aliases</primary>
                <secondary>keyboard shortcut for</secondary>
              </indexterm>Aliases (CTRL + A)</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Locate an Item using its Item Alias. Item Aliases may
              correspond to a Customer Item Number&mdash;or some other
              equivalence.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
        <para><screenshot>
            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="images/INTRO_CTRL-S.png" />
              </imageobject>
              <caption>Searchable List (CTRL + S)</caption>
            </mediaobject>
          </screenshot></para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Search (CTRL + S)</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Search for Items using a variety of search criteria. This
              shortcut enables you to look up Manufactured Items using partial
              values. In the above example, the user selected all available
              search options&mdash;except for the "Show Inactive Items"
              option&mdash;to search for a match for "MB-B." In this case, the
              application will search the master list of Items for any Item
              containing "MB-B" in either the Item Number, the first line of
              the Item description, and/or the second line of the Item
              description.</para>
              <para>You can also search for matches using any one or a
              combination of these search options. For example, let's say you
              are looking for any Manufactured Item containing the word "Bike"
              in the first line of the Item description. To perform this
              search, simply enter the word "Bike" in the "Search For" field,
              then select the "Search through Description 1" option. Leave the
              other options unchecked. Any Item containing the word "Bike" in
              the first line of its Item description will display in the
              results.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </section>
      <section id="Section456240">
        <title><indexterm significance="normal">
            <primary>ALT key</primary>
          </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
            <primary>keyboard shortcuts</primary>
            <secondary>ALT key</secondary>
          </indexterm>ALT Key</title>
        <para>You will notice throughout the application that several
        characters&mdash;or individual letters within words&mdash;are
        underlined. In the sample Bill of Materials screen, for example, the
        SAVE button has the first letter, "S", underlined. The first letter,
        "C", in the CANCEL button is also underlined. Alternately, notice that
        the MOVE DOWN button has the "W" underlined. The list could go
        on.</para>
        <para>If you depress the ALT key on your keyboard in combination with
        any of these underlined letters, the effect is the same as if you had
        used the mouse to select that button or field. For example, the
        following combination of keys will activate the PRINT button: ALT + P.
        The following keyboard shortcut will cancel or close a screen: ALT +
        C. Or, move a component Item down a notch in a Bill of Materials
        display with the following shortcut: ALT + W.</para>
      </section>
      <section id="Section474757">
        <title id="Anchor73705"><indexterm significance="normal">
            <primary>formats</primary>
            <secondary>related to dates</secondary>
          </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
            <primary>dates</primary>
            <secondary>formats for</secondary>
          </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
            <primary>keyboard shortcuts</primary>
            <secondary>for dates</secondary>
          </indexterm>Date Shortcuts</title>
        <para>xTuple ERP supports a number of keyboard shortcuts for dates.
        These shortcuts are designed to save you time when entering dates in
        date fields. Keep in mind, you are required to hit the TAB key after
        entering a shortcut value in a date field. The TAB key is required to
        complete all date shortcut entries. The following table describes
        these date shortcuts in more detail:</para>
        <note>
          <para>xTuple ERP accepts a number of different "input" formats for
          dates. Any of the following date formats will be accepted by the
          application:</para>
          <para>MM/DD/YY</para>
          <para>MM/DD/YYYY</para>
          <para>M or MM / D or DD / YY or YYYY</para>
          <para>While date input formats may vary, the "output" format (i.e.,
          how dates display on screen) is defined by your Locale
          settings.</para>
        </note>
        <table>
          <title>Date Shortcuts</title>
          <tgroup cols="2">
            <tbody>
              <row>
                <entry><para>0+TAB Key</para></entry>
                <entry><para>Entering the number "0" followed by the TAB key
                in an empty date field will automatically enter today's date
                in the date field.</para></entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry><para>+num</para></entry>
                <entry><para>The "+" symbol followed by a whole number will
                enter the date occurring num number of days after today's
                date:</para><para>Example:</para><para>Entering "+1" would
                give you tomorrow's date, "+2" would give you the
                day-after-tomorrow, etc.</para></entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry><para>-num</para></entry>
                <entry><para>The "-" symbol followed by a whole number will
                enter the date occurring num number of days before today's
                date:</para><para>Example:</para><para>Entering "-1" would
                give you yesterday's date, "-2" would give you the
                day-before-yesterday, etc.</para></entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry><para>num</para></entry>
                <entry><para>A standalone number will enter the day of the
                current month represented by that
                number.</para><para>Examples:</para><para>Entering "12" in the
                month of March, 2003 would give you March 12, 2003. Similarly,
                the number "23" would give you March 23, 2003,
                etc.</para><para>Any number from 1 to 99 may be entered. If
                the number entered is greater than the last day of the current
                month, the date will automatically default to the last day of
                the month. In other words, entering the numbers "99" or "75"
                or "32" would automatically enter the last day of the current
                month.</para></entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry><para>#num</para></entry>
                <entry><para>The "#" symbol followed by a whole number will
                enter the day of the current Julian calendar year represented
                by that number.</para><para>Examples:</para><para>Entering
                "#1" in the year 2003 would give you January 1, 2003.
                Similarly, "#100" would give you April 10, 2003. Entering
                "#365" would give you December 31, 2003.</para></entry>
              </row>
            </tbody>
          </tgroup>
        </table>
        <tip>
          <para>Some date fields support time-periods represented by
          words&mdash;such as "Earliest" and "Latest". Keep in mind that these
          words are case-sensitive. They will not work unless the first letter
          of the word is capitalized.</para>
        </tip>
      </section>
      <section>
        <title>Calendars</title>
        <para>In addition to the keyboard shortcuts for dates, you also have
        the option of selecting the calendar button located to the far right
        of every date field in the application. The calendar buttons are shown
        in the following screen shot next to the Start Date and End Date
        fields:</para>
        <para><mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/INTRO_calendars.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>Calendar Widget</caption>
          </mediaobject>The calendar functionality is simple to use. All you
        do is open the calendar, then select the date you want to be entered
        into the field. To change a date, simply reopen the calendar and
        select a new date. You can easily navigate between months--and even
        between years.</para>
        <tip>
          <para>The calendar can be used interchangeably with manually entered
          dates and date shortcuts. You don't have to use one or the
          other.</para>
        </tip>
      </section>
      <section id="Section476479">
        <title id="Anchor51567"><indexterm significance="normal">
            <primary>keyboard shortcuts</primary>
            <secondary>for toolbar buttons</secondary>
          </indexterm>Toolbar Buttons</title>
        <para>For users who prefer using buttons instead of drop-down menus,
        the application offers a variety of toolbar button options. <indexterm
            significance="normal">
            <primary>toolbar buttons</primary>
            <secondary>master list of</secondary>
          </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
            <primary>toolbars</primary>
            <secondary>buttons master list</secondary>
          </indexterm>The following screen shows the application desktop with
        all available toolbar buttons turned on:</para>
        <note>
          <para>You can control the display of toolbar buttons on your
          desktop. Turn them on or off on a module-by-module basis, using the
          settings available in the User Preferences section of the System
          module. In addition, you may drag-and-drop toolbar buttons, allowing
          them to float or attach to alternate locations on the application
          desktop.</para>
        </note>
        <para><screenshot>
            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="images/INTRO_toolbarMenu.png" />
              </imageobject>
              <caption>Toolbar Buttons</caption>
            </mediaobject>
          </screenshot></para>
        <para>To access the function described by a button, simply select the
        button using your mouse. Toolbar buttons function in the same way
        drop-down menu selections do&mdash;they simply provide a convenient
        shortcut. The complete list of available toolbar buttons is shown in
        the following table:</para>
        <table>
          <title>Toolbar Buttons Master List</title>
          <tgroup cols="3">
            <thead>
              <row>
                <entry><para>Image</para></entry>
                <entry><para>Function</para></entry>
                <entry><para>Module</para></entry>
              </row>
            </thead>
            <tbody>
              <row>
                <entry><para><screenshot>
                    <mediaobject>
                      <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/TOOLS_itemSites.png" />
                      </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                  </screenshot></para></entry>
                <entry><para>List Item Sites</para></entry>
                <entry><para>I/M</para></entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry><para><screenshot>
                    <mediaobject>
                      <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/TOOLS_dspInventoryAvailabilityByPlannerCode.png" />
                      </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                  </screenshot></para></entry>
                <entry><para>Inventory Availability by Planner
                Code</para></entry>
                <entry><para>I/M</para></entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry><para><screenshot>
                    <mediaobject>
                      <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/TOOLS_itemAvailabilityWorkbench.png" />
                      </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                  </screenshot></para></entry>
                <entry><para>Item Availability Workbench</para></entry>
                <entry><para>I/M</para></entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry><para><screenshot>
                    <mediaobject>
                      <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/TOOLS_items.png" />
                      </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                  </screenshot></para></entry>
                <entry><para>List Items</para></entry>
                <entry><para>P/D</para></entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry><para><screenshot>
                    <mediaobject>
                      <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/TOOLS_boms.png" />
                      </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                  </screenshot></para></entry>
                <entry><para>List BOMs</para></entry>
                <entry><para>P/D</para></entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry><para><screenshot>
                    <mediaobject>
                      <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/TOOLS_boos.png" />
                      </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                  </screenshot></para></entry>
                <entry><para>List BOOs</para></entry>
                <entry><para>P/D</para></entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry><para><screenshot>
                    <mediaobject>
                      <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/TOOLS_runMrpByPlannerCode.png" />
                      </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                  </screenshot></para></entry>
                <entry><para>Run MRP by Planner Code</para></entry>
                <entry><para>M/S</para></entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry><para><screenshot>
                    <mediaobject>
                      <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/TOOLS_dspPlannedOrdersByPlannerCode.png" />
                      </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                  </screenshot></para></entry>
                <entry><para>Planned Orders by Planner Code</para></entry>
                <entry><para>M/S</para></entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry><para><screenshot>
                    <mediaobject>
                      <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/TOOLS_shopFloorWorkbench.png" />
                      </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                  </screenshot></para></entry>
                <entry><para>Shop Floor Workbench</para></entry>
                <entry><para>W/O</para></entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry><para><screenshot>
                    <mediaobject>
                      <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/TOOLS_dspWoScheduleByPlannerCode.png" />
                      </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                  </screenshot></para></entry>
                <entry><para>W/O Schedule by Planner Code</para></entry>
                <entry><para>W/O</para></entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry><para><screenshot>
                    <mediaobject>
                      <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/TOOLS_listUnpostedPo.png" />
                      </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                  </screenshot></para></entry>
                <entry><para>List Unposted P/Os</para></entry>
                <entry><para>P/O</para></entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry><para><screenshot>
                    <mediaobject>
                      <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/TOOLS_dspPurchaseReqByPlannerCode.png" />
                      </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                  </screenshot></para></entry>
                <entry><para>Purchase Requests by Planner Code</para></entry>
                <entry><para>P/O</para></entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry><para><screenshot>
                    <mediaobject>
                      <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/TOOLS_customerInformationWorkbench.png" />
                      </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                  </screenshot></para></entry>
                <entry><para>Customer Information Workbench</para></entry>
                <entry><para>S/O</para></entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry><para><screenshot>
                    <mediaobject>
                      <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/TOOLS_listOpenSalesOrders.png" />
                      </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                  </screenshot></para></entry>
                <entry><para>List Open Sales Orders</para></entry>
                <entry><para>S/O</para></entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry><para><screenshot>
                    <mediaobject>
                      <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/TOOLS_uninvoicedShipments.png" />
                      </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                  </screenshot></para></entry>
                <entry><para>Uninvoiced Shipments</para></entry>
                <entry><para>S/O</para></entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry><para><screenshot>
                    <mediaobject>
                      <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/TOOLS_billingSelections.png" />
                      </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                  </screenshot></para></entry>
                <entry><para>Billing Selections</para></entry>
                <entry><para>S/O</para></entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry><para><screenshot>
                    <mediaobject>
                      <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/TOOLS_dspSummarizedBacklogByWhse.png" />
                      </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                  </screenshot></para></entry>
                <entry><para>Summarized Backlog by Site</para></entry>
                <entry><para>S/O</para></entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry><para><screenshot>
                    <mediaobject>
                      <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/TOOLS_issueStockToShipping.png" />
                      </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                  </screenshot></para></entry>
                <entry><para>Issue Stock to Shipping</para></entry>
                <entry><para>S/R</para></entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry><para><screenshot>
                    <mediaobject>
                      <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/TOOLS_postReceipts.png" />
                      </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                  </screenshot></para></entry>
                <entry><para>UnPosted Receipts</para></entry>
                <entry><para>S/R</para></entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry><para><screenshot>
                    <mediaobject>
                      <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/TOOLS_accounts.png" />
                      </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                  </screenshot></para></entry>
                <entry><para>List Accounts</para></entry>
                <entry><para>CRM</para></entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry><para><screenshot>
                    <mediaobject>
                      <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/TOOLS_contacts.png" />
                      </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                  </screenshot></para></entry>
                <entry><para>List Contacts</para></entry>
                <entry><para>CRM</para></entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry><para><screenshot>
                    <mediaobject>
                      <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/TOOLS_incidents.png" />
                      </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                  </screenshot></para></entry>
                <entry><para>Incident Workbench</para></entry>
                <entry><para>CRM</para></entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry><para><screenshot>
                    <mediaobject>
                      <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/TOOLS_toDoList.png" />
                      </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                  </screenshot></para></entry>
                <entry><para>List To-Do"s</para></entry>
                <entry><para>CRM</para></entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry><para><screenshot>
                    <mediaobject>
                      <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/TOOLS_projects.png" />
                      </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                  </screenshot></para></entry>
                <entry><para>List Projects</para></entry>
                <entry><para>P/M</para></entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry><para><screenshot>
                    <mediaobject>
                      <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/TOOLS_listUnpostedVouchers.png" />
                      </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                  </screenshot></para></entry>
                <entry><para>List Unposted Vouchers</para></entry>
                <entry><para>A/P</para></entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry><para><screenshot>
                    <mediaobject>
                      <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/TOOLS_selectPayments.png" />
                      </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                  </screenshot></para></entry>
                <entry><para>Select Payments</para></entry>
                <entry><para>A/P</para></entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry><para><screenshot>
                    <mediaobject>
                      <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/TOOLS_prepareCheckRun.png" />
                      </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                  </screenshot></para></entry>
                <entry><para>Prepare Check Run</para></entry>
                <entry><para>A/P</para></entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry><para><screenshot>
                    <mediaobject>
                      <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/TOOLS_viewCheckRun.png" />
                      </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                  </screenshot></para></entry>
                <entry><para>View Check Run</para></entry>
                <entry><para>A/P</para></entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry><para><screenshot>
                    <mediaobject>
                      <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/TOOLS_apAging.png" />
                      </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                  </screenshot></para></entry>
                <entry><para>A/P Aging</para></entry>
                <entry><para>A/P</para></entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry><para><screenshot>
                    <mediaobject>
                      <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/TOOLS_unpostedInvoices.png" />
                      </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                  </screenshot></para></entry>
                <entry><para>List Unposted Invoices</para></entry>
                <entry><para>A/R</para></entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry><para><screenshot>
                    <mediaobject>
                      <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/TOOLS_arWorkbench.png" />
                      </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                  </screenshot></para></entry>
                <entry><para>A/R Workbench</para></entry>
                <entry><para>A/R</para></entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry><para><screenshot>
                    <mediaobject>
                      <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/TOOLS_editCashReceipts.png" />
                      </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                  </screenshot></para></entry>
                <entry><para>Cash Receipt Edit List</para></entry>
                <entry><para>A/R</para></entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry><para><screenshot>
                    <mediaobject>
                      <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/TOOLS_arAging.png" />
                      </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                  </screenshot></para></entry>
                <entry><para>A/R Aging</para></entry>
                <entry><para>A/R</para></entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry><para><screenshot>
                    <mediaobject>
                      <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/TOOLS_journalEntries.png" />
                      </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                  </screenshot></para></entry>
                <entry><para>List Unposted Journal Entries</para></entry>
                <entry><para>G/L</para></entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry><para><screenshot>
                    <mediaobject>
                      <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/TOOLS_bankReconciliation.png" />
                      </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                  </screenshot></para></entry>
                <entry><para>Reconcile Bank Account</para></entry>
                <entry><para>G/L</para></entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry><para><screenshot>
                    <mediaobject>
                      <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/TOOLS_viewFinancialReport.png" />
                      </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                  </screenshot></para></entry>
                <entry><para>View Financial Report</para></entry>
                <entry><para>G/L</para></entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry><para><screenshot>
                    <mediaobject>
                      <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/TOOLS_viewTrialBalance.png" />
                      </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                  </screenshot></para></entry>
                <entry><para>View Trial Balances</para></entry>
                <entry><para>G/L</para></entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry><para><screenshot>
                    <mediaobject>
                      <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/TOOLS_dspEvents.png" />
                      </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                  </screenshot></para></entry>
                <entry><para>Event Notification</para></entry>
                <entry><para>System</para></entry>
              </row>
            </tbody>
          </tgroup>
        </table>
        <tip>
          <para>If you hover your mouse above a toolbar button, the name of
          the function associated with the button will appear. Use this
          technique to quickly learn the identity of the toolbar
          buttons.</para>
        </tip>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section id="Section456244">
      <title><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>common application buttons</primary>
        </indexterm>Common Application Buttons</title>
      <para>A set of common buttons appear throughout xTuple ERP. They are
      usually located to the far right side of the screen. They can be
      activated by a single mouse click, or by the use of associated keyboard
      shortcuts. The following descriptions explain some of the more common
      application buttons found within xTuple ERP:</para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>CLOSE</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Closes the screen you are currently working on, without
            saving any information you may have entered. Returns you to the
            previous screen.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>CANCEL</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Works the same way as the CLOSE button.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>SELECT</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Inserts a highlighted list item into a requesting field. The
            use of the SELECT button is illustrated in the example. In this
            Bill of Materials example, you would highlight an Item in the
            searchable master list of Items and then hit SELECT. The Item
            would then be automatically entered into the "Item Number" field
            on the Bill of Materials screen. You may bypass the SELECT button
            by double-clicking on a highlighted list item.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>EDIT</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Allows editing of information displayed on screen.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>VIEW</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Opens a read-only view of information displayed on
            screen.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>SAVE</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Saves any information you have entered and stores it in the
            xTuple Database.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>PRINT</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Sends the contents of a screen or report to your default
            printer, assuming you have a default printer assigned to your work
            station.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
    </section>
  </section>
</chapter>