<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2011 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section>
  <title>Allocate A/R Credit Memos</title>
  <para id="documentsWidget"><informalexample>
      <para>When processing Sales Orders or Invoices, you have the option to
      allocate open A/R Credit Memos to the document. To allocate open Credit
      Memos, select the "Allocate" link on the Line Items tab. The following
      screen will appear:</para>
      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/allocateARCreditMemo.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>Attach a Document</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <para>When allocating Credit Memos, you are presented with the following
      options:</para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Document Total</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Displays the total amount of the document being applied
            to.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Unallocated Balance</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Displays the open balance of the document being applied to.
            When Credit Memos are allocated to the document, the open balance
            will go down by the amount of the allocations. The balance will go
            back up if those allocations are cleared.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Credits</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Display lists the Customer's open Credit Memos. When a
            Credit Memo is applied to the document, the list will indicate the
            relationship between the two. If the allocation is cleared, the
            list will update to remove the relationship.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
      <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>ALLOCATE</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Highlight a Credit Memo and then select this button to
            allocate the Credit Memo to the document. Partial Credit Memo
            amounts may be allocated if the document's open balance is less
            than the full Credit Memo amount.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>CLEAR</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Highlight a Credit Memo and then select this button to clear
            the Credit Memo allocation.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
    </informalexample></para>
</section>
