<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section role="standard">
  <title>EDI Relation Pseudo-widget</title>
  <para><remark>This should really be part of the xtbatch docs</remark></para>
  <para id="edirelationWidget"><informalexample role="standard">
      <para>When associating EDI Profiles with EDI recipients, such as
      Customers, Ship-To Addresses, and Vendors, you are presented with the
      following options:</para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>EDI Profiles</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Display lists EDI Profiles associated with this recipient
            (e.g. current Customer) for a particular document type. It also
            shows whether EDI will be sent via email or FTP.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
      <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
      available:</para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>ATTACH</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Connect an existing EDI Profile to this EDI recipient for a
            particular document type.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>DETACH</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Detach the selected EDI Profile from the recipient for the
            selected document type.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>NEW</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Create a new EDI Profile and have the opportunity to attach
            it to the current recipient.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>EDIT</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Edit the selected EDI Profile.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
      <para>To attach an existing EDI Profile to the current recipient, select
      the ATTACH button. The following screen will appear:</para>
      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/edirelation_attach.png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>Attach an EDI Profile</caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Recipient</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>This shows the number of the Customer, Vendor, etc. which
            will receive EDI using the selected EDI Profile.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Recipient Type</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>This shows whether the Recipient is a Customer, Vendor, etc.
            This reduces confusion in cases where a Customer and Vendor have
            the same number (i.e., the same CRM Account is both a Customer and
            Vendor).</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Document Type</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Choose from this list the type of document you want to use
            the EDI Profile for.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>EDI Profiles</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Choose from this list the EDI Profile you want to attach for
            the selected document type.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
      <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
      available:</para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>CANCEL</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Closes the screen without attaching the EDI Profile,
            returning you to the previous screen.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>ATTACH</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Attaches the EDI Profile to the recipient and closes the
            screen, returning you to the previous screen.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
      <para>If there is no existing EDI Profile that suits your needs, you can
      create a new one by selecting the NEW button. This does the same thing
      as clicking the NEW button on the EDI Profiles window (see <xref
      linkend="ediProfilesTitle" />). After you have created the new EDI
      Profile and saved it, the Attach EDI Profile window will appear with the
      new EDI Profile selected. Now you can select the Document Type and click
      ATTACH. If you click CANCEL, the new EDI Profile will still be saved but
      will not be attached to the recipient.</para>
    </informalexample></para>
</section>
