<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section>
  <title>Parameter Widget</title>
  <para id="parameterwidget"><informalexample>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Apply Filter</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select a filter from the list of available filters, then
            select the QUERY button to generate results based on that filter.
            You can also build your own search criteria dynamically, using the
            "+" and "-" buttons. To learn more about working with search
            filters, please see <xref linkend="introSearchFilters" />.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>MORE</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select this button to show the parameters underlying the
            saved filter. To hide the details, simply click this button a
            second time.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Filter</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>When building your own search criteria, select from the
            following options:</para>
            <variablelist>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>SAVE</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Select this button to save your filter set to the list
                  of saved filters. Saved filters may be applied to future
                  searches. If you are modifying an already-existing
                  filter&mdash;and you want to keep your changes&mdash;be sure
                  to save them or they will be lost.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>MANAGE</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Select this button to reach the list of saved
                  filters.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>+</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Select to add new search parameters when building an
                  ad hoc query. Ad hoc searching is supported, but searches
                  must be saved if you want them to be available for future
                  use.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>-</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Select to remove search parameters when building an ad
                  hoc query. Ad hoc searching is supported, but searches must
                  be saved if you want them to be available for future
                  use.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
            </variablelist>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
    </informalexample></para>
</section>
