<?xml version="1.0" encoding="US-ASCII"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="parameteredit">
  <title>MetaSQL Parameter Editor</title>
  <para>The MetaSQL Parameter Editor lets you choose whether or not a MetaSQL
  query will use a particular Parameter and what the value of that Parameter
  should be. The value can be constrained to legal values by choosing a data
  type for it.</para>
  <para>The MetaSQL Parameter Editor is usually embedded in another window.
  Examples include the Export Data window and xTuple Connect's Review EDI
  Before Sending window. This is an example of what it looks like:<screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/parameteredit.png" />
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>This example shows a single Parameter called
  <literal>cust_number</literal>. The value of this parameter has not been set
  yet and it is not active, so it will not be used when a MetaSQL query is
  run.</para>
  <para>If you click the EDIT button you can set the value of this Parameter
  and whether it is active or not. You will see the following
  screen:<screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/parameterproperties.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption><para>The Parameter Properties window</para></caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When you open the Parameter Properties window, you are presented with
  the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Type</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Choose the data type of this parameter. Options include the
        following:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>String</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>This lets you enter free-form text and is the most common
              Type used.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Bool</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>This lets you choose either "True" or "False".</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Int</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>This restricts input to a valid integer value, reducing
              the potential for errors. This should be used when entering
              internal id numbers.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Double</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>This restricts input to valid numerical values, reducing
              the potential for errors. This should be used when entering
              monetary values, weights, and percentages.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>List</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>This allows entering a list of values. It is not used very
              often.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
        <tip>
          <para>Select "String" as the Type if you need to enter a date. Any
          text value that the PostgreSQL database server can convert to a
          valid date can be entered here.</para>
        </tip>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This is the name of the MetaSQL Parameter as it appears in the
        MetaSQL query. If you are using the Parameter Editor when executing a
        Query Set or MetaSQL Query from the xTuple ERP application, you should
        not change the Name.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Active</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Check this box to pass this parameter and its value to the
        MetaSQL Query.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Value</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Type or select the value you want to set for this Parameter. The
        appearance of this field will change based on the Type.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
