<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section role="xtconnect">
  <title>Send Document Electronically</title>
  <para id="submitEDIWidget"><informalexample>
      <para>When sending a document electronically, you may be presented with
      one of two screens, depending on whether the document will be sent by
      Email or by FTP. If you do not see either screen, that suggests the EDI
      Profile has been set to disable review before sending and will
      automatically be sent to the xTuple Connect Batch Manager.</para>
      <para><note>
          <para>Customers Vendors are set up to receive electronic deliveries
          of information using the "Transmission" tab on the Customer
          master.</para>
        </note></para>
      <para>If the document will be sent by Email, the following screen will
      appear:</para>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/submitEDI_email.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption><para>Review EDI Before Sending by Email</para></caption>
      </mediaobject>
      <para>The fields at the top of the window show basic information about
      the EDI that will be sent:</para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Document Type/Number</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>The type of document and document number will vary depending
            on the context. The following document types are supported: Quote,
            Sales Order, Invoice, Purchase Order.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>EDI Type</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Displays whether the EDI will be sent by Email or
            FTP.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
      <para>The information in the following fields will be populated from the
      EDI Profile. If you have the "EditEDIBeforeSending" privilege, you will
      be allowed to edit the contents of these fields. You are presented with
      the following Email-specific options:</para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>To</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>This is the Email address of the primary intended recipient
            of the Email. You can add Email addresses from a <link
            linkend="submitEDI-contactSearch">searchable list</link> of your
            CRM Contacts by clicking on the TO button.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Cc</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>This is the carbon copy (i.e., Cc:) Email address—a copy of
            the Email will be sent to this address. You can add Email
            addresses from a <link
            linkend="submitEDI-contactSearch">searchable list</link> of your
            CRM Contacts by clicking on the CC button.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Bcc</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>This is the blind carbon copy (i.e., Bcc:) Email address—a
            copy of the Email will be sent to this address but none of the
            recipients will see this address. You can add Email addresses from
            a <link linkend="submitEDI-contactSearch">searchable list</link>
            of your CRM Contacts by clicking on the BCC button.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Reply To</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>This is the reply-to address that will be set on the
            outgoing Email message. This controls the Email address used when
            someone replies to the Email sent by xTuple ERP.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Subject</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>This is the subject line that will be used for this
            Email.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>From</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>This is the Email address of the person sending the Email.
            It can be set to the address of the user running the application
            or a generic address (e.g. "sales@xtuple.com"). If it is left
            blank on this screen, the xTuple Connect Batch Manager will fill
            in the Email address of the user running the application at the
            time the EDI was prepared.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Message Body</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>This is the body of the Email message that will be sent.
            This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Send Email as HTML</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select if you want the body of the Email to be sent as HTML.
            If not selected, the Email will be sent as plain text.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Attachment Options</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Use the Attachment Options to control the contents and
            format of the file attached to this Email. The following options
            are available, depending on the settings in the EDI
            Profile:</para>
            <variablelist>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>No Attachment</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>No file will be attached to the Email.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Report</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>The named report will be run by the Batch Manager and
                  attached to the Email as a .PDF file.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Form</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>If the document is a Sales Order or an Invoice, the
                  Customer Form Assignment will be used. That report will be
                  run by the Batch Manager and attached to the Email as a .PDF
                  file.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Delimited Text</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>The Query Set defined in the EDI Forms for the EDI
                  Profile will be run. The results will be used to build a
                  file with the fields delimited by the character selected in
                  the drop-down list that appears when "Delimited Text" is
                  selected.</para>
                  <para>Pre-defined characters include the comma (",") and
                  tab. If you need to change the delimiter, select "[ not
                  delimited ]" from the drop-down menu, then replace that text
                  with your own single character. Normally, however, this
                  should be left to the value specified in the EDI
                  Profile.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>HTML</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>The Query Set defined in the EDI Forms for the EDI
                  Profile will be run. The results will be used to build an
                  HTML file. Each query will start a new HTML table.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>XML</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>The Query Set defined in the EDI Forms for the EDI
                  Profile will be run. The results will be used to build an
                  XML file. Each row of output will be represented by an XML
                  element named for the query that generated it and will
                  contain child elements for the individual fields. Each field
                  of output will be represented by an element with the name of
                  the query result column and will contain the value of that
                  field as the text of the element.</para>
                  <para>The resulting XML can be transformed to another format
                  by selecting from the list of XSLT mappings that appears
                  when "XML" is selected.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Include Header Lines</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>For Delimited Text, this will insert a line before
                  each query showing the query result column names separated
                  by the delimiting character. For HTML, this will insert a
                  row at the beginning of each query's results showing the
                  query results column names. This is ignored for PDF and XML
                  output.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>Output File</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>This is the name that will be given to the Email
                  attachment. For Forms and Reports it should end with a
                  ".pdf" suffix. For comma-delimited files the output file
                  should end with ".csv". Tab-delimited files should have a
                  ".tsv" suffix.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>PREVIEW</term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>This brings up a preview window to show what the
                  attachment will look like when generated by the Batch
                  Manager. It can show either reports or delimited text
                  files.</para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
            </variablelist>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
      <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>OK</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select to submit the requested action to the Batch Manager
            for processing. If the EDI will be sent by Email, there must be at
            least one Email address in either the To, Cc, or Bcc
            fields.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
      <para id="submitEDI-contactSearch">To search for Email addresses from
      within your CRM Contacts, select either the TO, CC, or BCC buttons. The
      following screen will appear:</para>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/submitEDI_contacts.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption><para>Search for Email Contacts</para></caption>
      </mediaobject>
      <para>When searching for Email Contacts, you are presented with the
      following options:</para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Search for</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Enter a string of letters or a full name to search for
            matches in your CRM Contacts list. The Contacts list will be empty
            by default until you begin entering letters to search and match
            for.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Contacts</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Display will be empty at first but will populate with CRM
            Contact records as soon as letters are entered in the search
            field. </para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>SELECT</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>Highlight a Contact and then use the SELECT button to choose
            the Contact record. The selected Contact's Email address (assuming
            it exists) will be added to the outbound Email, in the address
            field you specify.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
      <para>If the document will be sent by FTP, the following screen will
      appear:</para>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/submitEDI_ftp.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption><para>Review EDI Before Sending by FTP</para></caption>
      </mediaobject>
      <para>While the FTP attachment options will be the same as for sending
      Email, the transmission options will be different. Get the values for
      these from the EDI recipient (either your Vendor or Customer, depending
      on the document type). See the xTuple Connect Product Guide for
      suggestions on how to store these data.</para>
      <para>When entering FTP information, you are presented with the
      following options:</para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Server</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>This is the host name or Internet address of the FTP server
            to send the document to.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Login Name</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>This is the user name required to log in to the FTP
            server.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Password</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>This is the password required to log in to the FTP
            server.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Directory</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>This is the directory in which the recipient wants you to
            put the EDI message on the FTP server.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
      <para>If both the "Login Name" and "Password" fields are empty, the
      xTuple Connect Batch Manager will attempt an anonymous FTP, using the
      name "anonymous" for the "Login Name" and the Email address of the user
      submitting the EDI for the "Password".</para>
    </informalexample></para>
  <para></para>
</section>
