<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2010 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="configureRetail">
  <title>Configure Sales for Retail</title>
  <para>To configure the Sales module for xTuple POS, follow this path:
  <guimenuitem>System &gt; Configure Modules &gt; Sales</guimenuitem>. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <mediaobject>
    <imageobject>
      <imagedata fileref="images/configureSO_configureRetail.png" />
    </imageobject>
    <caption>POS Configuration Options</caption>
  </mediaobject>
  <para>When configuring settings for xTuple POS, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Next Retail Sale #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>All xTuple POS Sale transactions are tracked automatically with
        an identification number called a "Sale Number." When configuring the
        system, you can specify what number you would like to use for the
        first Sale. All subsequent Sales will generate an auto number based on
        the first.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Default Customer for Retail Sales</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select this option to identify a default Customer to be used for
        all Retail Sales. Use this option if you do not want to track
        individual Customer information at the point of sale. The default
        Customer specified here will always be used for Retail
        transactions&mdash;meaning, you won't need to collect and enter
        Customer information every time you make a Sale.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Customer #</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select a Customer to be used as the default Customer. The
              specified Customer will automatically be used for every Retail
              Sale. If you don't hide the "Customer" tab on the Retail Sale
              screen, the default Customer information will be shown. This
              gives you the flexibility to add new Customer information if you
              choose to.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Disable Choosing Customer at Cash Register</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to hide the "Customer" tab on the Retail Sale
              screen. The specified default Customer will always be used in
              the background.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Tax Zone Source</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify one of the following Tax Zone source options:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Site</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if you want Retail Sales to use the Tax Zone
              defined at the Retail Site level. If selected, the Tax Zone
              defined for the Cash Register's Retail Site will be used by
              default for every Retail Sale. This option would be a logical
              choice if you are not collecting Customer information at the
              point of sale.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Customer</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if you want Retail Sales to use the Tax Zone
              defined at the Customer level. If selected, each Retail Sale
              will use the Tax Zone specified for the Customer you are selling
              to.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
