<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2008 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section531874">
  <title id="Anchor28097"><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>receiving</primary>
      <secondary>entering of receipts</secondary>
    </indexterm>Enter Receipt</title>
  <para>To receive Orders into Inventory, select the "Enter Receipt" option.
  The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/enterPoReceipt.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Enter Order Receipts</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When receiving an Order, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Order #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the Order Number of the Purchase Order, Transfer Order or
        Sales Return whose Line Item(s) you want to receive into Inventory.
        The browse button located to the right of the field leads to a
        searchable list of Purchase Orders available for receiving. This
        option will be disabled if a Transfer Order is specified.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="standard">
      <term>Assign all Lot Controlled Items to single Lot #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you want all the Lot-controlled Items in a Receiving
        session to be assigned the same Lot Number. Lot Numbers are assigned
        when Receipt(s) are posted. This option applies to Lot-controlled
        Items only. There is no impact on received Items which are not
        Lot-controlled. For perishable Items, you will also be given the
        opportunity to enter an expiration date. Expiration dates apply only
        to Item Sites marked as perishable.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Order line Items</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists Order Line Items available for receipt
        confirmation.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>Before a Purchase Order can be received successfully, A/P Account
    Assignments for the specified Vendor must be in place.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without entering a Receipt, returning you to
        the application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>PRINT </term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to print the paperwork associated with the specified
        Order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>POST</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select this button to post the Receipt quantity to
        Inventory.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select this button to save the Receipt quantity for posting at a
        later time. Saved Receipts may be posted later from the List Unposted
        Receipts screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>ENTER RECEIPT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a Line Item, then select this button to reach the
        Receipt detail screen. Double-clicking on a Line Item will also bring
        you to the Receipt entry screen. This option will be disabled if a
        Transfer Order is specified.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>RECEIVE ALL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to receive all Line Items simultaneously.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>If the Item you are receiving is a <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>multiple location control</primary>
        <secondary>impact on receiving</secondary>
      </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>receiving</primary>
        <secondary>MLC impact on</secondary>
      </indexterm>Multiple Location Control (MLC) Item, you will be prompted
    to specify the Location you want to distribute the stock to.</para>
  </note>
  <xi:include href="enterPoitemReceipt.xml" xpointer="element(/1)"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
</section>
