<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2008 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section590099">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>financial reports</primary>
      <secondary>balance sheet type</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>balance sheet reports</primary>
    </indexterm>Balance Sheet Report</title>
  <para>The system ships with a basic Balance Sheet designed to generate
  Financial Reports using your Chart of Accounts data. In this section, we
  will examine this basic Balance Sheet.</para>
  <note>
    <para>Because the basic Balance Sheet is a system-defined Financial
    Report, it may not be modified (except to make it active or inactive).
    However, you may copy the report and modify the copy. You can think of the
    basic Balance Sheet as a template for building other, similar Financial
    Reports.</para>
  </note>
  <para>To view the basic Balance Sheet, select it for editing from the master
  list of Financial Reports. A message will alert you that this is a
  system-defined report which may only be viewed, not edited. Select the OK
  button to reach the following screen:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/GL_FR_basicBalSheet.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Basic Balance Sheet System-Defined</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>The "Row Layout" tab displays information on all the Account Groups
  and Account Numbers which make up the basic Balance Sheet. If this were a
  custom report you were creating, you would be able to add/remove Account
  Groups and Account Numbers to meet your specific needs.</para>
  <tip>
    <para>To build row layouts for the three standard report
    types&mdash;Income Statement, Balance Sheet, and Cash Flow&mdash;use the
    same techniques as when building Ad Hoc report row layouts. The only
    difference is you won"t need to specify which balances to calculate (e.g.,
    beginning, ending, etc.). The system determines which calculations will be
    done for the standard statement formats.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>When viewing row layouts for the basic Balance Sheet, you are
  presented with the following columns:</para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Group/Account Name</emphasis>: Lists the
      Account Groups and Account Types used in the report. The two main groups
      are ASSETS and LIABILITIES AND OWNERS EQUITY. All Accounts having
      Type=Asset are included in the ASSETS group. And within the LIABILITIES
      AND OWNERS EQUITY group all Accounts having Type=Liability, Type=Equity,
      and also Net Income are included.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Sub./Summ.</emphasis>: Indicates whether
      group information will be presented as a subtotal or summary line when
      the report is run. In the basic Balance Sheet, all Account Groups are
      subtotaled&mdash;except for the Net Income group, which is
      summarized.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Oper.</emphasis>: Specifies whether a group
      will be added to ("+") or subtracted from ("-") the group total. In the
      basic Income Statement, LIABILITIES AND OWNERS EQUITY are subtracted
      from the ASSETS group.</para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <note>
    <para>Select the VIEW button to see the system-defined settings for each
    Account Group and Account Type used in the basic Income Statement. When
    creating your own reports, you may choose to either imitate or alter these
    default settings.</para>
  </note>
  <para>In addition to row layouts, you may also define column layouts for
  your Financial Reports. Column layouts are used to specify the time buckets
  financial information will be sorted into. You specify a column layout to
  use when viewing or printing Financial Reports. You may define any number of
  column layouts. Each layout will be linked to either a pre-defined report
  definition or a custom report definition you create yourself.</para>
  <para>On the basic Balance Sheet, select the "Column Layouts" tab to view
  all the time buckets available for the report. If this were a custom report
  you were creating, you would be able to add/remove column layouts to meet
  your specific needs.</para>
  <tip>
    <para>See <xref linkend="Anchor94732" /> for specific examples describing
    the various column layout options.</para>
  </tip>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/GL_FR_basicBalSheetCols.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Basic Balance Sheet Column Layouts</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When viewing column layouts for the basic Balance Sheet, you are
  presented with the following column definitions&mdash;each of which defines
  a different time bucket available for viewing Balance Sheet
  information:</para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Current</emphasis>: Displays data for the
      current month (i.e., Accounting Period). The month used as the basis for
      the reporting is specified when the report is run. Uses the
      "FinancialReportMonth" report definition.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Current, Budget</emphasis>: Displays data
      for the current month, compared to Budget information for the current
      month. The month used as the basis for the reporting is specified when
      the report is run. Uses the "FinancialReportMonthBudget" report
      definition.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Current, Prior Month</emphasis>: Displays
      data for the current month, compared to the prior month end. The month
      used as the basis for the reporting is specified when the report is run.
      Uses the "FinancialReportMonthPriorMonth" report definition.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Current, Prior Quarter</emphasis>: Displays
      data for the current month, compared to the prior Quarter end. The month
      used as the basis for the reporting is specified when the report is run.
      Uses the "FinancialReportMonthPriorQuarter" report definition.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Current, Prior Year</emphasis>: Displays
      data for the current month, compared to the Prior Fiscal Year end. The
      month used as the basis for the reporting is specified when the report
      is run. Uses the "FinancialReportMonthPriorYear" report
      definition.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Current, Year Ago</emphasis>: Displays data
      for the current month, compared to the same month in the prior Fiscal
      Year. The month used as the basis for the reporting is specified when
      the report is run. Uses the "FinancialReportMonthPriorMonth" report
      definition.</para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <note>
    <para>Select the VIEW button to see the system-defined settings for each
    Account Group and Account Type used in the basic Income Statement. When
    creating your own reports, you may choose to either imitate or alter these
    default settings.</para>
  </note>
  <tip>
    <para>When creating a column layout, you can choose from the following
    standard report templates:</para>
    <para>FinancialReport (used by all Ad Hoc reports)</para>
    <para>FinancialReportMonth</para>
    <para>FinancialReportMonthBudget</para>
    <para>FinancialReportMonthDbCr</para>
    <para>FinancialReportMonthPriorMonth</para>
    <para>FinancialReportMonthPriorQuarter</para>
    <para>FinancialReportMonthPriorYear</para>
    <para>FinancialReportMonthQuarter</para>
    <para>FinancialReportMonthYear</para>
    <para>FinancialReportQuarter</para>
    <para>FinancialReportQuarterBudget</para>
    <para>FinancialReportQuarterPriorQuarter</para>
    <para>FinancialReportYear</para>
    <para>FinancialReportYearBudget</para>
    <para>FinancialReportYearPriorYear</para>
    <para>FinancialTrend (used by non-Ad-Hoc trend reports)</para>
    <para>If for some reason these templates don"t meet your needs, you can
    always use OpenRPT to a) modify them or b) create your own custom report
    templates.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>To view additional configuration options for the layout of the basic
  Balance Sheet, select the "Options" tab. The following screen will
  appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/GL_FR_basicBalSheetOpt.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Basic Balance Sheet Options</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>The layout for the basic Balance Sheet does not use any extra
  configuration options. However, if you were creating your own Balance Sheet
  layout, you could choose to a) include a Grand Total row and b) use
  alternate labels for Budget and Grand Total rows when viewing and/or
  printing the Financial Report.</para>
</section>