<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2008 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section524365">
  <title id="Anchor26666"><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>check runs</primary>
      <secondary>printing of</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>checks</primary>
      <secondary>printing multiple</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>accounts payable</primary>
      <secondary>printing checks for</secondary>
    </indexterm>Print Check Run</title>
  <para>To print a Check Run, select the "Print Check Run" option. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/AP_Pay_printChkRun.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Print Check Run</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <tip>
    <para>If Checks being printed contain reference lines which spill over and
    exceed one standard page, then consider using the report definition
    CheckMultiPage.xml. This Check Form is designed to support multiple pages
    for one Check number.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>When printing a Check Run, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Bank Account</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the Bank Account associated with the Check Run you want
        to print.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>First Check #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the first available Check Number in the Check Run for
        the specified Bank Account.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term># of Checks to Print</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify how many Checks should be printed in the Check Run.
        Check Numbers increment in intervals of one (1) beginning with the
        first Check Number displayed above. The maximum possible selection
        indicates the maximum number of Checks in the Check Run. Selecting a
        number less than the maximum will cause that number of Checks to be
        printed, leaving the remaining number still to be printed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without printing the Check Run, returning you
        to the application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>PRINT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Prints the Check Run, using the specified parameters.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>check runs</primary>
      <secondary>problems when printing</secondary>
    </indexterm>If for some reason you experience printing problems when
  printing a Check Run, select the NO button from the following screen:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/AP_Pay_chkPrtSuccess.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Print Message</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>If you select the NO button at the end of printing a Check Run, the
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/AP_Pay_reviewPrtChks.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Review List of Printed Checks</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>The Review Printed Checks screen lists all the Checks which were
  included in the Check Run.</para>
  <note>
    <para>The default action listed for all Checks in a Check Run is
    "Printed." Each Check will be marked as printed when you select the
    COMPLETE button, unless you specify one of the other possible actions:
    void, replace, etc.</para>
  </note>
  <para>When reviewing the list of Checks included in a Check Run, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>COMPLETE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to perform the specified action associated with each of
        the listed Checks. This should be the last option selected at the
        conclusion of your Check Run review. Selecting this option terminates
        the review process. If no action is specified for a Check, the status
        of the Check will remain as it was prior to printing the Check
        Run.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>UNMARK</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a Check Number and then select this option to remove
        any action associated with the Check. If no action is specified for a
        Check, the status of the Check will remain as it was prior to printing
        the Check Run.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>You may select multiple Checks for marking using the SHIFT or CTRL
    keys and your mouse.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>MARK AS PRINTED</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a Check Number and then select this option to mark the
        Check as printed. By default, all Checks in a Check Run are marked as
        printed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>VOID</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a Check Number and then select this option to mark the
        Check as voided. Before a Check can be replaced, it must first be
        voided.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>VOID &amp; REPLACE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a Check Number and then select this option to mark the
        Check as voided and then replace the Check with a new Check. Using
        this option, you can both void and replace a Check in one step.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SELECT ALL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Use this option to automatically select all Checks for marking,
        or unmarking.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>