<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2011 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="registration" role="standard">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>databases</primary>
      <secondary>registration for</secondary>
    </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>registration</primary>
      <secondary>commercial versions and</secondary>
    </indexterm>Registration</title>
  <para>Users of the commercial editions of xTuple ERP are required to enter a
  license key to verify their registration of the software. This requirement
  does not apply to users of the PostBooks edition. To register your
  commercial installation, select the "Registration" option. The following
  screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/registration.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Registration Information</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When registering your commercial installation, you are presented with
  the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Registration Key</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the license key you received from xTuple&mdash;or from
        your authorized xTuple solution provider. Once a valid license key has
        been entered, the following information will be displayed:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Customer</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the name of your company.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Expiration Date</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the date when your registration expires. Expired
              license keys can be renewed for another term either by
              contacting xTuple or your authorized xTuple solution
              provider.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Max Concurrent Users</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the maximum number of concurrent xTuple client
              connections you are licensed to have, as per the terms of your
              xTuple license agreement. Included in this total are concurrent
              connections made from xTuple ERP, xTuple Connect, and/or any
              other xTuple-branded client software. If you are exceeding your
              maximum number of licensed users, you should arrange to purchase
              more licenses either by contacting xTuple or your authorized
              xTuple solution provider. For non-xTuple client connections
              (e.g., pgAdmin, web interfaces, etc.), you are allowed up to
              double your number of licensed users. For example, if you have
              10 licensed users, then you would be allowed up to 20 non-xTuple
              client connections. Additional external connections are allowed
              for sites where the xTuple Web Portal is installed. To get an
              accurate view of all your current connections, use the following
              menu path from the graphical xTuple Desktop: <guimenu>Window
              &gt; Desktop &gt; Users Online</guimenu>.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
