<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2011 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section role="xtconnect">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>xtuple connect</primary>
      <secondary>configuration of</secondary>
    </indexterm> Configure xTuple Connect</title>
  <para>xTuple Connect is an extension of xTuple ERP that supports the
  automated integration of xTuple with other systems, transports xTuple
  information via mechanisms such as email and FTP, lets you schedule the
  start-time of long-running reports and database maintenance tasks, and
  allows setting up and running repeating jobs. It may be purchased from
  xTuple for use with all editions of xTuple ERP.</para>
  <para>There are two components to xTuple Connect:</para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>The xtConnect package adds features to the xTuple ERP application.
      These features include new menu options and windows and new buttons and
      fields on existing windows. These windows, buttons, and fields let you
      configure xTuple Connect and submit and schedule jobs to the xTuple
      Connect Batch Manager.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>The xTuple Connect Batch Manager client is a separate program that
      does the actual work. It runs continually, checking for jobs to start
      and running them at the appropriate time. The xTuple Connect Batch
      Manager runs the reports, sends the email, downloads files from FTP
      servers, and more.</para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>To configure the connection between xTuple Connect and xTuple ERP,
  select the "xTuple Connect" option. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/configxTupleConnect.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Configure xTuple Connect</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When configuring the connection between xTuple Connect and xTuple ERP,
  you are presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>xTuple Connect Enabled</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>If you have xTuple Connect installed on your system and you want
        to enable/activate it, then select this option.</para>
        <tip>
          <para>You should log out/log in after enabling xTuple Connect on
          your system.</para>
        </tip>
        <para>Once selected, any jobs submitted to the xTuple Connect Batch
        Manager will be processed. If the option is not selected, then you
        will not be able to submit jobs to the xTuple Connect Batch Manager.
        The following options should also be specified:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Default From Email Address</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter an email address to be used as the default "From"
              address in situations when no other "From" address is specified.
              For example, this feature would apply if no email address is
              entered in the "From" field when scheduling an Invoice for email
              delivery.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Purge Jobs after</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify how frequently (in days) you want to purge
              already-completed Batch Manager jobs.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Automatically Create Contacts During Email Sync</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you want new Contact records to be created in xTuple
        ERP when importing email from people you do not already have Contact
        records for. This option applies only if you are using the Email
        Integration feature for xTuple Connect. Enabling this option impacts
        Contact record creation only. It has no impact on your ability to
        import email. </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Exclude Contacts Matching</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>If you enable the configuration to create new Contact records
        when email is imported, you can develop an exclusion list (i.e., black
        list) to block users and/or domains you do not want to create Contact
        records for. The exclusion list supports pattern matching, which
        increases your ability to block the users and/or domains you do not
        want Contact records for.</para>
        <para>To develop an email exclusion list, select the NEW button. The
        following screen will appear:</para>
        <para><screenshot>
            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="images/emailExclusion.png" />
              </imageobject>
              <caption>Excluded Contacts List</caption>
            </mediaobject>
          </screenshot></para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
