<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2011 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="contactMerge">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>contacts</primary>
      <secondary>merging</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>contacts</primary>
      <secondary>managing</secondary>
    </indexterm>Contact Merge</title>
  <para>If you are importing Contact information&mdash;either through the
  xTuple web Portal or xTuple Email Integration or some other
  feature&mdash;it's likely you will encounter duplicate Contact records. The
  Contact Merge utility is designed to help you resolve this scenario. Using
  the Contact Merge utility, you can easily locate duplicate records and merge
  them into one single Contact record. In this way you can also preserve
  multiple email addresses for your Contacts.</para>
  <tip>
    <para>How-to information about using the Contact Merge utility is
    available on our community website here: <ulink
    url="http://www.xtuple.org/contactmerge">www.xtuple.org/contactmerge</ulink>.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>To begin using the Contact Merge utility, select the "Contact Merge"
  option. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/contactMerge.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Contact Merge Utility</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When using the Contact Merge utility, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Mode</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select one of the following modes to expedite processing:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Merge</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Allows the user to query Contacts using the specified
              search criteria. Merges all source Contact selections when
              "Merge" is clicked.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Purge</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays all merged Contacts. Purges all merged Contacts
              at once when "Purge" is clicked.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Merge and Purge</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Allows the user to query Contacts using the specified
              search criteria. Merges and purges source Contacts in one step
              when "Merge and Purge" is clicked.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Restore</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays all merged Contacts. Restores all merged Contacts
              at once when "Restore" is clicked.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Search for:</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter search terms or patterns to locate the Contact records you
        are looking for.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Search Through</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify which of the search filters you want to be included when
        you are searching for Contact records.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Find duplicates with matching criteria</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you want the Contact Merge utility to automatically
        locate duplicate records using search criteria you specify with your
        selections.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Contacts</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists Contact records matching the search criteria you
        specified. In this display you mark Contacts you want to merge as
        either "source" or "target" Contacts. When merging Contact records,
        source Contacts are merged into target Contacts&mdash;leaving behind
        only the target Contact record.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>In addition to the basic Contact references, specific data elements of
  a source Contact may also be carried over to the merged target
  Contact&mdash;information such as the notes, phone numbers, or the email
  address. To select these specific data elements for merging, go to the
  "Selections" tab":</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/contactMerge_selTab.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Selected Contacts</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When merging specific data elements for selected Contacts, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Source Contacts</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays any Contact records you specified as source Contacts on
        the "Contacts" tab. If you right-click on any of the cells of the
        Source Contacts list, you can choose to merge that cell to the target
        Contact. The cell's contents will turn blue when selected.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Target Contact</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the target Contact record. When you merge Contacts, the
        target Contact record will receive the specified data elements
        selected in the source Contact(s) records.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
