<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2011 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="dspMRPExceptions" role="standard">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>mrp</primary>
      <secondary>exceptions handling and</secondary>
    </indexterm> MRP Exceptions</title>
  <para>The MRP Exceptions feature set extends the MRP planning system by
  offering advice on existing Work Orders and Purchase Orders in the form of
  exception messages. The goal of these messages is to identify supply orders
  which need to be either scheduled farther into the future (i.e., pushed),
  scheduled closer to the present day (i.e., pulled), or removed as
  unnecessary (i.e., canceled). Using the "MRP Exceptions" screen, you can
  manage these exception messages manually&mdash;taking action as deemed
  necessary. Or you can automate the process using MRP and the Planner Code
  options designed for MRP Exception handling. For more information about the
  Planner Code settings related to MRP Exceptions, please see <xref
  linkend="plannerCode" />.</para>
  <para>To manage your MRP Exceptions, select the "MRP Exceptions" option. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/dspMRPException.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>MRP Exceptions</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When managing MRP Exceptions, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Filter By</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the primary filter you want to use when managing MRP
        Exceptions:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Planner Code</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>If selected, you will be presented with a range of Planner
              Code options to filter by.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Item</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>If selected, you will be prompted to enter the Item Number
              you want to filter by.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Site</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the Site filter you want to use:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>All Sites</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to display MRP Exceptions for all Sites.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Selected</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify Site whose MRP Exceptions you want to
              display.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Show Only</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>To limit the displayed information to include only results
        having exception messages, select one or both of the following
        options:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Schedule Exceptions</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to include exception message results for supply
              orders that need to be rescheduled&mdash;that is, either pushed
              into the future or pulled closer to the present day. Using the
              "Min. Days" feature, specify the minimum number of days you care
              about. For example, if you only want to see supply orders that
              are less than a week off schedule, enter a value of "6".</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Cancel Exceptions</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to include exception message results for supply
              orders that need to be canceled. Using the "Min. Quantity"
              feature, specify the minimum quantity you care about. For
              example, if you only want to see supply orders where the excess
              is less than 100 units, enter a value of "99".</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Exceptions</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists MRP Exceptions, using the specified parameters. If
        you do not limit the display using one or both of the "Show Only"
        options, some results may not have exception suggestions&mdash;and in
        those cases the information shown will resemble running availability.
        For rows where exceptions have been found, the details of the
        exception (push, pull, or cancel) will be shown under the "Exception
        Messages" column. Use the right-click menu to quickly take action on
        the exception messages.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CREATE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to generate MRP Exceptions. When selected, you will be
        presented with the "Run MRP Exceptions" screen which allows you to
        specify additional options. This button performs the same action as
        the "Create MRP Exceptions" flag that is available when you are
        running MRP. Depending on how your Planner Codes are set up, the
        action taken in response to MRP Exceptions may either be automatic or
        manual.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <xi:include href="runMRPException.xml" xpointer="element(/1)"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
</section>
