<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2011 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section518773" role="standard">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>planned orders</primary>
      <secondary>reporting for</secondary>
    </indexterm>Planned Orders</title>
  <para>The "Planned Orders" screen shows you the Planned Orders created by
  the Material Requirements Planning (MRP) system to meet existing demand.
  From this screen you can manage your Planned Orders&mdash;from releasing
  Orders to firming them, editing them, or deleting them. The information on
  this screen will be updated whenever MRP is run.</para>
  <para>Here are some tips for using this screen:</para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>Use the right-click menu to manage your Planned Orders.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>The Running Availability option on the right-click menu will help
      you to understand the relationship between Planned Orders and the demand
      they are pegged to.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>When a Planned Work Order is released, the Create Work Order
      screen will appear with Work Order details automatically filled
      in.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>Releasing a Planned Purchase Order results in a Purchase Request,
      which may in turn be released from the Purchase Request reports.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>In the case of Planned Purchase Orders, the quantity will always
      be represented in the Inventory Unit of Measure (UOM)&mdash;regardless
      of the Vendor UOM used on any existing Purchase Orders.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>Planned Orders must be firm before they will be considered as a
      valid source of supply by Material Requirements Planning (MRP) when MRP
      is run.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>Firm Planned Orders will display in blue.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>If you edit a firm Planned Order the Order will no longer be firm.
      It will have to be re-firmed.</para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>The following screenshot shows the "Planned Orders" screen:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/dspPlannedOrders.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Planned Orders</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>The default filter on the "Planned Orders" screen shows all Planned
  Orders for the current day. You can build your own search criteria using the
  following options:</para>
  <xi:include href="../widgets/parameterwidget.xml" xpointer="parameterwidget"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
</section>
