<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2011 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="syncCompanies" role="standard">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>companies, synchronizing of</primary>
    </indexterm>Synchronize Companies</title>
  <para>The synchronize Companies utility is designed to synchronize a parent
  database with child databases for the purpose of consolidated financial
  reporting. This utility will only be visible when external Company
  consolidation is enabled on the Accounting configuration screen&mdash;and
  then only when users have appropriate permissions.</para>
  <para>When you elect to synchronize a child database with a parent, the
  application will check to make sure a Currency Exchange Rate exists between
  the functional Currency of the child and that of the parent for each
  Accounting Period to be imported. The system will also check for needed
  Account Assignments, including the Unrealized Gain/Loss Account tied to the
  child Company's Currency. If any requirements are missing, the process will
  stop and you will be presented with an error message describing the missing
  information.</para>
  <para>Once all synchronization criteria are met, the synchronizer will
  import the Trial Balance of the child database to the Trial Balance table of
  the parent database in the parent's functional Currency using the Exchange
  Rate defined for the end of the specified Accounting Period(s) in the parent
  database. The parent database will keep a record of the Exchange Rate used
  for the import. If the Exchange Rate for that date is subsequently changed,
  the Exchange Rate record will be marked as "dirty"&mdash;and on the next
  subsequent synchronization, the Trial Balance data of the child will be
  re-imported using the new Exchange Rate. A warning will be shown when
  running Trial Balances or Financial Reports having "dirty" Exchange Rate
  data.</para>
  <para>To synchronize Companies, select the "Synchronize Companies" option.
  The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/syncCompanies.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Synchronize Companies</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When synchronizing Companies, you are presented with the following
  lists:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Periods</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select one or more Accounting Periods to synchronize.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Companies</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select one or more external Companies to synchronize.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SELECT ALL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Selects all the contents of the list above the button.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CLEAR SELECTION</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>De-selects all the contents of the list above the button.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SYNCHRONIZE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Executes the Company synchronization process.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
