<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">
<article>
  <title>Import Report GUI (<command>importrptgui</command>) Tool</title>

  <section>
    <title>Description</title>

    <para>The <command>importrptgui</command> tool is designed to simplify the
    process of uploading multiple reports to an OpenMFG database.</para>

    <para>When you open the utility, you will notice you are brought to the
    standard log in screen. Log in to the database where you want to upload
    your reports--these may be newly created reports, or updated versions of
    already existing reports.</para>

    <para>Using the ADD button on the GUI screen, browse for the directory
    where the report .xml files are located on your system. Once you have
    located and opened the directory where the files are stored, you may add
    them individually by double-clicking on them one-at-a-time. Or you may
    select all or a subset of the total using your window manager.</para>

    <para>If after you are done adding reports to the list you find a report
    which you do not want to upload, simply hightlight the reoprt and select
    the REMOVE button. THe report will be removed from the list, and it will
    not be uploaded. Once you are satisfied with your list of reports,
    highlight individual reports or use the SELECT ALL button to select all
    the reports for importing. Once the desired reports have been highlighted,
    select the IMPORT button. The hightlighted reports will be uploaded to the
    database you loggted into at the beginning of your session.</para>

    <para>By default all the reports you load into the
    <command>importrptgui</command> tool will be loaded with a grade of 0. If
    you wish to change this you may do so on a report-by-report basis. To do
    this double-click a report definition that you have opened. This will
    present you with a screen that allows you to change the value of the grade
    that report will be loaded as.</para>

    <para>To exit, select the EXIT option from the "File" menu.</para>
  </section>
</article>