<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2008 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section657140">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>invoices</primary>
      <secondary>email delivery of</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>electronic data interchange</primary>
      <secondary>invoice delivery using</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>EDI</primary>
      <see>electronic data interchange</see>
    </indexterm>E-mail Invoice Form</title>
  <para>To send a copy of a Customer Invoice by email, select the "E-mail
  Invoice Form" option. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/deliverInvoice.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>E-mail Invoice Form</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When sending a copy of a Customer Invoice by email, you are presented
  with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Invoices</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists all Invoices available for email delivery.
        Highlight the Invoice you want to schedule for email delivery using
        your mouse button.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>Customers are set up to receive email deliveries of information
    using the Electronic Data Interchange (EDI) tab on the Customer
    master.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>From</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The default address appearing in the "From" field will belong to
        the user who is currently logged in to the application. This address
        may be edited or changed. User email addresses are stored with user
        records at the system level.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Send To</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>If the Customer associated with the selected Invoice has been
        set up to receive email, then the default email address for that
        Customer will be automatically pre-populated here. Because this is an
        editable field, you may also change the email address.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Cc</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>If EDI is set up for the Customer, then the default carbon copy
        (i.e., Cc:) line found on the Customer master will be automatically
        pre-populated here. Because this is an editable field, you may also
        modify the Cc: line.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Subject</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>If EDI is set up for the Customer, then the default subject line
        found on the Customer master will be automatically pre-populated here.
        Because this is an editable field, you may also modify the subject
        line.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Filename</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>If EDI is set up for the Customer, then the default filename
        found on the Customer master will be automatically pre-populated here.
        Because this is an editable field, you may also modify the filename
        line. XML tags may be used in this field to dynamically generate
        filename text. In the example shown in the screenshot above, the
        filename will include the Document Type (i.e., Invoice) and the
        Document Number (i.e., Invoice Number).</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Email Body</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>If EDI is set up for the Customer, then the default email body
        found on the Customer master will be automatically pre-populated here.
        This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping. You may also edit
        the default email body.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Send Email as HTML</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you want the body of the Email to be sent as HTML. If
        not selected, the Email will be sent as plain text.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Mark Invoice as having been Printed</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to mark highlighted Invoice as having been
        printed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without scheduling an Invoice for email
        delivery, returning you to the application desktop.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SUBMIT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to submit requested action to the Batch Manager for
        processing.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>