<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2008 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section>
  <title>External Shipping Maintenance</title>
  <para>To create or maintain shipping data exported to external shipping
  packages like UPS WorldShip, select the NEW button. The following screen
  will appear:</para>
  <screenshot>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/externalShipping.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption>External Shipping Maintenance</caption>
    </mediaobject>
  </screenshot>
  <para>When entering new shipping data you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>S/O #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the Order Number of the Sales Order you want to maintain.
        The browse button located to the right of the field leads to a
        searchable list of Sales Orders available for maintenance.</para>
        <note>
          <para>The text below the S/O field represents the order type (i.e.,
          "SO") and Status (i.e., "C"). Below this text us the customer name
          (i.e., "Tremendous Toys Incorporated")</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Shipment #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the Shipment Number of the internal shipment order created
        to ship Sales Order. The browse button located to the right of the
        field leads to a searchable list of Shipment numbers.</para>
        <note>
          <para>The text below shipment number identifies the tracking number
          entered on the shipment order</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Shipper</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select the external third party shipper shipping this order
        (i.e., UPS, FedEx, etc.).</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Package Tracking Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the Package Tracking Number that represents the external
        shippers tracking number for the individual package, which could be
        comprised of one of many or one of one.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Tracking Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the Tracking Number that represents external shipper's
        tracking number for the entire order, which can be a group of
        packages.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Package Type</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select the package type identified on the</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Void</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select the List option if the shipment has been voided.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Billing Option</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the Billing Option which identifies how the shipment was
        billed by the external shipper (i.e., Prepaid, COD, etc.).</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Weight</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify weight of shipment reported to external shipper.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Base Freight</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the amount of the base freight charge to be charged to the
        specified Order. Freight charges may be entered during the creation or
        modification of an Order&mdash;or at the time of shipment.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Total Freight</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the amount of the total freight charge to be charged to
        the complete order including taxes and surcharges.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Last Updated</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Review automatic timestamp which identifies last modification to
        record.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>