<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2008 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section>
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>scripts</primary>
      <secondary>creating new</secondary>
    </indexterm>Script Editor</title>
  <para>To create a new script, select the NEW button. The following screen
  will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/scriptEditor.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create New Script</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When creating a new script, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a name to identify the script. The name of the script must
        match the name of the screen the script will be used for. If the
        script name does not match the screen name, the script will not be
        used. Because a single screen may require more than one script, you
        may save multiple scripts having the same name. The order, notes, and
        content of each script will distinguish one from the other.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Notes</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a brief description of the script.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Order</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the order in which the script should be run. The script
        having the lowest number (i.e., "0") will be run first, and then
        following scripts will be run in consecutive order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Enabled</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to enable the script. If not selected, the script will be
        disabled. A disabled script will not be run when the corresponding
        screen is executed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Script</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the content of the script using QtScript. You may type the
        script directly into this window, or you may import a script using the
        IMPORT SCRIPT button.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without saving any changes.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Saves the script and adds it to the scripts master list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>IMPORT SCRIPT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to import a script from your local file system into the
        database. This option is useful if you prefer to do your scripting
        using an external script editor. The script you import will be shown
        in the script window.</para>
        <warning>
          <para>Every time you import a script file, the new script will
          replace the script which was shown in the script window
          previously.</para>
        </warning>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>EXPORT SCRIPT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to export the script shown in the script window to your
        local file system. You would use this option if you need or want to
        edit the script and do not have a copy stored locally on your system.
        Once exported, the script can be edited using an external editor—and
        then re-imported into the database using the import option. Whenever
        you import a script file, it automatically replaces whatever script
        was in place before it.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>