<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2008 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="warehouse">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>sites</primary>
      <secondary>creating new</secondary>
    </indexterm>Site</title>
  <para>To create a new Site, select the NEW button. The following screen will
  appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/warehouse.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create New Inventory Site</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <tip>
    <para>Site Codes are abbreviations used to quickly and easily identify
    Sites. Keep these Codes short and meaningful so Employees will have an
    easy time identifying them.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>When creating a new Site, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Code</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The Site code is used to identify a given Site.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Type</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the Site Type from the list of user-defined values.
        Sites may be defined in any number of ways&horbar;as warehouses,
        stores, etc. To learn more about Site Types, see <xref
        linkend="siteTypesTitle" />.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Active</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to specify the Site is active. Not selecting means the
        Site will be considered inactive. To re-activate a Site, simply select
        this option.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Description</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a brief description of the Site.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>If a new Address is manually entered here, that Address will be
    added automatically to the master list of Addresses.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Address</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Manually enter Address information in the fields below&mdash;or
        use the browse button to select pre-existing Address information. The
        Site Address is used on shipping and receiving paperwork.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Street Address</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the street Address for the Site.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>City</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the city where the Site is located.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>State</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the state where the Site is located.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Postal Code</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the Postal Code for the Site.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Country</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the country where the Site is located.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>If a new Contact is manually entered here, that Contact will be
    added automatically to the master list of Contacts.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Contact</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Manually enter Contact information in the fields below&mdash;or
        use the browse button to select pre-existing Contact
        information.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Title</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select a Title from the list of available Titles.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>First</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the Contact's first name.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Last</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the Contact's last name.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Job Title</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the Contact's job title.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Voice</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the Contact's phone number.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Fax</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the Contact's fax number.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>E-Mail</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the Contact's e-mail address.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Post Unassigned Transactions to</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify a General Ledger Account to post unassigned transactions
        to. This account is used as a general bucket for General Ledger
        transactions which the system, for one reason or another, may not know
        how to handle. A transaction is considered unassigned if the affected
        Item Site does not have a Cost Category assigned to it for the
        transaction type in question. By specifying an Account to post
        unassigned transactions to, you can remove most of the ambiguous error
        messages that may result from inadequately assigned Item Site Cost
        Categories. For example, if an Inventory Asset Account is not defined,
        Inventory transactions may proceed&mdash;but the Asset portion of the
        transactions will be posted to the unassigned transaction
        Account.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Inventory Site</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if the Site is to be used for Inventory storage. The
        following options are available for Inventory Sites:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Next <indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>bills of lading</primary>
                <secondary>numbering of</secondary>
              </indexterm>Bill of Lading #</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>There are two parts to this field. These two parts include
              a "prefix" that will appear at the beginning of all
              system-generated bill of lading numbers for this Site and a
              starting number sequence (e.g., 10000, 20000, etc.). Use the
              first field window to prefix the bill of lading number with
              user-defined information (e.g., Site code). Prefixing bill of
              lading numbers may be helpful in tracking Items that were
              shipped to customers from a specific Site Location. Use the
              second part of this two-part field window to enter an unlimited
              number of whole numbers.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Next <indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>count tags</primary>
                <secondary>numbering of</secondary>
              </indexterm>Count Tag#</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>There are two parts to this field. These two parts include
              a "prefix" that will appear at the beginning of all
              system-generated Count Tag Numbers for this Site and a starting
              number sequence (e.g., 10000, 20000, etc.). Use the first field
              window to prefix the Count Tag Number with user-defined
              information (e.g., Site code). Use the second part of this
              two-part field window to enter an unlimited number of whole
              numbers.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>shipping sites</primary>
                <secondary>designation of</secondary>
              </indexterm>Shipping Site</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if the Site is used for Shipping. Not selecting
              means materials are not shipped from the Site.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Force the use of Count Slips</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to enforce the use of Count Slips. Not selecting
              means Count Slips will not be required when counting Inventory
              in this Site.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>zones</primary>
                <secondary>enforcing in sites</secondary>
              </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>sites</primary>
                <secondary>enforcing zones in</secondary>
              </indexterm>Enforce the use of Zones</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to enforce the use of Zones within the Site. A Site
              Zone is a defined section or area within a Site. For example,
              separate Site Zones might be designated to define areas where
              Orders are selected, Picked, and Packed. If selected, Zones may
              be specified when defining Site Locations. If not selected, Site
              Locations may not include Zones.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Shipping Commission</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter a commission percentage to be charged whenever
              Inventory is shipped from the Site. This is an optional feature
              to be used specifically for contract Sites, which charge a
              commission based on shipping volume. If the Site does not charge
              a commission, then this field may be ignored, leaving the
              default value of "0.00".</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>tax authorities</primary>
                <secondary>for sites</secondary>
              </indexterm>Tax Authority</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the Tax Authority associated with the Site.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>default FOB</primary>
                <secondary>in site master</secondary>
              </indexterm>Default F.O.B</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter default free on board (FOB) Terms for the Site. The
              default F.O.B. Terms will be entered on the Sales Order header
              for any Orders where the Site is specified as the Shipping
              Site.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para role="standard">Transit Sites are special Sites used by Transfer
  Orders. When Transfer Order Inventory is shipped from the Source Site, it is
  moved to a Transit Site. Inventory stays in the Transit Site until it is
  received at the Destination Site. If the Site is to be used as a Transit
  Site, select the "Transit Site" option. The following changes to the main
  screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/warehouse_transit.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create New Transit Site</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <tip>
    <para>Be sure to define a default Transit Site on your Inventory
    Configuration screen. This will make it easier to generate Transfer
    Orders, as Transit Sites are required for Transfer Orders.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>When defining a Site as a Transit Site, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Default Ship Via</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify a default Ship Via to be used by the Transit Site. The
        selected Ship Via will be used by default on the Transfer Order header
        whenever the specified Transit Site is used.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Default Shipping Form</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify a default Shipping Form to be used by the Transit Site.
        The selected Shipping Form will be used by default on the Transfer
        Order header whenever the specified Transit Site is used.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>The Shipping Form will be used when printing Packing Lists for the
    Transfer Order.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Default Cost Category</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify a default Cost Category to be used by the Transit Site.
        Associating a Cost Category with a Transit Site makes it possible for
        the system to create Item Sites for Transit Sites automatically when
        Transfer Order Inventory is shipped. This greatly simplifies the use
        of Transit Sites, as Item Sites do not need to be created manually
        beforehand. The accounting for in-transit goods is handled by the
        default Cost Category associated with the Transit Site.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>Consider creating a separate Cost Category for Transit Sites. In
    this way you can use unique Accounts to reflect the movement of Inventory
    which is in-transit.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Shipping Comments</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter shipping Comments you want to associate with the Transit
        Site. Shipping Comments entered here will be used on any Transfer
        Order which uses specified Transit Site. This is a scrolling text
        field with word-wrapping for entering shipping Comments.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without creating a Site, returning you to the
        previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Creates the Site and adds it to the master list of Sites.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To define ARBL (Aisle, Rack, Bin, Location) naming conventions for
  your Site Locations, select the "Site Locations" tab. The following screen
  will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/warehouse_locationsTab.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Site Locations Master List</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When defining ARBL naming conventions for your Site Locations, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>ARBL</primary>
          <secondary>enforcing in sites</secondary>
        </indexterm>Enforce ARBL Naming Convention</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to enforce the aisle, rack, bin, Location (ARBL) naming
        convention when defining Site Locations. Specify values for the
        following ARBL parameters:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Aisle Size</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the maximum number of characters allowed in an
              aisle name by using the arrow buttons or manually entering a
              value up to a maximum of 99. Also specify whether alpha
              characters are allowed in aisle names.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Rack Size</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the maximum number of characters allowed in a rack
              name by using the arrow buttons or manually entering a value up
              to a maximum of 99. Also specify whether alpha characters are
              allowed in rack names.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Bin Size</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the maximum number of characters allowed in a bin
              name by using the arrow buttons or manually entering a value up
              to a maximum of 99. Also specify whether alpha characters are
              allowed in bin names.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Location Size</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the maximum number of characters allowed in a
              Location name by using the arrow buttons or manually entering a
              value up to a maximum of 99. Also specify whether alpha
              characters are allowed in Location names.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>Site Zones are defined sections or areas within a Site. For example,
  separate Site Zones might be designated to define areas where Orders are
  selected, Picked, and Packed. To define or maintain Site Zones, select the
  "Site Zones" tab. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/warehouse_zonesTab.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Site Zones Master List</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When defining or maintaining Site Zones, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>zones</primary>
          <secondary>for sites</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sites</primary>
          <secondary>zones for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Site Zones</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display includes Site Zones for the specified Site.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Opens screen for creating a new Site Zone.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>EDIT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enables you to edit highlighted Site Zones. The edit screen is
        the same as that for creating a new Site Zone&mdash;except that when
        editing, the fields will contain Site Zone information.
        Double-clicking on a Site Zone also bring you to the editing
        screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>DELETE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a Site Zone and then select this button to remove the
        Zone from the list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>sites</primary>
      <secondary>creating zones in</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>zones</primary>
      <secondary>creating new in site</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>site zones</primary>
      <secondary>creating new</secondary>
    </indexterm>create a new Site Zone, select the NEW button. The following
  screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/warehouseZone.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create New Site Zone</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When creating a new Site Zone, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a unique name for the Site Zone.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Description</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a brief description of the Site Zone.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without adding a new Site Zone to the list of
        Site Zones.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Creates the Site Zone and adds it to the list of Site
        Zones.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To associate Comments with a Site, select the "Comments" tab. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/warehouse_commentsTab.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Add Site Comments</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Comments</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists the date Comment entered, Comment Type, user who
        entered Comment, and a content preview.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Opens screen for creating a new Comment.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>VIEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a Comment and then select this button to reach a
        read-only view of the Comment.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To create a new Comment, select the NEW button. The following screen
  will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/CommentNew.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create New Comment</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Comment Type</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify one of the following Comment Types from the drop-down
        list: ChangeLog or General. Comment Types are used to categorize
        Comments. Once you have specified a Comment Type, you may type your
        Comment in the main text area. The text area features word-wrapping
        and scroll-bar support for longer Comments.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without creating the Comment, returning you to
        the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Creates the Comment and adds it to the list of Comments.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>