<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2008 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="Section538592" role="openmfg">
  <title>Site Week</title>
  <para>Site weeks are used to define the days of the week when a
  Site is open for business. For example, a production Site may
  operate from Monday-Friday; whereas, the hours for a Shipping Site may
  also include the weekend.</para>
  <note>
    <para>The Constraint Management system considers work week settings when
    calculating time buffers for Item Sites.</para>
  </note>
  <para>To define the work week for a Site(s), select the "Site
  Week" option. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/whseWeek.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create New Site Work Week</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When defining the work week for a Site, you are presented with
  the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>All Sites</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to create a blanket schedule for all Sites. Specify
        which days the Sites are open for business. Settings made using
        this option will be inherited by all Sites.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>After creating a blanket schedule for all Sites, you may then
    switch to the selected mode and modify the schedules for individual
    Sites.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Selected</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select the Site whose work week you want to define. Specify
        which days the Site is open for business. Settings made using
        this option are specific to the selected Site.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To the far right of the screen, the following buttons are
  available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Closes the screen without creating work weeks for your
        Sites, returning you to the previous screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Creates the settings for any Site weeks you have
        defined.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
